<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>Diary of Mrs. Emma B. Andrews. Volume 14 1906-1907</title>
        <author>
          <persName ref="#Andrews_Emma_B">Emma B. Andrews</persName>
        </author>
        <editor>
          <persName ref="SK">Sarah Ketchley </persName>
        </editor>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>
          <orgName ref="#Emma_B_Andrews_Diary_Project">Emma B. Andrews Diary Project</orgName>
        </publisher>
        <address>
          <addrLine>University of Washington, Seattle, WA</addrLine>
        </address>
        <availability>
          <licence target="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/">This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</licence>
        </availability>
        <date>2021-02-03</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <p><name ref="#American_Philosophical_Society_Philadelphia">American Philosophical Society, Philadelphia</name></p>
      </sourceDesc>
      <encodingStmt>
        <projectDesc>
          <p>Established in 2010, the goals of the <name ref="#Emma_B_Andrews_Diary_Project">Emma B. Andrews Diary Project</name> include the transcription and digitization of a wide range of primary historical material from the <orgName ref="#'Golden_Age'">'Golden Age'</orgName> of <orgName ref="#Egyptian">Egyptian</orgName> archaeology at the end of the 19th and beginning of the 20th centuries. A founding partner of <name ref="#Newbook_Digital">Newbook Digital</name> Texts (www.newbookdigitaltexts.org), the <name ref="#EBA_Diary_Project">EBA Diary Project</name> offers undergraduate and graduate digital humanities education and internships at the <name ref="#University_of_Washington">University of Washington.</name> <persName ref="#Andrews_Emma_B">Emma B. Andrews</persName> is best remembered for her association with the millionaire lawyer turned archaeologist/art and antiquities collector, <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore M. Davis.</persName> Traveling to <placeName ref="#Egypt">Egypt</placeName> with him between 1889 and 1912, she kept detailed journals of these voyages along the <orgName ref="#Nile">Nile,</orgName> including his important yet under-reported excavations of over 20 significant tombs in the <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">Valley of the Kings.</placeName> <persName ref="#Emma">Emma</persName> provides a vital commentary on the archaeology and pioneering <orgName ref="#Egyptologists">Egyptologists</orgName> of the time, painting a revealing picture of the lives of the colonial gentry and the cultural and scientific literati in at the dawn of the twentieth century. Analysis of the content of her diaries, along with a broad range of additional primary source material, will afford scholars information about important historical resources for the first time.</p>
        </projectDesc>
      </encodingStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-11-15" type="entry">
        <dateline><name type="boat" ref="#SS_Konig_Albert">S.S. Koenig Albert</name> - <placeName ref="#Azores"> Off the Azores</placeName> - <date when="1906-11-15">Nov. 15th</date>.</dateline>
        <p>We left <placeName ref="#New_York">New York</placeName> on the 10th after spending 8 days between <placeName ref="#New_York">N.Y.</placeName> and <placeName ref="#Washington_DC">Washington</placeName>. I left an unfinished garden at <placeName ref="#Newport">Newport</placeName> - the weather for a week before we left being very stormy and bad. My flower borders I had to leave unsettled, and I shall have to manage them by long distance planting. I had hoped to have some leisure in <placeName ref="#New_York">N.Y.</placeName> but each day brought so many demands. <persName ref="#Hardy_Jean">Jean</persName> arrived this morning and <persName ref="#Newberry_Mary">Mary Newberry</persName> in the afternoon. We went over to <persName ref="#Washington_DC">Washington</persName> on the 4th - <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and I stopping with <persName ref="#Boal_Terry">Terry</persName> and <persName ref="#Boal_Mathilde">Mathilde</persName> in their very charming French appartment. <persName ref="#Hardy_Jean">Jean</persName> went out to <placeName ref="#Chevy_Chase">Chevy Chase</placeName>, where the <personGrp ref="#Wilsons">Wilsons</personGrp> are staying for a time, and spent a night and day with <persName ref="#Wilson_Alice">Alice</persName> - and then back to <placeName ref="#Baltimore">Baltimore</placeName> to stay with <persName ref="#Powell_Helen">Helen</persName>, until we picked her up 3 days later. I enjoyed seeing <placeName ref="#Washington_DC">Washington</placeName> again - and <persName ref="#Boal_Mathilde">Mathilde</persName> had 2 pleasant dinners for us. One day we drove out through the <placeName ref="#Rocky_Creek_Valley">Rocky Creek Valley</placeName> to <placeName ref="#Chevy_Chase">Chevy Chase</placeName>, where we had a lunch at the Country Club. We enjoyed everything during our short little visit - and especially the companionship of <persName ref="#Boal_Terry">Terry</persName> and <persName ref="#Boal_Mathilde">Mathilde</persName>. Dinners, teas and visits every day in <placeName ref="#New_York">New York</placeName>, and made me ready for the quiet of the sea voyage; and I have had a beautiful rest and pleasant occupations up here in my little sky appartment - consisting of the <orgName>Captain's</orgName> rooms on the bridge level. We passed the <placeName ref="#Azores">Azores</placeName> today - going quite close to the <placeName ref="#Sao_Jorge">island of St. George</placeName>.<pb n="2"/></p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-11-21" type="entry">
        <dateline><name type="boat" ref="#SS_Konig_Albert">S.S. Koenig Albert</name> - <date when="1906-11-21">Wednesday, Nov. 21</date>.</dateline>
          <p>Due tomorrow early at <placeName ref="#Naples">Naples</placeName>. A wonderful voyage - not one rough wave - sunshine, warmth, and a perfectly smooth sea - many pleasant people aboard - about 20 of us, going to <placeName ref="#Egypt">Egypt</placeName> on the <name type="boat" ref="#SS_Schleswig">Schleswig</name></p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-11-22" type="entry">
        <dateline><placeName ref="#Naples">Naples</placeName>. <name type="hotel" ref="#Grand_Hotel">Grand Hotel</name> - <date when="1906-11-22">Thursday. Nov. 22</date>.</dateline>
        <p>Friday. We got in this morning early - a bright, clear day, but with a cold wind blowing - characteristic weather for <placeName ref="#Naples">Naples</placeName> at this season. <placeName ref="#Vesuvius">Vesuvius</placeName> so quiet - not even a cloud of smoke about it. It has changed its outline very much since the last eruption - the cone is quite lost and the mountain looks dwarfed - the crater opening is on the other side now - from <placeName ref="#Naples">Naples</placeName> - and not a spark could be seen at night. We are the only guests apparently in this house except the young <persName ref="#Brunswick_Duke">Duke of Brunswick</persName> and his party whom we always see in Egypt. On his way I suppose, now. We are to be off tomorrow on the <name type="boat" ref="#SS_Schleswig">SS. Schleswig</name> for <placeName ref="#Alexandria">Alexandria</placeName>.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-11-27" type="entry">
        <dateline><placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName>. <name type="hotel" ref="#Shepheards_Hotel">Shepheards Hotel</name> - <date when="1906-11-27">Nov. 27</date>.</dateline>
        <p>After a beautiful voyage on the comfortable <name type="boat" ref="#SS_Schleswig">Schleswig</name>, we arrived Monday afternoon, in a pouring rain at <placeName ref="#Alexandria">Alexandria</placeName>. Fortunately the ship went to the dock - but the disembarking was bad enough. We just caught the train for <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName>. <persName ref="#Hunt_Arthur">Dr. Hunt</persName> and <persName ref="#Grenfell_Bernard">Dr. Grenfell</persName> were on the boat and we found them as always - delightful and interesting. The former especially I like. We are in our old rooms overlooking the <pb n="3"/>garden [smudged word] not many people here. It is said that all the newspapers talk of the unrest in <placeName ref="#Egypt">Egypt</placeName>, has frightened away many people. We found <persName ref="#Trefusis_Robert">Robert Trefusis</persName> waiting on the terrace at <name type="hotel" ref="#Shepeards_Hotel">Shepheards</name> for us. He is stopping here.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-11-29" type="entry">
        <dateline><placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> - <date when="1906-11-29">Wednesday, Nov. 29</date>.</dateline>
        <p>Have paid a visit to the boat, which looks in very good and advanced readiness for us. Have shopped a little, and unpacked everything, or <persName ref="#Amelie">Amelie</persName> has, for readjustment for the winter. They have added another floor to this hotel - giving 75 new rooms - nice suites with bath rooms. <persName ref="#Baehler_Charles">Mr. Bachler</persName> is no longer manager - though he gives a certain supervision to it. He has a very nice house now in the <name type="hotel" ref="#Ghezireh_Palace_Hotel">Ghezireh Palace</name> grounds, where he lives - and is a powerful member of the Egyptian Hotels Syndicate. His character is so high and sterling, that he carries great influence and confidence. The <name type="hotel" ref="#Savoy_Hotel">Savoy hotel</name> is building an addition almost as big as itself. The <name type="hotel" ref="#Hotel_du_Nil">Hotel du Nil</name>, has been torn down, and is rebuilding. The <name type="hotel" ref="#Grand_Hotel">Grand Hotel</placeName> comes down next summer, and a huge business block built in its place. The <name type="hotel" ref="#Ghezireh_Palace_Hotel">Ghezireh Palace Hotel</name> will also come down, and be rebuilt on modern lines. <name type="hotel" ref="#Semiramis_Hotel">Ritz</name> is building a charming looking hotel on the banks of the <placeName ref="#Nile">Nile</placeName> - a short distance from the <placeName ref="#British_Embassy">English Embassy</placeName>. The greater part of <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> is being pulled down, or built upon. The thought pervading everybody seems to be how to speculate and make the most money - and the price of land is abnormal and stupendous. <persName ref="#Hunt_Arthur">Dr. Hunt</persName> and <persName ref="#Grenfell_Bernard">Dr. Grenfell</persName> and <persName ref="Trefusis_Robert">Robert</persName> dined with us and we had a charming evening.<pb n="4"/></p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-11-30" type="entry">
        <dateline><placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> - <date when="1906-11-30">Friday, Nov. 30</date>.</dateline>
        <p>We had <persName ref="#Sayce_Archibald">Mr. Sayce</persName> and <persName ref="Trefusis_Robert">Robert</persName> to dine - <persName ref="#Sayce_Archibald">Mr. Sayce</persName> looks ill and bad - has had a bad cold; he is sad too, and bemoaned the fact that he was growing old - and had to give up some of his activities. It seems to me very pathetic and inconsistent to hear a clergyman making such complaints. "Far above the belief and dream of material living is the Life Divine, revealing spiritual understanding and man's dominion over the whole earth".</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-12-02" type="entry">
        <dateline><placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> - <date when="1906-12-02">Sunday, 2nd in Advent</date>.</dateline>
        <p>At home this morning. In the afternoon we foolishly elected to drive out to the <placeName ref="#Pyramids">Pyramids</placeName> for tea at the <name type="hotel" ref="#Mena_House_Hotel">Mena House</name> - forgetting how crowded it would be on a Sunday afternoon. The drive lost most of its pleasure and beauty from the crowd of whizzing motors that filled the air with dust and stench. Alas! how spoiled <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> is growing, on its march to modern improvements! <persName ref="#Trefusis_Robert">Robert</persName> went up to <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName> this evening.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-12-03" type="entry">
        <dateline><placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> - <date when="1906-12-03">Monday, Dec. 3rd</date>.</dateline>
        <p><persName ref="#Trefusis_Walter">Captain Trefusis</persName> came in from the <name type="hotel" ref="#Mena_House_Hotel">Mena House</name> today, dined with us. We like him so much. He has resigned from the army, being such an invalid. His years in the <placeName ref="#South_Africa">South of Africa</placeName> have told on him very much. At the boat most of the day.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-12-05" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1906-12-05">Wednesday, Dec. 5</date>.</dateline>
        <p>We took possession this morning of the boat. We have the tug <pb n="5"/><name type="boat" ref="#Thotmes">Thothmes</name> to draw us - a strong, staunch tug. Went through the bridge shortly after 2 o'clock - then through the new <placeName ref="#Ghizeh_Bridge">Ghizeh bridge</placeName>, and pulled up at 6:30 about 4 miles from <placeName ref="#Helwan">Helouan</placeName>. <persName ref="#Trefusis_Walter">Captain Trefusis</persName> stayed at the hotel with us, until we came away. We were quite sorry to part with him - very busy settling ourselves.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-12-06" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1906-12-06">Thursday, Dec. 6</date>.</dateline>
        <p>30 miles. The strong south wind still blows - it being the 12 day of it the Captain says. The river is tremendously high and broad this year, owing to the heavy rains in <placeName ref="#Abyssinia">Abyyssinia</placeName> - it is like a lake, rather than river and the current very strong - started at 6:30 A.M.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-12-07" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1906-12-07">Friday, Dec. 7</date>.</dateline>
        <p>44 miles. A lovely day, but strong, south wind - passed the <personGrp ref="Smith">Joe Smiths</personGrp> this morning at breakfast - but did not see them until we were almost past them. This constant south wind is hard for them.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-12-08" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1906-12-08">Saturday, Dec. 8</date>.</dateline>
        <p>45 miles. We have had our sails out several times today - but most of the time the wind was too strong for us. Made an early start at 5 P.M.<pb n="6"/></p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-12-09" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1906-12-09">Second Sunday in Advent</date>.</dateline>
        <p>53 miles. We started at early dawn this morning - stopping at <placeName ref="#Minya">Minia</placeName> for an hour for an express parcel - which after all didn't come. A strong and favourable wind most of the day, and aft sail out much of the time. Much warmer today.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-12-10" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1906-12-10">Monday, Dec. 10</date>.</dateline>
        <p>46 miles. A fine, beautiful sailing day - had out our sail much of the time. Passed the Aby Faida chain in fine style. It is a lonely river this year - few boats.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-12-11" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1906-12-11">Tuesday, Dec. 11</date>.</dateline>
        <p>37 miles. We started early, but there was a thick fog and we stuck in the sand. I looked at my clock and found it 5:30. It made me shudder in my warm bed to hear our poor men in the water, getting us off. Reached <placeName ref="#Assiout">Asy&#251;t</placeName> at 8:30 - passed through the lock which was open finely. Stopped to post letters, and get <persName ref="#Henry_Dr">Dr. Henry</persName> to see <persName ref="#Hardy_Jean">Jean</persName>, who has been ailing for a few days. Are lying tonight 4 miles above <placeName ref="#Abu_Tij">Aboutig</placeName>.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-12-12" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1906-12-12">Wednesday, Dec. 12</date>.</dateline>
        <p>50 miles. We reached <placeName ref="#Sohag">Sohag</placeName> about 5 o'clock and tied up for the night. A very strong cold wind blowing all day and sand flying. We have been passing through some of the most beautiful and highly cultivated country in <placeName ref="#Egypt">Egypt</placeName> for 2 days. The sugar cane crop <pb n="7"/> is almost ready for the harvest - and at this time the people come from the villages to the banks of the river, with their family, dogs, and flocks and herds, to watch their crops. They build little huts and stockades of dried dourra stalks. It has a very pretty, pastoral air.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-12-13" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1906-12-13">Thursday, Dec. 13</date>.</dateline>
        <p>51 miles. Pulled up at <placeName ref="#Nag_Hamadi">Nag Hamadi</placeName>, after dark, and will pass the bridge early tomorrow. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> issued orders that none of the men should go ashore - as the plague has been quite bad here and at <placeName ref="#Girga">Girga</placeName> lately. A better day than yesterday - though a high north wind has prevailed - and waves were high and rough.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-12-14" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1906-12-14">Friday, Dec. 14</date>.</dateline>
        <p>38 miles. Got through the bridge at 8:30 - a cold windy day with the most gorgeous sunset I ever saw. Tied up at 5:30 P.M.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-12-15" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1906-12-15">Saturday, Dec. 15</date>.</dateline>
        <p>44-1/2 miles. We arrived at 5 o'clock - and pulled up at a little spit of sand, opposite the <orgName ref="#American_Mission">American Mission</orgName>. The great sand bank opposite the town is almost unapproachable because of the shallowness of the water. <personGrp ref="#Murch">Mr. and Mrs. Murch</personGrp> came over to see us at once. We will get off on Monday. We have taken just 10 days from <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName>.<pb n="8"/></p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-12-16" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1906-12-16">Third Sunday in Advent. Sunday, Dec. 16</date>.</dateline>
        <p><persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName>, <persName ref="#Jones_Harold">Jones</persName> and the lunch baskets went over to the <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">Valley</placeName> this morning - <persName ref="#Hardy_Jean">Jean</persName> and I stayed at home. <persName ref="#Curelly_Charles_Trick">Mr. Curelly</persName>, and an artist <persName ref="#Tyndale_Walter">Mr. Tindale</persName>, were here to tea.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-12-17" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1906-12-17">Monday, Dec. 17</date>.</dateline>
        <p>29 miles. Did not get off until nearly 1 o'clock - owing to some trouble with rope of tug. A most lovely afternoon - with such a sunset. We were nearing <placeName ref="#Gebelein">Gebelein</placeName>, and the opposite bold Mt. range was touched to pink and deepening crimson, while the western sky was every beautiful shade of blue and soft rose pink, while the new little silver crescent of the moon made a heavenly effect.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-12-18" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1906-12-18">Tuesday, Dec. 18</date>.</dateline>
        <p>45 miles. The weather grows warmer - and is very fine - passed <placeName ref="#El_Kab">El Kab</placeName> at 2:30, much interested in seeing <persName ref="Somers_Clark_George">Mr. Somers-Clark</persName>'s house - apparently not yet finished. I like it much - and it is probably pretty and convenient inside. A fine situation looking up and down the river. The <name type="boat" ref="#Safa">Safa</name> was lying there - looking very big and fine. We are tonight about 4 miles above Edfu.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-12-19" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1906-12-19">Wednesday, Dec. 19</date>.</dateline>
        <p>64 miles. We stopped about 7 o'clock - with-in sight of the lights of <placeName ref="#Aswan">Asw&#226;n</placeName>. A most lovely day - absolutely hot. All the morning on deck. The night is still and warm, and quite <pb n="9"/>too beautiful for words. This delicious dry air is so welcome.</p>
      </div>
      <!--Freda and Mr Sammary mentioned -->
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-12-20" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1906-12-20">Thursday, Dec. 20</date>.</dateline>
        <p>We came around early to our old landing place at the little island. Found the <name type="boat" ref="#Zenet_el_Nil">Zenet-el-Nil</name> near us. Went into town by carriage from <name type="hotel" ref="#Cataract_Hotel">Gatarast Hotel</name>, to see <persName  ref="#">Freda</persName> i her new home. I quite liked her husband, <persName  ref="#">Mr. Sammary</persName> - who is a teacher, and manager or rather helper at the <orgName ref="#German_Mission_School">German Mission School</orgName>. <persName  ref="#">Freda</persName> herself looked much improved, much thinner. Their apartment on the ground floor, consisting of sitting room, bed room and kitchen, opened on to a very pretty garden. She was delighted to see me and <persName ref="#Hardy_Jean">Jean</persName>. We took her some little presents, and she introduced us to the <persName  ref="#Henry_Dr">Doctor</persName> and his sweet faced wife and took us through the rather small school. In the afternoon <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName>, <persName ref="#Hardy_Jean">Jean</persName> and I were rowed around to the <name type="hotel" ref="#Savoy_Hotel">Savoy Hotel</name>, and had tea in those delightful gardens.</p>
      </div>
      <!--define Philad-->
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-12-21" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1906-12-21">Friday, Dec. 21</date>.</dateline>
        <p>12 miles. We started with the tug about 7 o'clock. It was interesting getting up into those cataract waters again, and took me back to that morning, years ago, when on the <placeName ref="#Herdotus_Basin">Herodotus</placeName> we attempted getting up, and met with such a fiasco. It was tiresome and nervous getting through the 4 different locks, because of the crowding gyassas, and the consequent noise and shrieking. We entered the first lock at 8 A.M. and passed the last at 11 o'clock. The special cataract rais for the cataract, as we came out, took the tug <pb n="10"/>immediately over a pile of loose stones under the water, nearly upsetting her, and of course we followed, the stones grinding under our whole length. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> was furious and with reason. The river above the dam was a large lake - the palm trees more or less submerged, and <persName  ref="#">Philad</persName> standing in water. We passed <placeName ref="#Nubia">Deb&#244;t</placeName>, with its ruined Ptolemaic temple, and are now lying 2 miles above it - against a charming low desert shore. The day has been very hot - 78 on my cabana.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-11-22" type="entry">
        <dateline><placeName ref="#Naples">Naples</placeName>. <name type="hote l" ref="#Grand_Hotel">Grand Hotel</name> - <date when="1906-11-22">Thursday. Nov. 22</date>.</dateline>
        <p>Friday. We got in this morning early - a bright, clear day, but with a cold wind blowing - characteristic weather for <placeName ref="#Naples">Naples</placeName> at this season. <placeName ref="#Vesuvius">Vesuvius</placeName> so quiet - not even a cloud of smoke about it. It has changed its outline very much since the last eruption - the cone is quite lost and the mountain looks dwarfed - the crater opening is on the other side now - from <placeName ref="#Naples">Naples</placeName> - and not a spark could be seen at night. We are the only guests apparently in this house except the young <persName ref="#Brunswick_Duke">Duke of Brunswick</persName> and his party whom we always see in Egypt. On his way I suppose, now. We are to be off tomorrow on the <name type="boat" ref="#SS_Schleswig">SS. Schleswig</name> for <placeName ref="#Alexandria">Alexandria</placeName>.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-11-27" type="entry">
        <dateline><placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName>. <name type="hotel" ref="#Shepheards_Hotel">Shepheards Hotel</name> - <date when="1906-11-27">Nov. 27</date>.</dateline>
        <p>After a beautiful voyage on the comfortable <name type="boat" ref="#SS_Schleswig">Schleswig</name>, we arrived Monday afternoon, in a pouring rain at <placeName ref="#Alexandria">Alexandria</placeName>. Fortunately the ship went to the dock - but the disembarking was bad enough. We just caught the train for <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName>. <persName ref="#Hunt_Arthur">Dr. Hunt</persName> and <persName ref="#Grenfell_Bernard">Dr. Grenfell</persName> were on the boat and we found them as always - delightful and interesting. The former especially I like. We are in our old rooms overlooking the <pb n="3"/>garden [smudged word] not many people here. It is said that all the newspapers talk of the unrest in <placeName ref="#Egypt">Egypt</placeName>, has frightened away many people. We found <persName ref="#Trefusis_Robert">Robert Trefusis</persName> waiting on the terrace at <name type="hotel" ref="#Shepeards_Hotel">Shepheards</name> for us. He is stopping here.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-11-29" type="entry">
        <dateline><placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> - <date when="1906-11-29">Wednesday, Nov. 29</date>.</dateline>
        <p>Have paid a visit to the boat, which looks in very good and advanced readiness for us. Have shopped a little, and unpacked everything, or <persName ref="#Amelie">Amelie</persName> has, for readjustment for the winter. They have added another floor to this hotel - giving 75 new rooms - nice suites with bath rooms. <persName ref="#Baehler_Charles">Mr. Bachler</persName> is no longer manager - though he gives a certain supervision to it. He has a very nice house now in the <name type="hotel" ref="#Ghezireh_Palace_Hotel">Ghezireh Palace</name> grounds, where he lives - and is a powerful member of the Egyptian Hotels Syndicate. His character is so high and sterling, that he carries great influence and confidence. The <name type="hotel" ref="#Savoy_Hotel">Savoy hotel</name> is building an addition almost as big as itself. The <name type="hotel" ref="#Hotel_du_Nil">Hotel du Nil</name>, has been torn down, and is rebuilding. The <name type="hotel" ref="#Grand_Hotel">Grand Hotel</placeName> comes down next summer, and a huge business block built in its place. The <name type="hotel" ref="#Ghezireh_Palace_Hotel">Ghezireh Palace Hotel</name> will also come down, and be rebuilt on modern lines. <name type="hotel" ref="#">Ritz</name> is building a charming looking hotel on the banks of the <placeName ref="#Nile">Nile</placeName> - a short distance from the <placeName ref="#British_Embassy">English Embassy</placeName>. The greater part of <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> is being pulled down, or built upon. The thought pervading everybody seems to be how to speculate and make the most money - and the price of land is abnormal and stupendous. <persName ref="#Hunt_Arthur">Dr. Hunt</persName> and <persName ref="#Grenfell_Bernard">Dr. Grenfell</persName> and <persName ref="Trefusis_Robert">Robert</persName> dined with us and we had a charming evening.<pb n="4"/></p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-11-30" type="entry">
        <dateline><placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> - <date when="1906-11-30">Friday, Nov. 30</date>.</dateline>
        <p>We had <persName ref="#Sayce_Archibald">Mr. Sayce</persName> and <persName ref="Trefusis_Robert">Robert</persName> to dine - <persName ref="#Sayce_Archibald">Mr. Sayce</persName> looks ill and bad - has had a bad cold; he is sad too, and bemoaned the fact that he was growing old - and had to give up some of his activities. It seems to me very pathetic and inconsistent to hear a clergyman making such complaints. "Far above the belief and dream of material living is the Life Divine, revealing spiritual understanding and man's dominion over the whole earth".</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-12-02" type="entry">
        <dateline><placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> - <date when="1906-12-02">Sunday, 2nd in Advent</date>.</dateline>
        <p>At home this morning. In the afternoon we foolishly elected to drive out to the <placeName ref="#Pyramids">Pyramids</placeName> for tea at the <name type="hotel" ref="#Mena_House_Hotel">Mena House</name> - forgetting how crowded it would be on a Sunday afternoon. The drive lost most of its pleasure and beauty from the crowd of whizzing motors that filled the air with dust and stench. Alas! how spoiled <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> is growing, on its march to modern improvements! <persName ref="#Trefusis_Robert">Robert</persName> went up to <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName> this evening.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-12-03" type="entry">
        <dateline><placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> - <date when="1906-12-03">Monday, Dec. 3rd</date>.</dateline>
        <p><persName ref="#Trefusis_Walter">Captain Trefusis</persName> came in from the <name type="hotel" ref="#Mena_House_Hotel">Mena House</name> today, dined with us. We like him so much. He has resigned from the army, being such an invalid. His years in the <placeName ref="#South_Africa">South of Africa</placeName> have told on him very much. At the boat most of the day.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-12-05" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1906-12-05">Wednesday, Dec. 5</date>.</dateline>
        <p>We took possession this morning of the boat. We have the tug <pb n="5"/><name type="boat" ref="#Thotmes">Thothmes</name> to draw us - a strong, staunch tug. Went through the bridge shortly after 2 o'clock - then through the new <placeName ref="#Ghizeh_Bridge">Ghizeh bridge</placeName>, and pulled up at 6:30 about 4 miles from <placeName ref="#Helwan">Helouan</placeName>. <persName ref="#Trefusis_Walter">Captain Trefusis</persName> stayed at the hotel with us, until we came away. We were quite sorry to part with him - very busy settling ourselves.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-12-06" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1906-12-06">Thursday, Dec. 6</date>.</dateline>
        <p>30 miles. The strong south wind still blows - it being the 12 day of it the Captain says. The river is tremendously high and broad this year, owing to the heavy rains in <placeName ref="#Abyssinia">Abyyssinia</placeName> - it is like a lake, rather than river and the current very strong - started at 6:30 A.M.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-12-07" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1906-12-07">Friday, Dec. 7</date>.</dateline>
        <p>44 miles. A lovely day, but strong, south wind - passed the <personGrp ref="Smith">Joe Smiths</personGrp> this morning at breakfast - but did not see them until we were almost past them. This constant south wind is hard for them.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-12-08" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1906-12-08">Saturday, Dec. 8</date>.</dateline>
        <p>45 miles. We have had our sails out several times today - but most of the time the wind was too strong for us. Made an early start at 5 P.M.<pb n="6"/> </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-12-09" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1906-12-09">Second Sunday in Advent</date>.</dateline>
        <p>53 miles. We started at early dawn this morning - stopping at <placeName ref="#Minya">Minia</placeName> for an hour for an express parcel - which after all didn't come. A strong and favourable wind most of the day, and aft sail out much of the time. Much warmer today.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-12-10" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1906-12-10">Monday, Dec. 10</date>.</dateline>
        <p>46 miles. A fine, beautiful sailing day - had out our sail much of the time. Passed the Aby Faida chain in fine style. It is a lonely river this year - few boats.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-12-11" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1906-12-11">Tuesday, Dec. 11</date>.</dateline>
        <p>37 miles. We started early, but there was a thick fog and we stuck in the sand. I looked at my clock and found it 5:30. It made me shudder in my warm bed to hear our poor men in the water, getting us off. Reached <placeName ref="#Assiout">Asy&#251;t</placeName> at 8:30 - passed through the lock which was open finely. Stopped to post letters, and get <persName ref="#Henry_Dr">Dr. Henry</persName> to see <persName ref="#Hardy_Jean">Jean</persName>, who has been ailing for a few days. Are lying tonight 4 miles above <placeName ref="#Abu_Tij">Aboutig</placeName>.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-12-12" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1906-12-12">Wednesday, Dec. 12</date>.</dateline>
        <p>50 miles. We reached <placeName ref="#Sohag">Sohag</placeName> about 5 o'clock and tied up for the night. A very strong cold wind blowing all day and sand flying. We have been passing through some of the most beautiful and highly cultivated country in <placeName ref="#Egypt">Egypt</placeName> for 2 days. The sugar cane crop <pb n="7"/> is almost ready for the harvest - and at this time the people come from the villages to the banks of the river, with their family, dogs, and flocks and herds, to watch their crops. They build little huts and stockades of dried dourra stalks. It has a very pretty, pastoral air.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-12-13" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1906-12-13">Thursday, Dec. 13</date>.</dateline>
        <p>51 miles. Pulled up at <placeName ref="#Nag_Hamadi">Nag Hamadi</placeName>, after dark, and will pass the bridge early tomorrow. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> issued orders that none of the men should go ashore - as the plague has been quite bad here and at <placeName ref="#Girga">Girga</placeName> lately. A better day than yesterday - though a high north wind has prevailed - and waves were high and rough.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-12-14" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1906-12-14">Friday, Dec. 14</date>.</dateline>
        <p>38 miles. Got through the bridge at 8:30 - a cold windy day with the most gorgeous sunset I ever saw. Tied up at 5:30 P.M.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-12-15" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1906-12-15">Saturday, Dec. 15</date>.</dateline>
        <p>44-1/2 miles. We arrived at 5 o'clock - and pulled up at a little spit of sand, opposite the <orgName ref="#American_Mission">American Mission</orgName>. The great sand bank opposite the town is almost unapproachable because of the shallowness of the water. <personGrp ref="#Murch">Mr. and Mrs. Murch</personGrp> came over to see us at once. We will get off on Monday. We have taken just 10 days from <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName>.<pb n="8"/></p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-12-16" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1906-12-16">Third Sunday in Advent. Sunday, Dec. 16</date>.</dateline>
        <p><persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName>, <persName ref="#Jones_Harold">Jones</persName> and the lunch baskets went over to the <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">Valley</placeName> this morning - <persName ref="#Hardy_Jean">Jean</persName> and I stayed at home. <persName ref="#Curelly_Charles_Trick">Mr. Curelly</persName>, and an artist <persName ref="#Tyndale_Walter">Mr. Tindale</persName>, were here to tea.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-12-17" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1906-12-17">Monday, Dec. 17</date>.</dateline>
        <p>29 miles. Did not get off until nearly 1 o'clock - owing to some trouble with rope of tug. A most lovely afternoon - with such a sunset. We were nearing <placeName ref="#Gebelein">Gebelein</placeName>, and the opposite bold Mt. range was touched to pink and deepening crimson, while the western sky was every beautiful shade of blue and soft rose pink, while the new little silver crescent of the moon made a heavenly effect.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-12-18" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1906-12-18">Tuesday, Dec. 18</date>.</dateline>
        <p>45 miles. The weather grows warmer - and is very fine - passed <placeName ref="#El_Kab">El Kab</placeName> at 2:30, much interested in seeing <persName ref="Somers_Clark_George">Mr. Somers-Clark</persName>'s house - apparently not yet finished. I like it much - and it is probably pretty and convenient inside. A fine situation looking up and down the river. The <name type="boat" ref="#Safa">Safa</persName> was lying there - looking very big and fine. We are tonight about 4 miles above <placeName ref="#Edfou">Edfu</placeName>.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-12-19" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1906-12-19">Wednesday, Dec. 19</date>.</dateline>
        <p>64 miles. We stopped about 7 o'clock - with-in sight of the lights of <placeName ref="#Aswan">Asw&#226;n</placeName>. A most lovely day - absolutely hot. All the morning on deck. The night is still and warm, and quite <pb n="9"/>too beautiful for words. This delicious dry air is so welcome.</p>
      </div>
      <!--Freda and Mr. Sammary mentioned-->
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-12-20" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1906-12-20">Thursday, Dec. 20</date>.</dateline>
        <p>We came around early to our old landing place at the little island. Found the <name type="boat" ref="#Zenet_el_Nil">Zenet-el-Nil</name> near us. Went into town by carriage from <name type="hotel" ref="#Cataract_Hotel">Gatarast Hotel</name>, to see <persName  ref="#">Freda</persName> i her new home. I quite liked her husband, <persName  ref="#">Mr. Sammary</persName> - who is a teacher, and manager or rather helper at the <orgName ref="#German_Mission_School">German Mission School</orgName>. <persName  ref="#">Freda</persName> herself looked much improved, much thinner. Their apartment on the ground floor, consisting of sitting room, bed room and kitchen, opened on to a very pretty garden. She was delighted to see me and <persName ref="#Hardy_Jean">Jean</persName>. We took her some little presents, and she introduced us to the <persName  ref="#">Doctor</persName> and his sweet faced wife and took us through the rather small school. In the afternoon <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName>, <persName ref="#Hardy_Jean">Jean</persName> and I were rowed around to the <name type="hotel" ref="#Savoy_Hotel">Savoy Hotel</name>, and had tea in those delightful gardens.</p>
      </div>
      <!--define philad-->
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-12-21" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1906-12-21">Friday, Dec. 21</date>.</dateline>
        <p>12 miles. We started with the tug about 7 o'clock. It was interesting getting up into those cataract waters again, and took me back to that morning, years ago, when on the <placeName ref="#Herdotus_Basin">Herodotus</placeName> we attempted getting up, and met with such a fiasco. It was tiresome and nervous getting through the 4 different locks, because of the crowding gyassas, and the consequent noise and shrieking. We entered the first lock at 8 A.M. and passed the last at 11 o'clock. The special cataract rais for the cataract, as we came out, took the tug <pb n="10"/>immediately over a pile of loose stones under the water, nearly upsetting her, and of course we followed, the stones grinding under our whole length. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> was furious and with reason. The river above the dam was a large lake - the palm trees more or less submerged, and <persName  ref="#">Philad</persName> standing in water. We passed <placeName ref="#Nubia">Deb&#244;t</placeName>, with its ruined Ptolemaic temple, and are now lying 2 miles above it - against a charming low desert shore. The day has been very hot - 78 on my cabana.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-12-22" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1906-12-22">Saturday, Dec. 22nd</date>.</dateline>
        <p>66 miles. Made an early start at 5 - and tied up at 5 P.M. The day lovely - not quite so hot as yesterday. I got up at 6 o'clock to see the lovely morning with the exquisite desert colouring - and one of the first things I saw was the ruined little <placeName ref="#Temple_of_Kertasi">temple of Kertassi</placeName>, standing in the golden yellow sands under the light of the dawn. I was so interested too in the almost continuous villages on both sides of the river, so clear and orderly, the house solidly built of stones, and with some effort at architectural effect or rather ornament and with occasional white minarets and mosques - all of these villages struggling up - over the rough bare desert. The poor palms are still standing most of them in water, looking sad enough - with their yellowing and dying fronds. Others, farther back, on dry land showing several feet up their stems the mark of the water. As the day went on, the conditions improved somewhat. The villages became so interesting and a real artistic spirit seemed abroad. The houses had ornamental brick work "&#224; jour" across their fronts - often of excellent <pb n="11"/>workmanship and design - and frequently tiles and plates were used. In some of them, the ornamental balustrade around the top seemed to enclose earth in which small shrubs were planted. Altogether very interesting. The small temples seen in this part of the river from time to time are not very attractive. I have already visited them during my two former visits.</p>
      </div>
      <!--define shibbaik-->
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-12-23" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1906-12-23">Fourth Sunday in Advent. Dec. 23rd</date>.</dateline>
        <p>77 miles. We are lying tonight between the two towns of <placeName ref="#Genena">Genena</placeName> and <placeName ref="#">Shibb&#226;ik</placeName> - having made 77 miles. There are left 26 miles between this and <placeName ref="#Abu_Simbel">Abu Simbel</placeName> for tomorrow. This has been another perfect day and we have been coming through the most fertile and beautiful scenery I have seen on the <placeName ref="Nile">Nile</placeName>. We came, too, to the natural river with its current, and are free from the back water of the barrage. The palms have been magnificent - and such a rich, dark, polished green. Never have I seen such fine scent trees, and in such perfect bloom and so many of them, - large forest trees in fact. And the tamarasks look almost like English yews - so compact are they and so dark in colour. This afternoon in passing the interesting remains of the Roman fortress <placeName ref="#Qasr_Ibrim">Kasr Ibr&#226;m</placeName>, on its lofty rock, the scenery was quite beyond painting - the western side being a wonderful stretch of gold red desert, as far as the eye could see, broken by bold detached bare hills, their black iron coating making such contrasts in color. Quite too beautiful and impressive ever to be forgotten.<pb n="12"/></p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-12-24" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1906-12-24">Monday, Dec. 24th</date>.</dateline>
        <p>23 miles. We were off at 6 o'clock and reached <placeName ref="#Abu_Simbel">Abu Simbel</placeName> at 11:30 - tremendously hot. <personGrp ref="#Newman">Mr. and Mrs. Newman</personGrp> whose dahabya we knew was there as usual, came over at once to see us, and stayed until lunch - asked us to tea, and promised to come and dine with us. <persName ref="#Newman_Mr">Mr. Newman</persName> harrowed our feelings by telling us we must be careful of snakes in the temples - that 2 mornings before the track of a large, very large snake had been traced in the sand from a certain place into the larger temple, and they were feeling rather nervous about it. He has his painting tent just in front of the temple. We had pleasant visits with them and said goodbye after dinner to them.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-12-25" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1906-12-25">Tuesday, Dec. 25. Christmas</date>.</dateline>
        <p>76 miles. As we drew away from the bank at 8 o'clock this morning, we saw <persName ref="#Newman_Mr">Mr. N</persName>. on the bank, waving his white umbrella in farewell. We have made fast time today, and are lying at <placeName ref="#Wadi_es_Sebua">Sabua</placeName> tonight. Very hot today, and very high wind.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-12-26" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1906-12-26">Wednesday, Dec. 26</date>.</dateline>
        <p>95 miles. We have come at a tremendous pace today - the heat still holds. We are lying within 6 miles of <placeName ref="#Shellal">Shellal</placeName> at a lovely dry slope of sand - the air so dry and very warm. These moonlight nights are most lovely. I was on deck most of the day - in spite of the wind.<pb n="13"/></p>
      </div>
      <!--Freda mentioned -->
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-12-27" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1906-12-27">Thursday, Dec. 27</date>.</dateline>
        <p>46 miles. An early start brought us to <placeName ref="#Philae">Philae</placeName> at 7 o'clock, had a beautiful view of it - stopped an hour or more at <placeName ref="#Shellal">Shellal</placeName> to coal - passed the lock at 11 o'clock and stopped at <placeName ref="#Aswan">Asw&#226;n</placeName> just long enough to get our mail, and pay a hurried goodbye visit to <persName ref="#">Freeda</persName> at the Mission. Very hot all day - are lying 6 miles below <placeName ref="#Silsilis">Silsilis</placeName> - and <persName ref="#Maspero_Gaston">M. Maspero</persName> is just behind us. 46 miles in 5 hours is good going. Found a huge mail at <placeName ref="#Aswan">Asw&#226;n</placeName>.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-12-28" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1906-12-28">Friday, Dec. 28</date>.</dateline>
        <p>86 miles. Started at 6 A.M. and arrived at <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName> at 4 P.M. A charming day - hot, but with cool wind - a quick journey from <placeName ref="#Aswan">Asw&#226;n</placeName> at 12 noon yesterday to <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName> today at 4. The tug started down at once. She has taken us 1079 miles - about the distance from <placeName ref="#Naples">Naples</placeName> to <placeName ref="#Alexandria">Alexandria</placeName>. An expensive luxury but convenient.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-12-29" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1906-12-29">Saturday, Dec. 29</date>.</dateline>
        <p>We tied up on arriving yesterday to a little rag of a sand bank about where we were last year. The "Dongola" is the only other dahabya here. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> went over to the <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">Valley</placeName> this morning, and <persName ref="#Hardy_Jean">Jean</persName> and I went to see <persName ref="#Buchanan_Carrie">Miss Buchanan</persName> - <persName ref="#Carter_Howard">Mr. Carter</persName> came in for tea - so glad to see him.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-12-30" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1906-12-30">First Sunday after Christmas. Dec. 30</date>.</dateline>
        <p>A quiet pleasant day at home. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> and <persName ref="#Hardy_Jean">Jean</persName> at <placeName ref="#Karnak">Karnac</placeName> this <pb n="14"/>afternoon.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-12-31" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1906-12-31">Monday, Dec. 31</date>.</dateline>
        <p>Home all day. <persName ref="#Somers_Clarke_George">Mr. Somers-Clarke</persName> and <persName ref="#Carter_Howard">Mr. Carter</persName> were here this afternoon, and stayed to tea. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> and <persName ref="#Hardy_Jean">Jean</persName> at <placeName ref="#Karnak">Karnac</placeName>.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-01-01" type="entry">
        Jan. 1st. 1907. Mr. <persName ref="#Ayrton_Edward">Ayrton</persName> to lunch and <personGrp ref="#Pumpelly">Mr. and Mrs. Pumpelly</personGrp> with <persName ref="#Pumpelly_Raphael">Raphael Pumpelly</persName> were here to tea and <persName ref="#Smith_Joe">Joe Smith</persName> to dine. Very warm.
      </div>
<!-- Jan 1st entry doesn't make sense to me -->
<!-- New people: Pumpellys -->
<!-- Is "Joe Smith" "Joseph Lindon Smith"? -->

      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-01-01" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1907-01-01"></date>.</dateline>
        <p>Jan. 2nd. Wednesday. A telegram from <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie,</persName> saying she will arrive tomorrow at 9 A.M. All the <personGrp ref="#Pumpelly">Pumpellys</personGrp> dined with us.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-01-01" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1907-01-01"></date>.</dateline>
        <p>Thursday, Jan. 3rd. <persName ref=>Jean</persName> and I breakfasted at 8:30 and went over to <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName> and to the station to meet <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> who arrived promptly at 9. It is 5 years since she was here. The <persName ref="#Collins_Frances">Miss Collins</persName> arrived by the same train.</p>
      </div>
<!-- Who is Jean? -->
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-01-01" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1907-01-01"></date>.</dateline>
        <p>Friday, Jan. 4th. Mr. <persName ref="#Ayrton_Edward">Ayrton</persName> wrote a note this morning to <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> saying he had found a tomb. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> had intended going over today, so when he returned he reported that it promised something - but was still uncertain. <persName ref=>Jean</persName> and I went over to the hotel to pay some visits.</p>
      </div>
<!-- Who is Jean? -->
      <pb n="15"/>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-01-01" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1907-01-01"></date>.</dateline>
        <p>Saturday, Jan 5. Another note from Mr. <persName ref="#Ayrton_Edward">Ayrton</persName> saying the tomb was not a tomb! <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> was so disappointed. <personGrp ref="#Wiedemann">Dr. Wiedemann and his wife</personGrp> dined with us tonight. They are delightful people, and we had a charming evening.</p>
      </div>
<!-- New people: Wiedemanns -->
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-01-01" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1907-01-01"></date>.</dateline>
        <p>Sunday, Jan. 6. A quiet delightful morning - <persName ref="#Dalison_Max">Mr. Dalison</persName> came to lunch - some of <persName ref=>Jean's</persName> friends to tea.</p>
      </div>
<!-- Jean again -->
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-01-01" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1907-01-01"></date>.</dateline>
        <p>Monday, Jan. 7. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> went over to the <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">Valley</placeName> this morning - found it very hot - and when he got back quite late, told us that <persName ref="#Ayrton_Edward">Ayrton</persName> had this time found a real tomb. We are all going over tomorrow, and so are <personGrp ref="#Weigall">Mr. and Mrs. Weigall.</personGrp> <persName ref="#Lindon_Smith_Joseph">Joe Smith</persName> is staying at the <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">Valley</placeName> tonight with Ayrton. <persName ref=>Jean</persName> went to the hotel to lunch with <persName ref="#Peckett_Mrs">Mrs. Peckett</persName> - <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I had a beautiful lunch on deck, and at 3 o'clock went over to the hotel for her - <persName ref="#Peckett_Mrs">Mrs. Peckett,</persName> the <personGrp ref="#Collins">Misses Collins,</personGrp> and <persName ref="#Carter_Howard">Carter</persName> were there - we brought <persName ref="#Carter_Howard">Carter</persName> home with us, calling on our way back on their <name type="boat" ref="#Stella">dahabya "Stella"</name> on the <personGrp ref="#Smith">Smiths.</personGrp> <personGrp ref="#Weigall">Mr. and Mrs. Weigall</personGrp> came to tea.</p>
      </div>
<!-- "the Misses Collins" - is she referring to a singular Mrs. Collins or multiple Miss Collinses? -->
<!-- New person: Mrs. Peckett -->
<!-- Jean -->
<!-- "Carter" likely Howard Carter, but could it also be Edgar Bonham Carter? -->
<!-- New boat: "Stella" -->
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-01-01" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1907-01-01"></date>.</dateline>
        <p>Tuesday, Jan. 8th. All of us went over to the <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">Valley</placeName> this morning - found Mr. <persName ref="#Ayrton_Edward">Ayrton</persName> had cleared enough to show a small chamber which he thought was the whole tomb. But after lunch it was found that a doorway which had been sealed up as that in the tomb of <placeName ref="#Tjuyu">Touyou</placeName> and <placeName ref="#Yuya">Iuia</placeName> led to a corridor.</p>
      </div>
      <pb n="16"/>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-01-01" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1907-01-01"></date>.</dateline>
        <p>In removing some of the blocks of stone which hindered progress, a fine broken alabaster vase, and some bits of gold foil were found; so the work for the day was stopped, as it was too late to open it, the guards and police were sent for, and we rode home - speculating as to who the tomb had belonged. Mr. <persName ref=>Weigall</persName> and his wife were already camping in the <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">Valley</placeName> - and wanted <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and <persName ref=>Jean</persName> to stay with them the night - which they did - delighted at the opportunity. <persName ref="#Lindon_Smith_Joseph">Joe Smith</persName> and his wife also stayed. A very nice man, an <orgName>Englishman,</orgName> whom <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> had met the day before, lunched in the tomb with us, Mr. <persName ref=>David Erskin</persName> M.P. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> and I had a quiet evening alone - a most unusual thing.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-01-01" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1907-01-01"></date>.</dateline>
        <p>Jan. 9. Wednesday. We made rather an early start this morning - <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> and I, with <persName ref=>Amelie</persName> and <placeName ref=>Jones,</placeName> and <persName ref=>Hassein.</persName> When we arrived at the tomb, every one was waiting for us as the doorway and steps had been cleared, and everything ready for an entrance. <persName ref="#Ayrton_Edward">Ayrton, Weigall</persName> and <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> scrambled along the corridor over the tombs, and made a very difficult entrance. Mr. <persName ref=>Erskine,</persName> by invitation had joined us, we women, with Mr. <persName ref=>E., Mrs. Weigall,</persName> and <persName ref=>Joe</persName> and his wife, sat about on the rocks above, and waited straining our ears to catch the broken exclamations that reached us from below - "Aton! The rays of the <orgName>Sun" Tut-ankh-amen"</orgName> etc. and at last Mr. <persName ref=>Davis's</persName> voice rang out, "By <persName ref=>Jove, Queen Tyi,</persName> and no mistake" and so it proved. On the rough stones of the corridor rested a wooden door, 12 x 14 ft. long - 6 ft. wide, and a smaller one about 2 x 4 - with bronze doors and hinges - both doors covered with gold foil - the <pb n="17"/> smaller one in quite good condition, and on it the cartouche of <orgName>Tyi,</orgName> and that of her husband <persName ref=>Amenhotep III.</persName> The burial chamber was not large, but in a state of great confusion. The Queen would seem to have been laid in a great, highly decorated, wood shrine - parts of which were on the floor, or leaning against the wall, - the coffin on the floor - all showing hasty burial, or robbery or desecration. I did not go down - but <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie, Mrs. Weigall,</persName> and <persName ref=>Jean</persName> went down - one by one - <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> was determined that <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> should be the first one to see it, and she was the first woman to enter. All the men had been down. We had a big lunch with everyone, and a charming day. Very warm today. Thursday,</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-01-01" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1907-01-01"></date>.</dateline>
        <p>Jan.10. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> and the girls went again to the <orgName>Valley.</orgName> I wouldn't face that long ride in the hot sun today - and so had a nice quiet day at home. They came back very tired, bringing word of the many treasures of the tomb. Tomorrow the tomb is to be given over into the hands of a skillful photographer sent for from <placeName ref=>Cairo</placeName> - and <persName ref="#Lindon_Smith_Joseph">Joe Smith</persName> is also painting there.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-01-01" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1907-01-01"></date>.</dateline>
        <p>Jan. 11. Friday. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> came over in the <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">Valley</placeName> again - had <persName ref="#Carter_Howard">Carter</persName> lunching with us.</p>
      </div>
        <pb n="18"/>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-01-01" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1907-01-01"></date>.</dateline>
        <p>Jan. 12. Saturday. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> at home for a rest. The girls and I over at <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName> - visiting and shopping. <persName ref=>Mr. Erskine</persName> dined with us. A nice, big, handsome <orgName>Englishman.</orgName></p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-01-01" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1907-01-01"></date>.</dateline>
        <p>Jan. 13. 1st Sunday after Epiphany. <persName ref=>M.</persName> and <persName ref=>Mme.</persName> <persName ref=>Naville</persName> dined with us.
        <name>Luxor,</name> Jan. 14. Monday. A quiet day at home. The <name>Maspero's</name> boat arrived this morning. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> went over to see them - they are delighted with the finding of <placeName ref=>Tyi's</placeName> tomb - weather cool and pleasant - the mountains were wonderful at dawn this morning - the first rosy touch of the sun on their highest peaks until the whole range burned with a rosy light - transfused as it were - as if its colour came from itself.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-01-01" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1907-01-01"></date>.</dateline>
        <p>Tuesday, Jan. 15. It has been a dull, dark day with north wind in squalls. A pleasant visit from <persName ref=>M.</persName> and <persName ref=>Mme.</persName> <persName ref=>Maspero</persName> this afternoon and a nice cable from Mr. <persName ref=>Robinson</persName> of congratulation to <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo.</persName> this evening we had a gale, and were battered about - and rain fell for a time.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-01-01" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1907-01-01"></date>.</dateline>
        <p>Wednesday, Jan. 16. We had a hard rain for 2 hours this A.M. and it was cold. The <orgName>Masperos</orgName> went to the <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">Valley</placeName> in spite of it. Mme. <persName ref=>Maspero</persName> had my chair. <pb n="19"/> <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> went over later, and they had lunch with him.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-01-01" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1907-01-01"></date>.</dateline>
        <p>Thursday, Jan. 17. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> and <persName ref=>Jean</persName> went over to the <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">Valley</placeName> this morning. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> reports that they were clearing the corridor and bracing up stones which held part of wooden shrine. It is all under <name>Ayrton's</name> charge. <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I crossed to <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName> this morning. I went to the <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor Hotel</placeName> to see <persName ref=>Mrs. Congdon,</persName> who is better, and then joined <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> at the <placeName ref=>Temples,</placeName> and we took a carriage and drove to the <name>Girls Mission School</name> but found <persName ref=>Miss Buchanan</persName> was in <placeName ref=>Asy&#251;t</placeName> attending the yearly conference. Stopped at <placeName ref=>Mohassibs</placeName> for a little visit. The poor man looks old and ill. <persName ref=>Mr. Carter</persName> and <persName ref=>Rev.</persName> Mr. <persName ref=>Samms</persName> came to tea.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-01-01" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1907-01-01"></date>.</dateline>
        <p>Friday, Jan. 18. We all went over to <persName ref=>Karnac</persName> this afternoon - met <persName ref=>Mme.</persName> <persName ref=>Maspero</persName> and a friend there. Mr. <persName ref=>Sayce</persName> arrived early in the day - I sent him a note asking him to come to tea. <name>Saturday, Jan,</name> 19. At the <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">Valley.</placeName> <persName ref=>Dr. Wiedermann</persName> and wife, and Mr. <persName ref=>Sayce</persName> were over and lunched with us in the lunch tomb. I went down to the burial chamber and it is now almost easy of access - and saw the poor Queen as she lies now just a bit outside her magnificent coffin, with the vulture crown on her head - all the woodwork of the shrine, doors, etc. are heavily overlaid with gold foil - which under the influence of the <pb n="20"/> outer air is now peeling off - and I seemed to be walking on gold - and even the <orgName>Arab</orgName> working inside had some of it sticking in his wooly hair. Here is the sketch of the tomb and situation of objects. No. 1. mummy of Queen - partly overlaid by coffin No. 2 - both on the floor. 3,3,3,3, doors or panels - very large, heavily overlaid with gold, - the one with the x, has a beautiful portrait of <orgName>Queen.</orgName> All of them beautifully incised on the gold leaf. <name>Aton</name> rays on all and <orgName>Khuenatens</orgName> cartouche followed by an inscription "I made this for the great Queen <placeName ref=>Tyi,</placeName> royal mother". The 4 x-a against the wall are 4 large panels, all gold and inscriptions.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-01-01" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1907-01-01"></date>.</dateline>
        <p>Second Sunday after Epiphany - Jan. 20. Home all day - <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> and <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> went to <placeName ref=>Karnac</placeName> in the afternoon. Many visitors. <persName ref=>Mrs. Smith,</persName> Sir <persName ref=>Benjamin Stone,</persName> Mr. <persName ref=>Briggs</persName> and <persName ref=>Currelly; Mr. Sayce</persName> dined with us. Cool, all day - cold, now. My mountains were wonderful this A.M.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-01-01" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1907-01-01"></date>.</dateline>
        <p>Monday, Jan. 21. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> at the <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">Valley</placeName> all day - he reports all the panels being treated to paraffin to hold the gold in place. <persName ref=>Weidermans</persName> dined with us. Our new moon should have shown.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-01-01" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1907-01-01"></date>.</dateline>
        <p>Tuesday, Jan. 22. <persName ref=>Prof. Tarbell, Chicago University,</persName> called with a letter from Mr. <persName ref=>Lythgoe.</persName> <persName ref=>Robert Trefusis</persName> and <persName ref=>Harold Jones</persName> arrived from <placeName ref=>Abydos</placeName> - on coming back after some visits this afternoon found them here. They came back to dine.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-01-01" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1907-01-01"></date>.</dateline>
        <p>Wednesday, Jan. 23. <persName ref=>Robert</persName> and <persName ref=>H. Jones</persName> to dine again - discussed how to treat the panels and doors of shrine. <persName ref=>H.J.</persName> came here to paint or draw them, finds it very difficult - decided to take an impression of inscriptions by wax and plaster of paris - our little new moon showed for the first time tonight.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-01-01" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1907-01-01"></date>.</dateline>
        <p>Thursday, Jan. 24. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> at home today. <persName ref="#Ayrton_Edward">Ayrton</persName> and <persName ref="#Dalison_Max">Mr. Dalison</persName> lunched with us. We all went over to the new hotel, the "Winter <orgName>Palace"</orgName> to have tea and called on Mrs. <persName ref=>Harriman,</persName> who is lying opposite us in the new private steamer the <orgName>Soudan.</orgName> <persName ref=>Robert</persName> and <persName ref=>H.J.</persName> dined with us. Lovely day.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-01-01" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1907-01-01"></date>.</dateline>
        <p>Friday, Jan. 25. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> was all day at the <placeName ref=>Tomb</placeName> - entertained at luncheon, <persName ref=>Prof. Tarbell</persName> and <persName ref=>M. Lacau</persName> - <persName ref="#Ayrton_Edward">Ayrton, Weigall, Robert</persName> and <persName ref=>Harold Jones.</persName> They at last lifted the coffin off the mummy without much damage. Owing to <pb n="22"/> the past presence of water in the tomb, the coffin, except for the cover which is made of gold inlaid with lapis and carnelian, had gone into ruins - and her poor mummy turned into dust. They took off the vulture crown and saw a necklace and bracelets - but did not disturb them as they want a doctor to examine the skeleton and pronounce upon her sex, scientifically. They found the body wrapped in thick gold plates rather than foil. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> brought the crown home with him - and it now lies in the closet at the head of my bed! It is of solid gold, and represents the royal vulture, with out-spread wings and meeting behind the head, beautifully done in a fine r&#233;pouss&#233; style - every feather perfect. <persName ref=>Robert</persName> and <persName ref=>H.J.</persName> dined here.</p>
      </div>
<!-- Where's page 21? This entry moves to page 22, but there's no 21 before it - only 20. -->
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-01-01" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1907-01-01"></date>.</dateline>
        <p>Saturday, Jan. 26. We all went over to the <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">Valley</placeName> this morning and I made my last descent into the tomb. The morning was warm - my poor little donkeys were tired - for <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName> has been the prey of countless multitudes of tourists for weeks. It was our last opportunity to see the tomb and the <orgName>Queen.</orgName> She is nothing but a mass of black dust and bones. Everything is now to be taken out of the tomb, as soon as <persName ref=>Harold Jones</persName> finishes the drawing of the big door - everything has been likewise photographed. Mr. <persName ref=>David Erskine,</persName> M.P. a delightful <persName ref=>Englishman, Theo</persName> fell in with awhile ago, lunched with us for the 2d time in the lunch tomb. We had a merry lunch. <persName ref=>Mrs. Harriman</persName> and daughter, and <persName ref=>Miss Bishop</persName> came to see the tomb. <pb n="23"/> <name>Septuagesima</name></p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-01-01" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1907-01-01"></date>.</dateline>
        <p>Sunday, Jan. 27. I had my quiet little church today - about 4 o'clock as we were waiting for tea, on deck, we saw coming across the distant sands the procession of the treasures of the tomb on its way to us - <persName ref=>Weigall</persName> and <persName ref="#Ayrton_Edward">Ayrton</persName> on horses led the way, and a long procession of <orgName>Arabs</orgName> following carrying the boxes - and the sun striking the rifles of the accompanying sailors. It was really impressive. Our faluccas were sent for them, and a large native gyassa pressed into service - and they are now safely stowed on deck - the smaller things below. Dr. <persName ref=>Weideman</persName> and his wife and Mr. <persName ref=>Sayce</persName> dined with us.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-01-01" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1907-01-01"></date>.</dateline>
        <p>Monday, Jan. 28. A lovely warm day - <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> in the <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">Valley.</placeName> He says everything that is to be moved is out of the tomb. The ashes and bones of the Queen have been reverently gathered and put into a box - and left there - and the tomb is to be hermetically sealed. Mr. <persName ref=>Erskine</persName> dined with us.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-01-01" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1907-01-01"></date>.</dateline>
        <p>Tuesday, Jan. 29. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> took over <persName ref=>Mrs. Harriman</persName> and party to <placeName ref=>Medinet Habu</placeName> today. Mr. <persName ref=>Sayce</persName> came to tea, and we looked over many of the interesting treasure we have on board. <persName ref=>Jones</persName> had a carpenter here early this morning to construct a big box to hold everything that must stay on deck - and now this box 8-1/2 ft. long by 5 ft. high and broad is on our back upper deck and looks formidable and is safe against everything but a concerted raid.</p>
      </div>
        <pb n="24"/>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-01-01" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1907-01-01"></date>.</dateline>
        <p>Wednesday, Jan. 30. <persName ref=>M.</persName> and <persName ref=>Mme.</persName> <persName ref=>Maspero</persName> came to tea and to see the treasures. Mr. <persName ref=>Lacau</persName> with them. <persName ref=>Mrs. Harriman,</persName> her daughter and <persName ref=>Miss Bishop</persName> dined with us. They are on their way to Khartoum. Thursday,</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-01-01" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1907-01-01"></date>.</dateline>
        <p>Jan. 31. Mr. and Mrs. <persName ref=>S. R. Fuller,</persName> with a letter from Mr. and Mrs. <persName ref=>Jack Elliott</persName> of <placeName ref=>Rome,</placeName> came this morning and <personGrp ref=>Mr. and Mrs. Syms and their 2 daughters,</personGrp> people we used to know in the old <name>Bon Air</name> days, came to lunch - and several other visitors.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-02-01" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1907-01-01"></date>.</dateline>
        <p>Friday, Feb. 1. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> and <persName ref=>Jean</persName> in the <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">Valley</placeName> today. Mr. <persName ref="#Carter_Howard">Carter</persName> came to lunch with us.
        Saturday, Feb. 2. We all went to lunch with Mr. <persName ref=>Sayce.</persName> <persName ref=>M.</persName> and Mme. <persName ref=>Naville</persName> and <persName ref=>Mr.</persName> and <persName ref=>Mrs. Weigall</persName> were there - very pleasant. Then we went to the <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName> Hotel gardens to have tea with <persName ref=>Mr.</persName> and <persName ref=>Mrs. Fuller,</persName> who had a great gathering of people. I met for the first time <persName ref=>Miss Hazard,</persName> President of <name>Wellesley College,</name> and <persName ref=>Miss Bates</persName> Prof. of Literature of Wellesley. On our way home we stopped at the <placeName ref=>Winter Palace,</placeName> to see <persName ref=>Miss Tuckerman.</persName> <personGrp ref=>Mr. and Mrs. Guthrie</personGrp> of <placeName ref=>New York,</placeName> and the <orgName>Iddings of Cairo.</orgName> <persName ref=>Harold Jones</persName> dined with us.</p>
      </div>
        <pb n="25"/>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-02-01" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1907-01-01"></date>.</dateline>
        <p><name>Sexagesima</name> Sunday - Feb. 3. Mr. and Mrs. <persName ref=>Guthrie</persName> came to breakfast and stayed until 12 o'clock - perfectly enraptured with all the <orgName>Egyptian</orgName> talk and things. He is most interesting. Mr. and <persName ref=>Mme.</persName> <persName ref=>Naville</persName> came to lunch - and <persName ref=>Harold Jones.</persName> <persName ref="#Lindon_Smith_Joseph">Joe Smith</persName> and his wife and mother were here for tea. Mr. <persName ref=>Van Alen</persName> called, and <persName ref=>M.</persName> and <persName ref=>Mme.</persName> <persName ref=>Maspero</persName> and Mr. <persName ref=>Dalison</persName> dined with us. The day pleasant and warm - and the early morning dawn, ravishingly beautiful.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-02-01" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1907-01-01"></date>.</dateline>
        <p>Monday, Feb. 4. At home all day. <persName ref=>Misses Collins</persName> called this afternoon, and I showed them the treasures.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-02-01" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1907-01-01"></date>.</dateline>
        <p>Tuesday, Feb. 5. <persName ref="#Ayrton_Edward">Ayrton</persName> to lunch - the <persName ref=>Wiedemans</persName> and <persName ref=>Harte</persName> to tea.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-02-01" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1907-01-01"></date>.</dateline>
        <p>Wednesday, Feb. 6. <persName ref="#Lindon_Smith_Joseph">Joe Smith</persName> has been painting one of the beautiful <orgName>Tyi</orgName> heads of the canopic jars here all the morning. <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie, Jean</persName> and I lunched with <persName ref=>Mrs. Weigall.</persName> Mr. <persName ref=>W.</persName> ill and did not appear. Mr. <persName ref=>Smith</persName> lunched with <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> - and Mr. <persName ref=>Van Alen</persName> and friend had tea here, and saw the "find". After we left Mrs. <persName ref=>Weigalls</persName> we went to the <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor,</placeName> and had tea on the croquet lawn with the <persName ref=>Misses Collins</persName> - very pleasant. Mr. <persName ref=>Sayce</persName> sailed for <persName ref=>Asw&#226;n.</persName></p>
      </div>
        <pb n="26"/>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-02-01" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1907-01-01"></date>.</dateline>
        <p>Thursday, Feb. 7. Mr. and Mrs. <persName ref=>Henry Osborne</persName> of <placeName ref=>Milwaukie</placeName> called this morning. <persName ref=>Miss Tuckerman</persName> and her niece lunched with us. <persName ref=>Mrs. Murch</persName> and <persName ref=>Miss Bates</persName> were here for tea. <persName ref="#Lindon_Smith_Joseph">Joe Smith</persName> painting.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-02-01" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1907-01-01"></date>.</dateline>
        <p>Friday, Feb. 8 <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> was in the <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">Valley</placeName> today. Mr. <persName ref=>Van Alen</persName> and his friend, <persName ref="#Ayrton_Edward">Ayrton</persName> and <persName ref=>Jones</persName> lunched with him. <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie, Jean</persName> and I went over to the <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor Hotel</placeName> and head tea with <persName ref=>Mr. Carter.</persName></p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-02-01" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1907-01-01"></date>.</dateline>
        <p>Saturday, Feb. 9 <persName ref=>Mr. Smith</persName> still painting here - stayed to lunch, and went out afterwards with us to the <orgName>Tombs</orgName> of the <orgName>Queens.</orgName> A charming ride.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-02-01" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1907-01-01"></date>.</dateline>
        <p><placeName ref=>Quinquagesima</placeName> Sunday, Feb. 10. Mr. <persName ref="#Carter_Howard">Carter</persName> came this afternoon with <persName ref=>Lord</persName> and <persName ref=>Lady Halsbury</persName> to see the find and soon after <persName ref=>M.</persName> and <persName ref=>Mme.</persName> <persName ref=>Naville,</persName> their daughter and her husband, <persName ref=>M.</persName> and Mme. <persName ref=>Fatio</persName> came - and we had such a pleasant talk with <persName ref=>M. Naville</persName> over the treasures. Then we all went to the <placeName ref=>Masperos</placeName> for tea and to meet Sir <persName ref=>Wm.</persName> <persName ref=>Garstin</persName> and wife, Mr. <persName ref=>Goschen,</persName> and a major <persName ref=>Percira</persName> and his wife. We afterwards called on the <orgName>Livingstons.</orgName></p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-02-01" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1907-01-01"></date>.</dateline>
        <p>Monday, Feb. 11. It was warm today. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> over in <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor,</placeName> calling on <name>Miss Page</name> 27 <persName ref=>Buchanan,</persName> and <persName ref=>Miss Tuckerman.</persName> This afternoon <persName ref=>M. Maspero,</persName> Sir <persName ref=>William Garstin,</persName> Mr. <persName ref=>Goschen,</persName> and <persName ref=>Major</persName> and <persName ref=>Mrs. Percira</persName> came to tea and after were shown the find. <persName ref=>M. Maspero</persName> delighted <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> by saying they wanted him to have one of the canopic heads and he hoped he would choose the best one. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> replied he would not do that, but would choose the one having a stain across the head caused by dripping water. They were all delighted with the things - Sir <persName ref=>William,</persName> I found most interesting. It is raining a little tonight.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-02-01" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1907-01-01"></date>.</dateline>
        <p>Tuesday, Feb. 12. <persName ref=>Harold Jones</persName> began painting the beautiful <persName ref=>Tyl</persName> head this morning - and was here all day. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> took <persName ref=>Jean</persName> and <persName ref=>Miss Tuckerman</persName> with him to <orgName>Karnac.</orgName> Dr. and Mrs. <persName ref=>Pollack</persName> came to tea. Day very dark and threatening - and last night a hard gale was raging.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-02-01" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1907-01-01"></date>.</dateline>
        <p>Wednesday, Feb. 13. Ash Wednesday. <persName ref=>Harold Jones</persName> again painting. <persName ref=>Miss Tuckerman</persName> and <persName ref=>Joan</persName> came to lunch. In the afternoon we all went over to <persName ref=>Der el Bahari,</persName> and <persName ref=>M. Naville</persName> showed <persName ref=>Miss T.</persName> the temple. She was delighted with him and the opportunity. We went afterwards to tea with <persName ref=>Mme.</persName> <persName ref=>Naville</persName> at the <orgName>German</orgName> House. When we got home we found we had missed <persName ref=>M. Maspero.</persName> Mr. <persName ref=>Percy Machaye</persName> and <persName ref=>Lady Victoria,</persName> his wife; but <persName ref=>Harold Jones</persName> showed the treasures. We also missed Sir <persName ref=>Henry Craik.</persName></p>
      </div>
        <pb n="28"/>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-02-01" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1907-01-01"></date>.</dateline>
        <p>Thursday, Feb. 14. We were overwhelmed with people this A.M. A <personGrp ref=>Mr. and Mrs. Crocker</personGrp> introduced by letter from the <persName ref=>Folgers,</persName> and Mr. White. They both brought boat loads of people with them - a nuisance and impertinence! Mr. <persName ref=>Hall</persName> also came, but we lost the pleasure of his visit, by this crowd. 17 people at once in our little salon, is too much. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> and <persName ref=>Jean</persName> in the valley, they got home early, as <persName ref=>Lord</persName> and <persName ref=>Lady Cromer</persName> were coming at 5 o'clock. The <persName ref=>Weigalls,</persName> and a Mr. <persName ref=>Eric Villiers</persName> saw the things and then came the <persName ref=>Cromers</persName> and <persName ref=>M. Maspero,</persName> and <persName ref=>Lady Cromer</persName> was much interested and he much more so than he seemed. They were entranced with the boat and especially with my room. She is quite charming and he is interesting because of his achievements, and because of the power he wields.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-02-01" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1907-01-01"></date>.</dateline>
        <p>Friday, Feb. 15. All the family except myself went to the <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">Valley</placeName> today. <persName ref=>Miss Tuckerman</persName> with them. <persName ref=>Harold Jones</persName> and I had a pleasant quiet day. Mr. and Mrs. <persName ref=>John H. Livingston</persName> called. The <orgName>Masperos</orgName> started down the river today.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-02-01" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1907-01-01"></date>.</dateline>
        <p>Saturday, Feb. 16. <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and <persName ref=>Jean</persName> lunched with <persName ref=>Miss Tuckerman</persName> today. This afternoon the <persName ref=>Hutesons,</persName> and some friends of <persName ref=>Jeans, Dr. Schweinf&#252;rt,</persName> and <persName ref=>Fachery Pasha</persName> called. Quite warm.</p>
      </div>
        <pb n="29"/>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-02-01" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1907-01-01"></date>.</dateline>
        <p>1st Sunday in <placeName ref=>Lent.</placeName> Feb. 17. Mr. <persName ref=>Hall</persName> lunched with us. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> was in <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName> this A.M. and <persName ref="#Carter_Howard">Carter</persName> told him of various small and precious things which had been shown him by a native which had been stolen from <placeName ref=>Tyi's</placeName> tomb. The man had told <persName ref="#Carter_Howard">Carter</persName> that Mr. <persName ref=>Davis</persName> could have them all for 400. - provided no attempt at arrest was made! These fellows are difficult to deal with. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> told <persName ref="#Carter_Howard">Carter</persName> if the men would produce everything they had, and would show them, he might consider a price and promise no arrests to be made. Their practice is to mass together a lot of valuable things on such an occasion, with what has been stolen from a late find, and try to get a big price for all. Later in the day <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> went into <placeName ref=>Abd el Hamed's</placeName> and <placeName ref=>Ali's</placeName> shops on the river, and the latter handed him several small objects from the tomb - some gold "neferts" from the necklace, carnelian lotus flowers, and a lovely bit of gold and enamel from a necklace - only one of which we have - and it is marked No. 17 in hieroglyphic characters. <persName ref=>Ali</persName> would not take anything for these - among them one bearing <persName ref=>Aten's</persName> cartouche. It is humiliating to find that thieves have been among your trusted workmen - they have such chances in sifting d&#232;bris, to hide a valuable thing in their loose clothes. Mr. <persName ref=>Lythgoe</persName> and <persName ref=>Countess Henckel</persName> and her daughter <persName ref=>Countess Hahn</persName> came to tea - and <persName ref=>M.</persName> and <persName ref=>Mme.</persName> <persName ref=>Fatio</persName> and <persName ref=>Dalison</persName> dined with us. A lovely warm day.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-02-01" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1907-01-01"></date>.</dateline>
        <p>Monday, Feb. 18. A most unpleasant day of tremendous wind and sand flying in <pb n="30"/> clouds over us. No one ventured out. Mr. Lythgoe to lunch.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-02-01" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1907-01-01"></date>.</dateline>
        <p>Tuesday, Feb. 19. <name>Countess Henckel,</name> and <persName ref=>Hahn</persName> and <persName ref="#Ayrton_Edward">Ayrton</persName> to lunch. <persName ref="#Ayrton_Edward">Ayrton</persName> deeply distressed about the robbery. He suspects the trusted <persName ref=>Rais,</persName> or rather 2 sons of his. It is mysterious. <persName ref=>Harold Jones</persName> finished his two paintings of <persName ref=>Tyi,</persName> and went back to <placeName ref=>Abydos</placeName> tonight. A boat load of people came this afternoon with a note from Mrs. <persName ref=>Weigall</persName> asking that they might be shown the find. Miss <persName ref=>Tuckerman</persName> came to say goodbye, as she is off for Asw&#226;n.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-02-01" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1907-01-01"></date>.</dateline>
        <p>Thursday, Feb. 21st. Theo, <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I went over to <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName> this A.M. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> to see <persName ref=>Weigall</persName> about robbery. <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I to <name>Carter's</name> studio - asked him to tea. <persName ref="#Lindon_Smith_Joseph">Joe Smith,</persName> and wife, dined here. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> later went to the <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">Valley</placeName> with <persName ref=>Jean</persName> and <persName ref=>Countess Hahn.</persName></p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-02-01" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1907-01-01"></date>.</dateline>
        <p>Friday, Feb. 22. A quiet day on board. Rev. Mr. <persName ref=>Samms</persName> came in the afternoon to play chess with <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> and <persName ref=>Mr.</persName> and <persName ref=>Mrs. Smith</persName> came to tea.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-02-01" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1907-01-01"></date>.</dateline>
        <p>Saturday, Feb. 23. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> and <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> went to <name>Der el Medinet</name> this afternoon. <persName ref=>Robert Trefusis</persName> arrived unexpectedly. Prof. <persName ref=>Fairfield Osborn,</persName> his son, and Mrs. <persName ref=>Evert Jansen Wendell</persName> came - having sent on their letters of introduction <pb n="31"/> from Mrs. <persName ref=>Parsons</persName> and <persName ref=>Mary,</persName> some days before their arrival.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-02-01" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1907-01-01"></date>.</dateline>
        <p>Second Sunday in Lent. Feb. 24. Such a busy day - and such a tiresome afternoon. The very nice <orgName>Osborns,</orgName> son and Mr. <persName ref=>Wendell</persName> came at 11 A.M. to be shown the treasures - enraptured with them. <persName ref=>Dalison</persName> and <persName ref=>Robert</persName> to lunch. At 3 o'clock a farewell visit from <persName ref=>M.</persName> and Mme. <name>Naville,</name> and <persName ref=>M.</persName> and <persName ref=>Mme.</persName> <name>Fatio</name> - also from <persName ref=>Countess Henckel</persName> and <persName ref=>Countess Hahn</persName> - Mr. <name>Le Grain</name> and his wife had been formally asked to tea some days ago and Mr. <persName ref=>Weigall</persName> had written last evening asking if he might bring <persName ref=>Lord</persName> and <persName ref=>Lady Carnarvon,</persName> and <persName ref=>Mrs. Loring</persName> and her friend of <placeName ref=>Boston</placeName> to see the find, <persName ref=>Dr. Johnson</persName> belonging to the <orgName>Carnarvons.</orgName> These latter I thought simply intolerable. But it was tiresome! The nice <persName ref=>Osborns</persName> and Mr. <persName ref=>Wendell</persName> and <persName ref=>Robert</persName> dined here. A charming evening with charming people.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-02-01" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1907-01-01"></date>.</dateline>
        <p>Monday, Feb. 25. <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie, Theo</persName> and I over in <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName> this <persName ref=>A.M. Nettie</persName> and I to say goodbye to <persName ref=>Miss Buchanan</persName> and to call on the <orgName>Pollocks</orgName> - stopped at the <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor Hotel</placeName> for the <orgName>Miss Collins</orgName> who were coming to lunch. Such a nice visit, from two Scotch bodies I like so much. Mr. <persName ref=>Murch</persName> was here this morning, and he promised to bring his wife and our old friend <persName ref=>Mohammed Mohassib</persName> this afternoon to see the find. The poor old man has had a stroke this winter and is sadly changed. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> and the girls were away - but I showed him everything and we all had tea together. He <pb n="32"/> was pathetic - and I think we will hardly find him here next year. We are ready to get off tomorrow. I shall hate leaving my beautiful mountains and desert - our sand island has grown enormously - and the patches of wheat <persName ref=>Jones</persName> sowed for the fowls is now quite ornamental. But we do look forward to relief from continual visitors. Our young moon already makes the nights glorious.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-02-01" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1907-01-01"></date>.</dateline>
        <p>Tuesday, Feb. 26. Mr. <persName ref="#Carter_Howard">Carter, Ayrton,</persName> and <persName ref=>Robert</persName> came to say goodbye early - with over 2 policemen. We thought it best to ask for them, as we found our men were all in a funk about having so many treasures on board. We got away at noon. The <name>Smiths</name> are following us. We have made 23 miles. Tied up at 6:30.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-02-01" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1907-01-01"></date>.</dateline>
        <p>Wednesday, Feb. 27. 47 miles. We are lying this lovely night about 4 miles above <name>Kasr el Said</name> - having made a good record. It has been warm and the night is wonderful.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-02-01" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1907-01-01"></date>.</dateline>
        <p>Thursday, Feb. 28. 26 miles. We reached <placeName ref=>Nag Hamadi</placeName> at 9 o'clock this morning - and had to wait for the bridge. The <persName ref=>Smiths</persName> soon pulled up behind us - and the family came over, sweet babies and all, for a visit. <persName ref=>Joe</persName> has not yet joined them - telegraphed Mr. <persName ref=>Garstang</persName> at <placeName ref=>Abydos</placeName> that we would reach there tomorrow. Passed the bridge at one o'clock. 17</p>
      </div>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
