<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>Diary of Mrs. Emma B. Andrews. Volume 16 1908-1909</title>
        <author>
          <persName ref="#Andrews_Emma_B">Emma B. Andrews</persName>
        </author>
        <editor>
          <persName ref="#SK">Sarah Ketchley</persName>
        </editor>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>
          <orgName ref="#Emma_B_Andrews_Diary_Project">Emma B. Andrews Diary Project</orgName>
        </publisher>
        <address>
          <addrLine>University of Washington, Seattle, WA</addrLine>
        </address>
        <availability>
          <licence target="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/">This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial Share-Alike 4.0 International License.</licence>
        </availability>
        <date>2021-01-10</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <p><orgName ref="#American_Philosophical_Society_Philadelphia">American Philosophical Society, Philadelphia</orgName></p>
      </sourceDesc>
      <encodingStmt>
        <projectDesc>
          <p>Established in 2010, the goals of the <orgName ref="#Emma_B_Andrews_Diary_Project">Emma B. Andrews Diary Project</orgName> include the transcription and digitization of a wide range of primary historical material from the'Golden Age' of Egyptian archaeology at the end of the 19th and beginning of the 20th centuries. A founding partner of <orgName ref="#Newbook_Digital_Texts">Newbook Digital Texts</orgName> (www.newbookdigitaltexts.org), the <orgName ref="#EBA_Diary_Project">EBA Diary Project</orgName> offers undergraduate and graduate digital humanities education and internships at the <orgName ref="#University_of_Washington">University of Washington</orgName>. <persName ref="#Andrews_Emma_B">Emma B. Andrews</persName> is best remembered for her association with the millionaire lawyer turned archaeologist/art and antiquities collector, <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore M. Davis</persName>. Traveling to <placeName ref="#Egypt">Egypt</placeName> with him between 1889 and 1912, she kept detailed journals of these voyages along the <placeName ref="#Nile">Nile</placeName>, including his important yet under-reported excavations of over 20 significant tombs in the <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">Valley of the Kings</placeName>. <persName ref="#Andrews_Emma_B">Emma</persName> provides a vital commentary on the archaeology and pioneering Egyptologists of the time, painting a revealing picture of the lives of the colonial gentry and the cultural and scientific literati in at the dawn of the twentieth century. Analysis of the content of her diaries, along with a broad range of additional primary source material, will afford scholars information about important historical resources for the first time.</p>
        </projectDesc>
      </encodingStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-11-09" type="entry">
        <dateline>
            <date when="1905-11-09">Nov. 9. 1905.</date>
            <name type="boat" ref="#SS_Princess_Irene">SS. Princess Irene</name>
        </dateline>
        <p>This is the 13th day of our voyage! will reach <placeName ref="#Naples">Naples</placeName> tomorrow morning at 6 o'clock. I love that early morning entrance into these enchanted waters - to see the first gleam upon the crater and smoke of <placeName ref="#Vesuvius">Vesuvius</placeName> while all is dark and obscure below. The weather has been bad most of the way, and we are far behind time. The last few days have been fine - I am in the same spacious and luxurious rooms of the Captain that I had last year - and I have enjoyed them even more than I did then - their height and quiet - where through the door open night and day on my own little deck, I seem to possess the heavens and earth, and I have accomplished a lot of planning for the farm and for the garden. We know a few of our fellow-passengers - <personGrp ref="#Folger">Admiral and Mrs. Folger</personGrp>, <persName ref="#Mahan_Captain">Captain Mahan</persName> and family, <personGrp ref="#Whitehouse">Mr. and Mrs. Whitehouse</personGrp> of <placeName ref="#Irvington">Irvington</placeName> on the <placeName ref="#Hudson">Hudson</placeName> etc. <persName ref="#Dannomeuse_Captain">Captain Dannomeuse</persName> is the Prince of Captains - interesting, thoughtful and studious.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1905-11-12" type="entry">
            <dateline>
                <date when="1905-11-12">Nov. 12th.</date>
                <name type="boat" ref="#Brindist">Brindist</name>
            </dateline>
        <p>Reached <placeName ref="#Naples">Naples</placeName> Friday at 6 A.M. had a good landing - though later the rain began, and prevented us from doing anything but stay indoors the rest of the day. We had the same weather the next morning, until noon, when we left for <placeName ref="#Brindisi">Brindisi</placeName>, most of our time was spent with <persName ref="#Constantini_David">David Costantini</persName>, who had brought his new wife down to see us. We were quite pleased with her. A well dressed, lady like woman of the world, <pb n="109"/>evidently very fond of him - but the disparity in years would seem perhaps to make the result unhappy. She was a <persName ref="#Sahopek_Ida">Miss Ida Sahopek</persName> of <placeName ref="#New_York">New York</placeName>, and then a <persName ref="Wilderming_Mrs">Mrs. Wilmerding</persName>, from which marriage she gets her money. We had the usual tiring ride over here, arriving at 10:30 P.M. This hotel is drearier and dirtier than ever but the Captain of the <name type="boat" ref="#Isis">Isis</name> has take pity on us, and says we may go aboard for luncheon.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1905-11-15" type="entry">
            <dateline>
                <date when="1905-11-15">Wednesday, November 15, 1905.</date>
                <name type="hotel" ref="#Shepheards_Hotel">Shepheards Hotel</name>
                <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName>
            </dateline>
        <p>Arrived at <placeName ref="#Port_Said">Port Said</placeName> this morning at 6 o'clock. Caught the train, luggage and all in time to reach here at 5:30. To our amazement the hotel seems quite full. There is a great rush to <placeName ref="#Egypt">Egypt</placeName> it seems this winter. In our old rooms.</p>
        </div> 
        <div xml:id="EBA-1905-11-24" type="entry">
            <dateline>
                <date when="1905-11-24">Nov. 24th.</date>
            </dateline>
        <p>Came on board the <name type="boat" ref="#Beduin">Beduin</name> at noon - after a pleasant, busy week at <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName>. <personGrp ref="#Dennis">Mr. and Mrs. Dennis</personGrp> of <placeName ref="#Baltimore">Baltimore</placeName> are here. He is to work at <placeName ref="#Der_el_Bahari">Der el Bahri</placeName> this year. Saw <persName ref="##Somers_Clarke_George">Mr. Somers-Clarke</persName> who dined with us; <persName ref="#Breasted_Mr">Mr. Breasted</persName>, who with his wife are en route to the <placeName ref="#Sudan">Sudan</placeName> to copy inscriptions. Saw much of <!--- [Bonoham Carter?] --> <persName>Mr. Carter</persName> - who has at last resigned from the <orgName ref="#Serivce_des_Antiquities">Service des Antiquit&#232;s</orgName>. I was very glad to hear it. <!---[which Jean?]--><persName>Jean</persName> and I drove out to the country to the pretty little house he has taken, and had tea with him. He is going to devote himself to painting - a thing he should have done years ago. One of the most interesting men I have [not able to discern what was written.] <pb n="110"/> (L.H.) invited us to make him a visit at his farm, away up at the mouth of the <placeName ref="#Atbara_River">Atbara river</placeName>! How we would have liked it! He was taking up with him Mr. and <persName ref="#Idding_Mrs">Mrs. Idding</persName>, our new Vice-Consul. Mr. <!--[JP MORGAN?]--><persName>Morgan</persName> gave us a tea, where we met the <personGrp ref="#Iddings">Iddings</personGrp>. I had met him years ago at <placeName ref="#Rome">Rome</placeName>, one evening when Mrs. <persName ref="#Bronson_Mrs">Bronson</persName> gave us a dinner in her beautiful appartment in the <placeName>Palazzo Borghese.</placeName> He tells me that <persName>Ethel</persName> still occupies it. She is now <persName>Princopessa Ethel Rospigliosi</persName> - having married Prince <persName>Giovanni Battista Rospigliosi</persName> - a sensible marriage de convenance Mr. <persName>Iddings</persName> said - who has known the <name>Bronsons</name> intimately for years. <persName>Ethel</persName> gave her money, was received into the <placeName>Catholic Church</placeName> - and got his title, and was received in his family where she had long been, she and her mother, on intimate terms. We got off with a tug about 2 o'clock, which we will take as far as <name>Asy&#251;t</name> - <persName>Theodore</persName> being impatient to reach <orgName>Luxor.</orgName> <persName>Amelie</persName> has been the victim of repeated colds since she came to <placeName>Egypt</placeName> - and was in bed 2 days with rheumatism before we started. We made 16 miles today. 
          
        Saturday, Nov. 25. 47 miles. and are 7 miles above Wasta. 
          
        23 Sunday after Trinity. Nov. 26. 30 miles. Are lying at <placeName>Fashen</placeName> - having made 30 miles. <persName>Amelie</persName> much of the time in bed with cold and repeated attacks of dysentery. <persName>Jones</persName> half ill with a cold. 
          
        Page 111 Monday, Nov. 27th. [Unreadable] 	Head wind all day. Passed <persName>Mr. Sayce</persName> at 8:30 this morning. 
          
        <placeName>Tuesday,</placeName> Nov. 28th. 31 miles. Stopped at <placeName>Minia</placeName> for the mail at 4 o'clock. Mr. and <persName>Mrs. Frazer</persName> came over to see us - their boat being near us. 
          
        Wednesday, Nov. 29th. 45 miles. just below the troublesome <orgName>Gebel Abufeydah</orgName> - quite warm today. 
          
        Thursday, November 30th. 43 miles. A warm day - we dropped our tug on arriving here (Asy&#251;t) at 5:30 and will go on without it. 
          
        Silsilis. Feb. 8th, 1906. It is a far cry back to that day at <placeName>Asy&#251;t.</placeName> The next day I went to bed with a sudden cold which I had been fighting for 2-3 days - and there I stayed for nearly 4 weeks - more ill than I have ever been in my life, with a severe attack of bronchitis. That was a weary time. Page 112 It taught me much. We stayed in <placeName>Luxor</placeName> at our usual place at the sand bank opposite the town, for 7 weeks and 4 days. <persName>Theo</persName> very busy with his work. He unearthed 3-4 tombs. One only having any special interest - that of <name>Siptah,</name> an inimportant king of the XIX dynasty. We had of course visitors all day long - from those at breakfast to lunch - tea and dinner. I spent a great part of my time waiting for people to go! Mr. Agassig (sic Agassiz) and May were in <placeName>Luxor</placeName> several days, and we saw much of them, they are delighted with <placeName>Egypt</placeName> - with <placeName>Luxor</placeName> and its climate - and especially with the dahabya and our mode of life. We got away at last on the 4th and have made on our 3 days - 9 miles - 33-1/2 - 30. It has been very warm and cloudy for 2 days - yesterday a few drops of rain fell - and this evening it is raining sharply - after a short storm of strong wind. Very hot today. We were all quite limp and lazy - yesterday about 11 o'clock we saw away in the distance a dahabya at <placeName>Silsileh,</placeName> which we thought must be Mr. Sayce's. The wind failed however and we couldn't get on. All this morning we were tracking and pulling to an anchor - the river as smooth as a mirror. Just as we were almost in hailing distance of the <orgName>Istar,</orgName> we saw her pull out in the river, and start down. Mr. <persName>Sayce</persName> came over in his felucca for a few moments. He reports the prehistoric ground he has been examining to have been in time past completely plundered. Just before we tied up for the night, the <persName>Scarab</persName> overtook us, with Mr. and Mrs. <persName>Frank Gould</persName> and Mr. <persName>Newberry</persName> on board. We had hoped to reach <placeName>Asw&#226;n</placeName> before they did. Rained a little this evening. 
          
        Page 113 Friday, Feb. 9th. 36 miles. We have made a good day of it - and arrived at the big sycamore under the <placeName>Grenvill</placeName> tombs about 6:30. The day has been warm and clouded.
          
        Saturday, Feb. 10. It has been a very hot day - we sailed around to our old place on the rocky little island opposite the <placeName>Cataract Hotel</placeName> early this morning. This afternoon we rowed around the <placeName>Savoy Hotel,</placeName> and had tea in those charming gardens. Dined at the <placeName>Cataract Hotel</placeName> and met Mr. and <persName>Mrs. Whitehouse,</persName> Mr. and <persName>Mrs. Nemness, Dr. Morrell, Mr. Newberry</persName> and the <name>Goulds</name> from the <orgName>Scarab</orgName> - and glad to find <persName>Miss Morgan</persName> there. The new handsome big dining room was crowded with people - every one in full dress. <persName>Theo</persName> and I came away at 11 - leaving <persName>Jean</persName> and <persName>Robert</persName> for the dance.
        
        <placeName>Septuagesima</placeName> Sunday. Feb. 11. A horrid day of cold wind and rain. I never saw the atmosphere fuller of sand - and it came everywhere into the boat. It rained about 4 hours. The <orgName>Beduin</orgName> happily is water tight. <persName>Miss Morgan</persName> came over to dinner and Mr. <persName>Newberry</persName> to tea. The <name>Scarab</name> goes down tomorrow.
         
        Monday, Feb. 12. A high cold wind all day - but sunshine and a clear atmosphere Page 114 <persName>Jean</persName> and <persName>Robert</persName> and <persName>Miss Morgan</persName> went over to the <placeName>Busharin</placeName> village this morning - and we went with her to the <placeName>Savoy</placeName> this afternoon for tea. The gardens deliciously fresh after the rain. We dined with the <orgName>Whitehouses</orgName> at the <placeName>Cataract,</placeName> and had a charming evening. Saw the <persName>Hennops, Mr.</persName> and <persName>Mrs. Hall</persName> of <placeName>Boston,</placeName> and Mr. <persName>Talbot Kelley,</persName> the artist. We start down tomorrow. 
          
        Tuesday, Feb. 13. 13 miles. Started soon after breakfast with the usual contrary wind - but worked our way along to this point, lovely day, with cool wind. I hate to leave these red golden sands, these strange, sombre rocks - and the dry pure air of <placeName>Asw&#226;n</placeName> - it has a quality quite to itself. 
          
        Wednesday, Feb. 14. 33 miles. This has been one of the worst days I ever knew on the river. It began with a high wind and no sun, and soon began to rain - and kept on raining steadily the whole day. It was a miserable day for the men, who worked manfully at their oars, saturated as they must have been - and we are now lying below Silsilis. Passed the <orgName>Zenet-et-Nil</orgName> the other side of <placeName>Silsilis</placeName> just before dark. Did not see Mr. and <persName>Mrs. Bird.</persName> Thursday, 
          
        Feb. 15. 30 miles. Another bad day, beginning with a thick mist that <orgName>Page 115</orgName> has lasted the whole day in spite of a stiff north wind. It has been cold - we are at this time 5:30 - about 6 miles from <placeName>Edfou,</placeName> and it is already almost dark. We are floating by the aid of our "sea anchor". It is strange how few gyassas we see in this part of the river.
          
        Friday, Feb. 16. <name>El Kab.</name> 17-1/2 miles. We have had a clear day at last - but a very cold wind from the north, increasing as day wore on. We made the shore opposite <name>El Kab</name> with difficulty. Was much interested in the new house Mr. <persName>Somers-Clarke</persName> is building about a mile above <placeName>El Kab.</placeName> It is on a little spur from the hills, and must have a lovely view. It liked it very much. It fits with dignity and appropriateness into its surroundings. So sorry we could not stop and see it.
           
        Saturday, Feb. 17. 34 miles. Two miles from <placeName>Gebelen.</placeName> In spite of head winds we are now within 20 miles of <placeName>Luxor.</placeName> The morning was very cold. <name>Mercury</name> 54 in my room - and a cold wind all day. It grew warm about 5 P.M. and now at 10 o'clock there are no stars to be seen and it is warm and close. 
        
        <placeName>Sexigesima</placeName> Sunday. Feb. 18th. Luxor. 20 miles. Arrived at 2:30, found a great mail. We have fought the contrary wind all the five and a half days we have been coming from <placeName>Asw&#226;n</placeName> - on the moment of our arrival the <orgName>Page 116</orgName> south wind began to blow. Mr. <persName>Newberry</persName> came to dine. 
        
        Luxor. Feb. 19th. A terrific gale from the <placeName>S.W.</placeName> has been blowing all day. In spite of it, <persName>Theo</persName> and <persName>Robert</persName> went over to the <placeName>Valley</placeName> in clouds of dust. They stopped on the way home at <placeName>Der el Bahri</placeName> to see the big <orgName>Hathor</orgName> cow discovered there lately. <persName>Theo</persName> closes his general explorations today - but is going to clear out the tomb of Mentu-her-repshef's tomb (sic). This tomb was opened by <persName>Champollion,</persName> but has not been seen since his time, as it has become filled with stone and d&#233;bris. <persName>Theo</persName> thought he might find valuable inscriptions. 
        
        <placeName>Tuesday,</placeName> Feb. 20. Sir <persName>Thomas</persName> the Lady <persName>Acland</persName> came to tea - she is an aunt of <orgName>Robert's</orgName> - very nice people. We had Mr. and Mrs. <persName>Hennop, Grace Hennop,</persName> and <persName>Miss Ewart</persName> to dine - a pleasant evening - a cold day - and still wind. <placeName>Wednesday,</placeName> 
        
        Feb. 21st. Over to <placeName>Luxor</placeName> this morning to the <placeName>Hotel,</placeName> and to the school - find <persName>Miss Buchanan</persName> is in <placeName>Cairo</placeName> - our cold wind still holds. 
        
        Thursday, Feb. 22nd. We had the boat dressed with our flags in honour of the day - [not able to read]. <persName>Jean</persName> and I drove out to see <persName>Mrs. Weigall</persName> this Page 117 morning - met there <persName>Baron v. Bissing,</persName> who has just arrived - looking remarkably well. Young <persName>Mr. Mandsley</persName> to dine. 
        
        <div xml:id="EBA-1906-2-23" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1906-2-23">Friday, Feb. 23.</date>
          </dateline>
          <p>We all went over to the <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">Valley</placeName> this morning and lunched there in <persName ref="#Ayrton_Edward">Mr. Ayrton</persName>'s tent - in company with him and his two funny little dogs. He had many rather interesting fragments to show. In spite of very bad donkeys in my chair, the poor things are always worn out by this time of the year, I enjoyed the ride. The day was very warm - but I got home without feeling a bit tired. The sight of that splendid deep blue sky above those yellow, buttressed cliffs, without a speck of a cloud, and as I gazed into its soft depths burning to a violet purple it was worth seeing. <persName>Jean</persName> and <persName>Robert</persName> went over to the hotel to dine.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1906-2-24" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1906-2-24">Saturday, Feb. 24.</date>
          </dateline>
          <p>At home all day - wind strong. Called on <persName>Lady Acland</persName> at Savoy. <persName>Miss Bruce,</persName> the <persName>Miss Collins</persName> - and <persName>Mrs Dennis</persName> to tea.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1906-2-25" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1906-2-25">Sunday - Feb. 25.</date>
            <placeName ref="#Quinquagesima">Quinquagesima</placeName>
          </dateline>
          <p>Mr. <persName>Corelly</persName> came to lunch. <persName>Mrs. Hunt</persName> and <persName>Baron v. Bissing</persName> to tea - <persName>M.</persName> and Mme. <persName>Naville</persName> and Mr. <persName>Sayce</persName> to dine. I was very tired and sleepy.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1906-2-26" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1906-2-26">Monday, Feb. 26.</date> 
          </dateline>
          <p><persName>Theo</persName> and <persName>Robert</persName> went over to the <placeName>Valley</placeName> this morning taking <pb n="118"/> Mr. and <persName>Mrs. Laffan</persName> - I lent my chair to Mrs. <persName>L.</persName> it was a hot day, and I hated to have them go. They stopped on the way home and had tea with the <persName>Navilles</persName> at the <orgName>German</orgName> house. I had a missionary tea this afternoon - <persName>Miss Buchanan, Miss Gordon, Miss Atcheson,</persName> and Freda. <persName>Miss B.</persName> and I have had a great chat and a great deal to talk about, as <persName>Freda</persName> is to be married in April. She makes an excellent marriage - to a teacher in the <orgName>German</orgName> school at <placeName>Asw&#226;n,</placeName> a native, but a <orgName>Christian,</orgName> having lived in <placeName>England</placeName> - and speaking and writing <orgName>English</orgName> very well. <persName>Freda</persName> improves enormously and was baptized last summer at <placeName>Khartoum.</placeName> This man has a house furnished in <orgName>European</orgName> style, and bears an excellent character - and we all feel it a happy thing for her. But at the school they feel a little sad over it, as she will be so much missed. the new school building is almost finished - they have occupied for a year the lower floor - but are very crowded thus - it is a big, fine building - very substantial, with thick walls and high ceilings. It must always be cool - all the arrangements are admirable - a pretty chapel, a court, quite a garden - and such nice dormitories. There are now 230 pupils - and when finished, the building will accomodate 100 more. <persName>Miss Buchanan</persName> has 6 girls, who are to marry this spring - and she has been giving them herself in the evenings a course of training in family life - the care of children, and of the sick etc. I think the work she is doing is about the biggest in Egypt. Each one of her girls as they marry and have homes and children will form a leaven for succeeding generations.</p> 
        </div>
        <pb n="119"/>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1906-2-27" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1906-2-27">Tuesday, Feb. 27.</date> 
          </dateline>
          <p>Sir <persName>Thomas</persName> the <persName>Lady Acland</persName> to lunch - such a pleasant visit. <persName>Jean</persName> and I went over to the <placeName>Luxor</placeName> hotel to tea with those nice <orgName>Miss Collins</orgName> - in the garden, and had Scotch cake. Mr. <persName>Mandsley</persName> and Mr. <persName>Ayrton</persName> called after we got home. High wind all day. Paid farewell call to the <persName>Insingers,</persName> and took them some books.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1906-2-28" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1906-2-28">Ash-Wednesday, Feb. 28.</date> 
          </dateline>
          <p>We went over to <placeName>Luxor</placeName> this morning, <persName>Theo</persName> to the mission school, <persName>Jean</persName> and <persName>Robert</persName> to play tennis with <persName>Newberry</persName> and <persName>Mrs. Dennis,</persName> and I to church in the little chapel - Mr. <persName>Sayce</persName> assisted <persName>Mr. Cross.</persName> Met Sir <persName>Thomas</persName> and <persName>Lady Acland,</persName> the <persName>Miss Collins,</persName> and <persName>Miss Bruce.</persName> <persName>Jean</persName> and I went to tea with Mr. <persName>Sayce.</persName> <persName>Newberry, Mr.</persName> and <persName>Mrs. Weigall</persName> and <persName>Mrs. Dennis</persName> came after we got home. Mr. and Mrs. <persName>Laffan</persName> lunched with us. We start for <placeName>Cairo</placeName> tomorrow. Our tent is struck - the awnings down, and I for one, glad to get away from <placeName>Luxor</placeName> and its people - but not glad to say goodbye to the splendid <placeName>Theban</placeName> mountains and desert. We have spent 2 months and 3 days at Luxor.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1906-3-1" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1906-3-1">Thursday, March 1st.</date>
            <measure type="distance">40 miles.</measure>
          </dateline>
          <p>We have had a beautiful day - started at 6 o'clock A.M. and rowed until nearly 8 o'clock. We have a beautiful young moon now. I had an early farewell interview with my splendid mountains - touched to every shade of soft pink colour.</p>
        </div>
        <pb n="120"/>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1906-3-2" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1906-3-2">Friday, Mar. 2d.</date>
            <measure type="distance">12 miles.</measure>
          </dateline>
          <p><placeName>North</placeName> wind all day - we are about 6 miles below <placeName>Keneh</placeName> - passed the <orgName>Birds</orgName> on <placeName>Zenet-el-Nil</placeName> just above <placeName>Keneh.</placeName> They were lying by.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1906-3-3" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1906-3-3">Saturday, March 3d.</date>
            <measure type="distance">10 miles.</measure>
          </dateline>
          <p>We have been floating all day against an adverse wind - rather warm - <persName>Ammon-Ra</persName> went down.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1906-3-4" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1906-3-4">First Sunday in Lent.</date>
            <measure type="distance">11 miles.</measure>
          </dateline>
          <p>Made an early start at 6 A.M. but were obliged to pull up to a pleasant little low bank early in the afternoon. <persName>Passe Dischna</persName> at 8 o'clock - having seen it in the distance for hours yesterday. Very warm - <name>Isis</name> went down with tug.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1906-3-5" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1906-3-5">Monday, March 5th.</date>
            <measure type="distance">29 miles.</measure>
          </dateline>
          <p>The men began rowing this morning at 6 o'clock - quite calm and warm. Reached <persName>Nagh Hamadi</persName> at 8 o'clock, and waited for the bridge to open at 9:30. No wind all day and very warm. Arrived at <placeName>Balliana</placeName> about 6:30. <persName>Jean</persName> and <persName>Robert</persName> wishing to see <placeName>Abydos</placeName> tomorrow.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1906-3-6" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1906-3-6">March 6. Tuesday.</date>
            <placeName ref="#Balliana">Balliana</placeName>
          </dateline>
          <p>We had a great gale last night - it began to blow about 11 o'clock and I noticed how very black the sky was when I went to bed. <pb n="121"/> I had just fallen asleep, when I was wakened by the noise, and the running and calling of the sailors and the rattling of chains. I looked out of my window again, and saw that our stern was quite out in the stream - the wind coming from off shore - the boat had dragged the stern anchor - and the men were all busy getting out extra ropes, anchores, etc. <persName>Theo</persName> got up and lighted his candle, and strayed about the boat, looking out of the windows. It blew all night and grew cold - and was still blowing when <persName>J.</persName> and <persName>R.</persName> started for <placeName>Abydos</placeName> - <persName>Jean</persName> in my chair - and a gen d'armes, mounted, to go with them. <persName>Abydos,</persName> or rather <persName>Balliana,</persName> and its neighborhood being often turbulent. <persName>Theo</persName> and I had a nice day alone - and about 4 the rest came home, looking very tired, and much battered and covered with dust - the wind being very strong all day - and the air laden with dust.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1906-3-7" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1906-3-7">Wednesday, Mar. 7th.</date>
            <measure type="distance">5 miles.</measure>
          </dateline>
          <p>Although we started early, we were driven to the bank about 10 o'clock - where we are now lying - 3 miles above <placeName>Girgeh</placeName> - which can be plainly perceived across the sand. Hard and cold wind all day.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1906-3-8" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1906-3-8">Thursday, Mar. 8th.</date>
            <placeName ref="#Naviles">Naviles</placeName>
          </dateline>
          <p>Our men began rowing just as soon as there was light enough, but at 9 o'clock the gale was so strong, we had to pull up here, a mile below <placeName>Girga</placeName> - the <orgName>"Nakt-Heb"</orgName> french flag, is lying just above us, the "Gazelle" with Sir <persName>Talton Page</persName> 122 <persName>Sykes,</persName> just below.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1906-3-9" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1906-3-9">Friday, March 9th.</date>
            <measure type="distance">24 miles.</measure>
          </dateline>
          <p>The men worked with a will all day - though against the wind. We brought up at <placeName>Sohag,</placeName> about 6:30 this evening - posted letters and got a lot of fresh butter from <placeName>Cairo.</placeName> A wonderful moon tonight - full.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1906-3-10" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1906-3-10">Saturday, March 10th.</date>
          </dateline>
          <p>The wind so strong and contrary this morning we did not start until 8:30 and shortly after brought up against a high bank opposite the town, where we are still lying and will spend the night here.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1906-3-11" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1906-3-11">Second Sunday in Lent. March 11th.</date>
            <measure type="distance">25 miles.</measure>
          </dateline>
          <p>Our men began rowing at 4:30 this morning - as the night was very brilliant with a full moon. The north wind has been blowing all the time, sometimes less, but never ceasing. We are now lying against the cliffs of the northernmost end of the <placeName>Gebel Har&#234;di</placeName> - opposite <placeName>Tahtah.</placeName></p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1906-3-12" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1906-3-12">Monday, Mar. 12th.</date>
            <measure type="distance">23 miles.</measure>
          </dateline>
          <p>The usual conditions prevailed today, by hard work we made our miles - and are within 4 miles of <placeName>Aboutig</placeName> - we suppose.</p> 
        </div>
        <pb n="123"/>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1906-3-13" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1906-3-13">Tuesday, Mar. 13th.</date>
          </dateline>
          <p>We must have made 10 miles today and are within 5 miles of Asy&#251;t. Cold wind all day - tonight is overclouded and warmer.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1906-3-14" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1906-3-14">Wednesday, March 14th.</date>
            <measure type="distance">25 miles.</measure>
          </dateline>
          <p>Made Asy&#251;t at 7:30 this morning - stopped only long enough for <persName>Jones</persName> to get the mail, and <persName>Hassoon</persName> to get vegetables, meat etc. Got through the <persName>Weir</persName> very easily - and have had no wind or very little. It has been very warm - we are probably within 6 miles of <placeName>Manfalout.</placeName></p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1906-3-15" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1906-3-15">Thursday, March 15th.</date>
            <measure type="distance">36 miles.</measure>
          </dateline>
          <p>A very warm day - and an absolutely quiet one. The sailors worked valiantly, with an awning over them, from 5:30 A.M. We brought up at <placeName>Hag Kandil</placeName> at 6:30. Found the <orgName>Gazelle</orgName> lying here. At 6 o'clock this evening the mercury stood at 84 in my room - but a cool refreshing little wind from the south is going now.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1906-3-16" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1906-3-16">Friday, March 16th.</date>
          </dateline>
          <p>We left our landing place this morning early though a north wind was blowing hard - after an hour of struggle with it, we were forced to a big sand bank opposite <persName>Gebel Sheik Said</persName> - where we now are. The wind has raged all day - it has not been cold - but walking or staying on deck was impossible.</p> 
        </div>
        <pb n="124"/>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1906-3-17" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1906-3-17">Saturday, March 17th.</date>
          </dateline>
          <p>We are still lying where we were yesterday - and the weather has been the same. <persName>Theo</persName> sent one of the sailors this morning 7 miles across the sand to <persName>Melawi,</persName> to carry a telegram to <persName>Cook,</persName> ordering a tug to come up to us.We ought to have done this a week ago.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1906-3-18" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1906-3-18">Sunday, Mar. 18th. 3d Sunday in <placeName>Lent.</placeName></date>
          </dateline>
          <p><persName>Rodah.</persName> 13 miles. We brought up here suddenly about 11 o'clock this morning, with a strong wind from the east, and here we are still. We hope to meet our tug tomorrow. Indeed we have 2 tugs coming for us - one from <persName>Sheik Fadl,</persName> ordered this morning, and one from <placeName>Cooks, Cairo,</placeName> which started up yesterday - and which we ought to pick up on Tuesday - when we will dismiss the other one.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1906-3-18" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1906-3-18">Monday, Mar. 19th.</date>
            <measure type="distance">11 miles.</measure>
          </dateline>
          <p><persName>Beni Hassan.</persName> Started very early, but had to tie up about 10 o'clock - opposite the tombs - a spot we well know as we had to stay just here years ago for a week, on our way up - a gale is going on.</p>
        </div> 
        <!--[last 25 after this]-->
     <div xml:id="EBA-1906-03-20" type="entry">
       <dateline>
          <date when="1906-03-20">Tuesday, Mar. 20th.</date>
          <placeName ref="#Maghaghah">Maghagah</placeName>
          <measure type="distance">63 miles.</measure>
      </dateline>
        <p>I couldn't sleep last night because of the "fracas" - the gale made. It rained too. About 8 o'clock we heard the cheerful toot of the tug - and the <persName>Thothmes</persName> appeared having made fast time from <placeName>Cairo.</placeName> Following on her heels came the <orgName>Sugar Page</orgName> 125 Tug from <persName>Sheik Fadl</persName> - who had to be settled with and sent back before we started. The tug went upon the sand for half an hour but has made her miles against a tremendous wind.</p> 
      </div>  
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-03-21" type="entry">
       <dateline>
          <date when="1906-03-21">Wednesday, Mar. 21st.</date>
          <measure type="distance">84 miles.</measure>
        </dateline>
         <p>84 miles. The gale has continued without ceasing for a moment, and it is really cold. 8 miles of Bedreshchein.</p> 
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-03-22" type="entry">
       <dateline>
          <date when="1906-03-22">Thursday, Mar. 22d.</date>
          <measure type="distance">23 miles.</measure>
        </dateline>
        <p>We brought up at the bridge at 11 o'clock. <persName>Theo</persName> and <persName>Robert</persName> went in to <placeName>Shepheards</placeName> for the mail - were soon back as the bridge opened at 11:45 because of a flower show at the <orgName>Agricultural Gardens.</orgName> Fancy obstructing and interfering with a great commercial highway, because of a flower show! They always do it however - a tennis match, polo, races, what not! We got through without trouble - and were soon moored at the <placeName>Ghezireh Palace.</placeName> Drove into town in the afternoon.</p> 
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-03-23" type="entry">
       <dateline>
          <date when="1906-03-23">Friday, Mar. 23rd.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>We came up to the hotel this afternoon, finding our rooms all ready for us - our usual big ones - opening on the garden.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-03-24" type="entry">
       <dateline>
          <date when="1906-03-24">Saturday, Mar. 24.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>To the Museum this morning. Met <persName>v. Bissing</persName> - saw the splendid <orgName>Hathor</orgName> cow, found this winter at the <placeName>Mentu-hotep</placeName> temple at <placeName>Der el- Page</placeName> 126 Bahari. To <placeName>Cairo</placeName> this afternoon - tea at <placeName>Shepheards</placeName> - quite horrid in all that crowd, and blare of military music. Mr. <persName>Dalison</persName> to dine, pleasant evening.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-03-25" type="entry">
       <dateline>
          <date when="1906-03-25">Sunday, 4th in Lent. Mar. 25th.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>A warm, khamsiny morning - I had one of my huge windows wide open at 6:30 this morning - and the freshness of the lovely garden and the song of the birds was heavenly. They have all gone out to <placeName>Mena House</placeName> for the day. I beat a retreat from it, and have a quiet day before me - it being now 11 o'clock A.M. The great door of the sitting room where I am now writing stands open on the wide balcony with its awnings - and the birds come freely in and out.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-03-26" type="entry">
       <dateline>
          <date when="1906-03-26">Monday, Mar. 26th.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>Went to the <placeName>Bazaars</placeName> with <persName>Mr. Newberry</persName> this morning and to <placeName>Dataris</placeName> this afternoon to see some fine antiquities. A lovely little thing of <persName>Khuenaten</persName> and his wife - going to the <placeName>Berlin Museum.</placeName> <persName>V. Bissing</persName> came to dine.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-03-27" type="entry">
       <dateline>
          <date when="1906-03-27">Tuesday, Mar. 27th.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>Visiting etc. all day. <persName>Mr. Newberry</persName> to dine.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-03-31" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-03-31">Saturday, Mar. 31st.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>This is our last day here. Yesterday we lunched with Mr. <persName>Newberry</persName> at the Angelterre. Dr. <persName>Sandwith</persName> dined with us last evening. Page 127 <persName>Mrs. Dennis</persName> asked us to tea over here on the lawn, and then found that tea was never served there for less than 20 people. So we had it on the terrace. Mr. <persName>Newberry</persName> is dining with us tonight - and <persName>v. Bissing</persName> and Mr. <persName>Currelly</persName> came in after tea to say goodbye.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-04-06" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-04-06">Friday, April 6th.</date>
          <placeName ref="#Venice">Venice</placeName>
          <name type="hotel" ref="#Hotel_Britannia">Hotel Britannia</name>
        </dateline>      
        <p>We are thankful indeed to find ourselves safely and comfortably settled in our spacious usual appartments here. Such an uncomfortable transit as we have had across the <orgName>Mediterranean!</orgName> We left <placeName>Cairo</placeName> Sunday morning the 1st for <placeName>Port Said.</placeName> Mr. and <persName>Mrs. Dennis</persName> were on the train. Mr. <persName>Newberry</persName> at the station to say goodbye. We found the <persName>Osiris</persName> had a very full passenger list - we had to wait until Monday noon before the mail steamer got through the canal. We had feared rough weather, for the wind had been high for days. But our experience was more trying than anything we had ever met - we went directly out into a very rough sea - and soon almost every passenger had taken to his berth. I was not sick at any time - but I went to bed at 5 o'clock and did not get up until 10 o'clock P.M. on Wednesday - as it was too rough and dreadful to be up. That little <persName>Osiris</persName> not only stood on both ends, but rolled over and jumped out of the water fairly - speed was of course slackened, and we reached <placeName>Brindisi</placeName> on Thursday morning at 1:30 - 14 hours behind time. The boat was really much of the time under water and I heard tons of water pouring over the deck above me. Our train left at 3 o'clock A.M. we arrived at <name>Bologna</name> at 6 P.M. spent the night at that good hotel <placeName>Brum</placeName> - and were comforted by an excellent <orgName>Page 128</orgName> dinner and good beds, and arrived here about 6 o'clock this afternoon.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-04-07" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-04-07">Saturday, April 7th.</date>
        </dateline>   
        <p>A visit to <placeName>Salvedere's</placeName> this morning and to <placeName>San Marco,</placeName> and I went this afternoon to see our invalid friends the <persName>Bensons.</persName></p> 
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-04-08" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-04-08">Sunday, April 8th. Palm Sunday.</date>
        </dateline>   
        <p>The family went to the <placeName>Academia</placeName> this morning, I stayed home for a quiet morning and service. <persName>Theo</persName> and I went to <persName>Palazzo Capello</persName> at 3:30 and after a talk with Mr. and <persName>Mrs. Benson,</persName> went to <placeName>Palazzo Mula,</placeName> to have tea with the <name>Browns</name> in their pretty appartments.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-04-09" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-04-09">Monday, April 9th.</date>
        </dateline>   
        <p>To the <persName>Frari</persName> to see the pictures - found they had all been removed to the church of <placeName>S. Toma,</placeName> where we found it too dark to see them - the <placeName>Frari</placeName> actually seems to be under process of entire reconstruction - all the monuments taken down from the walls, and filled with scaffolding and derricks. After lunch to <placeName>Barozzi's</placeName> where we bought some beautiful stuffs - and then to <placeName>Florian's</placeName> to tea.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-04-10" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-04-10">Tuesday, April 10.</date>
        </dateline>   
        <p>I spent the morning with the <orgName>Bensons</orgName> - to the <placeName>Academia</placeName> in the afternoon - and again to tea at <placeName>Florians</placeName> - <persName>Mr.</persName> and <persName>Mrs. Brown</persName> dined with us.</p> 
      </div>
      <pb n="129"/>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-04-11" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-04-11">Wednesday, April 11.</date>
        </dateline>   
        <p>Shopping, sightseeing and visiting. Saw the Eden garden and had a lovely row.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-04-12" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-04-12">Thursday, April 12.</date>
        </dateline>   
        <p>Made the <name>Bensons</name> a long visit, this morning. Poor souls! weak, suffering and old - yet full of interest in life, and longing for an activity that will never come again to them! It is truly sad. The great hall and rooms of the <placeName>Palazzo,</placeName> were full of lovely flowers and freshness - and the garden was lovely with its blossoming trees. Such a contrast - <persName>Theo</persName> and I went to <placeName>Borozzi's</placeName> and another shop this afternoon and had tea at <placeName>Florians.</placeName> A good concert this evening at the <placeName>Hotel.</placeName></p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-04-13" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-04-13">Good Friday, April 13.</date>
        </dateline>   
        <p><persName>Theo</persName> and I went to say goodbye to the <name>Bensons</name> this morning. <persName>Theo</persName> left a very kind and substantial gift to Mr. <persName>Benson</persName> which will relieve them of all anxiety for a long time to come. At 2 o'clock we took the little hotel steamer and went to <placeName>Torcello.</placeName> It is undergoing a general repair - the fine <orgName>Campanile</orgName> is now finished and strengthened at which restorative work they have been busy for 2 years. But the whole of the young population, and the small island holds myriads of children, are such a nuisance, and such irrepressible beggars, that one's pleasure is almost ruined. I love those excursions among the islands of the lagoons?- with their strange water wave marked by clusters <orgName>Page 130</orgName> of poles - the slender campaniles rising from each island, with such a fine effect. For two days the world has been absorbed with the tragedy of the eruption of <placeName>Vesuvius</placeName> - on of the worst on record, - villages destroyed and buried in lava - desolation and loss of life everywhere. <placeName>Naples</placeName> itself is in darkness - covered with clouds of ashes - under the weight of which the big market, one church, and other buildings having collapsed with loss of life. <name>Capri</name> is said to be so covered with this volcanic ash, that crops and verdure are killed. We all separate tomorrow - <persName>Theo</persName> to <placeName>Vienna</placeName> to meet <persName>Eleanor</persName> - the rest of us to Florence.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-04-15" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-04-15">Easter Sunday, April 15.</date>
        </dateline>   
        <p>A most perfect Easter day - brilliant sunshine, and the constant clanging of the melodious <placeName>Florence</placeName> bells. I had my precious little <name>Christian Science</name> service, all alone at home. A very comfortable journey over from <placeName>Venice</placeName> yesterday. We are in our old rooms here at the <placeName>Grande Bretagne,</placeName> found a hearty welcome - and <persName>Franz</persName> and old <persName>Giulia</persName> ready to wait on us.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-04-16" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-04-16">Monday, April 16.</date>
        </dateline>   
        <p>Quite a busy day - tea at the <placeName>Villino</placeName> - <persName>Mary, Jean</persName> and <persName>Robert</persName> go off to <placeName>Rome</placeName> tomorrow for a week.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-04-17" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-04-17">Tuesday, April 17.</date>
        </dateline>   
        <p>The children got off today. <persName>Lizzie</persName> not very well. Mme. Page 131 <persName>Costantini</persName> made me a visit this afternoon - looking remarkably well, and very smart - asked me to lunch for Saturday. Wednesday. Cold, disagreeable weather - at home most of the day.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-04-21" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-04-21">Saturday, April 21st.</date>
        </dateline>   
        <p>I have been in the house for 2 days - weather bad, and slight cold. <persName>David Costantini</persName> called and left the <orgName>Ivories.</orgName> Mr. <persName>Berenson</persName> called. <persName>Nettie</persName> and I drove out today - and did some errands - <persName>Lizzie</persName> and she lunched with me - lovely day. The whole world is electrified by the horrible disaster in <placeName>California.</placeName> An earthquake has practically destroyed <placeName>San Francisco!</placeName> The accounts that have reached us from the wrecked and burning city seem too dreadful to be possible.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-05-04" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-05-04">May 4th. Saturday.</date>
          <placeName ref="#Florence">Florence</placeName>
        </dateline>   
        <p>We have now been here for 3 weeks and two days - and will leave for <placeName>Paris</placeName> tomorrow, where <persName>Theodore</persName> and <persName>Eleanor</persName> are now waiting for us. With the exception of two or three days, we have had the worst kind of weather - rain, cold winds and several hail storms. Driving for pleasure has been out of the question. I have had constant pleasant visits from and with <persName>Lizzie</persName> and the girls. <persName>Nettie</persName> and I lunched one day at "La <placeName>Loggia"</placeName> - the charming country home of the <orgName>Costantini's</orgName> - which they are thoroughly changing - making it as far [not able to read] the 15th century. It will be an enchanting place. We had one of the very pleasant teas with the <orgName>Newmans</orgName> which they always give us - and were to have lunched with the <persName>Berenson's</persName> at <placeName>I Tatti,</placeName> but the weather has been too cold.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-05-06" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-05-06">Monday, May 6th.</date>
          <placeName ref="#Paris">Paris</placeName>
          <name type="hotel" ref="#Hotel_Westminster">Hotel Westminster</name>
        </dateline>   
        <p>We had quite a comfortable journey on - though in a very shabby carriage for a "train de luxe". <persName>Lizzie</persName> and the girls lunched with us - <persName>Nettie</persName> and <persName>Mary</persName> went to the station with us. <persName>Costantini</persName> kindly turned up to wish us goodbye. Arrived in <placeName>Paris</placeName> on time! and found <persName>Theo, Eleanor</persName> and <persName>Jones</persName> at the station. In our old rooms here.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-05-08" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-05-08">May 8th. Tuesday.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>Bad weather yesterday - in the house all day. This morning <persName>Amelie</persName> and I drove out to the <placeName>Bois.</placeName> Charming - rained this afternoon.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-05-10" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-05-10">Thursday, May 10th.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>Continued bad weather - violent storms. Have so enjoyed <persName>Eleanor's</persName> visit. Sorry that she goes back to <placeName>Dresden</placeName> tomorrow.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>