<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>Diary of Mrs. Emma B. Andrews. Volume 12 1904-1905</title>
          <author>
          <persName ref="#Andrews_Emma_B">Emma B. Andrews</persName>
          </author>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Originally prepared by</resp>
          <persName ref="#SLK">Sarah L. Ketchley</persName>
        </respStmt>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>TEIPublisher development</resp>
          <persName ref="#EF">Emma Fritzberg</persName>
        </respStmt>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Historical Markup Tool development</resp>
          <persName ref="#AH">Audrey Holmes</persName>
        </respStmt>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>transcription</resp>
          <persName ref="#SJ">Sarah Johnson</persName>
          <persName ref="#CC">Chelsea Cooper</persName>
          <persName ref="#AF">Ariella Fish</persName>
          <persName ref="#JG">Janice Garr</persName>
          <persName ref="#MR">Megan Rowland</persName>
          <persName ref="#AS">Allison Skinner</persName>
          <persName ref="#TC">Tessa Carter</persName>
        </respStmt>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>proofreading and tagging</resp>
          <persName ref="#OH">Olivia Hyre</persName>
          <persName ref="#HB">Hannah Burrows</persName>
          <persName ref="#MT">Molly Taylor</persName>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>
          <orgName ref="#EBA_Diary_Project">Emma B. Andrews Diary Project</orgName>
        </publisher>
        <address>
          <addrLine>University of Washington, Seattle, WA</addrLine>
        </address>
        <availability>
          <licence target="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/">This work is
            licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International
            License.</licence>
        </availability>
        <date>08-2020</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <p><orgName ref="#American_Philosophical_Society">American Philosophical
          Society</orgName>,<placeName ref="#Philadelphia">Philadelphia</placeName></p>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Established in 2010, the goals of the <orgName ref="#EBA_Diary_Project">Emma B.
          Andrews Diary Project</orgName> include the transcription and digitization of a
          wide range of primary historical material from the 'Golden Age' of Egyptian
          archaeology at the end of the 19th and beginning of the 20th centuries. A founding
          partner of <orgName ref="#Newbook_Digital_Texts">Newbook Digital Texts</orgName>
          (www.newbookdigitaltexts.org), the <orgName ref="#EBA_Diary_Project">EBA Diary
            Project</orgName> offers undergraduate and graduate digital humanities education
          and internships at the <orgName ref="#University_of_Washington">University of
            Washington</orgName>.
          <persName ref="#Andrews_Emma_B">Emma B. Andrews</persName> is best remembered for her
          association with the millionaire lawyer turned archaeologist/art and antiquities
          collector, <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore M. Davis</persName>. Traveling
          to <placeName ref="#Egypt">Egypt</placeName> with him between 1889 and 1913, she kept
          detailed journals of these voyages along the <placeName ref="#Nile">Nile</placeName>,
          including his important yet under-reported excavations of over 20 significant tombs
          in the <placeName ref="#Bībān al-Mulūk">Valley of the Kings</placeName>.
          <persName ref="#Andrews_Emma_B">Emma</persName> provides a vital commentary on the
          archaeology and pioneering Egyptologists of the time, painting a revealing picture of
          the lives of the colonial gentry and the cultural and scientific literati in at the
          dawn of the twentieth century. Analysis of the content of her diaries, along with a
          broad range of additional primary source material, will afford scholars information
          about important historical resources for the first time.</p>
      </projectDesc>
      <editorialDecl>
        <correction>
          <p>Obvious misspellings (eg place names and people's names) which are misreadings of original handwritten diary are corrected
            with choice, sic and corr.</p>
        </correction>
        <normalization>
          <p>Original spelling and typography is otherwise retained.</p>
        </normalization>
      </editorialDecl>
    </encodingDesc>
    <revisionDesc> <!-- update this with major revision list-->
      <list>
        <item>
          <date when="2021-05-25">25 May 2021</date> Last checked by SLK. Updated header, fixed
          placeName and name tags. Ran XSLT script.</item>
      </list>
    </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <!-- Molly Taylor -->
      <!-- Near the end of this entry, she says that the 11th was "yesterday" but this entry is from the 26th. Maybe it originally said "26" and there was an ink blot or something to make it look like an "11"? -->
      <div xml:id="EBA-1904-11-27" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <pb n="53"/>
          <name type="boat" ref="#USS_Pocahontas">S.S. Prinzess Irene</name>. <!-- https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/USS_Pocahontas_(ID-3044) -->
          <date when="1904-11-27">Nov. 27, 1904 - First Sunday in Advent</date>. </dateline>
        <p>We left home very reluctantly on the 1st and went to <placeName ref="#Boston"
            >Boston</placeName> where we spent five charming days and on the 6th moved on to
            <placeName ref="#New_York">New York</placeName> where we found that the <name
            type="boat" ref="#USS_Pocahontas">Irene</name> would be four days late in sailing in
          consequence of some accident to her machinery. It was tremendously vexing to us, as we
          lost our <placeName ref="#Naples">Naples</placeName> steamer to <placeName ref="#Egypt"
            >Egypt</placeName> - and shall have to take our chance when we reach there, with what we
          can find. I saw some old friends in <placeName ref="#New_York">New York</placeName>, and
          made some pleasant visits, and to my great pleasure <persName ref="#Rogers_Mary">Mary
            Rogers</persName> who was staying in <placeName ref="#Orange_New_York"
            >Orange</placeName>, came over and spent two days with me. I found my rooms (we came
          aboard the <date when="1904-11-16">16th</date> and sailed early in the day) on the steamer
          most delightful - they are the Captain's rooms - very good sitting room - big bed room,
          and adjoining bath room, on the level of the bridge, and I am all alone with only the sea,
          and the life boats about me, and the Captain near in the chart room. It has been most
          delightful - and the quiet and the rest very precious. During the first night, we ran into
          a heavy storm and high seas - which resolved itself into a cyclone, from which or out of
          which the Captain retreated by turning south, and running <measure quantity="100"
            unit="mile">100 miles</measure> out of his course. I hadn't a qualm of sickness, but I
          stayed in bed, as there was so much movement, and as <persName ref="#Burgnoyne_Amelie"
            >Amelie</persName> was too ill to leave her room. Up at this height I got more motion -
          and how the wind roared and shrieked! I have never heard anything like it. The whole boat,
          as it were, took<pb n="54"/> to its bed. Then followed two or three days of heavy rain -
          and then we emerged into comparatively calm seas and brilliant sunshine - I have a door
          opening from my sitting room on my own private deck, and one from my bath room, so that I
          get all the air I want - and my private view, as it were, at any moment I want the
          limitless sea, and the heavens, which are wonderful beyond description now at night, with
          the full moon, and perfectly cloudless. This fine, steady steamer is not so fast as some -
          and we expected to take 12 days instead of 11 to <placeName ref="#Naples"
            >Naples</placeName> - which is the usual one - but the storms have so delayed us, that
          we did not reach <placeName ref="#Gibraltar">Gibraltar</placeName> until the <date
            when="1904-11-11">11th</date> - yesterday - and we will make <placeName ref="#Naples"
            >Naples</placeName> only the day after tomorrow, the 14th day of the voyage, where
            <persName ref="#Wilson_Alice">Alice Wilson</persName> will join us for the winter.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1904-11-29" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1904-11-29">Tuesday, Nov. 29. Grand Hotel - Naples</date>. </dateline>
        <p><persName ref="#Burgnoyne_Amelie">Amelie</persName> called me at 6 o'clock this morning as I had
          asked her to - I love to see the early dawn on <placeName ref="#Vesuvius"
            >Vesuvius</placeName> and the bay. But it was thick and murky - damp and cold. I had my
          last cup of coffee up in that little sky parlor of mine - and by that time I saw that
            <placeName ref="#Vesuvius">Vesuvius</placeName> was covered with snow - something I had
          never seen before - we landed about 11 o'clock - and were soon in our old rooms here,
          where <persName ref="#Wilson_Alice">Alice</persName> was waiting for us. We found on the
          table of our sitting room, some lovely orchids with the card of kind <persName
            ref="#Hanser_Mr #Hanser_Mrs">Mr. and Mrs. Hanser</persName>. The <persName ref="#McKeever_Misses">McKeever
            girls</persName> came to lunch with us - and then went back to the boat, bound for
            <placeName ref="#Genoa">Genoa</placeName> and <placeName ref="#St_Moritz">St.
            Moritz</placeName>. The <persName ref="#Longfellow_Ernest #Longfellow_Mrs">Longfellows</persName>, and
            <persName ref="#Hale_Miss">Miss Hale</persName> are<pb n="55"/> here - and the
            <persName ref="#Kissel_Mr #Kissel_Mrs">Kissels</persName> - and the 2 boys <persName
            ref="#Smith_Harold">Smith</persName> and <persName ref="#Ream_Robert_Clarke"
            >Ream</persName>.</p>
      </div>
      <!-- What is Sprenger-Müller? -->
      <div xml:id="EBA-1904-12-09" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1904-12-09">Dec. 9, 1904. Cairo. <name type="hotel" ref="#Shepheards_Hotel">Shepheards Hotel</name></date>. </dateline>
        <p>We left <placeName ref="#Naples">Naples</placeName> on <date when="1904-11-03">Saturday,
            the 3d</date> and made the weary, weary journey of 9 hours from there to <placeName
            ref="Brindisi">Brindisi</placeName> - <persName ref="#Hale_Miss">Miss Hale</persName>,
            <persName ref="#Perkins_Mrs">Mrs. Perkins</persName>, and <persName ref="#Morgan_Miss"
            >Miss Morgan</persName> were along. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M"
            >Theodore</persName> took <persName ref="#Hardy_Jean #Wilson_Alice">the girls</persName>
          and <persName ref="#Ream_Robert_Clarke">Ream</persName> and <persName ref="#Smith_Harold"
            >Smith</persName> to <placeName ref="#Pompeii">Pompeii</placeName> one day at <placeName
            ref="#Naples">Naples</placeName> - and one of the pleasantest things I did was visiting
            <persName ref="#Hanser_Mr #Hanser_Mrs">Mr. and Mrs. Hanser</persName> at their charming villa at
            <placeName ref="#Posillipo">Posillipo</placeName>. They are such kind nice people. One
          cold, windy afternoon we drove up to the <placeName ref="#Vomero">Vomero</placeName>, and
          after much searching found the <placeName ref="#">Sprenger-M&#252;ller</placeName> place
          which for 3 years I have been trying to discover.But he was not at home, greatly to my
          regret - though <persName ref="#Hanser_Mrs">Mrs. Hanser</persName> told me that as he was
          quite deaf, I would have found him difficult. I wanted to see his garden and talk to him -
          for he is a noted hybridigia and floriculturist. We had to spend the night and most of the
          day at that hideous hotel at <placeName ref="#Brindisi">Brindisi</placeName> - which we
          thought worse than usual. When we stumbled late at night out of the R.R. station, and got
          into the omnibus, <persName ref="#Hardy_Jean">Jean</persName>, <persName
            ref="#Wilson_Alice">Alice</persName> and I - we found it already occupied by a large man
          who said to me, "I guess we're going to have some fresh Americans on board"; <persName
            ref="#Hardy_Jean #Wilson_Alice">the girls</persName> said I replied in a chilling
          manner, "Yes, we are Americans" - "I thought so" he replied, it's so nice to hear the real
          thing"! While we might all be proud of being Americans, I don't think we relished being
          told in that nasal voice that we were the "real thing". Over the miseries of that 3 days
          voyage I will not linger! We were happy to land at <placeName ref="#Port_Said">Port
            Said</placeName> at 9 o'clock A.M. <date when="1904-12-07">Wednesday Dec. 7th</date>, and
          soon were<pb n="56"/> journeying to <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> by the new
          and improved route - an hour shorter than formerly - met all our nice people and
          established in time for tea in our charming appartment here.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1904-12-12" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1904-12-12">Monday, Dec. 12</date>. </dateline>
        <p>Very busy getting the <name type="boat" ref="#Beduin">Beduin</name> in order - and
          arranging to send <persName ref="#Abdul">Abdul</persName>, with his wife and child up to
          his native country <placeName ref="#Dongola">Dongola</placeName> - <persName ref="#Abdul"
            >Abdul</persName> has recovered remarkably - and seems stronger than he has been for
          three years - but we found that he had been drinking a good deal - and we decided it was
          better for him to go back to his own people - and to a warmer climate where he will be
          free from temptation. He has a bit of land there, and some palm trees, and <persName
            ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> has arranged for <persName
            ref="#Cook_Thomas">Cook</persName> to send him money from time to time - and it seems a
          happy solution to the dondition which has given us a good deal of anxiety lately.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1904-12-16" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1904-12-16">Friday, Dec. 16th</date>. </dateline>
        <p>We came on board this morning - a cold day with strong South wind blowing - and of course
          no prospect of sailing - but we were so glad to give up hotel life, and take possession
          once more of this little home. <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> did not seem very
          pleasant. We had heavy fogs each morning - and yesterday we had a fire built in our
          sitting room. We dined with <persName ref="#Morgan_Miss">Miss Morgan</persName> and her
          brothers one evening - and had a charming evening. They have altered the <name
            type="hotel" ref="#Sandwith_House">Sandwith house</name> - made it much larger - and is
          just finishing a magnificent ball room - one of the most lovely rooms of the kind I have
          ever seen. The boys, <placeName ref="#Smith_Harold">Smith</placeName> and <persName
            ref="#Ream_Robert_Clarke">Ream</persName>, have gone up the<pb n="57"/> river on one of
          Cooks steamers - Mr. <placeName ref="#Carter_Howard">Carter</placeName> dined and lunched
          with us several times - and we spent the day with him at the <name type="hotel"
            ref="#Mona_House">Mona House</name>, where he was staying. He is quite settled in a
          pleasant appartment - and looks better and happier than he did. We had tea one afternoon
          with <persName ref="#Peckitt_Amelia">Mrs. <choice><sic>Packett</sic><corr>Peckitt</corr>
          </choice></persName>, in her nice little home. I liked her husband - and she seemed
          quieter and less gushing than the <persName ref="#Peckitt_Amelia">Miss Kirkbride
          </persName> we met a year ago on the steamer coming outhere.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1904-12-17" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1904-12-17">Saturday, Dec. 17th</date>. </dateline>
        <p>Another day of south wind - and we have not moved. <persName ref="#Morgan_Miss">Miss
            Morgan</persName> and her brother came this morning to see the boat. The <persName
            ref="#Longfellow_Ernest #Longfellow_Mrs">Ernest Longfellows</persName>, with <persName ref="#Hale_Miss">Miss
            Hale</persName> and <persName ref="#Perkins_Mrs">Mrs. Perkins</persName> are on the
          dahabya <name type="boat" ref="#Agiz">Agiz</name>, with <persName ref="#Salah_Mohammed"
            >Salah</persName> as dragoman, going up, and waiting as we are for a favourable wind.
            <persName ref="#Carter_Howard">Mr. Carter</persName> and <persName ref="#Edgar_Mr">Mr.
            Edgar</persName> dined with us.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1904-12-18" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1904-12-18">Sunday, Dec. 18th</date>. <measure quantity="7" unit="mile">7
            miles</measure>. </dateline>
        <p>Came through the bridge yesterday and are lying near the <placeName
            ref="#British_Embassy">British embassy</placeName>. <persName ref="#Wilson_Alice"
            >Alice</persName>, <persName ref="#Hardy_Jean">Jean</persName> and I walked all about
          the streets near us this morning - they are so wide and well paved and shaded, that we
          found it very pleasant - we dared not go far from the boat, as the wind seemed at last to
          be changing. Any number of really handsome houses have been built in this quarter. At noon
          the wind fell - and it was quite warm - about 3:30 it came gently from the north, and we
          spread our sails and went away before it. The <name type="boat" ref="#Agiz">Agiz</name>
          also put out, and the <name type="boat" ref="#Isis">Isis</name>, with a <placeName
            ref="#Boston">Boston</placeName> man, <persName ref="#Brooks_Mr">Brooks</persName>, with
          the <persName ref="#Tuck">Tucks</persName>, and<pb n="58"/>
          <persName ref="#Morgan_Miss">Miss Morgan</persName>, going to <placeName ref="#Sakkarah"
            >Sakkarah</placeName>, also started. We made about <measure quantity="6" unit="mile">6
            miles</measure>, and are almost in sight of <placeName ref="#Hulwan"
          >Helouan</placeName>. The afternoon has been beautiful - and we sailed gently along the
          island of <placeName ref="#Rhoda">Rhodah</placeName> - the old dilapidated palaces looking
          so picturesque - and the evening lights so fine - the 3 boats are lying near each other
          tonight.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1904-12-19" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1904-12-19">Monday, Dec. 19th</date>. </dateline>
        <p>The <persName ref="#Longfellow_Ernest #Longfellow_Mrs">Longfellows</persName> came over to see us this
          morning - and after we went aboard the <name type="boat" ref="#Isis">Isis</name>, and the
            <persName ref="#Tuck_Mr #Tuck_Mrs">Tucks</persName> and <persName ref="#Morgan_Miss">Miss
            Morgan</persName> came back with us to see the boat - we were then going to the <name
            type="boat" ref="#Agiz">Agiz</name> to see <persName ref="#Hale_Miss">Miss
            Hale</persName> and <persName ref="#Perkins_Mrs">Mrs. Perkins</persName>, when we found
          their boat had started. We were soon off in a light wind - the river was crowded with
          boats, and we got into a great mix with them, and one of them caught her boom into our
          beautiful white sail and tore two holes in it, so we were obliged to stop and repair
          damages: <name type="boat" ref="#Isis">Isis</name> and <name type="boat" ref="#Agiz"
            >Agiz</name> ahead of us. We have made about <measure quantity="3" unit="mile">3
            miles</measure>, and are lying opposite <name type="boat" ref="#Tura">Tura</name>.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1904-12-20" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1904-12-20">Dec. 20th.- Tuesday</date>. </dateline>
        <p>Cloudy with rain at times - wind S.E. and S.W. tracked - and have made probably <measure
            quantity="1" unit="mile">a mile</measure>!</p>
      </div>
      <!-- There's no p. 58? -->
      <div xml:id="EBA-1904-12-21" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1904-12-21">Dec. 21. Wednesday</date>. </dateline>
        <p>Weather cold, squally and disagreeable - heavy clouds and contrary winds - and some
          difficult turns. The <name type="boat" ref="#Agiz">Agiz</name> has disappeared, we left
          the <name type="boat" ref="#Isis">Isis</name> at <placeName ref="#Sakkarah"
            >Sakkarah</placeName> - made very little over <measure quantity="11" unit="mile">11
            miles</measure>.<pb n="59"/></p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1904-12-22" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1904-12-22">Dec. 22d - Thursday</date>. </dateline>
        <p>We began sailing about 11 o'clock - the wind grew strong and we went dashing along in
          rather an alarming way. Then a sudden squall struck us - we had to drop our sails, and
          were driven to shore - a wildly exciting time getting our sails furled - and we lay the
          rest of the day rocking under bare poles. As the evening drew on the wind fell, and we
          were able to cross the river and find a better place. Such a heavenly night! a full moon -
          and grand palm trees above us on the bank. Made <measure quantity="7" unit="mile">7
            miles</measure>.</p>
      </div>
      <!-- Explains what a "reis" is: https://imalqata.wordpress.com/2012/02/25/our-reis-hassan-mohammed-ail-ahmed/ -->
      <div xml:id="EBA-1904-12-23" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1904-12-23">Friday, Dec. 23d</date>. <measure quantity="14" unit="mile">14
            miles</measure>. </dateline>
        <p>We did little until about 3 o'clock - when a light wind began and the Reis concluded to
          stop for the night - as the little dahabyah <name type="boat" ref="#Bijou">Bijou</name>
          had pulled up behind us - with some of his friends in the crew. But as a favourable wind
          began to rise <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> sent out word that
          they must be off - so up came our stakes and we started in a fair wind and kept on until
          about 5 o'clock - we came to a difficult bend in the river and stopped for the night.
          Cold, with heavy clouds and some rain. Discouraging!</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1904-12-24" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1904-12-24">Saturday, Dec. 24th</date>. <measure quantity="6" unit="mile">6
            miles</measure>.</dateline>
        <p>Adverse winds - and made our few miles by tracking. A sharp rain last night.<pb n="60"
          /></p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1904-12-25" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1904-12-27">Dec. 25, Sunday. Christmas</date>. </dateline>
        <p>A perfectly calm, but beautiful day and warm. After our usual distribution of gifts - the
          men started their tracking, and we have made <measure quantity="11" unit="mile">11
            miles</measure>. This makes a week getting <measure quantity="56" unit="mile">56
            miles</measure>.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1904-12-26" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1904-12-27">Monday, Dec. 26th</date>. <measure quantity="10" unit="mile">10
            miles</measure>. </dateline>
        <p>Another delightful warm day - tracked all the morning. About 4 this afternoon a light n.
          wind came, so that we sailed for 2 hours. The river is full of birds - passed thousands of
          ducks today. They are clever enough to lift just before danger approaches - I believe they
          recognize a dahabya - the only dangerous craft for them, as the natives in their boats
          never molest them. The little, tidy unoccupied dahabya "<name type="boat" ref="#Bijou"
            >Bijou</name>" still keeps with us,</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1904-12-27" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1904-12-27">Tuesday, Dec. 27th</date>. <measure quantity="3" unit="mile">3
            miles</measure>. </dateline>
        <p>Which the poor men have made by continuous tracking. Clear and cool. The eastern desert
          and mountains made most lovely effects.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1904-12-28" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1904-12-28">Wednesday, Dec. 28</date>. <measure quantity="6" unit="mile">6
            miles</measure>. </dateline>
        <p>When we started out at 8 o'clock this morning the wind was almost in our favour. But
          again it failed and the men tracked all day - and were tired enough when <persName
            ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> ordered that they should tie up at 5
            o'clock.<pb n="61"/></p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1904-12-29" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1904-12-29">Thursday, Dec. 29</date>. <measure quantity="5" unit="mile">5
            miles</measure>. </dateline>
        <p>A little breeze and much tracking.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1904-12-30" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1904-12-30">Friday, Dec. 30</date>. <measure quantity="5" unit="mile">5
            miles</measure>. </dateline>
        <p>The same history as yesterday, except the wind has been very strong - veering from S.E.
          to south.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1904-12-31" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1904-12-31">Saturday, Dec. 31</date>. <measure quantity="4.5" unit="mile"
            >4-1/2 miles</measure>. </dateline>
        <p>A strong head wind - tracked and pulled to anchor.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1904-01-01" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1904-01-01">Sunday, Jan. 1st, 1905</date>. <measure quantity="6" unit="mile">6
            miles</measure>. </dateline>
        <p>We had hoped for a change of luck to-day, but the conditions remain unchanged. Day
          cool.</p>
      </div>
      <!-- Where is Fashen? There are several "Matar" results on Getty in Egypt. Where is Kolosna? Where is Gebel et Teu? -->
      <div xml:id="EBA-1904-01-02" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1904-01-02">Monday, Jan. 2d</date>. <measure quantity="43" unit="mile">43
            miles</measure>. </dateline>
        <p><placeName ref="#Dayr_Samalut">Samalut</placeName>. At last Fortune has given us a
          favourable wind - a light wind beginning early, grew into a steady, fine sailing wind -
          and we began leaving the miles behind us in a good old fashioned manner. We soon passed
            <placeName ref="#Fashen">Fashen</placeName>, then <placeName ref="#Maghaghah"
            >Maghaghah</placeName>, <placeName ref="#">Matar</placeName>, and <placeName ref="#Kolosna"
            >Kolosna</placeName>, and are now lying at <placeName ref="#Dayr_Samalut"
            >Samalut</placeName>, almost opposite the <placeName>Gebel et Teu</placeName> - with its
          Coptic convent. Late in the afternoon we caught sight of the <name type="boat" ref="#Agiz"
            >Agiz</name>, in a bend of the river before us.</p>
      </div>
      <!-- "Ettie" should be "Nettie" right? -->
      <div xml:id="EBA-1904-01-03" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1904-01-03">Tuesday, Jan. 3d</date>. <measure quantity="25" unit="mile">25
            miles</measure>. </dateline>
        <p>Another good, but light wind brought us about one<pb n="62"/> o'clock to <placeName
            ref="#Al_Minya">Minia</placeName> - where we stopped until 3:30 for mail and supplies.
            <persName ref="#Salah_Mohammed">Saleh</persName> was there this morning - he must have
          sailed well into the night. The weather is growing milder. A huge mail - and bad news
          again from <placeName ref="#Milwaukee">Milwaukee</placeName> - poor <persName
            ref="#Gwynne_Maria">Gwynne</persName> again in hospital - very serious. Dear <persName
            ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Ettie</persName> continually in my thoughts. Made <measure
            quantity="5" unit="mile">five miles</measure> from <placeName ref="#Al_Minya"
            >Minia</placeName>.</p>
      </div>
      <!-- Siege of Port Arthur - should we have a tag for world events? -->
      <div xml:id="EBA-1904-01-04" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1904-01-04">Wednesday, Jan. 4th</date>. <measure quantity="23" unit="mile">23
            miles</measure>. </dateline>
        <p>A gentle sailing breeze all day - occasionally dying out. Passed <placeName
            ref="#Bani_Hassan">Beni Hassan</placeName> about 11 o'clock. <placeName
            ref="#Rawdaw_Jazirat_ar-">Rhodah</placeName> at 3 - and are now within a mile or so of
            <placeName ref="#Mallawi">Mellawie</placeName> - a charming really warm day. We have
          been immersed in the newspapers - and in the extraordinary news of the protracted siege of
          Port Arthur. What a slaughter - what heroism on the part of the Japanese - what hopeless
          demoralization and incompetency of the Russians - a harrowing thing to think of.</p>
      </div>
      <!-- Where  is Hag Kandil? -->
      <div xml:id="EBA-1904-01-05" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1904-01-05">Thursday, Jan. 5</date>. <measure quantity="8" unit="mile">8
            miles</measure>. </dateline>
        <p>A warm, beautiful day - we are lying tonight about a mile above <placeName ref="#Hag_Kandil">Hag
            Kandil</placeName>.</p>
      </div>
      <!-- On Getty, a hill comes up for Gebel Abu Foda. Make sure she's actually talking about a hill. -->
      <div xml:id="EBA-1904-01-06" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1904-01-06">Friday, Jan. 6th</date>. <measure quantity="26" unit="mile">26
            miles</measure>. </dateline>
        <p>A very exciting day - we began early in a gentle enough manner - but the wind steadily
          grew stronger and when we came to the great turn at the approach to the <placeName
            ref="#Abu_Fudah_Jabal">Gebel Abu Feda</placeName> the Reis took to the bank and furled
          his sail. There we stayed for 3<pb n="3"/> hours, when he thought it safe to go out again.
          The river is now so full of gyassas, that sailing is sometimes risky - as we entered the
          part of the river under the cliffs, there were many of them about, and in the gale which
          broke upon us, we came nearly to our destruction by one of these bearing down upon us,
          quite unmanageable. The shrieking of the wind, the cries of the sailors were exciting. At
          one time we had 13 men on the boom trying to furl the sail - as soon as we found ourselves
          able, we dropped our anchors, and after, pulled to shore - thankful enough to make
          ourselves fast. The worst experience we have ever had.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1904-01-07" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1904-01-07">Saturday, Jan. 7</date>. <measure quantity="30" unit="mile">30
            miles</measure>. </dateline>
        <p>The gale continued all night - a fine north wind this morning which lasted all day,
          sailed calmly through the dam at <placeName ref="#Assiout">Asyut</placeName>, and stopped
          for our mail. I did not go off the boat. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName>
          and <persName ref="#Hardy_Jean #Wilson_Alice">the girls</persName> went for a walk, and
          met the <persName ref="#Fraser_Mr #Fraser_Mrs">Frasers</persName> - their boats are being repaired, and
          they are now living on a rented one. An exquisite little moon has dawned upon us!</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1904-01-08" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1904-01-08">1st Sunday after Epiphany. Jan. 8th</date>. <measure quantity="64"
            unit="mile">64 miles</measure>. </dateline>
        <p>A wonderful day for us. We began in a light favourable wind at 7:30 and we have gone on
          splendidly and uninterruptedly the whole day in spite of many awkward turns - passed the 2
          dahabyas which started out before us at <placeName ref="#Assiout">Asyut</placeName> - and
          about 1 o'clock overhauled the <name type="boat" ref="#Agiz">Agiz</name> on the sand -
          exchanged passing greetings<pb n="64"/> and offered help - but she was soon off and after
          us and only arrived where we are an hour and a half after we had tied up. <persName
            ref="#Salah_Mohammed">Saleh</persName> came in this evening to say all was well - they
          were 2 hours on the sand.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1904-01-09" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1904-01-09">Jan. 9th - Monday. 34-1/2 miles</date>. <measure quantity="34.5"
            unit="mile">34-1/2 miles</measure>. </dateline>
        <p>We had a letter from <persName ref="#Higby_Mary">Mary Higby</persName> at <placeName
            ref="#Assiout">Asy&#251;t</placeName>, telling of <persName ref="#Gwynne_Maria"
            >Gwynne's</persName> better condition. Last night was very cold. <persName ref="#Amelie"
            >Amelie</persName> brought in to show me <name type="animal" ref="#Billy">Billy's</name>
          bowl of water which always stands on deck, frozen solid! the second occurrence of the kind
          we have known on the <placeName ref="#Nile">Nile</placeName>. The mercury was 49 in my
          room. But the day has been warm and splendid - and the little new moon and Venus close to
          her made such a splendid picture just above a group of 3 solitary palms on the bank that I
          could not get my usual nap before dinner.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1904-01-10" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1904-01-10">Tuesday, Jan. 10th</date>. <measure quantity="18" unit="mile">18
            miles</measure>. </dateline>
        <p><placeName ref="#Nag_Hammadi">Nagh Hamadi</placeName> - which we reached by 4 o'clock of
          course finding the bridge closed. The <name type="boat" ref="#Agiz">Agiz</name> drew up
          about an hour later and <persName ref="#Hale_Miss">Miss Hale</persName> and <persName
            ref="#Perkins_Mrs">Mrs. Perkins</persName> came over to see us.</p>
      </div>
      <!-- [the page is cut off] - how should I tag/mark this? -->
      <!-- Where's Kasr es Sayd? I found a drawing of it (https://bit.ly/3ei9xyB) but no reference in Getty.-->
      <div xml:id="EBA-1904-01-11" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1904-01-11">Wednesday, Jan. 11th. <placeName>Kasr es Sayd</placeName>
          </date>. <measure quantity="8" unit="mile">8 miles</measure>. </dateline>
        <p>We sailed through the bridge at 9 o'clock this morning. When we came to the great bend of
          the river here, we could go no further - and were obliged to tie up against a very high
          bank. The <name type="boat" ref="#Agiz">Agiz</name> had to do the same - we went over to
          see [the page is cut off].<pb n="65"/></p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1904-01-12" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1904-01-12">Thursday, Jan. 12th</date>. <measure quantity="26" unit="mile">26
            miles</measure>. </dateline>
        <p>We are about <measure quantity="4" unit="mile">four miles</measure> below <placeName
            ref="#Qina">Keneh</placeName> tonight, we have been sailing since 6 o'clock. The Reis
          finding a light favourable wind blowing at that time, got off very quietly - I, of course,
          from my room, heard the preparations, and lifting a corner of my curtain looked out. And
          what a sense of wonderful beauty was before me. The bold range of cliffs behind <placeName
            ref="#Qina">Keneh</placeName>, were standing transfused with a luminous rose colour -
          their bases all in blue darkness and shadow - and we were sailing over a gold, pink river
          - the reflection from the big mountain stretching to where we were lying. A splendid
          wonder it was!</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1904-01-13" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1904-01-13">Friday, Jan. 13th</date>. <measure quantity="23" unit="mile">23
            miles</measure>. </dateline>
        <p>We have had a diversified day of wind - strong and light - and calms - and have made our
          miles by every known craft of <placeName ref="#Nile">Nile</placeName> sailorship. The
            <name type="boat" ref="#Agiz">Agiz</name> has been near us most of the time - though
          yesterday we beat her 4 hours.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1904-01-14" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1904-01-14">Saturday, Jan. 14th.</date>. <measure quantity="16.5" unit="mile"
            >16-1/2 miles</measure>. </dateline>
        <p>We have worked hard all day - hoping to reach <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName>,
          as we were last within a mile of <placeName ref="#Naqadah">Nagada</placeName>. But winds
          were very light and contrary and we tracked most of the time. The <name type="boat"
            ref="#Agiz">Agiz</name>, and <name type="boat" ref="#Bijou">"Bijou"</name> being behind
          us - until, about one o'clock a great bend in the river brought our boat to a standstill -
          and the others with their keels were able to hold on - and passed us - we have all been
          tracking ever since - the others about a mile before us. The weather<pb n="66"/> has been
          both hot and cold - the sun quite powerful - and the wind keen and cold.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1904-01-15" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1904-01-15">2d Sunday after Epiphany. Jan. 15</date>. <placeName ref="#Luxor"
            >Luxor</placeName>. <measure quantity="6" unit="mile">6 miles</measure>. </dateline>
        <p>We tracked and pulled through a perfect calm this morning - until just as we came to the
          town a good breeze sprang up, and we sailed up to our old place on the sand island - and
          have a beautiful view of the mountains. The <name type="boat" ref="#Agiz">Agiz</name> came
          along half an hour after, and went across just under the castle, where we used to go. Very
          few dahabyas here - and the town very quiet.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1904-01-16" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1904-01-16">Monday, Jan. 16</date>. </dateline>
        <p>Very busy this morning, settling etc. a great scrubbing going on outside and inside - and
          a wash literally of 4 weeks. <name type="animal" ref="#Billy">Billy's</name> enjoys our
          island enormously and spends his time chasing the birds, and barking at all comers.
            <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> and <persName ref="#Wilson_Alice"
            >Alice</persName> went over to the town this morning - paid a visit to <persName
            ref="#Mohassib_Mohammed">Mohamed Mohassib</persName> - <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M"
            >Theo</persName> reports him still grieving for his son - and looking very old and sad.
            <persName ref="#Quibell_Annie_Pirie">Mrs. Quibell</persName> came in this afternoon
          looking so very well. <persName ref="#Quibell_James">Mr. Q</persName>. arrives tonight
          from <placeName ref="#Aswan">Asw&#226;n</placeName>.</p>
      </div>
      <!--  -->
      <div xml:id="EBA-1904-01-17" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1904-01-17">Tuesday, Jan. 17th</date>. </dateline>
        <p><persName ref="#Wilson_Alice">Alice</persName> and I went over to town this morning and
          paid a visit to <persName ref="#Buchanan_Carrie">Miss Buchanan</persName> and <persName
            ref="#Nubeewya">Nubeewya</persName> - <persName ref="#Buchanan_Carrie">Miss
          B</persName>. a little pale and tired looking - <persName ref="#Nubeewya"
            >Nubeewya</persName> quite the reverse. Their new building begins to make quite a<pb
            n="67"/> showing at the lower end of the town. The second story is almost ready for the
          roof, and the first will be ready for occupation by the <date when="1904-03-01">1st of
            March</date>. <persName ref="#Nubeewya">Nubeewya</persName> was very happy to see me
          again - <persName ref="#Buchanan_Carrie">Miss B</persName>. had written me that she had
          asked to be baptized - it was just after they came back from <placeName ref="#Ar_Ramlah"
            >Ramleh</placeName> in September. <persName ref="#Nubeewya">Nubeewya</persName> went to
            <persName ref="#Buchanan_Carrie">Miss B</persName>. and said, "I want to be a Christian"
          "I don't believe in our Prophet any more, but I believe in your Christ". <persName
            ref="#Buchanan_Carrie">Miss B</persName>. had always refrained from talking to her of
          her religion - so she said "why do you want to be a Christian?" "Because all the good,
          kind people I know are Christians". She has become they tell me a joy in the house - what
          a transformation for a little savage 3 years ago! <persName ref="#Perkins_Mrs">Mrs. Perkins</persName>
          and <persName ref="#Hale_Miss">Miss Hale</persName> to lunch.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1904-01-18" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1904-01-18">Wednesday, Jan. 18</date>. </dateline>
        <p>A rather warm still day - <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> went over to
            <placeName ref="#Der_el_Bahari">Der el Bahari</placeName> to see <persName
            ref="#Naville_Edouard">M. Naville</persName>. The <name type="boat" ref="#Agiz"
            >Agiz</name> started up the river today, towing.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1904-01-19" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1904-01-19">Thursday, Jan. 19</date>. </dateline>
        <p>A quiet day at home - and busy - <persName ref="#Miller_Mrs">Mrs. Miller</persName> and
            <persName ref="#Miller_Capt">Capt. Miller</persName> with their two girls called this
          evening. They had sent a letter introductory a few days since from <persName
            ref="#Parsons_John">Mr. John Parsons</persName> of <placeName ref="#New_York">New
            York</placeName>. Pleasant people - first visit in <placeName ref="#Egypt"
            >Egypt</placeName> - though <persName ref="#Miller_Capt">Capt. Miller</persName>
          formerly of the navy had been with <persName ref="#Grant">Grant</persName> in his trip
          around the world, and stopped at <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName>.<pb n="68"
          /></p>
      </div>
      <!-- Now that we can no longer use personGrp, I don't know what to do for the Misses Collinses anymore. We only know  -->
      <div xml:id="EBA-1904-01-20" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1904-01-20">Friday, Jan. 20th</date>. </dateline>
        <p>Rather warmer today - <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and the
            <persName ref="#Miller_Capt #Miller_Mrs">Millers</persName> rode over to <placeName
            ref="#Medinet_Habu">Medinet Abu</placeName> - <persName ref="#Wilson_Alice"
            >Alice</persName> and I to see <persName ref="#Buchanan_Carrie">Miss Buchanan</persName>
          and afterwards to the <name type="hotel" ref="#Luxor_Hotel">Luxor Hotel</name> for tea
          with the <persName ref="#Collins_Misses">Misses Collins</persName> - Nice, simple Scotch bodies they are,
          I like them.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1904-01-21" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1904-01-21">Saturday, Jan. 21st</date>. </dateline>
        <p>We have had a long days excursion to <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">The Tombs of
            the Kings</placeName>. <persName ref="#Quibell_James #Quibell_Annie">Mr. and Mrs.
            Quibell</persName> met us and lunched with us. The <persName
            ref="#Miller_Capt #Miller_Mrs">Millers</persName> went along, but did not lunch with us.
          A lot of people over there, so we went up to the <persName ref="#ThotmesIV">Thothmes
            IV</persName> plateau, and had our lunch there. A splendid vantage ground - but a cool
          wind was blowing - neither I or <persName ref="#Quibell_Mrs">Mrs. Quibell</persName> went
          down into any of the <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">Tombs</placeName> - and I came
          home early. I was in my chair and the donkeys were not very good. And the detestable Sugar
          people have spoiled every thing on this side. Those lovely rides we used to have through
          those smiling fields, are gone now forever! They have built canals and railways to carry
          their sugar cane - and the jolting, noisy little trains are always hustling up and down
          with their loads of sugar cane. It was quite an unwarrantable usurpation too, everyone
          says. <persName ref="#Edgar_Mr">Mr. Edgar</persName> also lunched with us - and <persName
            ref="#Jones_Harold">Jones</persName> took a lot of interesting photographs.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1904-01-22" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1904-01-22">3d Sunday after Epiphany - Jan. 22</date>. </dateline>
        <p>A quiet day at home. <persName ref="#Quibell_James">Mr. Quibell</persName> dined with
            us.<pb n="69"/></p>
      </div>
      <!-- There's apparently a famous temple for Mentuhotep II but none for Mentuhotep I (who, apparently, might not have actually existed). I'm assuming she's talking about that one. -->
      <!-- What is "Ex. So."? A political position in Egypt or something? I might be misreading the entry, but is it possible that M. Naville is the "Egypt Ex. So."? -->
      <!-- What is "the Society"? -->
      <!-- As for the man nmaed Sethe, since he's not really important other than his name, it might be nice to instead explain in his "biography" why is sname is so special to German archaeologists? (Just looked it up - Kurt Sethe was a famous German archaeologist) -->
      <div xml:id="EBA-1904-01-23" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1904-01-23">Monday, Jan. 23d</date>. </dateline>
        <p>A really cold day, with high blustering winds - in spite of which <persName
            ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and <persName
            ref="#Hardy_Jean #Wilson_Alice">the girls</persName> went over again to the <persName
            ref="#Mentuhotep_II">Mentuhotep</persName>
          <placeName ref="#Mentuhotep_Mortuary_Temple">temple</placeName> - and stopped for tea with
            <persName ref="#Quibell_James">Mr. Quibell</persName>. <persName
            ref="#Naville_Edouard #Naville_Mme">M. and Mme. Naville</persName> dined with us. They
          are a pair of giants - and handsome ones too, and we found them very pleasant. He is much
          pleased with the lift <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> has given him
          for the <placeName ref="#Mentuhotep_Mortuary_Temple">Temple</placeName>. A gift of Â£100 -
          it seems the <placeName ref="#Egypt">Egypt</placeName> Ex. So. is at present much hampered
          by lack of funds. <persName ref="#Petrie_William">Petrie</persName>, who is excavating at
            <placeName ref="#Masa_Jabal">Mt. Sinai</placeName>, everyone thinks unwisely, claims
          most of the money the Society has for his work - he has so embroiled himself with all his
          surroundings, natives decline working for him - and steal almost everything he has -
          assistants leave him etc. So it was feared that the every interesting work at the
            <placeName ref="#Mentuhotep_Mortuary_Temple">Mentuhotep temple</placeName> would have to
          stop for a time. The <persName ref="#Naville_Edouard #Naville_Mme">Navilles</persName> go
          over there to stay, tomorrow, in the fine house the German Government has built there and
          I was so amused when he replied to <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore's</persName>
          question of "Are you quite alone there?" "Practically yes - there is a G&#246;ttingen man
          there by the name of <persName ref="#Sethe">Sethe"</persName> - as this is an awesome name
          to the German archaeological world, it seemed very funny.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1904-01-24" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1904-01-24">Tuesday, Jan. 24</date>. </dateline>
        <p>Another disagreeable day of cold and wind. The <persName ref="#Miller_Capt #Miller_Mrs"
            >Millers</persName> to lunch. We have been living in such exciting interest for weeks in
          the Russio-Japanese war. <placeName ref="#Port_Arthur">"Has Port Arthur</placeName>
          fallen?" has been the question with which we have greeted each mail. Then came the news of
          its disgraceful capitulation - the incredible evidences of the rottenness of<pb n="70"/>
          of the Russian government - army - navy - individuals! Never in all history has there been
          so disgraceful an expos&#233;s of a peoples dishonor and perfidy. Today came the telegram
          of the revolutionary disturbances in <placeName ref="#St_Petersburg">St.
            Petersburg!</placeName> - harrowing in its sadness!</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1904-01-25" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1904-01-25">Wednesday, Jan. 25</date>. </dateline>
        <p>A cold S. wind all day. The young men, <placeName ref="#Smith_Harold">Smith</placeName>
          and <persName ref="#Ream_Robert_Clarke">Ream</persName>, appeared this morning, arriving
          from <placeName ref="#Aswan">Asw&#226;n</placeName> last evening. They are at the <name
            type="hotel" ref="#Luxor_Hotel">Luxor Hotel</name>. They all went over to the <placeName
            ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">Tombs of the Kings</placeName> this afternoon. <persName
            ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> tells me he has arranged with <persName
            ref="#Quibell_James">Mr. Quibell</persName> to quit work up where they are in the
            <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">Valley</placeName> - and to send the men to join
          those already working up north of the Tomb of <persName ref="#Amenhotep_II">Amenhotep
            II</persName>.</p>
      </div>
      <!-- Who is the other Buchanan? -->
      <div xml:id="EBA-1904-01-26" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1904-01-26">Thursday, Jan. 26th</date>. </dateline>
        <p>The <persName ref="#Miller_Capt #Miller_Mrs">Millers</persName> came to say goodbye.
            <persName ref="#Hardy_Jean">Jean</persName> and I went to <persName
            ref="#Buchanan_Carrie">Miss Buchanans</persName> for tea - such a pleasant visit - and
            <persName ref="#Nubeewya">Nubeewaya</persName> so delightful and astounding. <placeName
            ref="#Smith_Harold">Smith</placeName> and <persName ref="#Ream_Robert_Clarke"
            >Ream</persName> dined with us. Bridge of course followed; high winds.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1904-01-27" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1904-01-27">Friday, Jan. 27</date>. </dateline>
        <p>A nice quiet day - the rest went to <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Queens">Tombs of
            Queens</placeName> - then back here to tea. Very cold.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1904-01-28" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1904-01-28">Saturday, Jan. 28</date>. </dateline>
        <p>The whole cavalcade went to <placeName ref="#Karnak">Karnak</placeName>. I took my
          exercise with<pb n="71"/>
          <name type="animal" ref="#Billy">Billy</name> on the sands.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1904-01-29" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1904-01-29">4th Sunday after Epiphany. Jan. 29</date>. </dateline>
        <p>A quiet pleasant day for me. <persName ref="#Lindon_Smith_Joseph #Lindon_Smith_Corinna"
            >Mr. and Mrs. Joe Smith</persName> came to dine.</p>
      </div>
      <!-- Paul's Rose Catalogue is probably like flower catalogues you can buy today. -->
      <div xml:id="EBA-1904-01-30" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1904-01-30">Monday, Jan. 30</date>. </dateline>
        <p>I have been very busy all day with Paul's Rose Catalogue - getting up my rose list for
          this year. There are such complex questions about Rose growing at the Reef. Just before
          the night fell I noticed a strange looking dahabya pulling up at the bank opposite us -
          quite new to me, - the <name type="boat" ref="#Sahabiha">"Sahabiha"</name> flying the
          Stars and Stripes - and soon after the lamps were lighted, who should appear but <persName
            ref="#Campbell_Dr #Campbell_Mrs">Dr. and Mrs. Campbell</persName>! We were so glad to
          see them - and they have the <name type="boat" ref="#Sahabiha">Sahabiha</name> - it is a
          boat built for the <persName ref="#Abbas_II">Khedives</persName> mother, and of course on
          the hareem lines. They too, took a month for coming up.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1904-01-31" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1904-01-31">Tuesday, Jan. 31</date>. </dateline>
        <p>Cool. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> had gone with 3 boys - young
            <persName ref="#Arrowsmith">Arrowsmith</persName> and 2 others from <placeName
            ref="#Groton">Groton</placeName>, with a letter from <persName ref="#Gardiner_Alan">Mr.
            Gardiner. </persName></p>
      </div>

<!-- Hannah Burrows -->
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-02-02" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-02-02">Thursday, Feb. 2d.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>Two very quiet days - <persName ref="#Peckitt_Reginald #Peckitt_Amelia">the <choice>
          <sic>Picketts</sic><corr>Peckitts</corr></choice></persName> from <placeName ref="#Cairo">
          Cairo</placeName>, who are here in their R.R. car, dined with us.<pb n="72"/></p>
      </div>
      <pb n="72"/>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-02-03" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-02-03">Friday, Feb. 3d.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>We were at home all day, until in the afternoon we visited the <name type="boat"
            ref="#Agiz">Agiz</name>, who arrived today - then to the <name type="boat"
            ref="#Sabiha">Sabiha</name> to see <persName ref="#Campbell_Dr #Campbell_Mrs">the
            Campbells</persName>. They have an interesting and rather pretty little boat - built in
          the Hareem style - it was built and belongs to the <persName ref="#Abbas_II"
            >Khedive</persName>'s mother. A visit from <persName ref="#Maspero_Gaston">M.
            Maspero</persName> after we got home - and <persName ref="#Smith_Harold"
            >Smith</persName> and <persName ref="#Ream_Robert_Clarke">Ream</persName> came for
          bridge in the evening. <persName ref="#Maspero_Gaston">Maspero</persName>'s dined with us
          and the <persName ref="#Theodant_Abbe">Abb&#233; Th&#232;odant</persName>.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-02-05" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-02-05">Fifth Sunday after Epiphany. Feb. 5th.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p><persName ref="#Smith_Harold">Smith</persName> and <persName ref="#Ream_Robert_Clarke"
            >Ream</persName> came to breakfast - <persName ref="#Hardy_Jean">Jean</persName> went
          over with them afterwards to church. <persName ref="#Ayrton_Edward">Mr. Ayrton</persName>
          to lunch and a visit from the <name type="boat" ref="#Agiz">Agiz</name> people, who came
          to tea, and we made <persName ref="#Perkins_Mrs">Mrs. Perkins</persName> and <persName
            ref="#Hale_Miss">Miss Hale</persName> stay for dinner. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M"
            >Theo</persName> went immediately after lunch with <persName ref="#Ayrton_Edward">Mr.
            Ayrton</persName> over to <persName ref="#Quibell_James #Quibell_Annie_Pirie">the
            Quibells</persName> and the busy day came to an end.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-02-06" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-02-06">Monday, Feb. 6th.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>A very windy day - <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> and <persName
            ref="#Hardy_Jean #Wilson_Alice">the girls</persName> in spite of it, went over to the
            <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">Valley</placeName>, where when <persName
            ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> appeared the workmen greeted him with a
          cheer, and he knew it meant some sign of promise - and the men had found the lintel of a
          door to a tomb. They said they might clear it to the entrance in a few days. Very
          encouraging.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-02-07" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-02-07">Tuesday, Feb. 7th.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>A calm, warm day. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> came back from <name
            type="hotel" ref="#Luxor_Hotel">Luxor</name> this noon, with a most beautiful statuette
          in silver he had bought of <persName ref="#Mohassib_Mohammed">Mohassib</persName>. In<pb
            n="73"/> style and treatment it suggests that Egyptian statuette in bronze and silver,
          the Lady Tak&#251;shit, now in <placeName ref="#Athens">Athens</placeName> and shown in
          the "Struggle of Nations" by <persName ref="#Maspero_Gaston">Maspero</persName>. <persName
            ref="#Smith_Harold">Smith</persName> and <persName ref="#Ream_Robert_Clarke"
            >Ream</persName> went with <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> and
            <persName ref="#Weigall_Arthur">Weigall</persName>, who had lunched here, to the
            <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">Valley</placeName>, and the two first dined with
          us. <persName ref="#Lindon_Smith_Joseph #Lindon_Smith_Corinna">Mr. and Mrs. Joe
            Smith</persName> came in during the evening.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-02-10" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-02-10">Friday, Feb. 10.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>This is the third day of cold, strong S. wind we have had. Sand flying in clouds. There
          was literally no stirring abroad.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-02-11" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-02-11">Saturday, Feb. 11th.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p><persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> and <persName ref="#Weigall_Arthur">Mr.
            Weigall</persName> went over to the <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings"
            >Valley</placeName> today; several steps leading to the door of the tomb uncovered.
            <persName ref="#Weigall_Arthur">Weigall</persName> came in for tea - after which
            <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> went over to the <name type="boat"
            ref="#Miriam">Miriam</name> to see <persName ref="#Maspero_Gaston">M. Maspero</persName>
          about the tomb, <persName ref="#Quibell_James">Quibell</persName> being away. He
          authorized <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> to open it, and <persName
            ref="#Weigall_Arthur">Mr. Weigall</persName> will look after it. <persName
            ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> wrote <persName ref="#Quibell_Mrs">Mrs.
            Quibell</persName> about it, explaining.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-02-12" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-02-12">6th Sunday after Epiphany - Feb. 12.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>A <persName ref="#Porch_Mr.">Mr. Porch</persName> came to lunch with <persName
            ref="#Weigall_Arthur">Mr. Weigall</persName>. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M"
            >Theo</persName> met him the other day. He is English, a devot&#233; to flints. He has
          been encamped near <placeName ref="#Al_Qurnah">Q&#251;rna</placeName>, at the mouth of a
          little rock tomb, he is a handsome agreeable little fellow - seems to know every one - and
          especially all <placeName ref="#Italy">Italy</placeName> and Italians. He travels
          everywhere with an Italian servant who would seem to be a half savant. His ancestral home
          in <placeName ref="#England">England</placeName><pb n="74"/> is <placeName
            ref="#Glastonbury">Glastenbury Abbey</placeName> - he goes very soon to <placeName
            ref="#India">India</placeName> - with this servant and a camel he has come all the way
          from the <placeName ref="#Red_Sea">Red Sea</placeName> to <name type="hotel"
            ref="#Luxor_Hotel">Luxor</name>. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> and
            <persName ref="#Weigall_Arthur">Weigall</persName> rode over to the <placeName
            ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">Valley of the Kings</placeName> this afternoon - when
            <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> got home he brought with him two or
          three queer parcels - and he had an air of great elation. He first unwrapped a yoke of a
          chariot, finely decorated in gold and colour - in perfect condition, then a long baton, or
          wand of office - also finely decorated - then produced a large beautiful green, hard stone
          scarab, with gilded bands, beautifully inscribed even to the wings. He said that the
          workmen had reached the door of the tomb chamber, and they went down into it. A small
          aperture had been broken in this door, large enough to admit a man. This door was of
          stone, plastered with mud - with many seals on it - and the tomb had been broken into in
          ages gone by - for the things <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> found in
          the corridor and brought home, had no doubt been dropped by the thieves. <persName
            ref="#Weigall_Arthur">Weigall</persName> remained behind, to sleep with the guards at
          the tomb, and <persName ref="#Lindon_Smith_Joseph #Lindon_Smith_Corinna">Mr. and Mrs.
            Smith</persName> also went over to stay with him. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M"
            >Theo</persName> wrote a note to <persName ref="#Maspero_Gaston">M. Maspero</persName>
          and <persName ref="#Sayce_Archibald">Mr. Sayce</persName> who arrived on the <name type="boat"
            ref="#Istar">Istar</name> yesterday, to come and see the things. They all came over
          in the evening. <persName ref="#Amos_Mrs.">Mrs. Sheldon Amos</persName>, who is staying
          with <persName ref="#Sayce_Archibald">Mr. Sayce</persName>, also came. </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-02-13" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-02-13">Monday, Feb. 13th.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>We all made an early start for the <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings"
            >Valley</placeName> this morning. <persName ref="#Wilson_Alice">Alice</persName> has not
          been feeling very well for a few days - and was so melancholy at the idea of being left
          behind on the opening day of the tomb, that I persuaded <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M"
            >Theodore</persName> to send for one of <name type="boat" ref="#Victoria">the
            Victorias</name> that occasionally take people over - and she and I rode over most
          comfortably. We had to<pb n="75"/> go on our donkeys across the wide sand waste - and then
          take the carriage and we had to get out for the ascent and the descent of the high canal
          embankment. But the moment we entered the <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings"
            >valley</placeName>, the going was very good. We found <persName ref="#Weigall_Arthur"
            >Weigall</persName> and <persName ref="#Smith_Mr #Smith_Mrs">the Smiths</persName>, the
          native Inspector, and <persName ref="#Maspero_Gaston">Maspero</persName> and his Secretary
          soon arrived. The inner door was ordered down - and while it was being done, <persName
            ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> and <persName ref="#Maspero_Gaston">M.
            Maspero</persName> made a long hot climb to look at a certain site the latter thought
          favourable - and the rest of us sat on the rocks, or in the carriage from which the horses
          had been taken. <persName ref="#Smith_Mrs">Mrs. Smith</persName> who was wildly
          enthusiastic about the whole thing, said that the night had been one of the most beautiful
          she had ever spent. They felt the cold very much, and got up twice to make tea - and again
          very early and climbed to one of the highest points to see the sun rise. In half an hour
          the native Inspector came out of the tomb and said to <persName ref="#Weigall_Arthur"
            >Weigall</persName> "the entrance is free". He and <persName ref="#Smith_Mr">Mr.
            Smith</persName> went down, and in a short time <persName ref="#Weigall_Arthur"
            >Weigall</persName> came up pale and breathless. I thought he had been affected by bad
          air - but it was only excitement - for he ejaculated "wonderful" "extraordinary" etc.
            <persName ref="#Smith_Mr">Mr. Smith</persName> said, "there is everything there but a
          grand piano., - the place is crowded with furniture and coffins". We waited until
            <persName ref="#Maspero_Gaston">M. Maspero</persName> and <persName
            ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> were back, when they at once went down and
          stayed a long time. The tomb was so accessible, opening by its first flight of steps on a
          level with the pathway - from which a short descending corridor leads to another short
          stairway, which gives immediate access to the tomb chamber. It lies just between No's 3
          and 4 - the former an unfinished tomb intended for Ramses III - 4 also unfinished - the
          tomb of <persName ref="#Rameses_XII">Ramses XII</persName>. Neither <persName
            ref="#Maspero_Gaston">M. Maspero</persName> or <persName ref="#Quibell_James"
            >Quibell</persName> thought<pb n="76"/> this site worth working, but <persName
            ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> in his thorough way said he should go on
          clearing up both sides of that side valley - and it was just by this method that he found
          the tomb of Thothmes IV and Hatshepsut. It is remarkable that this tomb, crowded in
          between 3 and 4 could have escaped complete spoilation. When these men at last appeared
          they told us wondrous tales, and allowed us one by one to go down - by the light of
          candles I could see a dim glitter of gold everywhere and a confusion of coffins and
          mummies. Arrangements were made at once for bringing electric wires into the tomb, as the
            <persName ref="#Connaught_Duke">Duke of Connaught</persName> was expected in the
          afternoon and <persName ref="#Maspero_Gaston">M. Maspero</persName> was very pleased to be
          able to give him such a sight. Then we all went up to the Thothmes IV plateau, where
            <persName ref="#Jones_Daniel">Jones</persName> had lunch for us. Too soon after this
            <persName ref="#Maspero_Gaston">M. Maspero</persName> and <persName
            ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> started for the tomb again in the hot sun -- and
          we followed. They went immediately into it - and when in about 20 minutes I saw one
          rushing up and demanding water and brandy, I knew that <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M"
            >Theo</persName> must have fainted as he did a few years ago, under exactly the same
          circumstances. When I reached the first flight of steps, I saw that two people were
          supporting him at the bottom step, bathing his head and hands. He called up to me however
          that he was about over it - and was soon able to be helped up - and took refuge in the
          carriage - and soon seemed none the worse for it. About 4 o'clock, the <persName
            ref="#Connaught_Duke">Duke</persName> and his party arrived with a military escort - and
          went down into the tomb. We had withdrawn to a respectful distance and were sitting on the
          rocks - when the <persName ref="#Connaught_Duke">Duke</persName>, a fine soldierly looking
          fellow and <persName ref="#Maspero_Gaston">M. Maspero</persName> emerged. The <persName
            ref="#Connaught_Duke">Duke</persName> strode over the rocks to where <persName
            ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> was, and heartily congratulated him, and
          begged to <pb n="77"/> present him to the <persName ref="#Connaught_Duchess"
            >Duchess</persName>. After they left, <persName ref="#Quibell_James">Mr.
            Quibell</persName> came very much disgruntled, to find the tomb had been opened in his
          absence. <persName ref="#Maspero_Gaston">M. Maspero</persName> discovered by the various
          inscriptions in the tomb, that it was the burial place of Yuaa and Tuaa, the father and
          mother of the great Queen Tyi, wife of Amenhotep III. The cartouche of this king is on
          many of these things - and that of a daughter of his - Set-amen. All the objects so far as
          they have been seen, are in perfect order and good and very beautiful. </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-02-14" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-02-14">Tuesday, Feb. 14th.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>Another day with all the family again to the <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings"
            >Valley</placeName>. Again I had the carriage and took <persName ref="#Maspero_Louise"
            >Mme. Maspero</persName> with me. <persName ref="#Sayce_Archibald">Mr. Sayce</persName>
          and <persName ref="#Sheldon_Amos_Mrs.">Mrs. Sheldon Amos</persName> also went over - and
          we had an open lunch table at the Thothmes plateau - all of these, with the <persName
            ref="#Theodant_Abbe">Abb&#233; Th&#232;odant</persName>, <persName ref="#Weigall_Arthur"
            >Weigall</persName>, <persName ref="#Smith_Harold">Smith</persName> and <persName
            ref="#Ayrton_Edward">Ayrton</persName>. After we got home, <persName ref="#Watson_Capt."
            >Capt. Watson</persName> of the <persName ref="#Connaught_Duke">Duke</persName>'s party
          called, also <persName ref="#Maspero_Gaston">Maspero</persName>, <persName ref="#Lacau_M"
            >Lacau</persName>, and the <persName ref="#Theodant_Abbe">Abb&#233;</persName>.
            <persName ref="#Graham_John_Sir">Sir John</persName> and <persName ref="#Evans_Lady"
            >Lady Evans</persName> dined with us. The tomb was visited today by the <persName
            ref="#Eugenie_Empress">Ex-Empress Eug&#233;nie</persName>, and also by <persName
            ref="#Adolphe_Gustave_Prince">Prince Gustave Adolphe</persName> of Sweden. He and
            <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> seem to have struck up quite a
          friendship. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> was much pleased with him -
          a sensible, intelligent young fellow. He was very enthusiastic over what he saw, and said,
          "Moi, Je suis aussi explorer - je fouille dans mon pays - si ca m'arrivera de venir ice
          pour fouiller comme vous!" One of his aid-de-camps after sent <persName
            ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Mr. Davis</persName> a note thanking him again and again. Also
          the <persName ref="#Cavendish_Spencer_Duke">Duke</persName> and <persName
            ref="#Cavendish_Louisa_Duchess">Duchess of Devonshire</persName> saw it.</p>
        <pb n="78"/>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-02-15" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-02-15">Wednesday, Feb. 15.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p><persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> and <persName ref="#Sayce_Archibald"
            >Mr. Sayce</persName> went over to the tomb and spent the day - we stayed at home - a
          calm day - <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> sent his Thothmes book to the
            <persName ref="#Connaught_Duke">Duke of Connaught</persName>. In the evening after he
          got back, <persName ref="#Yarde-Buller_Capt.">Capt. Yarde-Buller</persName> A.D.C. to his
          H.R.H. called to thank him, and afterwards <persName ref="#Watson_Capt.">Capt.
            Watson</persName> came in and joined him. <persName ref="#Watson_Capt.">Capt.
            W</persName>. was very entertaining with his talk about his experiences - having been
          with <persName ref="#Kitchener_Herbert">Kitchener</persName> through the whole of the
          campaign in the <placeName ref="#Sudan">Soudan</placeName>. <persName ref="#Lacau_M">M.
            Lacau</persName> dined with us.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-02-16" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-02-16">Thursday, Feb. 16.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>A warm, calm day - over to the <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">Valley</placeName>
          again, but I in my donkey chair. I saw the different things found in the tombs well today
          for the first time - as they had been brought out of the tomb and placed in that of Ramses
          XII. The most wonderful and varied collection of beautiful things in perfect condition.
          The 2 mummies of Yuaa and Tuaa, well preserved and very impressive, despite the fact that
          Tuaa's eyes are wide open. They had double coffins of the finest workmanship literally
          overlaid with gold - chairs, boxes, 3 funeral couches, vases, scarabs, a great roll of
          papyrus, etc etc. extraordinarily rich - a wonderful find. At 3 o'clock <persName
            ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> received a note from <persName
            ref="#Waters_Capt.">Capt. Waters</persName>, which had been sent over from the dahabya,
          saying their Royal Highnesses would be glad to come about 5 o'clock to the boat if it
          would be convenient. So we had to drop everything, order out donkeys, and hurry home the 7
          miles. We had just time to wash our faces, and take off our hats, when they arrived, also
          in riding dress. The <persName ref="#Connaught_Duke">Duke</persName>, <persName
            ref="#Connaught_Duchess">Duchess</persName>, their daughter<pb n="79"/>
          <persName ref="#Margaret_Princess">Princess Margaret</persName>, a Lady in Waiting and
            <persName ref="#Buller_Capt.">Capt. Buller</persName>. I never met simpler, pleasanter
          people. They were very much interested in every thing - and it was queer to see them in my
          room, which they declared lovely. They stayed over an hour, and evidently enjoyed
          themselves, and parted most fraternally from <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M"
            >Theodore</persName> - Gen. Sir <persName ref="#Maxwell_John_Sir">John
            Maxwell</persName> was also with them. <persName ref="#Maspero_Gaston #Maspero_Louise"
            >M. and Mme. Maspero</persName>, the <persName ref="#Theodant_Abbe">Abb&#233;</persName>,
          called to say goodbye as they start down the river tomorrow. <persName
            ref="#Sayce_Archibald">Mr. Sayce</persName> and <persName ref="#Sheldon_Amos_Mrs.">Mrs.
            Amos</persName> also called.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-02-17" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-02-17">Friday, Feb. 17.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>A quiet day and evening at home! Lovely!</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-02-18" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-02-18">Saturday, Feb. 18.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p><persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> and <persName
            ref="#Hardy_Jean #Wilson_Alice">the girls</persName> went to the <placeName
            ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">Valley</placeName> again - <persName ref="#Weigall_Arthur"
            >Weigall</persName> came back with them and had tea. He still sleeps at the tomb.
            <persName ref="#Naville_Edouard #Naville_Mme">M. and Mme. Naville</persName> to tea.
            <persName ref="#Sayce_Archibald">Mr. Sayce</persName> dined with us. He starts down on
          Monday. We start for <placeName ref="#Aswān">Asw&#226;n</placeName> tomorrow - I don't
          know for what unless to give <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> a rest.
          We can only stay a day or two.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-02-19" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-02-19">Septuagesima Sunday - Feb. 19. 9 miles.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p><persName ref="#Ayrton_Edward">Mr. Ayrton</persName> came to breakfast - we were off at
          noon, and with difficulty reached <placeName ref="#Armant">Erment</placeName>. It is so
          nice to be free of people once more.<pb n="80"/></p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-02-20" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-02-20">Monday, Feb. 20. 42 miles.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>A beautiful warm day - we are about a mile below <placeName ref="#El_Kab">El
            Kab</placeName>.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-02-21" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-02-21">Tuesday, Feb. 21. 53 miles.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>A fine sailing day - we are from 2 to 3 miles below <placeName ref="#Kawm_Umbū">Kom
            Ombo</placeName>.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-02-22" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-02-22">Wednesday, Feb. 22. <placeName ref="Aswān">Asw&#226;n</placeName>.
            28-1/2 miles.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>We arrived about 3 o'clock - and have ever since been wondering why we came. But the dry,
          warm air is delicious, and so are the red-yellow sands. Are lying at our old island.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-02-23" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-02-23">Thursday, Feb. 23.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p><persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and I have been home all day -
            <persName ref="#Hardy_Jean #Wilson_Alice">the girls</persName> went to the <placeName
            ref="#Aswan_High_Dam">Barrage</placeName> this afternoon with <persName ref="#Amelie"
            >Amelie</persName> - wind.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-02-24" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-02-24">Friday, Feb. 24.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>A very high wind all day. <persName ref="#Hardy_Jean #Wilson_Alice">Girls</persName>
          lunched at the <name type="hotel" ref="#Cataract_Hotel">Cataract Hotel</name> with
            <persName ref="#Hooper_Mary_J #Hooper_Josephine_G #Hooper_Mabel">the Boston Hooper
            girls</persName> - who came over to the boat late in the afternoon. <persName
            ref="#Morrell_Dr">Dr. Morrell</persName> called this morning. <persName
            ref="#Hardy_Jean #Wilson_Alice">The girls</persName> and I with <persName
            ref="#Jones_Daniel">Jones</persName> were at the Bazaar this morning - <persName
            ref="#Hardy_Jean">Jean</persName> and I went for tea to the <name type="hotel"
            ref="#Savoy_Hotel">Savoy</name> - and had it in the garden back of the hotel. it was
          charming - the gardens are of real extent, and wonderfully improved. So much more
            attractive<pb n="81"/> than the <name type="hotel" ref="#Cataract_Hotel">Cataract
            Hotel</name>. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> has been trying to find
          a tug - but failed.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-02-25" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-02-25">Saturday, Feb. 25. 12 miles.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>We got off at 7:30 and are now within 14 miles of <placeName ref="#Kawm_Umbū">Kom
            Ombo</placeName> - a really warm day.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-02-26" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-02-26">Sexigesima Sunday. Feb. 26. 26 miles.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>The men have worked nobly from since 4 o'clock this morning - working most of the time -
          we are lying 3 miles above <placeName ref="#Gebel_el_Silsila">Silsileh</placeName>.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-02-27" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-02-27">Monday, Feb. 27. 40-1/2 miles.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>The men began at 3 o'clock, and have rowed until 6 P.M. We passed 3 dahabyas going
          up.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-02-28" type="entry">
        <dateline> Near <placeName ref="#El_Kab">El Kab</placeName>. <date when="1905-02-28"
            >Tuesday, Feb. 28. 38 miles.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>We have had a warm day and evening - many clouds about - fear N. wind tomorrow.<placeName
            ref="#Gebelein">Gebelen</placeName>.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-03-01" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-03-01">Wednesday, March 1st. 9 miles.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>We have had such gales of wind today, and have worked along in all sorts of ways, but
          have only reached <placeName ref="#Armant">Erment</placeName>, or a little below it, and
          tied up at 6 o'clock.<pb n="82"/></p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-03-02" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <name type="hotel" ref="#Luxor_Hotel">Luxor</name> - <date when="1905-03-02">March 2nd. -
            Thursday.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>Starting very early this morning we reached our old mooring place on the sand opposite
          the <placeName ref="#Castle_Carter">Castle</placeName>, at 8 o'clock. <name type="hotel"
            ref="#Luxor_Hotel">Luxor</name> looks quite deserted. We were a little over 5 days
          coming down. We found <persName ref="#Campbell_Dr #Campbell_Mrs">the Campbells</persName>
          here, and they came over to see us at once. <persName ref="#Weigall_Arthur">Mr.
            Weigall</persName> also came in with many interesting things to say. Quite warm - we all
          rode over to <placeName ref="#Der_el_Bahari">Der el Bahari</placeName> - and had tea with
            <persName ref="#Ayrton_Edward">Mr. Ayrton</persName> at the little stone house. I saw
          for the first time the beautiful sarcophagus found by <persName ref="#Naville_Edouard"
            >Naville</persName> on the terrace of the <placeName ref="#Temple_of_Mentu-hotep"
            >Mentuhotep temple</placeName> - of one of the "favourites" of the King - Kau-it - quite
          exquisite. <persName ref="#Ayrton_Edward">Mr. Ayrton</persName> says there were several
          graves found. I think he said 7 - three of them bearing names of which the above was one -
          the rest were nameless. <persName ref="#Wilson_Alice">Alice</persName> and I came directly
          home, but <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> and <persName
            ref="#Hardy_Jean">Jean</persName> went on to <persName
            ref="#Quibell_James #Quibell_Annie_Pirie">the Quibells</persName>. <persName
            ref="#Campbell_Dr #Campbell_Mrs">The Campbells</persName> started down the river this
          afternoon.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-03-03" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-03-03">Friday, March 3rd. Very warm.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p><persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and <persName ref="#Hardy_Jean"
            >Jean</persName> off to <placeName ref="#Karnak">Karnak</placeName> this morning. The
          boxes began arriving from the tomb this morning, and were taken to a big felucca just
          behind us. It looked quite awful to see the long line of men, staggering over those wide
          burning sands, in that hot sun, carrying such loads. <persName ref="#Quibell_James">Mr.
            Quibell</persName> and <persName ref="#Weigall_Arthur">Weigall</persName> came with
          them, and the latter in to lunch with us. It will be impossible to get them all over
          today. There were several policemen - and <persName ref="#Quibell_James">Mr.
            Quibell</persName> and a force will sleep there tonight. <persName ref="#Ayrton_Edward"
            >Ayrton</persName> came to dine. I had expected <persName ref="#Buchanan_Carrie">Miss
            Buchanan</persName> and <persName ref="#Nubeewya"><choice><sic>Nubaweeya</sic>
            <corr>Nubeewya</corr></choice></persName> to tea this
          afternoon and was so disappointed that they were<pb n="83"/> prevented. <persName
            ref="#Lacau_M">M. Lacau</persName> was here however, and <persName ref="#Insinger_Miss"
            >Miss Insinger</persName>. To tea with <persName ref="#Buchanan_Carrie">Miss
            Buchanan</persName>, <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName>, <persName
            ref="#Hardy_Jean">Jean</persName> and I, and had such a pleasant visit.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-03-04" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-03-04">Saturday, March 4th.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>A very hot day - we all went over to <name type="hotel" ref="#Luxor_Hotel">Luxor</name>
          and met the <persName ref="#Forbes-Leith_Mrs #Burn_Colonel #Burn_Mrs"
            >Forbes-Leiths</persName>, who are coming to dine tonight. <persName
            ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> has arranged with the Sugar Co. of <placeName
            ref="#Nag_Hammadi">Nag Hamadi</placeName>, to give us a tug on the 8th. We have had a
          charming dinner - <persName ref="#Forbes_Leith_Mrs">Mrs. Forbes-Leith</persName> -
            <persName ref="#Burn_Colonel #Burn_Mrs">Col. and Mrs. Burn</persName> (her daughter and
          son-in-law) and <persName ref="#Tweedah_Mrs.">Mrs. Tweedah</persName>. They were delighted
          with everything here. We get off tomorrow. </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-03-05" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-03-05">Quinquagesima Sunday. March 5th.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>We did not get off this morning, as a gale from the north was raging. <persName
            ref="#Weigall_Arthur">Weigall</persName> here for breakfast. We had waffles - which he
          said always seemed to him like eating "warm pillows". <persName ref="#Ayrton_Edward">Mr.
            Ayrton</persName> came in late this afternoon, with the Capt. from <placeName
            ref="#Kons">Kons</placeName>, with whom he had been to look at the huge prehistoric
          cemetery up near <placeName ref="#Kawm_Umbū">Kom Ombo</placeName>. It is supposed to be a
          secret - and he reported most favourably about it - and says it has the appearance of
          being absolutely untouched. He will begin work upon it at once for <persName
            ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName>. <persName
            ref="#Quibell_James #Quibell_Annie_Pirie">The Quibells</persName> called to say
          goodbye. Altogether we have been at <name type="hotel" ref="#Luxor_Hotel">Luxor</name>
          this year 5 weeks and 3 days.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-03-06" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-03-06">Monday March 6th. 22-1/2 miles.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>We got off this morning at 7 o'clock - in almost a calm - but had to give up rowing and
          begin floating<pb n="84"/> before we were out of sight of <name type="hotel"
            ref="#Luxor_Hotel">Luxor</name> - and so we have come along, and are now near <placeName
            ref="#Naqadah">Nagada</placeName> - day has been very cool.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-03-07" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-03-07">Tuesday, March 7th. 28 miles.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>The usual north wind has prevailed today - but in spite of it we are now lying nearly
          opposite <placeName ref="#Keneh">Keneh</placeName>, having been driven to the bank at 5
          o'clock, with our nose down stream. The wind is howling tonight - everything is banging
          and rattling. We are hoping our tug may come to meet us tomorrow.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-03-08" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-03-08">Ash-Wednesday, Mar. 8th.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>We laid at our place of last night, until a few minutes before 3 o'clock, our tug
          appeared - and soon we were swiftly and smoothly putting the miles behind us - until at 8
          o'clock, we had tied up at <placeName ref="#Nag_Hammadi">Nag Hamadi</placeName> - very
          cold - and high winds.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-03-09" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-03-09">Thursday, Mar. 9th. 51 miles.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>Passed the bridge at 8:30 and pulled up on the other side for mail, marketing etc. Got a
          huge mail bag of letters and papers - and were soon off - the tug is a powerful one, and
          we have come 51 miles since 9:30 - against this northern gale. It has been astounding to
          see the towns appear one after the other. First <placeName ref="Ballānah"
            >Balliana</placeName>, where were lying the <name type="boat" ref="#Sabiha"
            >Sabiha</name> with <persName ref="#Campbell_Dr #Campbell_Mrs">the
          Campbells</persName>, and the <name type="boat" ref="#Zenet-el-Nil">Zenet-el-Nil</name>
          with <persName ref="#Bird_Group">the Birds</persName> - we had only time to wave to them
          as we rushed by. Then came <placeName ref="#Jirjā">Girga</placeName> - and then <placeName
          ref="#Khārifat_al_Minshāh">Menshia</placeName> appeared as if by magic - then<pb n="85"/>
          we were upon <placeName ref="#Akhmīm">Akmim</placeName> - and about 5:30 pulled up at
          <placeName ref="#Sohag">Sohag</placeName>. The sky has been filled with clouds - no
          sunshine - and the exquisite little moon seen tonight for the first time. Passed the
          <name type="boat" ref="#Isis">Isis</name>, and the <name type="boat" ref="#Ammon_Ra">
          Ammon-Ra</name>, late in the afternoon.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-03-10" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-03-10">Friday, Mar. 10th. 73 miles.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>Started at 6:30 much of the time a high wind - and cold. The thermometer in my room was
          at 50 this morning - but the air most delicious - with a bright sun, and almost a winters
          crispness in the air. The tug went on the sand for a few minutes this morning. Made
            <placeName ref="#Assiout">Asy&#251;t</placeName> about 3 o'clock - having passed the
            <name type="boat" ref="#Bijou">Bijou</name> with <persName
            ref="#Smith_Mr #Smith_Mrs #Smith_Howard">the Smith family</persName> aboard this side
          of <placeName ref="#Abu_Tij">Aboutig</placeName>. Got our mail at <placeName
            ref="#Assiout">Asy&#251;t</placeName> - had an exciting time getting through the Weir.
          Heard that <persName ref="#Sayce_Archibald">Mr. Sayce</persName> left <placeName
            ref="#Assiout">Asy&#251;t</placeName> yesterday.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-03-11" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-03-11">Saturday, Mar. 11th. 88 miles.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>A cold north wind all day - tug was twice on the sand. We passed <persName
            ref="#Sayce_Archibald">Mr. Sayce</persName> just above <placeName ref="#Ar_Rawḍah"
            >Rada</placeName> - and pulled up at <placeName ref="#Al_Minya">Minia</placeName> at
          5:30 at the edge of the wide sand bank that lies in front of the town -which seems to make
          a general promenade, and playground for the town - many boys engaged in football.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-03-12" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-03-12">First Sunday in Lent, Mar. 12th. 64-1/2 miles.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p><placeName ref="#Fashen">Fashen.</placeName> We have had a difficult river in places
          today - and a crowd of gyassas, so that we had to<pb n="86"/> leave the tug, and the men
          rowed a short distance to <placeName ref="#Fashen">Fashen</placeName>. Were detained 3
          hours at <placeName ref="#Ash_Shaykh_Faḍl">Sheik Fadle</placeName>, the tug getting
          coal.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-03-13" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <placeName ref="#Wasta">Wasta</placeName> - <date when="1905-03-13">Monday, Mar. 13th. 37
            miles.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>We dismissed our tug as by agreement at <placeName ref="#Wasta">Wasta</placeName> - where
          we arrived at noon, and have had to wait, as the N. wind was so strong.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-03-14" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-03-14">Tuesday, Mar. 14. 30 miles.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>We started at 7 this morning - not being in a hurry now to reach <placeName ref="#Cairo"
            >Cairo</placeName>. It has been cool, but most delightful - the air having such a
          delicious quality, and we did so enjoy being without a tug.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-03-15" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-03-15">Wednesday, Mar. 15th. 11 miles.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>We pulled up here at <placeName ref="#Bedrashyn">Bedresheyn</placeName> at 6 o'clock -
          such a pretty resting place - with the splendid palms characteristic of this neighborhood
          above us across the sand. We stopped about a mile above <placeName ref="#Hulwan"
            >Helouan</placeName> on the opposite side for an hour to rest the men this afternoon,
          and had a charming walk through the fields and among the palms - and saw on the high road
          just beyond us, the carriages, omnibusses, automobiles, and other horrid evidences of
            civilization.<pb n="87"/></p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-03-16" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-03-16">Thursday, Mar. 16th.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>We have had the day at <placeName ref="#Ṣaqqâra">Sakara</placeName> - it was hot. About
          40 people lunching at <persName ref="#Mariette">Mariette</persName>'s house. I did not go
          to a single tomb - having gone only for the ride which is so beautiful until you reach the
          desert and even then, that great plateau of wavy, undulating, uncompromising desert, has
          its impressiveness - and always its splendid air. But those paths through those great palm
          forests, and the fertile fields is charming beyond description. But it was not coming home
          - the donkeys in my chair were miserable, tired to death poor things by the hard service
          of the winter - and the donkey boys vociferous and unpleasant, and I was glad to reach the
          comfort of the shaded deck, tea, and <name type="animal" ref="#Billy">Billy</name>'s
          affectionate greetings.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-03-17" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-03-17">Friday, Mar. 17. 15 miles.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p><placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName>. We reached here at 11:30 - got through the
          bridge in the usual exciting manner, and tied up in our old quarters beneath the <name
            type="hotel" ref="#Ghezireh_Palace_Hotel">Ghezireh Palace Hotel</name> at 3 o'clock.
          Very hot. <persName ref="#Weigall_Arthur">Weigall</persName> down from <name type="hotel"
            ref="#Luxor_Hotel">Luxor</name> for his exams - dined with us.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-03-18" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-03-18">Saturday, Mar. 18.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>Home all day. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName>, <persName
            ref="#Jones_Daniel">Jones</persName> and the men, carried by boat over to <placeName
            ref="#Boulaq_Museum">the museum</placeName> this morning the antiquities we brought down
          from <name type="hotel" ref="#Luxor_Hotel">Luxor</name>. I was glad to get rid of them.<pb
            n="88"/></p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-03-19" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-03-19">Second Sunday in Lent, Mar. 19.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p><persName ref="#Watson_Colonel #Watson_Mrs #Watson_Baby">Col. and Mrs. Watson and
            baby</persName> to tea this afternoon. <persName ref="#Bonham_Carter_Edward">Mr.
            Edgar</persName> came in and <persName ref="#Carter_Howard">Mr. Carter</persName> down
          from <placeName ref="#Ṭanṭā">Tanta</placeName> to dine and talk our affairs over with
            <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> - he looks wretched.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-03-20" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-03-20">Monday, Mar. 20.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>Wasted the morning in <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName>.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-03-21" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-03-21">Tuesday, Mar. 21.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>A cold disagreeable day - with gale - thunder and lightning. <persName
            ref="#Hooper_Mary_J #Hooper_Josephine_G #Hooper_Mabel">The 3 Hooper girls</persName>
          of <placeName ref="#Boston">Boston</placeName> dined with us - very nice people. To
            <placeName ref="#Boulaq_Museum">the Museum</placeName> this morning, to see the things
          from the tomb which are now pretty well unpacked. A whole, large room has been given them.
          The <name type="boat" ref="#Bijou">Bijou</name>, with <persName
            ref="#Smith_Mr #Smith_Mrs">the Smiths</persName> came down on Sunday, and is just ahead
          of us.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-03-22" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-03-22">Wednesday, Mar. 22.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p><persName ref="#Carter_Howard">Mr. Carter</persName> to lunch - we dined at the <name
            type="hotel" ref="#Ghezireh_Palace_Hotel">Hotel - (Ghezireh)</name> with the <persName
            ref="#Forbes-Leith_Admiral #Forbes-Leith_Mrs">Forbes-Leiths</persName> - several
          pleasant people.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-03-23" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-03-23">Thursday, Mar. 23rd.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>A really, cold day, with high wind - went to the <name type="hotel"
            ref="#Grand_Continental_Hotel">Continental Hotel</name> this afternoon to hear <persName
            ref="#Maspero_Gaston">M. Maspero</persName>, on "the Find" - a lecture for the benefit
          of the <orgName ref="#YMCA">Y.M.C.A.</orgName> of <placeName ref="#Cairo"
            >Cairo</placeName> - a crowded hall. Everyone showed much interest. It was difficult to
          hear him - as his voice was low, with the usual French monotonous manner.<pb n="89"/></p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-03-24" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-03-24">Friday, March 24th.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>At home and busy all the morning - <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName>
          engaged the <name type="boat" ref="#Nitseris">Nitseris</name> the other day to take us to
          the <placeName ref="#Al_Qanāţir_al_Khayrīyah">Barrage</placeName> this afternoon. We asked
            <persName ref="#Watson_Mr #Watson_Mrs">Mr. and Mrs. Watson</persName>, and the
            <persName ref="#Hooper_Mary_J #Hooper_Josephine_G #Hooper_Mabel">Hooper
            girls</persName>. We had never seen this <placeName ref="#Al_Qanāţir_al_Khayrīyah"
            >Barrage</placeName> and I have always wanted to see the river below <placeName
            ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName>, and so it was very interesting. It took us about an hour
          and a half - so that we didn't have any time for the <placeName
            ref="#Al_Qanāţir_al_Khayrīyah">Barrage</placeName>, and very little time for that
          beautiful garden - the best in Egypt. The whole thing was very un-Egyptian - the two
          barrages, one over the <placeName ref="#Dumyāţ_Far'">Damietta</placeName>, the other over
          the <placeName ref="#Rashī_Far'">Rosetta</placeName> branch - with their long line of
          arches and towers - with the land between made into this park-like garden. The whole
          effect was rather Venetian. Home by 7 o'clock - having had tea on the way back.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-03-25" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-03-25">Saturday, <choice>
              <sic>Nov.</sic>
              <corr>March</corr>
            </choice> 25.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>At <placeName ref="#Boulaq_Museum">the Museum</placeName> this morning - <persName
            ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> showed <persName ref="#Burn_Mrs">Mrs.
            Burn</persName> about - as she was not able to be with her mother and father, <persName
            ref="#Forbes-Leith_Admiral #Forbes-Leith_Mrs">Admiral and Mrs. Forbes Leith</persName>
          the other day, when they saw the things. She went from there to the train, as they all
          join their yacht at <placeName ref="#Alexandria">Alexandria</placeName>, and go for a
          Mediterranean tour to <placeName ref="#Holy_Land">the Holy Land</placeName>, <placeName
            ref="#Greece">Greece</placeName>, etc.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-03-26" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-03-26">3d Sunday in Lent, Mar. 26.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>Home all day - a worse Khamsin condition than yesterday. Ther. 86 in the shade, about 5
          o'clock we went for a drive towards the <placeName ref="#Pyramids">Pyramids</placeName> -
          very delightful. <persName ref="#Sandwith_Dr">Dr. Sandwith</persName> for dinner. He
          seemed tired and dull - without his old sparkle. He sails on Thursday for 2<pb n="90"/>
          months in <placeName ref="#United_States_of_America">America</placeName>.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-03-27" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-03-27">Monday, Mar. <choice><sic>28th</sic><corr>27th</corr></choice></date>
        </dateline>
        <p>This has been a busy day - in town in the morning - <persName ref="#Hardy_Jean"
            >Jean</persName> and <persName ref="#Wilson_Alice">Alice</persName> to the <persName
            ref="#Lindon_Smith_Joseph #Lindon_Smith_Corinna">Lindon-Smiths</persName> to lunch.
            <persName ref="#Newman_Mr #Newman_Mrs">Mr. and Mrs. Newman</persName> in the afternoon
          came in and after that we all went to <persName ref="#Morgan_Miss">Miss
          Morgan</persName>'s garden reception - which was charming - a delightful band playing and
          many people we knew. A quiet evening - our last on the boat.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-03-28" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-03-28">Tuesday, Mar. <choice><sic>29th</sic><corr>28th</corr></choice>.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>To <placeName ref="#Boulaq_Museum">the Museum</placeName> with <persName
            ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> - the room with the "find" is now open to
          the public. <persName ref="#Campbell_Dr #Campbell_Mrs">Dr. and Mrs. Campbell</persName>
          were there. They leave tomorrow on the <name type="boat" ref="#Roumanie">Roumanie</name>.
            <persName ref="#Morgan_Miss">Miss Morgan</persName> and <persName ref="#Sandwith_Dr">Dr.
            Sandwith</persName> also go on it. Left the boat for the Hotel and are now up at the
            <placeName ref="#Ghezireh_Palace_Hotel">Ghezireh Palace</placeName>.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-03-29" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-03-29">Wednesday, Mar. <choice><sic>30th</sic><corr>29th</corr></choice>.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p><persName ref="#Hardy_Jean">Jean</persName> and <persName ref="#Wilson_Alice"
            >Alice</persName> dined in town with <persName ref="#Peckitt_Reginald #Peckitt_Amelia">
            the <choice><sic>Pecketts</sic><corr>Peckitts</corr></choice></persName>
            this evening and <persName ref="#Lindon_Smith_Joseph">Joe Smith</persName> and <persName
            ref="#Lindon_Smith_Corinna">wife</persName> dined with us and we all went in to the
            concert at <name type="hotel" ref="#Shepheards_Hotel">Shepheards</name>.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-03-30" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-03-30">Thursday, Mar. <choice><sic>31st</sic><corr>30th</corr></choice>.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p><persName ref="#Wilson_Alice">Alice</persName> and I spent the morning at the Zoo. After
          the rain of last night the gardens were lovely. <persName ref="#Lacau_M">Monsieur<choice><sic>
            Lackau</sic><corr>Lacau</corr></choice></persName> dined with us.<pb n="91"/></p>
      </div>

      <!-- Olivia Myhre -->
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-04-01" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-04-01"><choice><sic>Friday, April 1st</sic><corr>Saturday, April 1st</corr></choice></date>. </dateline>
        <p>A last visit to the <placeName ref="#Boulaq_Museum">Museum</placeName> this morning and
          drove in town all of us at 3:30 to make some visits - in spite of the threatening skies.
          We stopped at the <placeName ref="#Ottoman_Bank">Ottoman Bank</placeName> a moment as we supposed -
          and a heavy rain began as <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> went in -
          in a moment or two it had so increased that we sat there in the closed carriage nearly an
          hour before <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> could come out. I never saw
          such a down pour - with constant thunder and lightening - as there is little or no
          drainage in <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName>, the streets soon became veritable
          rivers - and when we could start for home, it was like driving along the bed of a
          river.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-04-02" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-04-02"><choice><sic>Saturday, April 2d</sic><corr>Sunday, April 2nd</corr></choice></date>. </dateline>
        <p>To town this afternoon with many last things and visits to make - tea at <name
            type="hotel" ref="#Shepheards_Hotel">Shepheards</name> - <persName ref="#Carter_Howard"
            >Carter</persName> dined with us - we leave tomorrow.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-04-06" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <placeName ref="#Venice">Venice</placeName>. <date when="1905-04-06"><choice><sic>Thursday, April
            7th</sic><corr>Thursday, April 6th</corr></choice></date>. </dateline>
        <p>We left <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> on the morning of the 3rd at 11 o'clock
          - and reached <placeName ref="#Port_Said">Port Said</placeName> about 4 o'clock. <persName
            ref="#Carter_Howard">Mr. Carter</persName> came with us - we had to wait for the mail
          until the next day at 9 o'clock P.M. Had the most lovely crossing ever known - arriving at
            <placeName ref="#Brindisi">Brindisi</placeName> last evening, about 9 o'clock. It was
          midnight before we got off - reaching <placeName ref="#Bologna">Bologna</placeName> for
          tea, and <persName ref="#Acri">Acri</persName> by evening. we are now in our old rooms at
          the <name type="hotel" ref="#Britannia">Britannia</name>. The crossing was the very best
          we ever made.<pb n="92"/></p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-04-07" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-04-07">Friday, April 7th</date>. </dateline>
        <p>We went out this morning to <placeName ref="#Salvadores">Salvadores</placeName> and
            <placeName ref="#Barozzi">Barozzi</placeName>'s - then to the <placeName ref="San_Marco"
            >San Marco</placeName>. It is undergoing extensive repairs - some say that it will be
          necessary to renew the foundations - a large part of the nave is shut off. In the
          afternoon to <placeName ref="#Palazzo_Capello">Palazzo Capella</placeName> to see the
            <persName ref="#Benson_Mr #Benson_Mrs">Bensons</persName>. Found him very ill and suffering though he
          was sitting in his chair - very sad.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-04-08" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-04-08">Saturday, April 8th</date>. </dateline>
        <p>I went again this morning and stayed a long time with the <persName ref="#Benson_Mr #Benson_Mrs"
            >Bensons</persName>. Before coming home went into the garden - full of spring beauty
          and growth. It is sad to see the riant beauty of a garden, when those who cared for it,
          and loved it, are gone from it never to return.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-04-09" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-04-09">Sunday, 5th in Lent - April 9th</date>. </dateline>
        <p>To the <placeName ref="#Basilica_di_Santa_Maria_Gloriosa_dei_Frari">Frari</placeName>
          this morning which we found filled with scaffolding - were able to see the great <persName
            ref="#Mantegna_Andrea">Mantegna</persName>. Then I went to the <placeName
            ref="#Pallazo_Capello">Pallazo di Capello</placeName>. Poor <persName ref="#Benson_Mr"
            >Mr. Benson</persName> apparently very low - did not see him as he was in bed under the
          influence of opiates. Sat some time with <persName ref="#Benson_Mrs">Mrs.
            Benson</persName>. Cold weather and high winds. <persName ref="#Newberry_Percy">Mr.
            Newberry</persName> arrived today - to arrange with <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M"
            >Theodore</persName> about the "Find" publication, as he is going to write a description
          of the contents of the tomb. He is staying here with us. <persName ref="#Nash_Paul">Mr.
            Nash</persName> dined with us, and we dined in the big dining room which we never did
          before. The music was really delightful.<pb n="93"/></p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-04-10" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-04-10">Monday, April 10th</date>. </dateline>
        <p>To the <persName ref="#Benson_Mr #Benson_Mrs">Bensons</persName> this afternoon, and found him better.
          I went into his room, found him sitting up in bed, and looking brighter. It is sad that
          great hall and those great rooms with all their pretty things, and those two old people
          fading out of life!</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-04-11" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-04-11">Tuesday, April 11th</date>. </dateline>
        <p>At the <placeName ref="#Gallerie_dell_Accademia">Academia</placeName> and <placeName
            ref="#San_Marco">St. Marco</placeName> again. <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette"
            >Nettie</persName>, <persName ref="#Newberry_Percy">Newberry</persName>, <persName
            ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and I went to have tea with the <persName
            ref="#Johnson_Group">Johnsons</persName>. Their rambling, beautiful old place is in better
          order than it was last year - and in spite of the rain yesterday and that of last night,
          we walked about the garden, which was a fairy land of blossoming trees. <persName
            ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I stopped at the <placeName
            ref="#Palazzo_Capello">Palazzo Capello</placeName> on our way home. <persName
            ref="#Benson_Mr">Mr. Benson</persName> still better.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-04-12" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-04-12">Wednesday, April 12th</date>. </dateline>
        <p>Home this morning - <persName ref="#Newberry_Percy">Mr. Newberry</persName> and I went to
          say goodbye to the <persName ref="#Benson_Mr #Benson_Mrs">Bensons</persName>. Found him sitting up and
          quite bright. <persName ref="#Hohenloke_Prince">Prince Hohenloke</persName> came in and we
          left him there. <persName ref="#Nash_Paul">Mr. Nash</persName> dined with us.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-04-13" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-04-13">Thursday, April 13th</date>. </dateline>
        <p><persName ref="#Hardy_Jean">Jean</persName>, <persName ref="#Newberry_Percy">Mr.
            Newberry</persName>, <persName ref="#Wilson_Alice">Alice</persName> and I went to
            <placeName ref="#San_Marco">San Marco</placeName> this morning. <persName
            ref="#Johnston_Mr #Johnston_Mrs">Mr. and Mrs. Johnstone</persName> arrived just after breakfast to see
          the shawabti and photographs of the tomb. And we were all off at noon for <placeName
            ref="#Milan">Milan</placeName>. <persName ref="#Nash_Paul">Mr. Nash</persName> came to
          say goodbye.<pb n="94"/></p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-04-16" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <name type="hotel" ref="#Hotel_Cavour">Hotel Cavour</name> - <placeName ref="#Milan"
            >Milan</placeName>. <date when="1905-04-16">Palm Sunday, April 16th</date>. </dateline>
        <p>We had a perfectly charming ride over here on Thursday afternoon. The country so green
          and smiling - all the people working in their vineyards and fields - and above all the
          snowy peaks of the <placeName ref="#Alps">Alps</placeName>, and great masses of dark blue
          and white clouds about them. It was nice being in <placeName ref="#Milan"
            >Milan</placeName> again, and at this best of hotels, where we are so at home. We are in
          our old rooms; and found the pretty table ready in our sitting room, with the best dinner
          we have had in many a month. The next morning we all went to the <placeName ref="#Brera"
            >Brera</placeName>, and after lunch <persName ref="#Newberry_Percy">Newberry</persName>
          went off and <persName ref="#Cigala_Enrique_Martini_di">Cigala</persName> arrived from
            <placeName ref="#Turin">Turin</placeName>. Yesterday morning we spent at the <placeName
            ref="#Museo_Poldi_Pezzoli">Paldo-Pezzoli</placeName>. It was good to see our old
          favourites again. In the afternoon <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName>,
            <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName>, <persName
            ref="#Cigala_Enrique_Martini_di">Cigala</persName> and I went to the <placeName
            ref="#Castello_Sforzesco">Castello</placeName>, which they have been much restoring
          these past 2 years. It is quite a wonderful place, as building - old fortress, castle etc.
          They are rebuilding and restoring on exactly the old lines. A store of beautiful things to
          see, especially the recumbent figure of <persName ref="#Gaston_de_Foix"><choice><sic>Caston
          </sic><corr>Gaston</corr></choice> le
            Foix</persName> on his tomb by <persName ref="#Agostino_Busti">Bambaja</persName>. Today
          we went to <placeName ref="#Bergamo">Bergamo</placeName>, in spite of the threatening
          weather. We took 2 hours going, and the same time coming back, in a veritable omnibus
          train. We took our lunch with us, and ate it immediately on our arrival just outside the
          station, under a little arbour covered by Wistaria vines just coming into bloom. Then we
          went to the <orgName ref="#Motalli_Gallery">Motalli gallery</orgName> and while there the
          storm began. It was impossible to get up to the hill town - and we drove back to the
          station in a pouring rain, reaching home with thankful hearts in time for tea. The first
          night of our arrival we went to "<placeName ref="#Teatro_alla_Scala">La Scala</placeName>"
          to hear<pb n="95"/>
          <name type="event" ref="#Don_Pasquale">Don Pasquale</name> given. We had one of the best loges in the house
          - the orchestra was immense - the scenery wonderful - but what a performance to call
          musical - and how strange to discover that so many people live who can take Italian Opera
          seriously! <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> and I went to the back of the
          box, piled the cushions behind us - and I took a quiet nap. It was 12 o'clock when the
          ballet began, and as the girls were wild to see it, <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M"
            >Theo</persName> and I came home, and sent the carriage back for them. The next night
          they all went again - but I declined and stayed at home.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-04-17" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-04-17">Monday, April 17th</date>. </dateline>
        <p>Morning at <placeName ref="#Biblioteca_Ambrosiana">Ambrosiana</placeName> and <placeName
            ref="#Brera">Brera</placeName>. While we were at breakfast this morning <persName
            ref="#Jones_Harold">Jones</persName> brought the news, that the railway strike which has
          been talked of for some time had been declared this morning - and that for the present no
          R.R. tickets would be sold. But this evening the accounts are more encouraging and we hope
          to get off tomorrow morning, <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> and
            <persName ref="#Wilson_Alice">Alice</persName> for <placeName ref="#Dresden"
            >Dresden</placeName> - the rest for <placeName ref="#Florence">Florence</placeName>.
          Walked in the Park with <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName>.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-04-18" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-04-18">Tuesday, April 18th</date>. </dateline>
        <p><persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> and <persName ref="#Wilson_Alice"
            >Alice</persName> got off this morning - not knowing if they could get through or not,
          but I had a telegram from him at <placeName ref="#Verona">Verona</placeName> this
          afternoon, saying they were all right. They breakfasted at 6:30 - and I came in to have a
          cup of coffee with them - and just then received a telegram from the <name type="hotel"
            ref="#Hotel_Royal_Grande_Bretagne">Grande Bretagne</name>, <placeName ref="#Florence"
            >Florence</placeName>, saying "impossible to give rooms until Thursday". Greatly
          disappointed - but have since heard that<pb n="96"/> no train for <placeName
            ref="#Florence">Florence</placeName> had gone out. They are making a great effort to
          send the through trains - the station and even some parts of the roads are guarded by
          soldiers. <persName ref="#Cigala_Enrique_Martini_di">Cigala</persName> made 3 attempts
          today to get back to <placeName ref="#Turin">Turin</placeName> - saying goodbye soon after
          breakfast - found no train going - came back for lunch - said goodbye again - returned
          again, went to drive with us, and had tea, and then made his final adieux. We spent most
          of the morning in the charming little park near here.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-04-19" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-04-19">Wednesday, April 19th</date>. </dateline>
        <p>The day has been cold and stormy - <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName>
          and <persName ref="#Hardy_Jean">Jean</persName> spent the morning in the <placeName
            ref="#Brera">Brera</placeName>. We hope to get off tomorrow. But are most snug and
          comfortable at this best of hotels. Several people have arrived in automobiles, not being
          able to get through by rail. <placeName ref="#Milan">Milan</placeName> is such a hot bed
          for anarchism, that I would as soon not be in it at this time.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-04-21" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <name type="hotel" ref="#Hotel_Royal_Grande_Bretagne">Hotel Grande Bretagne</name> -
            <placeName ref="#Florence">Florence</placeName>. <date when="1905-04-21">Good Friday,
            April 21st</date>. </dateline>
        <p>We made a successful journey yesterday from <placeName ref="#Milan">Milan</placeName> -
          we had a guard of soldiers on our train, there were soldiers in the stations, at the
          cross-roads, in control of the sentry boxes, switches, tunnels, etc. so that we probably
          made the safest journey of our lives. The strike is about over - it was never one of wages
          - but aimed against railway reforms, which the Gov. is instituting - and the Gov. has met
          the strikers with such prompt measures, that it has collapsed. The rain poured all day -
          we were an hour and a half late - and found my<pb n="97"/> poor, dear <persName ref="#Buttles_Mary">Mary</persName> had been waiting nearly two hours. We found our rooms ready - as familiar as possible - <persName ref="#Fletcher_Julia_Constance">Julia</persName> and <persName ref="#Hagemeyer_Francisca_de_la_Escosura">Francis</persName> in attendance - and we have spent most of the day with <persName ref="#Buttles_Lizzie">Lizzie</persName> and <persName ref="#Hardy_Jean #Wilson_Alice">the girls</persName> at the <placeName ref="#Villino">Villino</placeName>. Everything seems very quiet in <placeName ref="#Florence">Florence</placeName>, as no church bells, one of the characteristic features of <placeName ref="#Florence">Florence</placeName>, are rung during Passion week.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-04-22" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-04-22">Saturday, April 22d</date>. </dateline>
        <p>A pleasant day - <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> took <persName
            ref="#Hardy_Jean">Jean</persName> to the <placeName ref="#Duomo_di_Firenze"
            >Duomo</placeName> this morning to see the ridiculous ceremony of the "scoppic" -while
            <persName ref="#Buttles_Mary">Mary</persName> and I had a charming ride and visit in the
            <placeName ref="#Parco_delle_Cascine">Cascine</placeName>. They all lunched here, and we
          went to tea with the <persName ref="#Hagemeyer_Group">Hagemeyers</persName>, in their new
          appartment and saw the new baby. <persName ref="#Buttles_Mary">Mary</persName> came back
          to dinner. In the evening I went to <persName ref="#Bend_Mrs">Mrs. Bend's</persName>
          sitting room, just above ours, to see her and <persName ref="#Bend_Beatrice"
            >Beatrice</persName>.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-04-23" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-04-23">Easter Sunday, April 23rd</date>. </dateline>
        <p>Lunched with <persName ref="#Buttles_Lizzie">Lizzie</persName> today as it was her
          birthday - and stayed the day with her.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-04-24" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-04-24">Monday, April 24th</date>. </dateline>
        <p><persName ref="#Buttles_Lizzie">Lizzie</persName> and <persName
            ref="#Hardy_Jean #Wilson_Alice">the girls</persName> to lunch - <persName
            ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I, taking <persName ref="#Amelie"
            >Amelie</persName>, went to the <placeName ref="#Museo_Nazionale_del_Bargello"
            >Bargello</placeName>. <persName ref="#Bend_Mrs">Mrs. Bend</persName>, <persName
            ref="#Bend_Beatrice">Beatrice</persName> and <persName ref="#Whitney_Pauline">Miss
            Whitney</persName> spent the evening with us.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-04-25" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-04-25">Tuesday, April 25</date>. </dateline>
        <p>Bank, shopping and visiting. <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> to
          lunch. Home with her for tea.<pb n="98"/></p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-04-26" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-04-26">Wednesday, April 26th</date>. </dateline>
        <p><persName ref="#Hardy_Jean">Jean</persName> and I with <persName ref="#Amelie"
            >Amelie</persName> drove up to the <placeName ref="#Giardino_delle_Rose">Rose
            Garden</placeName> - and came home laden with roses - most of which I carried up to the
            <placeName ref="#Villino">Villino</placeName> where we stayed all day. The <persName
            ref="#Bend_Group">Bends</persName> and <persName ref="#Whiting_Pauline">Miss
            Whiting</persName> again in the evening. They go off to-morrow to <placeName
            ref="#Ravenna">Ravenna</placeName> and <placeName ref="#Venice">Venice</placeName>.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-04-27" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-04-27">Thursday, April 27th</date>. </dateline>
        <p>At home this morning - <persName ref="#Buttles_Lizzie">Lizzie</persName> and <persName
            ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> came to lunch, and we went for tea to the
            <persName ref="#Newman_Group">Newmans</persName> - a charming visit to a perfectly charming
          and artistic home - stayed disgracefully late.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-04-28" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-04-28">Friday, April 28th</date>. </dateline>
        <p><persName ref="#Hardy_Jean">Jean</persName> and I drove out to <name type="historical"
            ref="#Villa_I_Tatti">I Tatti</name> this morning to lunch - the day was warm and
          wholly charming - and the world most beautiful. <persName ref="#Berenson_Bernard"
            >Berensen</persName> looks better than he has done for 3 years. His nice sister
            <persName ref="#Abbott_Senda_Berenson">Senda</persName> was there, looking ill and worn.
          We sat out under the cypresses and had coffee and talked, until it was time to drive home.
          In the evening we dined at the <placeName ref="#Villino">Villino</placeName>. <persName
            ref="#Cust_Mr">Mr. Cust</persName> and <persName ref="#Burton_Harry">Mr.
            Burton</persName> were there - and a beautiful little dinner. <persName
            ref="#Buttles_Mary">Mary</persName> able to be up - but looking a bit tired.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-04-29" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-04-29">Saturday April 29th</date>. </dateline>
        <p>Home all the morning writing letters. <persName ref="#Hardy_Jean">Jean</persName> and
            <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> shopped a little and drove up to
            <placeName ref="#San_Miniato">San Miniato</placeName>. All went to a pretty and
          elaborate tea at <placeName ref="#Bennett_Miss">Miss Bennetto</placeName>.<pb n="99"/></p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-04-30" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-04-30">Sunday, April 30th</date>. </dateline>
        <p>I have been the whole day with <persName ref="#Buttles_Mary">Mary</persName> at the
            <placeName ref="#Villino">Villino</placeName>. She is much better. <persName
            ref="#Hardy_Jean">Jean</persName> and I called on <persName ref="#Hagemeyer_Francis_de_la_Escosura">Mrs.
            Hagemeyer</persName> on our way home. Lovely weather.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-05-01" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-05-01"><choice><sic>>Monday, April 31st</sic><corr>Monday, May 1st</corr></choice</date>. </dateline>
        <p><persName ref="#Buttles_Mary">Mary</persName> and I did some shoppings this morning - and
          all the family came to lunch and stayed to tea.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-05-02" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-05-02"><choice><sic>Tuesday, May 1st</sic><corr>Tuesday, May 2nd</corr></choice></date>. </dateline>
        <p>I and <persName ref="#Hardy_Jean #Wilson_Alice">the girls</persName> drove about this
          morning - went at <placeName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</placeName>'s request to
            <orgName ref="#Constantini">Costantini</orgName>'s to see <persName
            ref="#Constantini_David">David C</persName> about <placeName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M"
            >Theo</placeName>'s pictures. The place greatly improved and very pretty. <persName
            ref="#Buttles_Lizzie">Lizzie</persName> and <persName ref="#Hardy_Jean #Wilson_Alice"
            >the girls</persName> to lunch and we all went to <persName ref="#Cust_Mr">Mr.
            Custs</persName> to tea - and bravely climbed his 97 steps to his interesting
          appartment, and had an amusing and pleasant visit.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-05-03" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-05-03"><choice><sic>Wednesday, May 2d</sic><corr>Wednesday, May 3rd</corr></choice></date>. </dateline>
        <p>A busy morning - <persName ref="#Buttles_Lizzie">Lizzie</persName> gave us a charming tea
          with several pleasant friends - we spent the whole day there - and the little <placeName
            ref="#Villino">villino</placeName> looked so pleasant - the sunny rooms, and tiny garden
          - and <name type="animal" ref="#Rex">Rex</name> and his antics. I am so pleased that they
          have taken a cottage at <placeName ref="#Vallambrosa">Vallambrosa</placeName> for the
          summer and will go up the 1st of June with <name type="animal" ref="#Rex">Rex</name> and
          the two maids and have their own home. <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName>
          and <persName ref="#Buttles_Mary">Mary</persName> came home with us, as <persName
            ref="#Cust_Mr">Mr. Cust</persName> and <persName ref="#Burton_Harry">Harry
            Burton</persName> were coming to dine. <persName ref="#Burton_Harry">Harry</persName>
          brought his beautiful photographs to show us - and we had a nice and merry evening.<pb
            n="100"/></p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-05-04" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-05-04"><choice><sic>Thursday, May 3rd</sic><corr>Thursday, May 4th</corr></choice></date>. </dateline>
        <p>I had a letter from <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> this morning
          saying we would find him in <placeName ref="#Paris">Paris</placeName> when we arrived. We
          all went to the <placeName ref="#Gallerie_dell_Accademia">Academia</placeName> this
          morning - then to the <placeName ref="#Giardino_delle_Rose">Rose garden</placeName> - and
          brought home some lovely roses. <persName ref="#Newman_Mr #Newman_Mrs">Mr. and Mrs.
            Newman</persName> and <persName ref="#Buttles_Lizzie">Lizzie</persName> to lunch, and
            <persName ref="#Hardy_Jean #Wilson_Alice">the girls</persName> as well as <persName
            ref="#Smith_Harold">Harold Smith</persName> and <persName ref="#Ream_Robert_Clarke">Bob
            Ream</persName> came to tea. Threatening weather.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-05-08" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <placeName ref="#Paris">Paris</placeName> - <name type="hotel" ref="#Hotel_Westminster"
            >Hotel Westminster</name>. <date when="1905-05-08">Monday, May 8th</date>. </dateline>
        <p>Our last 2 days in <placeName ref="#Florence">Florence</placeName> were very busy - <persName ref="#Hardy_Jean #Wilson_Alice">the girls</persName> came early - <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I went to the <placeName ref="#Uffizi_Gallery">Uffizzi</placeName>, and I saw my favourites - and two charming recent acquisitions "<objectName ref="#Adoration_of_the_Magi">Madonna adoring the Infant Christ</objectName>" ascribed to <persName ref="#Lippi_Filippino">Filippino Lippi</persName> - which seems to suggest more the manner of both <persName ref="#Botticelli_Sandro">Botticelli</persName> and <persName ref="#Lippi_Fra_Filippo">Fra Lippo Lippi</persName> - and a rare picture by the Umbrian master, <persName ref="#Caporali_Bartolomeo">B. Caporali</persName>, <objectName ref="#Virgin_and_Child_Enthroned">a Holy Family</objectName> - with background in gold, and lovely colouring and expression. The new Director <persName ref="#Ricci_Corrado">Ricci</persName>, who has done such good work in <placeName ref="#Milan">Milan</placeName> and other cities in reorganizing and rearranging the picture galleries, is now engaged in evolving order and sequence into the long neglected <placeName ref="#Uffizi_Gallery">Uffizi</placeName> - and it already shows marked improvement. We walked about the corridors, and looked at the views from those lofty windows, as well as the pictures, and went out on the great roof of the <placeName ref="#Loggia_dei_Lanzi">Loggia dei Longi</placeName>, which is going to be made into a kind of roof garden. We found ourselves almost on a level with the <placeName ref="#Palazzo_Vecchio">Palazzo Vecchio</placeName> tower, and just under it. Then we walked through the gallery to the <placeName ref="#Palazzo_Pitti">Pitti</placeName>, and so home. In the afternoon <persName ref="#Smith_Harold">Smith</persName> and <persName ref="#Ream_Robert_Clarke">Ream</persName> came to the <name type="hotel" ref="#Hotel_Westminster">Hotel</name>, and we all<pb n="101"/> drove to the <placeName ref="#Villino">Villino</placeName> for tea. <persName ref="#Hardy_Jean">Jean</persName> and I stayed to dinner - and we hated to come away and say goodbye to the sweet little house. Saturday dawned cold and stormy - we had the carriage and <persName ref="#Buttles_Mary">Mary</persName> went with me to the bank - and to the English Bakery to get some things for our tea basket on the train. <persName ref="#Buttles_Lizzie">Lizzie</persName> and <persName ref="#Hardy_Jean #Wilson_Alice">the girls</persName> to lunch - and the latter went in the omnibus with us to the station. <persName ref="#Burton_Harry">Harry Surton</persName> came also. We had a very comfortable journey here - two compartments in the train-de-luxe - one <persName ref="#Hardy_Jean">Jean</persName> and <persName ref="#Amelie">Amelie</persName> occupied - and the other I had to myself, a connecting door made them pleasant. I did not pull down the blinds of my windows - so that the dawn wakened me - and I piled my pillows and sat up in bed to see the dawn come upon the snow covered peaks - a lovely scenery all day - until as we drew near <placeName ref="#Paris">Paris</placeName> the rain began - and was pouring when we arrived. Found <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> installed in our old quarters, with a bright fire - and after dinner we sat talking late. Today has been cold, cloudy and damp. We have been busy - as we have only 5 days here.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-05-13" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-05-13">Saturday, May 13th</date>. </dateline>
        <p>We are quite ready to go over to <placeName ref="#London">London</placeName> tomorrow. it
          has been rather nice here - not too much shopping and dressmaking. We have seen a good
          deal of <persName ref="#Johnson_Cecile_Davis_de_Lagarde">Cecile de Lagarde</persName> - we
          had hoped to take her home with us, but her father is obdurate - but she is going over to
            <placeName ref="#London">London</placeName> with us.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-05-18" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-05-18">Thursday, May 18th</date>. </dateline>
        <!--col. watson?-->
        <p>Our journey over from <placeName ref="#Paris">Paris</placeName> the other day was a
          really pleasant<pb n="102"/> one. <persName ref="#Busk_Daisy">Daisy Busk</persName> came
          with us. They sail on the 20th. The weather was good - the channel boat "<name type="boat"
            ref="#le_Nord">Le Nord</name>" was big and comfortable. The 3 girls stayed on deck and
          enjoyed it. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> and I took possession of the
          cabin de luxe, he took one sofa and I the other and slept all the way over. We had an
          enormous number of passengers, as the <placeName ref="#Brindisi">Brindisi</placeName>
          train was just in, and such an amount of luggage, that we were 2 hours late leaving
            <placeName ref="#Dover">Dover</placeName>. It was nice to be in <placeName
            ref="#England">England</placeName> once more. We reached our hotel of last year, <name
            type="hotel" ref="#Buckland_Manor_Hotel">Bucklands</name>, in time for dinner which was
          served in our large pleasant sitting room. <persName ref="#Fielding_Everard">Everard
            Fielding</persName> came in the evening, as pleasant as ever, and looking very well.
          Monday the racket began. <persName ref="#Hardy_Jean #Wilson_Alice">the girls</persName>
          and I went to <persName ref="#Nicolls">Nicolls</persName>, and ordered our tailor gowns.
          In the afternoon we all went to the wonderful <placeName ref="#Wallace_Collection">Wallace
            Collection</placeName>, and came home really tired. <persName ref="#Newberry_Percy">Mr.
            Newberry</persName> dined with us and we had a nice evening. We find <persName
            ref="#Carter_Howard">Mr. Carter</persName> has gone out to <persName ref="#Egypt"
            >Egypt</persName>, and <persName ref="#Newberry_Percy">Newberry</persName> goes himself
          in June. Tuesday we spent the whole of the morning at the <placeName
            ref="#South_Kensington_Museum">South Kensington Museum</placeName> - and came home more
          dead than alive. Poor <persName ref="#Hardy_Jean">Jean</persName> had such a headache that
          she had to take to her bed, where she stayed. Such a disappointment too, as <persName
            ref="#Fielding_Everard">Fielding</persName> was dining here, and we were going to the
            <placeName ref="#Royal_Court_Theater">Court Theatre</placeName> to hear one of <persName
            ref="#Shaw_George_Bernard">Bernard Shaw</persName>'s plays - <name type="event" ref="#John_Bulls_Other_Island">John Bulls other Island</name>".
          It was admirably done, and very amusing. Wednesday <persName ref="#Hardy_Jean"
            >Jean</persName> was all right again - we were driving all the morning - very bright
          weather, but cold, gusty winds.<persName ref="#Newberry_Percy">Mr. Newberry</persName>
          came to lunch, and after <persName ref="#Rathbone_Mr">Mr. Rathbone</persName>, bringing me
          most lovely roses. In, all the afternoon. Today we have been shopping and driving, lunched
          with <persName ref="#Farrer_William_Sir">Sir William Farrer</persName> - he looking so
          well - and so bright<pb n="103"/> and charming - but grown quite deaf. <persName
            ref="#Watson_Colonel">Col. Watson</persName> was there. <persName ref="#Farrer_Gaspard"
            >Gaspard Farrer</persName> dined with us - also <persName ref="#Cary_Elwes_Gervase">Mr.
            Cary-Elwes</persName> and <persName ref="#Cary_Elwes_Winifred_Lady">Lady
            Winifred</persName> - who took <persName ref="#Hardy_Jean">Jean</persName> and <persName
            ref="#Johnson_Cecile_Davis_de_Lagarde">C&#233;cile</persName> on to a concert at a
          private house.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-05-19" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-05-19">Friday, May. 19</date>. </dateline>
        <p>At home all the morning. We all went to the <orgName ref="#Royal_Court_Theater">Court
            Theatre</orgName> again to the Matin&#233;e of "<name type="event" ref="#You_Can_Never_Tell">You never can Tell</name>" by <persName
            ref="#Shaw_George_Bernard">Bernard Shaw</persName>. <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette"
            >Nettie</persName> and I heard it there three years ago - an amusing, charming play. Not
          so strong in character representation as "<name type="event" ref="#John_Bulls_Other_Island">John Bulls other Island</name>". <persName
            ref="#Watson_Major">Major</persName>, and <persName ref="#Wilson_Mrs">Mrs.
            Wilson</persName> made us a visit this evening. She sails tomorrow for <placeName
            ref="#United_States_of_America">America</placeName>.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-05-20" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-05-20">Saturday, May. 20</date>. </dateline>
        <p>A cold rainy day. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> and <persName
            ref="#Johnson_Cecile_Davis_de_Lagarde">C&#233;cile</persName> went to the <placeName
            ref="#British_Museum">British Museum</placeName> and <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M"
            >Theo</persName> came home pale and weary. <persName ref="#Fielding_Everard"
            >Fielding</persName> came at 3:30 - then he and <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M"
            >Theo</persName> went out and <persName ref="#Hardy_Jean #Wilson_Alice">the
            girls</persName> and I for a drive in the Park - the rain having stopped. But we found a
          cold, high wind. Soon after we got home, and were comforting ourselves with hot tea,
            <persName ref="#Rathbone_Mr">Mr. Rathbone</persName> called, and made one of his
          charming visits. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> brought <persName
            ref="#Fielding_Everard">Fielding</persName> back to dinner, and they are now looking at
          the Egyptian photos.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-05-21" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-05-21">Sunday, 4th After Easter</date>. </dateline>
        <p>I went to the <orgName ref="#First_Church_of_Christian_Science">First Church of Christian
            Science</orgName> this morning in <placeName ref="#Sloane_Terrace"><choice>
              <sic>Sloam</sic>
              <corr>Sloane</corr>
            </choice> Terrace</placeName> and found the same large reverent congregation that I
          found there last year. it is really bitterly cold today. <persName ref="#Fielding_Everard"
            >Mr. Field- <pb n="104"/> ing</persName> came back with <persName
            ref="#Hardy_Jean #Wilson_Alice">the girls</persName> from the <orgName ref="#Roman_Catholic">R.
            Catholic</orgName> and stayed to lunch. He took <persName
            ref="#Johnson_Cecile_Davis_de_Lagarde">C&#233;cile</persName> to a concert at <placeName
            ref="#Queens_Hall">Queen's Hall</placeName> this afternoon, and both of <persName
            ref="#Hardy_Jean #Wilson_Alice">the girls</persName> to the first performance of
            <persName ref="#Shaw_George_Bernard">Bernhard Shaw</persName>'s play at the <orgName
            ref="#Royal_Court_Theater">Court Theatre</orgName>, "<name type="event" ref="#Man_and_Superman">Man and Superman</name>". I went to see
            <persName ref="#Farrer_Miss">Miss Farrer</persName> this afternoon - such a pleasant
          visit, - the old fashioned rooms looking so bright this cold day, with bright fires and
          lovely flowers.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-05-22" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-05-22">Monday, May 22nd</date>. </dateline>
        <p>Shopping and <placeName ref="#National_Gallery">National Gallery</placeName> this morning
          - driving in afternoon, and dined with the <persName ref="#Rathbone_Mr #Rathbone_Mrs #Rathbone_Elena"
            >Rathbones</persName> this evening - and are just home - 1:30 A.M. Every one else is
          gone to bed - where I ought to be. A charming dinner - I sat between <persName
            ref="#Rathbone_Mr">Mr. Rathbone</persName> and <persName ref="#Landon_Perceval">Percival
            Landon</persName>-- who was the special correspondent of the <bibl><title>"Times"</title></bibl> with the young
          husband expedition to <placeName ref="#Tibet">Thibet</placeName>. There were also "<persName ref="#Grainger_Percy">Percy
            <choice><sic>Granger</sic><corr>Grainger</corr></choice></persName>" a clever rising musical pianist and two lesser lights - and they
          gave us some lovely music after dinner. He has the most extraordinary facility with the
          piano, and makes most novel and unheard of harmonies. <persName
            ref="#de_Trafford_Agnes_Mary_Pia_Fielding_Lady">Lady Agnes de Trafford</persName> came
          in during the evening, and about 11:30 <persName ref="#Cary_Elwes_Winifred_Lady">Lady
            Winifred</persName> and <persName ref="#Elwes_Cary_Gervase">Mr. Cary Elwes</persName>
          arrived, and he sang two or three delightful songs. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M"
            >Theodore</persName> was quite scandalized with our late hours.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-05-23" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-05-23">Tuesday, May 23</date>.
        </dateline>
        <p><persName ref="#Cary_Elwes_Winifred_Lady">Lady Winnie</persName> came to take <persName
            ref="#Hardy_Jean #Wilson_Alice">the girls</persName> to the <placeName
            ref="#National_Portrait_Gallery">National Portrait Gallery</placeName>. In the afternoon
          we went down to <persName ref="#Sargent_John_Singer">Sargents</persName>
          <placeName ref="#John_Sargents_Studio">Studio</placeName> and had tea with him and were so
          interested in him and his belongings. A sincere,<pb n="105"/> simple, and unaffected man -
          with no aim at artistic fittings in his studio. <persName ref="#Rathbone_Mr Rathbone_Mrs">Mr. and Mrs.
            Rathbone</persName> were there. This evening we have had an entrancing evening at
            <placeName ref="#Theater_Royal_Drury_Lane">Drury Lane Theatre</placeName> - <persName
            ref="#Irving_Henry">Irving</persName> as Shylock, and the
          captivating <persName ref="#Matthison_Edith_Wynne">Mrs. Mathewson</persName> as Portia. A wonderful performance
          - the setting so fine and perfect - <persName ref="#Irving_Henry">Irving</persName> looks
          very old - and received a real ovation. The theatre was bitterly cold - all the men wore
          overcoats - and the women wraps - and we wished for hot water bottles and blankets.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-05-24" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-05-24">Wednesday, May 24</date>. </dateline>
        <p>A very busy day - <persName ref="#Trefusis_Robert">Robert Trefusis</persName> came up
          from <placeName ref="#Eton_College">Eton</placeName> and spent most of the day here.
            <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> and I got a quiet hour at the
            <placeName ref="#National_Gallery">Nat. Gallery</placeName>, <persName
            ref="#Rathbone_Mr">Mr. Rathbone</persName> and <persName ref="#Newberry_Percy"
            >Newberry</persName> to lunch and to tea as well - and this evening we had a rational,
          charming dinner at the <placeName ref="#Ingleborough_Estate">Farrer boys house</placeName>.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-05-25" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-05-25">Thursday, May 25</date>.
        </dateline>
        <p>Out all the morning - <persName ref="#Hardy_Jean #Wilson_Alice">the girls</persName> went off at 12 o'clock with <persName ref="#Rathbone_Mr">Mr. Rathbone</persName> to see Knole- <persName ref="#Rathbone_Elena">Elena Rathbone</persName> came to lunch - <persName ref="#Trotti_Count">Count Trotti</persName> was also here - directly after lunch I took <persName ref="#Amelie">Amelie</persName> and went out to <placeName ref="#Guildford">Guildford</placeName> to see <persName ref="#Upton_Mr">Mr. Upton</persName> of the <placeName ref="#Guildford_Hardy_Plant_Nursery">Hardy Plant Nursery</placeName> - and enjoyed myself. A quiet evening at home.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-05-26" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-05-26">Friday, May 26</date>. </dateline>
        <p>We went out to <placeName ref="#Oxford">Oxford</placeName> today, taking <persName ref="#Rathbone_Mr">Mr. Rathbone</persName> with us, and lunched at <placeName ref="#Queens_Hall">Queens</placeName> with <persName ref="#Sayce_Archibald">Mr. Sayce</persName>. We saw <placeName ref="#Magdalen_College">Magdalene</placeName>, <placeName ref="#Christ_College">Christ</placeName>, <placeName ref="#New_College">New <pb n="106"/> College</placeName> and <placeName ref="#St_Johns_College">St. Johns</placeName> - and went down to the river in the afternoon to see the races. It was such a pretty sight - the day was so warm - the country so lovely - the Thorns all in bloom as well as the chestnuts. We went to the <placeName ref="#Balliol_Barge">Baliel barge</placeName> to see the boats - and had tea there - then back to <placeName ref="#Magdalen_College">Magdalen</placeName> to hear the Service of Song, but were just one minute and a half too late, as we found the door of the chapel obdurately closed; so we went back to the <name type="hotel" ref="#Randolph_Hotel">Randolph</name> and stayed until it was train time. We had a saloon carriage going and coming, and had dinner baskets for coming home - as we were not due until 9 o'clock. <persName ref="#Rhys_John_Sir">Principal Rhys</persName> and his <persName ref="#Rhys_Elspeth_Hughes_Davies">wife</persName>, and a nice fellow <persName ref="#Hodgson_Richard">Mr. Hodgson</persName> were at the lunch.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-05-27" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-05-27">Saturday, May 27</date>. </dateline>
        <p>Shopping this morning - <persName ref="#Hardy_Jean">Jean</persName> went with <persName
            ref="#Fielding_Everard">Mr. Fielding</persName> at 12, on the river for a row. <persName
            ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName>, <persName
            ref="#Johnson_Cecile_Davis_de_Lagarde">Cecile</persName> and I drove out to <placeName
            ref="#Wimbledon_Common">Weinbledon Common</placeName> to take tea with <persName
            ref="#Preece_William_Henry_Sir">Sir William Preece</persName> and his daughters. After
          getting beyond <placeName ref="#Putney">Putney</placeName> we came to the <placeName
            ref="#Wimbledon_Common">Common</placeName> which I had never seen. It lies so high and
          is so big, that the air was delightful - coming over miles of heather and gorse. <persName
            ref="#Preece_William_Henry_Sir">Sir William</persName> has a charming old fashioned
          house, with room after room looking on the garden - and the house filled with rare Persian
          things - arms, stuffs, tiles etc. The greater part of his collection is at <placeName
            ref="#South_Kensington_Museum">South Kensington</placeName>. Met some pleasant people -
          lovely drive home. <persName ref="#Fielding_Everard">Fielding</persName> came in late this
          evening.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-05-28" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-05-28">Sunday, May 28</date>.
        </dateline>
        <!--second christian science church-->
        <p><persName ref="#Johnson_Cecile_Davis_de_Lagarde">Cecile</persName> and I went for a drive in the Park before I went to<pb n="107"/> church - which was held in the <placeName ref="#Aeolian_Hall">Aeolian Hall</placeName>, <placeName ref="#Bond_Street">Bond St</placeName>. One of the prettiest and simplest concert halls I ever saw - and a very large congregation of the best class. This is the <orgName>Second Christian Science Church</orgName>. <persName ref="#Fielding_Everard">Everard Fielding</persName> came to lunch after which we took <persName ref="#Hardy_Jean #Wilson_Alice">the girls</persName> to <placeName ref="#Kew">Kew</placeName>, and <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> and I drove first to call on <persName ref="#Sandwith_Mrs">Mrs. Sandwith</persName>, whom we found at home looking very well and pretty. Then to <persName ref="#Luling_Elena_W">Miss Lulling</persName> - and then about <placeName ref="#Regents_Park">Regent Park</placeName>. After we got home, <persName ref="#Farrer_Gaspard">Gaspard</persName> and <persName ref="#Farrer_Harry">Harry Farrer</persName> called. <persName ref="#Fielding_Everard">Fielding</persName> again to dinner, and he and <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> are now playing chess.</p>
      </div>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
