<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>Diary of Mrs. Emma B. Andrews. Volume 18 1911-1912</title>
        <author>
          <persName ref="#Andrews_Emma_B">Emma B. Andrews</persName>
        </author>
        <editor>
          <persName ref="#SK">Sarah Ketchley</persName>
        </editor>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>
          <orgName ref="#Emma_B_Andrews_Diary_Project">Emma B. Andrews Diary Project</orgName>
        </publisher>
        <address>
          <addrLine>University of Washington, Seattle, WA</addrLine>
        </address>
        <availability>
          <licence target="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/">This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</licence>
        </availability>
        <date>Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <p><orgName ref="#American_Philosophical">American Philosophical</orgName> Society, <placeName ref="#Philadelphia">Philadelphia</placeName></p>
      </sourceDesc>
      <encodingStmt>
        <projectDesc>
          <p>Established in 2010, the goals of the <orgName ref="#Emma_B_Andrews_Diary_Project">Emma B. Andrews Diary Project</orgName> include the transcription and digitization of a wide range of primary historical material from the'Golden Age' of Egyptian archaeology at the end of the 19th and beginning of the 20th centuries. A founding partner of <orgName ref="#Newbook_Digital_Texts">Newbook Digital Texts</orgName> (www.newbookdigitaltexts.org), the <orgName ref="#EBA_Diary_Project">EBA Diary Project</orgName> offers undergraduate and graduate digital humanities education and internships at the <orgName ref="#University_of_Washington">University of Washington.</orgName> <persName ref="#Andrews_Emma_B">Emma B. Andrews</persName> is best remembered for her association with the millionaire lawyer turned archaeologist/art and antiquities collector, <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore M. Davis</persName>. Traveling to <placeName ref="#Egypt">Egypt</placeName> with him between 1889 and 1912, she kept detailed journals of these voyages along the <placeName ref="#Nile">Nile</placeName>, including his important yet under-reported excavations of over 20 significant tombs in the <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">Valley of the Kings</placeName>. <persName ref="#Andrews_Emma_B">Emma</persName> provides a vital commentary on the archaeology and pioneering Egyptologists of the time, painting a revealing picture of the lives of the colonial gentry and the cultural and scientific literati in at the dawn of the twentieth century. Analysis of the content of her diaries, along with a broad range of additional primary source material, will afford scholars information about important historical resources for the first time.</p>
        </projectDesc>
      </encodingStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <pb n="86"/>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1911-10-16" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1911-10-16">Sunday, October 16. 1911</date>.
        </dateline>
        <p>We left home by <placeName ref="#Fall_River">Fall River</placeName> boat, and reached <placeName ref="#New_York">New York</placeName> the next morning. I did some shopping that day, went to the theatre to hear an amusing play of 'Bunty pulls the strings' a Scotch play, given by Scotch actors, and much in vogue now. <persName ref="#Powell_Chilton">Chilton Powell</persName> dined with us and saw the play with us - and <persName ref="#Newberry_Mary">Mary Newberry</persName> and <persName ref="#Ghio_Anita">Anita</persName> were with us - both stopping at the <placeName type="hotel" ref="#Holland_Hotel">Holland</placeName> with us.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1911-10-21" type="entry">
        <dateline>
           <date when="1911-10-21">Oct. 21st</date>.
           <name type="boat" ref="#SS_Berlin">SS. Berlin</name>.
        </dateline>
        <p>Sailed this morning for <placeName ref="#Genoa">Genoa</placeName> - where we will wait 15 days for our boat for <placeName ref="#Alexandria">Alexandria</placeName>. Have my old appartment which is the Captain's, and very commodious and comfortable, and which I occupied two years ago. We know a few of the passengers. The 4 days we passed in <placeName ref="#New_York">New York</placeName> were dismal in the extreme - it rained all the time, I took a severe cold, and did not go out of the house after the first day - and had to cancel a long standing engagement to drive with the <persName ref="#Fairfield_Osborn_Henry #Fairfield_Osborn_Mrs">Fairfield Osborns</persName>, who had invited a lot of pleasant people to meet us. It was altogether a great piece of disappointment, that visit in <placeName ref="#New_York">New York</placeName>.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1911-10-25" type="entry">
        <dateline>
           <date when="1911-10-21"><choice><sic>Oct. 2. Wednesday</sic><corr>Oct. 25th. Wednesday</corr></choice></date>
           <placeName ref="#Genoa">Genoa</placeName>
        </dateline>
        <p>Arrived on a cold, damp morning - came to the <name type="hotel" ref="#Hotel_Miramare">Hotel Miramare</name><pb n="87"/> which had been recommended to us. Until we passed the <placeName ref="#Azores">Azores</placeName>, we had a fairly good passage - though warm and misty - after that to <placeName ref="#Gibraltar">Gibraltar</placeName> bright weather, but tremendous rolling - slow but very disconcerting. After leaving <placeName ref="#Gibraltar">Gibraltar</placeName> we began a hustle with the <placeName ref="#Mediterranean_Sea">Mediterranean</placeName>, and we were cruelly battered about - could not make the landing at <placeName ref="#Algiers">Algiers</placeName> and the little mail boat that came out to us, on returning lost her Captain and one sailor. We find this hotel the most delightful one we have ever known - large airy appartments, with every luxury - perfect service - and food. My corner room is the most charming room I have ever seen - and the large sitting room next it is the same - and the string of bedrooms next the salon, made an imposing array. <persName ref="#Constantini_David">David Costantini</persName> arrived for a few days and <persName ref="#Burton_Harry">Harry Burton</persName> met us at the steamer and stayed the night, going back to <placeName ref="#Florence">Florence</placeName> and coming with the girls, <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and <persName ref="#Buttles_Mary">Mary Buttles</persName> for a week before the steamer sailed. We motored a good deal along that lovely coast, and it would have been delightful had the roads been good and the motors comfortable. We were all glad when the <name type="boat" ref="#SS_Prinz_Heinrich">Prinz Heinrich</name> arrived and took us off for <placeName ref="#Alexandria">Alexandria</placeName> on the 18th.<!--[figure out date]--> I was really tired of that wide view from our windows of the <name type="hotel" ref="#Hotel_Miramare">Miramare</name> which stands high, but rather close to that busy port. We arrived at <placeName ref="#Alexandria">Alexandria</placeName> on the <date when="1911-11-21">21st, Nov.</date> having again been cruelly buffetted by that merciless <placeName ref="#Mediterranean_Sea">Mediterranean</placeName>. Arrived in <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> at 9:20 and were immediately installed in our old pleasant appartment, looking on the garden, which we have occupied for several years.</p>
        <pb n="88"/>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1911-12-02" type="entry">
        <dateline>
           <date when="1911-12-02">Saturday. Dec. 2nd</date>.
        </dateline>        
        <p>We came on the <name type="boat" ref="#Beduin">Beduin</name> this afternoon to stay, and were indeed happy to take up this enchanting life again. Everything was in order, and we were soon settled. <persName ref="#Burton_Harry">Harry</persName> left for <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName> today. We had a pleasant week in <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> - saw many of our old friends. <persName ref="#Alston_Judge #Alston_Mrs">Judge Alston and his wife</persName> lunched with us on the boat, <persName ref="#Trefusis_Walter #Graham_Margery_Miss">Capt. Trefusis and his wife</persName> lunched another day.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1911-12-03" type="entry">
        <dateline>
           <date when="1911-12-03">Sunday. Dec. 3rd</date>.
        </dateline>      
        <p>A lot of people this afternoon - and we very busy with all our little settlings.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1911-12-04" type="entry">
        <dateline>
           <date when="1911-12-04">Monday. Dec. 4th</date>.
        </dateline>              
        <p>Tug arrived about 9 o'clock - and we were off for the opening of the bridge at 10 - a good run of about <measure type="distance">25 miles</measure>, and tied up about 5 o'clock.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1911-12-05" type="entry">
        <dateline>
           <date when="1911-12-05">Tuesday, Dec. 5th</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>Started about 6 this morning - tied up at 5 o'clock, and are <measure type="distance">8 miles</measure> from <placeName ref="#Benisoef">Benisoef</placeName>. <measure type="distance">40 miles</measure>.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1911-12-06" type="entry">
        <dateline>
           <date when="1911-12-06">Wednesday. Dec. 6th</date>.
        </dateline>   
        <p>Went from 6 A.M. to 6 P.M. <measure type="distance">34 miles</measure> - a wonderful moon tonight.</p>
        <pb n="89"/>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1911-12-07" type="entry">
        <dateline>
           <date when="1911-12-07">Thursday. Dec. 7th</date>
           <measure type="distance">50-1/2 miles</measure>.
        </dateline>
       <p><measure type="distance">50-1/2 miles</measure>. The usual start at 6 A.M. - reached <placeName ref="#Shaykh_Fadl">Sheik Fadl</placeName> at 10, where the tug stopped for coal, so that we sailed away to <placeName ref="#Al_Minya">Minia</placeName> in fine style and made it at 5 o'clock. A lovely day.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1911-12-08" type="entry">
        <dateline>
           <date when="1911-12-08">Friday. Dec. 8th</date>.
           <measure type="distance">50 miles</measure>.
        </dateline>
        <p>Off at 6 A.M. bringing up at 5:30 P.M. at the beginning of the <placeName ref="#Abu_Fudah_Jabal">Abu Feda Gebel</placeName>.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1911-12-09" type="entry">
        <dateline>
           <date when="1911-12-09">Saturday. Dec. 9th</date>.
           <measure type="distance">55 miles</measure>.
        </dateline>
        <p>Started at 6, but there was such a dense fog, that after slowly feeling our way, we stopped at 7:30 sailed until 4:30, when in a sudden turn of the river, the dahabya collided with the tug with such force, that she broke her steering gear. The men are working at it now.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1911-12-10" type="entry">
        <dateline>
           <date when="1911-12-10">Sunday. Dec. 10th</date>.
           <measure type="distance">34 miles</measure>.
        </dateline>
        <p>The men worked all night, and the tug was able to go on as usual. We landed at <placeName ref="#Asyut">Asy&#251;t</placeName> at 10:20, staying until 12 - and tied up at 5:30.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1911-12-11" type="entry">
        <dateline>
           <date when="1911-12-11">Monday. Dec. 11th</date>.
           <measure type="distance">43 miles</measure>.
        </dateline>
        <p>The river about here is enormously wide, and the channel difficult, so we have had to proceed<pb n="90"/> cautiously - and are now lying at <placeName ref="#Sohag">Sohag</placeName>.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1911-12-12" type="entry">
        <dateline>
           <date when="1911-12-12">Tuesday. Dec. 12 and Wed. 13th</date>.
           <measure type="distance">51 miles</measure>.
        </dateline>
        <p>Reached <placeName ref="#Naj_Hammadi ">Nag Hamadi</placeName> at 7:30, just after the bridge opened, indeed we practically reached it last night. A most lovely day.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1911-12-14" type="entry">
        <dateline>
           <date when="1911-12-14">Dec. 14th. Thursday</date>.
           <measure type="distance">47 miles</measure>.
        </dateline>
        <p> We arrived this afternoon about 3:30, and came very nearly to our old tying ground. The sand bank is vast - and water very shallow. We have made our voyage in 14 days from our landing place in <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> - but last year we took only 10 days.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1911-12-16" type="entry">
        <dateline>
           <date when="1911-12-16">Dec. 16th</date>.
        </dateline> 
        <p><persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> went to the <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">Valley</placeName> this afternoon to stay some days. We are busy settling.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1911-12-24" type="entry">
        <dateline>
           <date when="1911-12-24">Sunday. Dec. 24th. Fourth Sunday in Advent</date>.
        </dateline> 
        <p>I have little to chronicle this week. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> did not come until the afternoon of the 6th day of his absence - and looking so much better - and happy to be in his beloved <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">Valley</placeName> and at work once more. <persName ref="#Burton_Harry">Harry Burton</persName> and <persName ref="#Crane_Lancelot">Lancelot Crane</persName> are there and hard at work, and <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> says the little house is in fine order, cleaned, disinfected, colour washed etc. and that it is comfortable and pleasant. <pb n="91"/><persName ref="#Weigall_Hortense">Mrs. Weigall</persName>, <persName ref="#Winlock_Herbert">Mr. Winlock</persName>, <persName ref="#Carter_Howard">Mr. Carter</persName> and <persName ref="#Lasco_Mr">Mr. Lasco</persName> have been here.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1911-12-31" type="entry">
        <dateline>
           <date when="1911-12-31">Sunday. Dec. 31st. First Sunday after Christmas</date>.
        </dateline>
        <p>A quiet week. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> in the <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">Valley</placeName> since <date when="1911-12-27">Wednesday</date> - but returns today. <persName ref="#Anthony_Mr">Mr. Anthony</persName> had tea with us on <date when="1911-12-29">Friday</date>. The girls and I have amused ourselves in many ways. The weather cold, with high winds. River falling rapidly - and the sand roof which has formed so rapidly between us and the main channel shows each day more prominently.</p>
      </div>
      <!--[Next 1/3]-->
      <!--[How do we tag the antiquities: "Three delicious little girls from the tomb of Menna in the Sheik Abu el Negga? Couldn't find these places in the indices]-->
      <!--[also unsure of if/how to tag "the girls" mentioned in all these entries?]-->
      <div xml:id="EBA-1912-01-07" type="entry">
        <dateline>
           <date when="1912-01-07">Sunday. 1st after Epiphany. Jan. 7th</date>.
        </dateline>
        <p><persName ref="#McQuay_Mr"><choice><sic>Mr. Mcquay</sic><corr>Mr. McQuay</corr></choice></persName> and <persName ref="#Baird_Mr">Mr. Baird</persName> called on New Years Day - and the girls and I went over to the hotel for tea with <persName ref="#Anthony_Mr">Mr. Anthony</persName>. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> went to <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">the Valley</placeName> on Wednesday. On Thursday we had a frightful gale, dust blowing everywhere. We went on Friday to the commencement exercises at the <orgName ref="#American_Mission">Mission School</orgName> - remarkable and interesting. <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> tremendously impressed. <persName ref="#Carter_Howard">Mr. Carter</persName> to breakfast - and on Saturday we drove out to <persName ref="#Carter_Howard">Mr. Carter</persName>'s for tea and saw his paintings. The girls had not seen his pictures for 5 years, and thought he had advanced enormously. Among them was the one I ordered last year. Three delicious little girls from the tomb of Menna in the Sheik Abu el Negga. I am delighted with them. <persName ref="#Whymper_Charles">Mr. Whymper</persName> lunched with us before we went. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> came back from <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">the Valley</placeName> this afternoon.</p>
      <pb n="92"/>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1912-01-10" type="entry">
        <dateline>
           <date when="1912-01-10">Wednesday. Jan. 10th</date>.
        </dateline>
        <p>We are having a very cold winter - and this morning the air was so thick the mountains could not be seen. Our little stoves have been in use almost every day lately. <persName ref="#Burton_Harry">Harry Burton</persName> lunched with us yesterday. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> to <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">the Valley</placeName> this afternoon to stay over Sunday.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1912-01-12" type="entry">
        <dateline>
           <date when="1912-01-12">Friday. Jan. 12th</date>.
        </dateline>
        <p><persName ref="#Whiting_Mrs">Miss Whiting</persName> and her party came to tea - and <persName ref="#Carter_Howard">Mr. Carter</persName> happened along too, and a nice, long visit.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1912-01-13" type="entry">
        <dateline>
           <date when="1912-01-13">Saturday. Jan. 13th</date>.
        </dateline>
        <p><persName ref="#Layard_Lady">Lady Layard</persName> and her <choice><sic>nice</sic><corr>niece</corr></choice> <persName ref="#Alderson_Miss">Miss Alderson</persName> came to tea. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> arrived while they were here, from <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">the Valley</placeName>. He has asked them to lunch with him in the bungalow in <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">the Valley</placeName>.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1912-01-16" type="entry">
        <dateline>
           <date when="1912-01-16">Tuesday. Jan. 16</date>.
        </dateline>
        <p><persName ref="#Trefusis_Robert">Robert Trefusis</persName> to dinner.</p>
      </div>
      <!--[Need info on the Adam Gordon Morris party. Who are the "Ernest Longfellows" mentioned here? Ernest and his wife or sister? What is "Nitocris" and is it tagged correctly?]-->
      <div xml:id="EBA-1912-01-17" type="entry">
        <dateline>
           <date when="1912-01-17">Wednesday. Jan. 17</date>.
        </dateline>
        <p><persName ref="#Buttles_Mary">Mary</persName> and I called on the <persName ref="#Gordon_Morris_Adam">Adam Gordon Morris</persName> party, who have that hideous little <persName ref="#Nitocris">Nitocris</persName> - a very pleasant woman was with them - a <persName ref="#Godwin_Miss">Miss Godwin</persName> of <placeName ref="#New_York">New York</placeName>. We then went to see <persName ref="#Maspero_Louise">Madame Maspero</persName>, and <persName ref="#Layard_Lady">Lady Layard</persName> who were out - and then into the <placeName ref="#Winter_Palace">Winter Palace</placeName> for tea, and found the <persName ref="#Longfellow_Ernest">Ernest Longfellows</persName>, <persName ref="#Whymper_Charles">Mr. Whymper</persName> and <persName ref="#Trefusis_Robert">Robert Trefusis</persName> and sat a long time talking.
      <pb n="93"/> </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1912-01-20" type="entry">
        <dateline>
           <date when="1912-01-20">Saturday. Jan. 20th</date>.
        </dateline>
        <p><persName ref="#Layard_Lady">Lady Layard</persName>, <persName ref="#Alderson_Miss">Miss Alderson</persName>, and I drove out to the Bungalow for lunch - a charming companion - <persName ref="#Alderson_Miss">Miss Alderson</persName> was on a donkey - <persName ref="#Layard_Lady">Lady Layard</persName> is very much of a grand personage - but is simple and charming. Our visit was somewhat intruded upon by <persName ref="#Maspero_Gaston">M. Maspero</persName> and a large party of French people - they brought their own luncheon and crockery - and were soon out of the way. A charming ride home. A jackal ran across our path and disappeared.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1912-01-24" type="entry">
        <dateline>
           <date when="1912-01-24">Wednesday. Jan. 24th</date>.
        </dateline>
        <p><persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> came back from <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">the Valley</placeName> on Monday - and returned this afternoon - <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and <persName ref="#Buttles_Mary">Mary</persName> with <persName ref="#Layard_Lady">Lady Layard</persName> and <persName ref="#Alderson_Miss">Miss Alderson</persName> spent the morning at <placeName ref="#Medinet_Habu">Medinet Habu</placeName>.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1912-01-26" type="entry">
        <dateline>
           <date when="1912-01-26">Sunday. Jan. 26th</date>.
        </dateline>
        <p>I had the misfortune to break one of my teeth the other day, and had to go to <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> to get it mended - arranged by telegram with <persName ref="#Duprey_Dr">Dr. Duprey</persName> - we, <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName>, <persName ref="#Buttles_Mary">Mary</persName> and I left <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName> on the evening on the 7 o'clock train de luxe, and reached <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> at 8:30 A.M. the next day. They had our rooms ready for us at <name type="hotel" ref="#Shepheards_Hotel">Shepheards</name>. We spent the morning at <persName ref="#Cecile_Madame">Madame C&#233;cile</persName>'s after clothes - at 2 P.M. <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> went with me to the dentist for an hour, afterwards the girls went to the bazaar - crowds of Americans arrived in the afternoon at <name type="hotel" ref="#Shepheards_Hotel">Shepheards</name> from <name type="boat" ref="#SS_Adriatic">SS. Adriatic</name>. The girls much amused with the show in the evening. The next morning the girls went to the <orgName ref="#Boulaq_Museum">Museum</orgName>, and I stayed at home<pb n="94"/> to welcome my dear <persName ref="#Perkins_Mrs">Mrs. Perkins</persName>, who is passing through <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> for <placeName ref="#United_States_of_America">America</placeName> on her way home from <placeName ref="#India">India</placeName>. Such a nice talk we had. In the afternoon another successful and a farewell visit to <persName ref="#Duprey_Dr">Dr. Duprey</persName>, and we left <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> at 6:30 P.M. for <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName>. I have never been in more comfortable sleeping trains. The girls and I went to tea with <persName ref="#Layard_Lady">Lady Layard</persName> at the <name type= "hotel" ref="#Luxor_Hotel">Luxor Hotel</name>, <persName ref="#Legrain_Madame">Madame LeGrain</persName>, the <persName ref="#Guadalmina_Marquesa">Marquesa Guadalmina</persName>, <persName ref="#Whymper_Charles">Mr. Whymper</persName> and ourselves.</p>
      </div>
      <!--[who is the Servian minister?]-->
      <div xml:id="EBA-1912-01-29" type="entry">
        <dateline>
           <date when="1912-01-29">Monday 29</date>.
        </dateline>
        <p><persName ref="#Layard_Lady">Lady Layard</persName>, <persName ref="#Alderson_Miss">Miss Alderson</persName>, <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and <persName ref="#Buttles_Mary">Mary</persName> went to <placeName ref="#Der_el_Bahari">Der el Bahri</placeName>, taking lunch with them, a very hot day for such an excursion. In the afternoon <persName ref="#Maspero_Gaston #Maspero_Louise">M. and Mme. Maspero</persName>, with the Servian minister and <persName ref="#Jeannot_Mlle">Mlle. Jeannot</persName>, and <persName ref="#Carter_Howard">Mr. Carter</persName> were here for tea, and <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> came home from <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">the Valley</placeName>.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1912-01-30" type="entry">
        <dateline>
           <date when="1912-01-30">Tuesday. Jan. 30th</date>.
        </dateline>
        <p>It has been deliciously warm for two days - that light, pure warm air that is a happiness to breathe. We were shocked to hear of the death of the <persName ref="#Duke_of_Fife">Duke of Fife</persName> at <placeName ref="#Aswan">Assuan</placeName> - what a winter those unfortunate people have had! The girls went with <persName ref="#Layard_Lady"><choice><sic>Lady Laird</sic><corr>Lady Layard</corr></choice></persName> and <persName ref="#Alderson_Miss">Miss Alderson</persName> to the <name type= "hotel" ref="#Luxor_Hotel">Luxor Hotel</name>. <persName ref="#Baird_Mr">Mr. Baird</persName> and <persName ref="#McQuay_Mr">Mr. McQuay</persName> lunched with us. <persName ref="#Warren_Lloyd">Young Lloyd Warren</persName> came after with letters from <persName ref="#Stevens_Joe">Joe Stevens</persName> and <persName ref="#Rowland_Mrs">Mrs. Rowland</persName>. <persName ref="#Layard_Lady">Lady Layard</persName> and <persName ref="#Alderson_Miss">Miss Alderson</persName> came to dine.</p>
      <pb n="95"/>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1912-01-31" type="entry">
        <dateline>
           <date when="1912-01-31">Wednesday. Jan. 31</date>.
        </dateline>
        <p>Another beautiful hot day. Home all day, <persName ref="#Glover_Mr #Glover_Mrs">Mr. and Mrs. Glover</persName> and daughters who brought a card of introduction from <persName ref="#Weigall_Arthur">Mr. Weigall</persName> had tea with us. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> went to <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">the Valley</placeName> yesterday.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1912-02-01" type="entry">
        <dateline>
           <date when="1912-02-01">February 1st. Thursday</date>.
        </dateline>
        <p>At home all day. The girls took <persName ref="#Layard_Lady">Lady Layard</persName> and <persName ref="#Alderson_Miss">Miss Alderson</persName> to <placeName ref="#Karnak">Karnak</placeName> this morning where <persName ref="#Legrain_M">M. Legrain</persName> devoted himself to them, and made a very pleasant visit for them. About one o'clock a violent gale and sand storm burst upon us - and it is still going on. We are deluged and covered with dust - but it has grown cooler.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1912-02-02" type="entry">
        <dateline>
           <date when="1912-02-02">Friday. Feb. 2nd</date>.
        </dateline>
        <p>A very busy morning letter writing - about noon <persName ref="#Layard_Lady">Lady Layard</persName> and <persName ref="#Alderson_Miss">Miss Alderson</persName> came in for a farewell visit - they go to <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> tomorrow to stay with <persName ref="#Kitchener_Herbert">Lord Kitchener</persName>. We saw them again this afternoon at the <persName ref="#Maspero_Gaston #Maspero_Louise"><choice><sic>Maspero's</sic><corr>Masperos'</corr></choice></persName> <name type="boat" ref="#Miriam">boat</name>, where <persName ref="#Maspero_Gaston">M. Maspero</persName> gave a farewell tea to a few friends. They start down the river on Monday. A lovely moonlit, quiet night - a boon indeed.</p> 
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1912-02-03" type="entry">
        <dateline>
           <date when="1912-02-03">Saturday. Feb. 3rd</date>.
        </dateline>
        <p><persName ref="#Buttles_Mary">Mary</persName> and I to town this morning. Met the <persName ref="#Contardone_Contessa">Contessa Contardone</persName> and <persName ref="#Jeannot_Mlle">Mlle. Jeannot</persName>, and we went into some of the shops - such an amusing incident occurred! In the afternoon <persName ref="#Buttles_Mary">Mary</persName> and I went to make some belated calls. To the <orgName ref="#American_Mission">American Mission</orgName> to see <persName ref="#Phillips_Mr #Phillips_Mrs">Mr. and Mrs. Phillips</persName>,<pb n="96"/> to the <name type="hotel" ref="#Savoy_Hotel">Savoy</name> to call on the <persName ref="#Guadalmina_Marquesa"><choice><sic>Marchesa Guadelmina</sic><corr>Marquesa Guadalmina</corr></choice></persName> - and had a most pleasant visit. Then to <placeName ref="#Karnak">Karnak</placeName> to see <persName ref="#Legrain_Madame">Madame LeGrain</persName>, and had tea there. The <name type="boat" ref="#Hyksos">'Hyksos' steamer</name> came down and stopped for the night near us - she is the boat the <persName ref="#Duchess_of_Fife">Princess Royal</persName> and the <persName ref="#Duke_of_Fife">Duke of Fife</persName> always have had. There is to be something like a memorial service in the chapel here tomorrow. The bereaved family! how sad it is.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1912-02-04" type="entry">
        <dateline>
           <date when="1912-02-04">Septuagesima Sunday - Feb. 4th</date>.
        </dateline>
        <p>A quiet, warm day - and a delightful one. <persName ref="#Buttles_Mary">Mary</persName> and I were rowed down this afternoon to see the <persName ref="#Nicol_Erskine #Nicol_Mrs">Nicols</persName> - but they were not at home. The <persName ref="#Maspero_Gaston #Maspero_Louise">Masperos</persName> left this A.M.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1912-02-05" type="entry">
        <dateline>
           <date when="1912-02-05">Monday. Feb. 5th</date>.
        </dateline>
        <p><persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> came back from <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">the Valley</placeName> this afternoon. The day has been delightfully hot.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1912-02-06" type="entry">
        <dateline>
           <date when="1912-02-06">Tuesday. Feb. 6th</date>.
        </dateline>
        <p>Another warm lovely day - and all those nights are so wonderfully beautiful with the full moon. After the <name type="boat" ref="#Hyksos">Hyksos</name> moved off this A.M. we pulled around the sand to her place - and are so quiet here. <persName ref="#Morgan_John_Pierpont">Mr. Morgan</persName> on his fine new steamer came in last night at 10 o'clock and soon after breakfast <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> and I went across to see them. They were very glad to see me. He has his nice sister <persName ref="#Burns_Mrs">Mrs. Burns</persName>, <persName ref="#Lythgoe_Albert #Lythgoe_Mrs">Mr. and Mrs. Lythgoe</persName> and <persName ref="#Lawrence_Bishop">Bishop Lawrence</persName> and his wife <!--need tag?--> with him.</p>
      <pb n="97"/>
      </div>
      <!--[Izzy]-->
      <div xml:id="EBA-1912-02-07" type="entry">
        <dateline>
           <date when="1912-02-07">Wednesday. Feb. 7th</date>.
        </dateline>
        <p>A really hot day - quite delightful - at home all the time. <persName ref="#Morgan_John_Pierpont">Mr. Morgan</persName> and <persName ref="#Burns_Mrs">Mrs. Burns</persName> came to lunch - and we had a very pleasant visit. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> went to the <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">Valley</placeName> at 5 o'clock - accompanied by <persName ref="#Jones_Daniel">Jones</persName>. We had a call from <persName ref="#Ralli_Pandolfi">Mr. Pandolfi Ralli</persName> - of <placeName ref="#London">London</placeName> - who brought me a letter from <persName ref="#Layard_Lady">Lady Layard</persName> saying he was an old friend of theirs - rather an interesting person.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1912-02-08" type="entry">
        <dateline>
           <date when="1912-02-08">Thursday. Feb. 8th</date>.
        </dateline>
        <p><persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and <persName ref="#Buttles_Mary">Mary</persName> went out to the <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">Valley</placeName> - taking one of the sand carts - I wrote letters and in the afternoon made some calls - very warm, but delightful.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1912-02-09" type="entry">
        <dateline>
           <date when="1912-02-09">Friday. Feb. 9th</date>.
        </dateline>
        <p>Another warm day - and some wind. <persName ref="#Morgan_John_Pierpont">Mr. Morgan</persName> went up at 2 o'clock.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1912-02-10" type="entry">
        <dateline>
           <date when="1912-02-10">Saturday. Feb. 10th</date>.
        </dateline>
        <p><persName ref="#Buttles_Mary">Mary</persName> and I went off this morning to the <name type="boat" ref="#Memnon"><choice><sic>Mennon</sic><corr>Memnon</corr></choice></name>, but found no one at home. <persName ref="#Nicol_Erskine #Nicol_Mrs">Mr. and Mrs. Nicol</persName> to tea - a charming day.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1912-02-11" type="entry">
        <dateline>
           <date when="1912-02-11">Sexigesima Sunday, Feb. 11th</date>.
        </dateline>
        <p>At home all day. In the afternoon <persName ref="#Molesworth_Lady">Lady Molesworth</persName>, <persName ref="#Contardone_Contessa">the Contessa</persName> and that nice young man, <persName ref="#de_Cuadra_Luis_Count">Count Luis de Cuadra</persName>, son of the <persName ref="#Guadalmina_Marquesa"><choice><sic>Marquisa de Guadolmina</sic><corr>Marquesa de Guadalmina</corr></choice></persName>, and <persName ref="#Grey_Robert">Mr. Robert Grey</persName> called. A lovely night.</p>
      <pb n="98"/>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1912-02-12" type="entry">
        <dateline>
           <date when="1912-02-12">Monday, Feb. 12th</date>.
        </dateline>
        <p>Another absolutely perfect day. We went over by appointment to the <name type="boat" ref="#Mavis">Mavis</name> to see <persName ref="#Nicol_Erskine">Mr. Nicol</persName>'s pictures - two beautiful ones. One of them already sold to <persName ref="#Lanthrop_Barbour">Mr. Barbour Lathrop</persName>. They are busy packing, as they leave on <date when="1912-02-15">Thursday</date>, for <placeName ref="#Palestine">Palestine</placeName>, where he wished to get a few weeks of painting in the desert before the hot weather. This afternoon <persName ref="#Eastwick_Mr #Eastwick_Mrs">Mr. and Mrs. Eastwick</persName> came to tea - a very pleasant visit.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1912-02-13" type="entry">
        <dateline>
           <date when="1912-02-13">Tuesday. Feb. 13th</date>.
        </dateline>
        <p>Such a warm, nice day - until about 2 o'clock it grew hotter and a furious wind came up, filling the air with dust, - at 5 o'clock it was all over. The afternoon was busy. <persName ref="#Burton_Harry">Harry</persName> here to lunch. Young <persName ref="#Murray_Keith">Keith Murray</persName>, <persName ref="#McDonnel_Mr">Mr. McDonnel</persName>, of <placeName ref="#England">England</placeName>, sent here by <persName ref="#Wilson_Alice">Alice Wilson</persName> - <persName ref="#Bauldwin_Mr #Bauldwin_Mrs">Mr. and Mrs. Bauldwin</persName> (<placeName ref="#New_York">New York</placeName>), <persName ref="#Carnarvon_Lord #Carnarvon_Lady">Lord and Lady Carnarvon</persName>, <persName ref="#Cadwalader_John">Mr. John L. Cadwalader</persName>, <persName ref="#Ruth_Miss">Miss Ruth</persName> from <placeName ref="#New_York">N.Y.</placeName> and <persName ref="#Markow_Mrs">Mrs. Markow</persName> of <placeName ref="#Philadelphia">Philadelphia</placeName>, called, followed by <persName ref="#Merriman_Mr #Merriman_Mrs">Mr. and Mrs. D. Merriman</persName>, of <placeName ref="#Boston">Boston</placeName>, to our very great pleasure and surprise coming from the '<placeName ref="#Egypt">Egypt</placeName>'. This evening a splendid display of the Zodiacal light.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1912-02-21" type="entry">
        <dateline>
           <date when="1912-02-21">Wednesday. Feb. 21st</date>.
        </dateline>
        <p>I went over to the town this morning with <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> - and after attending to some necessary things we walked in the garden of the <name type="hotel" ref="#Winter_Palace">Winter Palace</name> - it was very warm and the flies were tormenting - but the hoopoes were lovely. <persName ref="#Whymper_Charles">Mr. Whymper</persName> came to lunch - and in the afternoon <persName ref="#Wheelright_Mrs">Mrs. Wheelright</persName> and her daughter from the <placeName ref="#Thames">Thames</placeName> <!--river of boat?-->were here to tea. Such<pb n="99"/> charming people. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> went to the <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">Valley</placeName>.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1912-02-22" type="entry">
        <dateline>
           <date when="1912-02-22">Thursday. Feb. 22nd</date>.
        </dateline>
        <p>We had the boat dressed in all its colors in honor of Washington's birthday- and it made a very pretty sight. I have spent most of the day writing letters etc. <persName ref="#Contardone_Contessa">Contessa de Contardone</persName> and <persName ref="#Rodier_M">M. Rodier</persName> were here for tea - a pleasant and amusing visit.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1912-03-01" type="entry">
        <dateline>
           <date when="1912-03-01">Friday. March 1st</date>.
        </dateline>
        <p>I have been greatly worried about <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> for some days, she has seemed so unlike herself - and about a week ago we sent for <persName ref="#Dunn_Dr">Dr. Dunn</persName> - whom she did not like at all - and after the 4th visit declined seeing him again. Fortunately <persName ref="#Wheelright_Mrs">Mrs. Wheelright</persName> who is on the <name type="boat" ref="#Thames">Thames</name> near us, has a <persName ref="#Williams_Agusta">Augusta Williams</persName> with her, who is at the head of <orgName ref="#Vincent_Hospital">Vincent Hospital</orgName> in <placeName ref="#Boston">Boston</placeName> - and who offered her services at once. She brought <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> around at once, and was so charming and cheery a person, that we all lost our hearts to her. <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> seemed to have a touch of Drugue fever, with severe pains all over her. We have decided to go up as far as <placeName ref="#Abu_Simbel">Abu Simbel</placeName>. I hardly think it wise at this time of the year, but we want to see it, under its new manifestation. <persName ref="#Burton_Harry">Harry Burton</persName> is going with us, and we have to give him <persName ref="#Burgoyne_Amelie">Amelie</persName>'s room - and leave her behind - we will have a tug and start on the <date when="1912-03-03">3rd</date>.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1912-03-06" type="entry">
        <dateline>
           <date when="1912-03-06">Wednesday. March 6th</date>.
        </dateline>
        <p>Arrived at 10:20 this morning at <placeName ref="#Aswan">Asw&#226;n</placeName> - and left on the <date when="1912-03-08">8th</date><pb n="100"/>arriving at <placeName ref="#Abu_Simbel">Abu Simbel</placeName> on the <date when="1912-03-10">10th</date> day <!--not sure about these dates-->- very busy winds, and very uncomfortably warm. The sand was blowing about us - and as it was quite a walk over to the <placeName ref="#Temple_of_Abu_Simbel">Temple</placeName> we waited for the morning to visit it, and made a call on the <persName ref="#Newman_Mr #Newman_Mrs">Newmans</persName> instead. The next morning we all, except <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName>, went up to the <placeName ref="#Temple_of_Abu_Simbel">temple</placeName>, <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> on a donkey, I carried in my chair, the rest walking. Very interesting to see the change made by taking away those mountains of engulfing sand. The morning was too delicious, the scent of the crops - the larks singing everywhere, and all that strange, wild desolate, Nubian country. Sailed away at 10 o'clock at last, turning our faces homeward - arrived back at <placeName ref="#Aswan">Asw&#226;n</placeName> at 5 o'clock P.M. and remained the night - the next day making <measure type="distance">90 miles</measure> - arriving at <name type="hotel" ref="#Luxor_Hotel">Luxor</name> the following day about 3 o'clock. While on the way up to <placeName ref="#Abu_Simbel">Abu Simbel</placeName>, I made a charming visit to <persName ref="#Bird_Mr #Bird_Mrs">Mr. and Mrs. Bird</persName>, on their desert island, which they have made to blossom like the rose. <persName ref="#Somers_Clarke_George">Mr. Somers-Clarke</persName> designed and built their house which has as its foundation the great granite rocks of the cataract - and which is as solid as the rocks - and so well placed and designed. The garden covers the whole island - and is most interesting and charming.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1912-03-22" type="entry">
        <dateline>
           <date when="1912-03-22">Friday. Mar. 22nd</date>.
        </dateline>
        <p>Had an uneventful journey down to <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> - arrived at 3:30 - and went to our usual mooring place - the little patch of garden full of bloom.</p>
      <pb n="101"/>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1912-04-02" type="entry">
        <dateline>
           <date when="1912-04-02">Tuesday. April 2nd</date>.
           <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName>
        </dateline>
        <p>We have been here 11 days - and sail tomorrow on the <name type="boat" ref="#SS_Prinz_Heinrich">Prinz Heinrich</name> for <placeName ref="#Genoa">Genoa</placeName>, via <placeName ref="#Corfu">Corfu</placeName> - <placeName ref="#Naples">Naples</placeName>. It is tiresome to make this long voyage. It has been charming here - though we have been very quiet - and have done little visiting - and the last week we have been staying at the <name type="hotel" ref="#Ghezireh_Palace_Hotel">Ghezireh Palace Hotel</name> with the usual charming rooms overlooking the Garden - <persName ref="#Coats_Mrs #Coats_Miss">Mrs. and Miss Coats</persName> are here as always - so pleasant to see from year to year. She, Mrs. Coats such a placid type of a nice old English woman. The girls have worked hard at sight seeing and visiting. <persName ref="#Burton_Harry">Harry Burton</persName> has been with us most of the time, and is going with us to <placeName ref="#Florence">Florence</placeName>. Weather not too warm.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1912-04-08" type="entry">
        <dateline>
           <date when="1912-04-08">Easter Monday. April 8th. 1912</date>.
        </dateline>
        <p><placeName ref="#Genoa">Genoa</placeName> - we had such a tiresome voyage. It was interesting seeing <placeName ref="#Corfu">Corfu</placeName> again - but it added to the days. The <persName ref="#Wilhelm_Friedrich_II">German Emperor</persName>was there at his Castle - and 3 great German Steamships in the harbour. We reached <placeName ref="#Naples">Naples</placeName> yesterday - but did not land - and here we are back in our old quarters at this best of hotels, the <name type="hotel" ref="#Hotel_Miramare"><choice><sic>Mimare</sic><corr>Miramare</corr></choice></name> which seems something like home. Tomorrow we go to <placeName ref="#Florence">Florence</placeName>.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1912-04-09" type="entry">
        <dateline>
           <date when="1912-04-09">Tuesday. April 9th</date>.
           <placeName ref="#Florence">Florence</placeName>
        </dateline>
        <p><persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> and <persName ref="#Burton_Harry">Harry</persName> elected to go by motor here - and we went by train - we expected them to arrive before we did, at 10 o'clock P.M. But we passed them near <placeName ref="#Spezia_La">Spezia</placeName>, the rain pouring in torrents - and we thought they would stop somewhere for the night. But they did not arrive<pb n="102"/> until 12:30 - and <persName ref="#Jones_Daniel">Jones</persName> and I who were sitting up for them, were very anxious. They had bad roads and continuous rain. Our pleasure in being once more in <placeName ref="#Florence">Florence</placeName>, was marred by an illness of <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName>'s. It began with an ulcerated tooth, which gave him extreme pain, but the dentist treated it, and we hoped it was over. <persName ref="#Burton_Harry">Harry</persName> was every day at the hotel with us, and <persName ref="#Constantini_David">David Costantini</persName> was very kind and devoted - and was with us almost every day, and motored and played cards with <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> - when the weather was good, which was seldom. We had fires every day. Pleasant visits with the <persName ref="#Hagermeyer_Mr #Hagermeyer_Mrs">Hagermeyer</persName>'s and with the <persName ref="#Kirk_Mr #Kirk_Mrs">Kirks</persName> - old <persName ref="#Kirk_Mrs"> Mrs. Kirk</persName> is very remarkable. She is 86 years old and as active mentally and physically as ever, and very intelligent. She rises very early, and works in her garden of which she is extravagantly fond, and is now amusing herself in writing a history of her life. It is a pleasure to meet her and talk to her. We spent all afternoon with them, such a pleasant old Italian house just outside <placeName ref="#Florence">Florence</placeName> - we could only walk through part of it, as it was cold and windy.</p>
        <p>I only went into one church while here because of the cold, and <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I went into <placeName ref="#Santa_Croce">S. Croce</placeName>, my favourite Florentine church, one morning. We were all devoted to <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> - in his wretched state - and the last day of our stay we went out to <persName ref="#Constantini_David">David Costantini</persName>'s beautiful house and had tea. <persName ref="#Constantini_Mrs">Mrs. Costantini</persName> was in <placeName ref="#Paris">Paris</placeName> - we are leaving on the 24th for <placeName ref="#Milan">Milan</placeName> for 3 or 4 days - and will go from there directly to <placeName ref="#London">London</placeName>.</p>
      <pb n="103"/>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1912-05-05" type="entry">
        <dateline>
           <date when="1912-05-05"><choice><sic>Sunday. April 5th</sic><corr>Sunday. May 5th</corr></choice></date>
        </dateline>
        <p>We had 5 miserable days in <placeName ref="#Milan">Milan</placeName>. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> was so suffering. We were as usual at that pleasant <name type="hotel" ref="#Hotel_Cavour">Cavour</name>, and <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and <persName ref="#Burton_Harry">Harry</persName> went with us to see us off to <placeName ref="#London">London</placeName>. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> fortunately found an excellent dentist - who came twice to see him each day. He was so brave and patient - but the treatment was very heroic, and he is much pulled down by it - quite a comfortable ride to the <placeName ref="#Calais">Calais</placeName> landing, and on Tuesday afternoon at 5 o'clock we reached <placeName ref="#London">London</placeName>, and settled ourselves in our old pleasant appartment at <placeName ref="#Bucklands">Bucklands</placeName>.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1912-05-29" type="entry">
        <dateline>
           <date when="1912-05-29">Tuesday. May 29th</date>.
        </dateline>
        <p>We are finally off for home tomorrow, and will sail on the <name type="boat" ref="#SS_Kronprinzessen_Cecelia">Kronprinzessen Cec&#232;lia</name>. She usually makes the voyage in 5 days but as all the boats take a long southern course, to avoid possible ice, we will not reach <placeName ref="#New_York">New York</placeName> before Wednesday. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> still does not feel quite like himself, but has improved very much. We have been very busy, visiting with our friends, shopping, etc. But above all motoring over this beautiful country, we have the same motor we had last year, and <persName ref="#Bradford">Bradford</persName> the excellent chauffeur - who verily I think knows all the roads in <placeName ref="#England">England</placeName>. <persName ref="#Knagenhjelm_Eleanor">Eleanor Knagenhjelm</persName> and <persName ref="#Wilson_Alice">Alice Wilson</persName> came from <placeName ref="#Dresden">Dresden</placeName> the day after we got here. <persName ref="#Wilson_Alice">Alice</persName> goes home with us. <persName ref="#Knagenhjelm_Eleanor">Eleanor</persName> was so very kind and devoted to her <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">uncle</persName>, played bridge interminably with him, and was so useful and kind, and a great comfort. Our greatest pleasure was going to the <name type="event" ref="#Chelsea_International_Flower_Show">International Flower Show</name>, held in <placeName ref="#Chelsea_Gardens">Chelsea Gardens</placeName> - a wonderful thing! Then we made a visit to <placeName ref="#Guildford">Guildford</placeName> to see <pb n="104"/><persName ref="#Upton_Mr">Mr. Upton</persName> and to see his garden - and order some rock plants. There are so many all together delightful things to do in <placeName ref="#London">London</placeName> - it would take months to see them all!</p>
      </div>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>