<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model  href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>Diary of Mrs. Emma B. Andrews. Volume 13 1905-1906</title>
        <author>
          <persName ref="#Andrews_Emma_B">Emma B. Andrews</persName>
        </author>
        <editor>
          <persName ref="#SK">Sarah Ketchley</persName>
        </editor>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>
          <orgName ref="#Emma_B_Andrews_Diary_Project">Emma B. Andrews Diary Project</orgName>
        </publisher>
        <address>
          <addrLine>University of Washington, Seattle, WA</addrLine>
        </address>
        <availability>
          <licence target="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/">This work is licensed
            under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial Share-Alike 4.0 International
            License.</licence>
        </availability>
        <date>2021-01-10</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <p><orgName ref="#American_Philosophical_Society_Philadelphia">American Philosophical
            Society, Philadelphia</orgName></p>
      </sourceDesc>
      <encodingStmt>
        <projectDesc>
          <p>Established in 2010, the goals of the <orgName ref="#Emma_B_Andrews_Diary_Project">Emma
              B. Andrews Diary Project</orgName> include the transcription and digitization of a
            wide range of primary historical material from the'Golden Age' of Egyptian archaeology
            at the end of the 19th and beginning of the 20th centuries. A founding partner of
              <orgName ref="#Newbook_Digital_Texts">Newbook Digital Texts</orgName>
            (www.newbookdigitaltexts.org), the <orgName ref="#EBA_Diary_Project">EBA Diary
              Project</orgName> offers undergraduate and graduate digital humanities education and
            internships at the <orgName ref="#University_of_Washington">University of
              Washington</orgName>. <persName ref="#Andrews_Emma_B">Emma B. Andrews</persName> is
            best remembered for her association with the millionaire lawyer turned archaeologist/art
            and antiquities collector, <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore M.
              Davis</persName>. Traveling to <placeName ref="#Egypt">Egypt</placeName> with him
            between 1889 and 1912, she kept detailed journals of these voyages along the <placeName
              ref="#Nile">Nile</placeName>, including his important yet under-reported excavations
            of over 20 significant tombs in the <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">Valley of the
              Kings</placeName>. <persName ref="#Andrews_Emma_B">Emma</persName> provides a vital
            commentary on the archaeology and pioneering Egyptologists of the time, painting a
            revealing picture of the lives of the colonial gentry and the cultural and scientific
            literati in at the dawn of the twentieth century. Analysis of the content of her
            diaries, along with a broad range of additional primary source material, will afford
            scholars information about important historical resources for the first time.</p>
        </projectDesc>
      </encodingStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-11-09" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-11-09">Nov. 9. 1905.</date>
          <name type="boat" ref="#SS_Princess_Irene">S.S. Princess Irene</name>
        </dateline>
        <p>This is the 13th day of our voyage! will reach <placeName ref="#Naples"
            >Naples</placeName> tomorrow morning at 6 o'clock. I love that early morning entrance
          into these enchanted waters - to see the first gleam upon the crater and smoke of
            <placeName ref="#Vesuvius">Vesuvius</placeName> while all is dark and obscure below. The
          weather has been bad most of the way, and we are far behind time. The last few days have
          been fine - I am in the same spacious and luxurious rooms of the Captain that I had last
          year - and I have enjoyed them even more than I did then - their height and quiet - where
          through the door open night and day on my own little deck, I seem to possess the heavens
          and earth, and I have accomplished a lot of planning for the farm and for the garden. We
          know a few of our fellow-passengers - <personGrp ref="#Folger">Admiral and Mrs.
            Folger</personGrp>, <persName ref="#Mahan_Captain">Captain Mahan</persName> and family,
            <personGrp ref="#Whitehouse">Mr. and Mrs. Whitehouse</personGrp> of <placeName
            ref="#Irvington">Irvington</placeName> on the <placeName ref="#Hudson_River"
            >Hudson</placeName> etc. <persName ref="#Dannomeuse_Captain">Captain
            Dannomeuse</persName> is the Prince of Captains - interesting, thoughtful and
          studious.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-11-12" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-11-12">Nov. 12th.</date>
          <placeName ref="#Brindisi">Brindisi</placeName>
        </dateline>
        <p>Reached <placeName ref="#Naples">Naples</placeName> Friday at 6 A.M. had a good landing -
          though later the rain began, and prevented us from doing anything but stay indoors the
          rest of the day. We had the same weather the next morning, until noon, when we left for
            <placeName ref="#Brindisi">Brindisi</placeName>, most of our time was spent with
            <persName ref="#Constantini_David">David Costantini</persName>, who had brought his new
          wife down to see us. We were quite pleased with her. A well dressed, lady like woman of
          the world, <pb n="109"/>evidently very fond of him - but the disparity in years would seem
          perhaps to make the result unhappy. She was a <persName ref="#Schenck_Ida">Miss Ida
            Schenck</persName> of <placeName ref="#New_York">New York</placeName>, and then a
            <persName ref="#Wilmerding_Mrs">Mrs. Wilmerding</persName>, from which marriage she gets
          her money. We had the usual tiring ride over here, arriving at 10:30 P.M. This hotel is
          drearier and dirtier than ever but the Captain of the <name type="boat" ref="#Isis"
            >Isis</name> has take pity on us, and says we may go aboard for luncheon.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-11-15" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-11-15">Wednesday, November 15, 1905.</date>
          <name type="hotel" ref="#Shepheards_Hotel">Shepheards Hotel</name>
          <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName>
        </dateline>
        <p>Arrived at <placeName ref="#Port_Said">Port Said</placeName> this morning at 6 o'clock.
          Caught the train, luggage and all in time to reach here at 5:30. To our amazement the
          hotel seems quite full. There is a great rush to <placeName ref="#Egypt">Egypt</placeName>
          it seems this winter. In our old rooms.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-11-24" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-11-24">Nov. 24th.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>Came on board the <name type="boat" ref="#Beduin">Beduin</name> at noon - after a
          pleasant, busy week at <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName>. <personGrp ref="#Dennis"
            >Mr. and Mrs. Dennis</personGrp> of <placeName ref="#Baltimore">Baltimore</placeName>
          are here. He is to work at <placeName ref="#Der_el_Bahari">Der el Bahri</placeName> this
          year. Saw <persName ref="#Somers_Clarke_George">Mr. Somers-Clarke</persName> who dined
          with us; <persName ref="#Breasted_Mr">Mr. Breasted</persName>, who with his wife are en
          route to the <placeName ref="#Sudan">Sudan</placeName> to copy inscriptions. Saw much of <!--- [Bonoham Carter?] -->
          <persName>Mr. Carter</persName> - who has at last resigned from the <orgName
            ref="#Service_des_Antiquities">Service des Antiquit&#232;s</orgName>. I was very glad to
          hear it. <persName ref="#Hardy_Jean">Jean</persName> and I drove out to the country to the
          pretty little house he has taken, and had tea with him. He is going to devote himself to
          painting - a thing he should have done years ago. One of the most interesting men I have
          [not able to discern what was written.] <pb n="110"/> (L.H.) invited us to make him a
          visit at his farm, away up at the mouth of the <placeName ref="#Atbara_River">Atbara
            river</placeName>! How we would have liked it! He was taking up with him <personGrp
            ref="#Iddings">Mr. and Mrs. Idding</personGrp>, our new Vice-Consul. <persName
            ref="#Morgan_John_Pierpont">Mr. Morgan</persName> gave us a tea, where we met the
            <personGrp ref="#Iddings">Iddings</personGrp>. I had met him years ago at <placeName
            ref="#Rome">Rome</placeName>, one evening when <persName ref="#Bronson_Mrs">Mrs.
            Bronson</persName> gave us a dinner in her beautiful appartment in the <name
            type="hotel" ref="#Palazzo_Borghese">Palazzo Borghese</name>. He tells me that <persName
            ref="#Chandler_Ethel">Ethel</persName> still occupies it. She is now Princopessa Ethel
          Rospigliosi - having married Prince <persName ref="#Rospigliosi_Giovanni">Giovanni
            Battista Rospigliosi</persName> - a sensible marriage de convenance <persName
            ref="#Iddings_Mr">Mr. Iddings</persName> said - who has known the <personGrp
            ref="#Bronson">Bronsons</personGrp> intimately for years. <persName
            ref="#Chandler_Ethel">Ethel</persName> gave her money, was received into the Catholic
          Church - and got his title, and was received in his family where she had long been, she
          and her mother, on intimate terms. We got off with a tug about 2 o'clock, which we will
          take as far as <placeName ref="#Assiout">Asy&#251;t</placeName> - <persName
            ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> being impatient to reach <placeName
            ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName>. <persName ref="#Burgoyne_Amelie">Amelie</persName> has
          been the victim of repeated colds since she came to <placeName ref="#Egypt"
            >Egypt</placeName> - and was in bed 2 days with rheumatism before we started. We made
            <measure type="distance">16 miles</measure> today.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-11-25" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-11-25">Nov. 25.</date>
          <measure type="distance">47 miles</measure>
        </dateline>
        <p>and are 7 miles above <placeName ref="#Wasta">Wasta</placeName>.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-11-26" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-11-26">23 Sunday after Trinity. Nov. 26.</date>
          <measure type="distance">30 miles</measure>
        </dateline>
        <p>Are lying at <placeName ref="#Fashen">Fashen</placeName> - having made 30 miles.
            <persName ref="#Burgoyne_Amelie">Amelie</persName> much of the time in bed with cold and
          repeated attacks of dysentery. <persName ref="#Jones_Daniel">Jones</persName> half ill
          with a cold.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-11-27">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-11-27">Monday, Nov. 27th.</date></dateline>
        <p><pb n="111"/>Head wind all day. Passed <persName ref="#Sayce_Archibald">Mr.
            Sayce</persName> at 8:30 this morning.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-11-28" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-11-28">Tuesday, Nov. 28th.</date>
          <measure type="distance">31 miles</measure>
        </dateline>
        <p>Stopped at <placeName ref="#Minya">Minia</placeName> for the mail at 4 o'clock.
            <personGrp ref="#Fraser">Mr. and Mrs. Fraser</personGrp> came over to see us - their
          boat being near us.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-11-29" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-11-29">Nov. 29th.</date>
          <measure type="distance">45 miles</measure>
        </dateline>
        <p>just below the troublesome <placeName ref="#Gebel_Abufeydah">Gebel Abufeydah</placeName>
          - quite warm today.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1905-11-30">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1905-11-30">Thursday, November 30th.</date>
          <measure type="distance">43 miles</measure>
        </dateline>
        <p>A warm day - we dropped our tug on arriving here (<placeName ref="#Assiout"
            >Asy&#251;t</placeName>) at 5:30 and will go on without it.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-02-08">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-02-08">Feb. 8th., 1906.</date>
          <placeName ref="#Silsilis">Silsilis</placeName>
        </dateline>
        <p>It is a far cry back to that day at <placeName ref="#Assiout">Asy&#251;t</placeName>. The
          next day I went to bed with a sudden cold which I had been fighting for 2-3 days - and
          there I stayed for nearly 4 weeks - more ill than I have ever been in my life, with a
          severe attack of bronchitis. That was a weary time. <pb n="112"/> It taught me much. We
          stayed in <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName> at our usual place at the sand bank
          opposite the town, for 7 weeks and 4 days. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M"
            >Theo</persName> very busy with his work. He unearthed 3-4 tombs. One only having any
          special interest - that of <persName ref="#Siptah">Siptah</persName>, an inimportant king
          of the XIX dynasty. We had of course visitors all day long - from those at breakfast to
          lunch - tea and dinner. I spent a great part of my time waiting for people to go!
            <personGrp ref="#Agassig">Mr. Agassig and May</personGrp> were in <placeName
            ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName> several days, and we saw much of them, they are delighted
          with <placeName ref="#Egypt">Egypt</placeName> - with <placeName ref="#Luxor"
            >Luxor</placeName> and its climate - and especially with the dahabya and our mode of
          life. We got away at last on the 4th and have made on our 3 days - 9 miles - 33-1/2 - 30.
          It has been very warm and cloudy for 2 days - yesterday a few drops of rain fell - and
          this evening it is raining sharply - after a short storm of strong wind. Very hot today.
          We were all quite limp and lazy - yesterday about 11 o'clock we saw away in the distance a
          dahabya at <placeName ref="#Gebel_el_Silsila">Silsileh</placeName>, which we thought must
          be <persName ref="#Sayce_Archibald">Mr. Sayce</persName>'s. The wind failed however and we
          couldn't get on. All this morning we were tracking and pulling to an anchor - the river as
          smooth as a mirror. Just as we were almost in hailing distance of the <name type="boat"
            ref="#Istar">Istar</name>, we saw her pull out in the river, and start down. <persName
            ref="#Sayce_Archibald">Mr. Sayce</persName> came over in his felucca for a few moments.
          He reports the prehistoric ground he has been examining to have been in time past
          completely plundered. Just before we tied up for the night, the <name type="boat"
            ref="#Scarab">Scarab</name> overtook us, with <personGrp ref="#Gould">Mr. and Mrs. Frank
            Gould</personGrp> and <persName ref="#Newberry_Percy">Mr. Newberry</persName> on board.
          We had hoped to reach <placeName ref="#Aswan">Asw&#226;n</placeName> before they did.
          Rained a little this evening.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-02-09">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-02-09">Friday, Feb. 9th.</date>
          <measure type="distance">36 miles</measure>
        </dateline>
        <p>We have made a good day of it - and arrived at the big sycamore under the <!---[cant find info on this]-->
          <placeName>Grenvill</placeName> tombs about 6:30. The day has been warm and clouded.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-02-10" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-02-10">Saturday, Feb. 10.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>It has been a very hot day - we sailed around to our old place on the rocky little island
          opposite the <name type="hotel" ref="#Cataract_Hotel">Cataract Hotel</name> early this
          morning. This afternoon we rowed around the <name type="hotel" ref="#Savoy_Hotel">Savoy
            Hotel</name>, and had tea in those charming gardens. Dined at the <name type="hotel"
            ref="#Cataract_Hotel">Cataract Hotel</name> and met <personGrp ref="#Whitehouse">Mr. and
            Mrs. Whitehouse</personGrp>, <personGrp ref="#Nemness">Mr. and Mrs. Nemness</personGrp>,
            <persName ref="#Morrell_Dr">Dr. Morrell</persName>, <persName ref="#Newberry_Percy">Mr.
            Newberry</persName> and the <personGrp ref="#Gould">Goulds</personGrp> from the <name
            type="boat" ref="#Scarab">Scarab</name> - and glad to find <persName ref="#Morgan_Miss"
            >Miss Morgan</persName> there. The new handsome big dining room was crowded with people
          - every one in full dress. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> and I came
          away at 11 - leaving <persName ref="#Hardy_Jean">Jean</persName> and <persName
            ref="#Trefusis_Robert">Robert</persName> for the dance.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-02-11" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-02-11">Septuagesima. Sunday. Feb. 11.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>A horrid day of cold wind and rain. I never saw the atmosphere fuller of sand - and it
          came everywhere into the boat. It rained about 4 hours. The <name type="boat"
            ref="#Beduin">Beduin</name> happily is water tight. <persName ref="#Morgan_Miss">Miss
            Morgan</persName> came over to dinner and <persName ref="#Newberry_Percy">Mr.
            Newberry</persName> to tea. The <name type="boat" ref="#Scarab">Scarab</name> goes down
          tomorrow.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-02-12" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-02-12">Monday, Feb. 12.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>A high cold wind all day - but sunshine and a clear atmosphere <pb n="114"/>
          <persName ref="#Hardy_Jean">Jean</persName> and <persName ref="#Trefusis_Robert"
            >Robert</persName> and <persName ref="#Morgan_Miss">Miss Morgan</persName> went over to
          the <!---[Busharin?]-->
          <placeName>Busharin</placeName> village this morning - and we went with her to the <name
            type="hotel" ref="#Savoy_Hotel">Savoy</name> this afternoon for tea. The gardens
          deliciously fresh after the rain. We dined with the <personGrp ref="#Whitehouse"
            >Whitehouses</personGrp> at the <name type="hotel" ref="#Cataract_Hotel"
          >Cataract</name>, and had a charming evening. Saw the <personGrp ref="#Hennops"
            >Hennops</personGrp>, <personGrp ref="#Hall">Mr. and Mrs. Hall</personGrp> of <placeName
            ref="#Boston">Boston</placeName>, and <persName ref="#Talbot_Kelly">Mr. Talbot
            Kelley</persName>, the artist. We start down tomorrow.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-02-13" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-02-13">Tuesday, Feb. 13.</date>
          <measure type="distance">13 miles</measure>
        </dateline>
        <p>Started soon after breakfast with the usual contrary wind - but worked our way along to
          this point, lovely day, with cool wind. I hate to leave these red golden sands, these
          strange, sombre rocks - and the dry pure air of <placeName ref="#Aswan"
            >Asw&#226;n</placeName> - it has a quality quite to itself.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-02-14" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-02-14">Wednesday, Feb. 14.</date>
          <measure type="distance">33 miles</measure>
        </dateline>
        <p>This has been one of the worst days I ever knew on the river. It began with a high wind
          and no sun, and soon began to rain - and kept on raining steadily the whole day. It was a
          miserable day for the men, who worked manfully at their oars, saturated as they must have
          been - and we are now lying below <placeName ref="#Silsilis">Silsilis</placeName>. Passed
          the <!---[???]--> <orgName>Zenet-et-Nil</orgName> the other side of <placeName ref="#Silsilis"
            >Silsilis</placeName> just before dark. Did not see <personGrp ref="#Bird">Mr. and Mrs.
            Bird</personGrp>.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-02-15" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-02-15">Thursday, Feb. 15.</date>
          <measure type="distance">30 miles</measure>
        </dateline>
        <p>Another bad day, beginning with a thick mist that <pb n="115"/>has lasted the whole day
          in spite of a stiff north wind. It has been cold - we are at this time 5:30 - about
            <measure type="distance">6 miles</measure> from <placeName ref="#Edfou"
            >Edfou</placeName>, and it is already almost dark. We are floating by the aid of our
          "sea anchor". It is strange how few gyassas we see in this part of the river.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-02-16" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-02-16">Friday, Feb. 16.</date>
          <placeName ref="#El_Kab">El Kab</placeName>
          <measure type="distance">17-1/22 miles</measure>
        </dateline>
        <p>We have had a clear day at last - but a very cold wind from the north, increasing as day
          wore on. We made the shore opposite <placeName ref="#El_Kab">El Kab</placeName> with
          difficulty. Was much interested in the new house <persName ref="#Somers_Clarke_George">Mr.
            Somers-Clarke</persName> is building about a mile above <placeName ref="#El_Kab">El
            Kab</placeName>. It is on a little spur from the hills, and must have a lovely view. It
          liked it very much. It fits with dignity and appropriateness into its surroundings. So
          sorry we could not stop and see it.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-02-17" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-02-17">Saturday, Feb. 17.</date>
          <measure type="distance">34 miles</measure>
        </dateline>
        <p><measure type="distance">Two miles</measure> from <placeName ref="#Gebelein"
            >Gebelen</placeName>. In spite of head winds we are now within <measure type="distance"
            >20 miles</measure> of <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName>. The morning was very
          cold. Mercury 54 in my room - and a cold wind all day. It grew warm about 5 P.M. and now
          at 10 o'clock there are no stars to be seen and it is warm and close.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-02-18" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-02-18">Sexigesima Sunday. Feb. 18th.</date>
          <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName>
          <measure type="distance">20 miles</measure>
        </dateline>
        <p>Arrived at 2:30, found a great mail. We have fought the contrary wind all the five and a
          half days we have been coming from <placeName ref="#Aswan">Asw&#226;n</placeName> - on the
          moment of our arrival the <pb n="116"/> south wind began to blow. <persName
            ref="#Newberry_Percy">Mr. Newberry</persName> came to dine.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-02-19" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-02-19">Feb. 19th.</date>
          <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName>
        </dateline>
        <p>A terrific gale from the S.W. has been blowing all day. In spite of it, <persName
            ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> and <persName ref="#Trefusis_Robert"
            >Robert</persName> went over to the <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings"
            >Valley</placeName> in clouds of dust. They stopped on the way home at <placeName
            ref="#Der_el_Bahari">Der el Bahri</placeName> to see the big <persName ref="#Hathor"
            >Hathor</persName> cow discovered there lately. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M"
            >Theo</persName> closes his general explorations today - but is going to clear out the
          tomb of <persName ref="#Mentuherkhepeshef">Mentu-her-repshef</persName>'s tomb. This tomb
          was opened by <persName ref="#Champollion_Jean">Champollion</persName>, but has not been
          seen since his time, as it has become filled with stone and debris. <persName
            ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> thought he might find valuable inscriptions.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-02-20" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-02-20">Tuesday, Feb. 20.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p><persName ref="#Acland_Thomas_Sir">Sir Thomas</persName> the <persName ref="#Acland_Lady"
            >Lady Acland</persName> came to tea - she is an aunt of <persName ref="#Trefusis_Robert"
            >Robert</persName>'s - very nice people. We had <personGrp ref="#Hennop">Mr. and Mrs.
            Hennop</personGrp>, <persName ref="#Hennop_Grace">Grace Hennop</persName>, and <persName
            ref="#Ewart_Miss">Miss Ewart</persName> to dine - a pleasant evening - a cold day - and
          still wind.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-02-21" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-02-21">Wednesday, Feb. 21st.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>Over to <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName> this morning to the <name type="hotel"
            ref="#Luxor_Hotel">Hotel</name> and to the school - find <persName
            ref="#Buchanan_Carrie">Miss Buchanan</persName> is in <placeName ref="#Cairo"
            >Cairo</placeName> - our cold wind still holds.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-02-22" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-02-22">Thursday, Feb. 22nd.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>We had the boat dressed with our flags in honour of the day - [not able to read].
            <persName ref="#Hardy_Jean">Jean</persName> and I drove out to see <persName
            ref="#Weigall_Hortense">Mrs. Weigall</persName> this <pb n="117"/> morning - met there
            <persName ref="#von_Bissing_Baron">Baron v. Bissing</persName>, who has just arrived -
          looking remarkably well. Young <persName ref="#Mandlsey_Mr">Mr. Mandsley</persName> to
          dine.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-02-23" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-02-23">Friday, Feb. 23.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>We all went over to the <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">Valley</placeName> this
          morning and lunched there in <persName ref="#Ayrton_Edward">Mr. Ayrton</persName>'s tent -
          in company with him and his two funny little dogs. He had many rather interesting
          fragments to show. In spite of very bad donkeys in my chair, the poor things are always
          worn out by this time of the year, I enjoyed the ride. The day was very warm - but I got
          home without feeling a bit tired. The sight of that splendid deep blue sky above those
          yellow, buttressed cliffs, without a speck of a cloud, and as I gazed into its soft depths
          burning to a violet purple it was worth seeing. <persName ref="#Hardy_Jean"
            >Jean</persName> and <persName ref="#Trefusis_Robert">Robert</persName> went over to the
          hotel to dine.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-02-24" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-02-24">Saturday, Feb. 24.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>At home all day - wind strong. Called on <persName ref="#Acland_Lady">Lady
            Acland</persName> at <name type="hotel" ref="#Savoy_Hotel">Savoy</name>. <persName
            ref="#Bruce_Miss">Miss Bruce</persName>, the <persName ref="#Collins_Frances">Miss
            Collins</persName> - and <persName ref="#Dennis_Mrs">Mrs Dennis</persName> to tea.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-02-25" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-02-25">Sunday - Feb. 25.</date>
          <placeName ref="#Quinquagesima">Quinquagesima</placeName>
        </dateline>
        <p><choice><sic>Mr. Corelly</sic><corr><persName ref="#Curelly_Mr">Mr. Curelly</persName></corr></choice>came to lunch. <persName
            ref="#Hunt_Mrs">Mrs. Hunt</persName> and <persName ref="#von_Bissing_Baron">Baron v.
            Bissing</persName> to tea - <personGrp ref="#Naville">M. and Mme. Naville</personGrp>
          and <persName ref="#Sayce_Archibald">Mr. Sayce</persName> to dine. I was very tired and
          sleepy.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-02-26" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-02-26">Monday, Feb. 26.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p><persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> and <persName ref="#Trefusis_Robert"
            >Robert</persName> went over to the <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings"
            >Valley</placeName> this morning taking <pb n="118"/>
          <personGrp ref="#Laffan">Mr. and Mrs. Laffan</personGrp> - I lent my chair to <persName
            ref="#Laffan_Mrs">Mrs. L.</persName> it was a hot day, and I hated to have them go. They
          stopped on the way home and had tea with the <personGrp ref="#Naville"
            >Navilles</personGrp> at the German house. I had a missionary tea this afternoon -
            <persName ref="#Buchanan_Carrie">Miss Buchanan</persName>, <persName
            ref="#Duff_Gordon_Miss">Miss Gordon</persName>, <persName ref="#Atcheson_Miss">Miss
            Atcheson</persName>, and <persName ref="#Sammary_Freda">Freda</persName>. <persName
            ref="#Buchanan_Carrie">Miss B</persName>. and I have had a great chat and a great deal
          to talk about, as <persName ref="#Sammary_Freda">Freda</persName> is to be married in
          April. She makes an excellent marriage - to a teacher in the German school at <placeName
            ref="#Aswan">Asw&#226;n</placeName>, a native, but a Christian, having lived in
            <placeName ref="#England">England</placeName> - and speaking and writing English very
          well. <persName ref="#Sammary_Freda">Freda</persName> improves enormously and was baptized
          last summer at <placeName ref="#Khartoum">Khartoum</placeName>. This man has a house
          furnished in European style, and bears an excellent character - and we all feel it a happy
          thing for her. But at the school they feel a little sad over it, as she will be so much
          missed. the new school building is almost finished - they have occupied for a year the
          lower floor - but are very crowded thus - it is a big, fine building - very substantial,
          with thick walls and high ceilings. It must always be cool - all the arrangements are
          admirable - a pretty chapel, a court, quite a garden - and such nice dormitories. There
          are now 230 pupils - and when finished, the building will accomodate 100 more. <persName
            ref="#Buchanan_Carrie">Miss Buchanan</persName> has 6 girls, who are to marry this
          spring - and she has been giving them herself in the evenings a course of training in
          family life - the care of children, and of the sick etc. I think the work she is doing is
          about the biggest in Egypt. Each one of her girls as they marry and have homes and
          children will form a leaven for succeeding generations.</p>
      </div>
      <pb n="119"/>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-02-27" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-02-27">Tuesday, Feb. 27.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p><persName ref="#Acland_Thomas_Sir">Sir Thomas</persName> the <persName ref="#Acland_Lady"
            >Lady Acland</persName> to lunch - such a pleasant visit. <persName ref="#Hardy_Jean"
            >Jean</persName> and I went over to the <name type="hotel" ref="#Luxor_Hotel">Luxor
            hotel</name> to tea with those nice <persName ref="#Collins_Frances">Miss
            Collins</persName> - in the garden, and had Scotch cake. <persName ref="#Mandsley_Mr"
            >Mr. Mandsley</persName> and <persName ref="#Ayrton_Edward">Mr. Ayrton</persName> called
          after we got home. High wind all day. Paid farewell call to the <personGrp
            ref="#Insingers">Insingers</personGrp> and took them some books.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-02-28" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-02-28">Ash-Wednesday, Feb. 28.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>We went over to <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName> this morning, <persName
            ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> to the mission school, <persName
            ref="#Hardy_Jean">Jean</persName> and <persName ref="#Trefusis_Robert">Robert</persName>
          to play tennis with <!--[which Newberry]-->
          <persName>Newberry</persName> and <persName ref="#Dennis_Mrs">Mrs. Dennis</persName>, and
          I to church in the little chapel - <persName ref="#Sayce_Archibald">Mr. Sayce</persName>
          assisted <persName ref="#Cross_Mr">Mr. Cross</persName>. Met <persName
            ref="#Acland_Thomas_Sir">Sir Thomas</persName> and <persName ref="#Acland_Lady">Lady
            Acland</persName>, the <personGrp ref="#Collins">Miss Collins</personGrp>, and <persName
            ref="#Bruce_Miss">Miss Bruce</persName>. <persName ref="#Hardy_Jean">Jean</persName> and
          I went to tea with <persName ref="#Sayce_Archibald">Mr. Sayce</persName>.
          <persName>Newberry</persName>, <personGrp ref="#Weigall">Mr. and Mrs. Weigall</personGrp>
          and <persName ref="#Dennis_Mrs">Mrs. Dennis</persName> came after we got home. <personGrp
            ref="#Laffan">Mr. and Mrs. Laffan</personGrp> lunched with us. We start for <placeName
            ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> tomorrow. Our tent is struck - the awnings down, and I
          for one, glad to get away from <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName> and its people -
          but not glad to say goodbye to the splendid <placeName ref="#Thebes">Theban</placeName>
          mountains and desert. We have spent 2 months and 3 days at <placeName ref="#Luxor"
            >Luxor</placeName>.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-03-01" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-03-01">Thursday, March 1st.</date>
          <measure type="distance">40 miles.</measure>
        </dateline>
        <p>We have had a beautiful day - started at 6 o'clock A.M. and rowed until nearly 8 o'clock.
          We have a beautiful young moon now. I had an early farewell interview with my splendid
          mountains - touched to every shade of soft pink colour.</p>
      </div>
      <pb n="120"/>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-03-02" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-03-02">Friday, Mar. 2d.</date>
          <measure type="distance">12 miles.</measure>
        </dateline>
        <p>North wind all day - we are about <measure type="distance">6 miles</measure> below
            <placeName ref="#Keneh">Keneh</placeName> - passed the Birds on <placeName
            ref="#Zenet_el_nil">Zenet-el-Nil</placeName> just above <placeName ref="#Keneh"
            >Keneh</placeName>. They were lying by.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-03-03" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-03-03">Saturday, March 3d.</date>
          <measure type="distance">10 miles.</measure>
        </dateline>
        <p>We have been floating all day against an adverse wind - rather warm - <name type="boat"
            ref="#Ammon_Ra">Ammon-Ra</name> went down.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-03-04" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-03-04">First Sunday in Lent.</date>
          <measure type="distance">11 miles.</measure>
        </dateline>
        <p>Made an early start at 6 A.M. but were obliged to pull up to a pleasant little low bank
          early in the afternoon. <placeName ref="#Passe+Dischna">Passe Dischna</placeName> at 8
          o'clock - having seen it in the distance for hours yesterday. Very warm - <name
            type="boat" ref="#Isis">Isis</name> went down with tug.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-03-05" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-03-05">Monday, March 5th.</date>
          <measure type="distance">29 miles.</measure>
        </dateline>
        <p>The men began rowing this morning at 6 o'clock - quite calm and warm. Reached <placeName
            ref="#Nag_Hammadi">Nagh Hamadi</placeName> at 8 o'clock, and waited for the bridge to
          open at 9:30. No wind all day and very warm. Arrived at <placeName ref="#Balliana"
            >Balliana</placeName> about 6:30. <persName ref="#Hardy_Jean">Jean</persName> and
            <persName ref="#Trefusis_Robert">Robert</persName> wishing to see <placeName
            ref="#Abydos">Abydos</placeName> tomorrow.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-03-06" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-03-06">March 6. Tuesday.</date>
          <placeName ref="#Balliana">Balliana</placeName>
        </dateline>
        <p>We had a great gale last night - it began to blow about 11 o'clock and I noticed how very
          black the sky was when I went to bed. <pb n="121"/> I had just fallen asleep, when I was
          wakened by the noise, and the running and calling of the sailors and the rattling of
          chains. I looked out of my window again, and saw that our stern was quite out in the
          stream - the wind coming from off shore - the boat had dragged the stern anchor - and the
          men were all busy getting out extra ropes, anchores, etc. <persName
            ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> got up and lighted his candle, and strayed about
          the boat, looking out of the windows. It blew all night and grew cold - and was still
          blowing when <persName ref="#Hardy_Jean">J</persName>. and <persName
            ref="#Trefusis_Robert">R.</persName> started for <placeName ref="#Abydos"
            >Abydos</placeName> - <persName ref="#Hardy_Jean">Jean</persName> in my chair - and a
          gen d'armes, mounted, to go with them. <placeName ref="#Abydos">Abydos</placeName>, or
          rather <placeName ref="#Balliana">Balliana</placeName>, and its neighborhood being often
          turbulent. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> and I had a nice day alone -
          and about 4 the rest came home, looking very tired, and much battered and covered with
          dust - the wind being very strong all day - and the air laden with dust.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-03-07" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-03-07">Wednesday, Mar. 7th.</date>
          <measure type="distance">5 miles.</measure>
        </dateline>
        <p>Although we started early, we were driven to the bank about 10 o'clock - where we are now
          lying - <measure type="distance">3 miles</measure> above <placeName ref="#Girga"
            >Girgeh</placeName> - which can be plainly perceived across the sand. Hard and cold wind
          all day.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-03-08" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-03-08">Thursday, Mar. 8th.</date>
          <placeName ref="#Naviles">Naviles</placeName>
        </dateline>
        <p>Our men began rowing just as soon as there was light enough, but at 9 o'clock the gale
          was so strong, we had to pull up here, a mile below <placeName ref="#Girga"
            >Girga</placeName> - the "<orgName ref="#Nakt-Heb">Nakt-Heb</orgName>" french flag, is
          lying just above us, the <name type="boat" ref="#Gazelle">"Gazelle"</name> with <persName
            ref="#Sykes_Talton">Sir Talton</persName>
          <pb n="122"/>
          <persName ref="#Sykes_Talton">Sykes</persName>, just below.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-03-09" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-03-09">Friday, March 9th.</date>
          <measure type="distance">24 miles.</measure>
        </dateline>
        <p>The men worked with a will all day - though against the wind. We brought up at <placeName
            ref="#Sohag">Sohag</placeName>, about 6:30 this evening - posted letters and got a lot
          of fresh butter from <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName>. A wonderful moon tonight -
          full.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-03-10" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-03-10">Saturday, March 10th.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>The wind so strong and contrary this morning we did not start until 8:30 and shortly
          after brought up against a high bank opposite the town, where we are still lying and will
          spend the night here.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-03-11" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-03-11">Second Sunday in Lent. March 11th.</date>
          <measure type="distance">25 miles.</measure>
        </dateline>
        <p>Our men began rowing at 4:30 this morning - as the night was very brilliant with a full
          moon. The north wind has been blowing all the time, sometimes less, but never ceasing. We
          are now lying against the cliffs of the northernmost end of the <placeName
            ref="#Gebel_Harêdi">Gebel Harêdi</placeName> - opposite <placeName ref="#Tahta"
            >Tahtah</placeName>.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-03-12" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-03-12">Monday, Mar. 12th.</date>
          <measure type="distance">23 miles.</measure>
        </dateline>
        <p>The usual conditions prevailed today, by hard work we made our miles - and are within
            <measure type="distance">4 miles</measure> of <placeName ref="#Abu_Tij"
            >Aboutig</placeName> - we suppose.</p>
      </div>
      <pb n="123"/>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-03-13" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-03-13">Tuesday, Mar. 13th.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>We must have made <measure type="distance">10 miles</measure> today and are within
            <measure type="distance">5 miles</measure> of <placeName ref="#Assiout"
            >Asyût</placeName>. Cold wind all day - tonight is overclouded and warmer.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-03-14" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-03-14">Wednesday, March 14th.</date>
          <measure type="distance">25 miles.</measure>
        </dateline>
        <p>Made <placeName ref="#Assiout">Asyût</placeName> at 7:30 this morning - stopped only long
          enough for <persName ref="#Jones_Daniel">Jones</persName> to get the mail, and <persName
            ref="#Hassoun">Hassoon</persName> to get vegetables, meat etc. Got through the Weir very
          easily - and have had no wind or very little. It has been very warm - we are probably
          within <measure type="distance">6 miles</measure> of <placeName ref="#Manfalout"
            >Manfalout</placeName>.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-03-15" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-03-15">Thursday, March 15th.</date>
          <measure type="distance">36 miles.</measure>
        </dateline>
        <p>A very warm day - and an absolutely quiet one. The sailors worked valiantly, with an
          awning over them, from 5:30 A.M. We brought up at <placeName ref="#Hag_Kandil">Hag
            Kandil</placeName> at 6:30. Found the <name type="boat" ref="#Gazelle">Gazelle</name>
          lying here. At 6 o'clock this evening the mercury stood at 84 in my room - but a cool
          refreshing little wind from the south is going now.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-03-16" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-03-16">Friday, March 16th.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>We left our landing place this morning early though a north wind was blowing hard - after
          an hour of struggle with it, we were forced to a big sand bank opposite <placeName
            ref="#Gebel_Sheik_Said">Gebel Sheik Said</placeName> - where we now are. The wind has
          raged all day - it has not been cold - but walking or staying on deck was impossible.</p>
      </div>
      <pb n="124"/>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-03-17" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-03-17">Saturday, March 17th.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>We are still lying where we were yesterday - and the weather has been the same. <persName
            ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> sent one of the sailors this morning <measure
            type="distance">7 miles</measure> across the sand to <placeName ref="#Mallawi"
            >Melawi</placeName>, to carry a telegram to <orgName ref="#Cook">Cook</orgName>,
          ordering a tug to come up to us.We ought to have done this a week ago.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-03-18" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-03-18">Sunday, Mar. 18th. 3d Sunday in Lent.</date>
          <placeName ref="#Rhodah">Rodah</placeName>
          <measure type="distance">13 miles</measure>
        </dateline>
        <p>We brought up here suddenly about 11 o'clock this morning, with a strong wind from the
          east, and here we are still. We hope to meet our tug tomorrow. Indeed we have 2 tugs
          coming for us - one from <placeName ref="#Shaykh_Fadl">Sheik Fadl</placeName>, ordered
          this morning, and one from <orgName ref="#Cook">Cooks</orgName>, <placeName ref="#Cairo"
            >Cairo</placeName>, which started up yesterday - and which we ought to pick up on
          Tuesday - when we will dismiss the other one.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-03-19" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-03-19">Monday, Mar. 19th.</date>
          <measure type="distance">11 miles.</measure>
          <placeName ref="#Beni_Hassan">Beni Hassan</placeName>.
        </dateline>
        <p> Started very early, but had to tie up
          about 10 o'clock - opposite the tombs - a spot we well know as we had to stay just here
          years ago for a week, on our way up - a gale is going on.</p>
      </div>
      <!--[last 25 after this]-->
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-03-20" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-03-20">Tuesday, Mar. 20th.</date>
          <placeName ref="#Maghaghah">Maghagah</placeName>
          <measure type="distance">63 miles.</measure>
        </dateline>
        <p>I couldn't sleep last night because of the "fracas" - the gale made. It rained too. About
          8 o'clock we heard the cheerful toot of the tug - and the <name type="boat"
            ref="#Thothmes">Thothmes</name> appeared having made fast time from <placeName
            ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName>. Following on her heels came the <name type="boat"
            ref="#Sugar_Tug">Sugar Tug</name>
          <pb n="125"/>from <placeName ref="#Shaykh_Fadl">Sheik Fadl</placeName> - who had to be
          settled with and sent back before we started. The tug went upon the sand for half an hour
          but has made her miles against a tremendous wind.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-03-21" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-03-21">Wednesday, Mar. 21st.</date>
          <measure type="distance">84 miles.</measure>
        </dateline>
        <p>The gale has continued without ceasing for a moment, and it is really cold. <measure
            type="distance">8 miles</measure> of <placeName ref="#Bedrashyn"
            >Bedreshchein</placeName>.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-03-22" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-03-22">Thursday, Mar. 22d.</date>
          <measure type="distance">23 miles.</measure>
        </dateline>
        <p>We brought up at the bridge at 11 o'clock. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M"
            >Theo</persName> and <persName ref="#Trefusis_Robert">Robert</persName> went in to <name
            type="hotel" ref="#Shepheards_Hotel">Shepheards</name> for the mail - were soon back as
          the bridge opened at 11:45 because of a flower show at the <placeName
            ref="#Agricultural_Gardens">Agricultural Gardens</placeName>. Fancy obstructing and
          interfering with a great commercial highway, because of a flower show! They always do it
          however - a tennis match, polo, races, what not! We got through without trouble - and were
          soon moored at the <placeName ref="#Ghezireh_Palace">Ghezireh Palace</placeName>. Drove
          into town in the afternoon.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-03-23" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-03-23">Friday, Mar. 23rd.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>We came up to the <name type="hotel" ref="#Shepheards_Hotel">hotel</name> this afternoon,
          finding our rooms all ready for us - our usual big ones - opening on the garden.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-03-24" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-03-24">Saturday, Mar. 24.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>To the <placeName ref="#Boulaq_Museum">Museum</placeName> this morning. Met <persName
            ref="#von_Bissing_Baron">v. Bissing</persName> - saw the splendid <persName
            ref="#Hathor">Hathor</persName> cow, found this winter at the <placeName
            ref="#Temple_of_Mentu-hotep">Mentu-hotep temple</placeName> at <placeName
            ref="#Der_el_Bahari">Der el-Bahari</placeName>.<pb n="126"/> To <placeName ref="#Cairo"
            >Cairo</placeName> this afternoon - tea at <name type="hotel" ref="#Shepheards_Hotel"
            >Shepheards</name> - quite horrid in all that crowd, and blare of military music.
            <persName ref="#Dalison_Max">Mr. Dalison</persName> to dine, pleasant evening.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-03-25" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-03-25">Sunday, 4th in Lent. Mar. 25th.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>A warm, khamsiny morning - I had one of my huge windows wide open at 6:30 this morning -
          and the freshness of the lovely garden and the song of the birds was heavenly. They have
          all gone out to <name type="hotel" ref="#Mena_House_Hotel">Mena House</name> for the day.
          I beat a retreat from it, and have a quiet day before me - it being now 11 o'clock A.M.
          The great door of the sitting room where I am now writing stands open on the wide balcony
          with its awnings - and the birds come freely in and out.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-03-26" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-03-26">Monday, Mar. 26th.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>Went to the <placeName ref="#Khan_al_Khalili">Bazaars</placeName> with <persName
            ref="#Newberry_Percy">Mr. Newberry</persName> this morning and to <placeName
            ref="#Dataris">Dataris</placeName> this afternoon to see some fine antiquities. A lovely
          little thing of <persName ref="Akhenaten">Khuenaten</persName> and his wife - going to the
            <placeName ref="#Berlin_Museum">Berlin Museum</placeName>. <persName
            ref="#von_Bissing_Baron">V. Bissing</persName> came to dine.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-03-27" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-03-27">Tuesday, Mar. 27th.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>Visiting etc. all day. <persName ref="#Newberry_Percy">Mr. Newberry</persName> to
          dine.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-03-31" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-03-31">Saturday, Mar. 31st.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>This is our last day here. Yesterday we lunched with <persName ref="#Newberry_Percy">Mr.
            Newberry</persName> at the <placeName ref="#Hotel_d'Angleterre">Angelterre</placeName>.
            <persName ref="#Sandwith_Dr">Dr. Sandwith</persName> dined with us last evening.<pb
            n="127"/>
          <persName ref="#Dennis_Mrs">Mrs. Dennis</persName> asked us to tea over here on the lawn,
          and then found that tea was never served there for less than 20 people. So we had it on
          the terrace. <persName ref="#Newberry_Percy">Mr. Newberry</persName> is dining with us
          tonight - and <persName ref="#von_Bissing_Baron">V. Bissing</persName> and <persName
            ref="#Currelly_Charles_Trick">Mr. Currelly</persName> came in after tea to say
          goodbye.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-04-06" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-04-06">Friday, April 6th.</date>
          <placeName ref="#Venice">Venice</placeName>
          <name type="hotel" ref="#Hotel_Britannia">Hotel Britannia</name>
        </dateline>
        <p>We are thankful indeed to find ourselves safely and comfortably settled in our spacious
          usual appartments here. Such an uncomfortable transit as we have had across the <placeName
            ref="#Mediterranean_Sea">Mediterranean</placeName>! We left <placeName ref="#Cairo"
            >Cairo</placeName>
          <date when="1906-04-01">Sunday morning the 1st</date> for <placeName ref="Port_Said">Port
            Said</placeName>. <personGrp ref="#Dennis">Mr. and Mrs. Dennis</personGrp> were on the
          train. <persName ref="#Newberry_Percy">Mr. Newberry</persName> at the station to say
          goodbye. We found the <name type="boat" ref="#Osiris">Osiris</name> had a very full
          passenger list - we had to wait until <date when="1906-04-02">Monday</date> noon before
          the mail steamer got through the canal. We had feared rough weather, for the wind had been
          high for days. But our experience was more trying than anything we had ever met - we went
          directly out into a very rough sea - and soon almost every passenger had taken to his
          berth. I was not sick at any time - but I went to bed at 5 o'clock and did not get up
          until 10 o'clock P.M. on <date when="1906-04-04">Wednesday</date> - as it was too rough
          and dreadful to be up. That little <name type="boat" ref="#Osiris">Osiris</name> not only
          stood on both ends, but rolled over and jumped out of the water fairly - speed was of
          course slackened, and we reached <placeName ref="#Brindisi">Brindisi</placeName> on <date
            when="1906-04-05">Thursday</date> morning at 1:30 - 14 hours behind time. The boat was
          really much of the time under water and I heard tons of water pouring over the deck above
          me. Our train left at 3 o'clock A.M. We arrived at <placeName ref="#Bologna"
            >Bologna</placeName> at 6 P.M. spent the night at that good hotel <name type="hotel"
            ref="#Hotel_Brun">Brum</name> - and were comforted by an excellent<pb n="128"/> dinner
          and good beds, and arrived here about 6 o'clock this afternoon.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-04-07" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-04-07">Saturday, April 7th.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>A visit to <placeName ref="#Salvadores">Salvadore</placeName>'s this morning and to
            <placeName ref="#San_Marco">San Marco</placeName>, and I went this afternoon to see our
          invalid friends the <personGrp ref="#Benson">Bensons</personGrp>.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-04-08" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-04-08">Sunday, April 8th. Palm Sunday.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>The family went to the <placeName ref="#Gallerie_dell_Accademia">Academia</placeName>
          this morning, I stayed home for a quiet morning and service. <persName
            ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> and I went to <placeName ref="#Palazzo_Capello"
            >Palazzo Capello</placeName> at 3:30 and after a talk with <personGrp ref="#Benson">Mr.
            and Mrs. Benson</personGrp>, went to <placeName ref="#Palazzo_Mula">Palazzo
            Mula</placeName>, to have tea with the <personGrp ref="#Brown">Browns</personGrp> in
          their pretty appartments.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-04-09" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-04-09">Monday, April 9th.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>To the <placeName ref="#Basilica_di_Santa_Maria_Gloriosa_dei_Frari">Frari</placeName> to
          see the pictures - found they had all been removed to the church of <placeName
            ref="#San_Toma">S. Toma</placeName>, where we found it too dark to see them - the
            <placeName ref="#Basilica_di_Santa_Maria_Gloriosa_dei_Frari">Frari</placeName> actually
          seems to be under process of entire reconstruction - all the monuments taken down from the
          walls, and filled with scaffolding and derricks. After lunch to <placeName ref="#Barozzi"
            >Barozzi</placeName>'s where we bought some beautiful stuffs - and then to <placeName
            ref="#Caffe_Florian">Florian</placeName>'s to tea.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-04-10" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-04-10">Tuesday, April 10.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>I spent the morning with the <personGrp ref="#Benson">Bensons</personGrp> - to the
            <placeName ref="#Gallerie_dell_Accademia">Academia</placeName> in the afternoon - and
          again to tea at <placeName ref="#Caffe_Florian">Florians</placeName> - <personGrp
            ref="#Brown">Mr. and Mrs. Brown</personGrp> dined with us.</p>
      </div>
      <pb n="129"/>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-04-11" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-04-11">Wednesday, April 11.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>Shopping, sightseeing and visiting. Saw the <placeName ref="#Garden_of_Eden">Eden
            garden</placeName> and had a lovely row.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-04-12" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-04-12">Thursday, April 12.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>Made the <personGrp ref="#Benson">Bensons</personGrp> a long visit, this morning. Poor
          souls! weak, suffering and old - yet full of interest in life, and longing for an activity
          that will never come again to them! It is truly sad. The great hall and rooms of the
            <placeName ref="#Palazzo_Capello">Palazzo</placeName>, were full of lovely flowers and
          freshness - and the garden was lovely with its blossoming trees. Such a contrast -
            <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> and I went to <placeName
            ref="#Barozzi">Borozzi</placeName>'s and another shop this afternoon and had tea at
            <placeName ref="#Caffe_Florian">Florians</placeName>. A good concert this evening at the
            <name type="hotel" ref="#Hotel_Britannia">Hotel</name>.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-04-13" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-04-13">Good Friday, April 13.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p><persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> and I went to say goodbye to the
            <personGrp ref="#Benson">Bensons</personGrp> this morning. <persName
            ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> left a very kind and substantial gift to
            <persName ref="#Benson_Mr">Mr. Benson</persName> which will relieve them of all anxiety
          for a long time to come. At 2 o'clock we took the little hotel steamer and went to
            <placeName ref="Torcello">Torcello</placeName>. It is undergoing a general repair - the
          fine <placeName ref="#St_Marks_Campanile">Campanile</placeName> is now finished and
          strengthened at which restorative work they have been busy for 2 years. But the whole of
          the young population, and the small island holds myriads of children, are such a nuisance,
          and such irrepressible beggars, that one's pleasure is almost ruined. I love those
          excursions among the islands of the lagoons- with their strange water wave marked by
            clusters<pb n="130"/> of poles - the slender campaniles rising from each island, with
          such a fine effect. For two days the world has been absorbed with the tragedy of the
          eruption of <placeName ref="Vesuvius">Vesuvius</placeName> - on of the worst on record, -
          villages destroyed and buried in lava - desolation and loss of life everywhere. <placeName
            ref="#Naples">Naples</placeName> itself is in darkness - covered with clouds of ashes -
          under the weight of which the big market, one church, and other buildings having collapsed
          with loss of life. <placeName ref="#Capri">Capri</placeName> is said to be so covered with
          this volcanic ash, that crops and verdure are killed. We all separate tomorrow - <persName
            ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> to <placeName ref="#Vienna">Vienna</placeName>
          to meet <persName ref="#Knagenhjelm_Eleanor">Eleanor</persName> - the rest of us to
            <placeName ref="#Florence">Florence</placeName>.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-04-15" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-04-15">Easter Sunday, April 15.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>A most perfect Easter day - brilliant sunshine, and the constant clanging of the
          melodious <placeName ref="#Florence">Florence</placeName> bells. I had my precious little
          Christian Science service, all alone at home. A very comfortable journey over from
            <placeName ref="#Venice">Venice</placeName> yesterday. We are in our old rooms here at
          the <name type="hotel" ref="#Hotel_Grande_Bretagne">Grande Bretagne</name>, found a hearty
          welcome - and <persName ref="#Franz">Franz</persName> and old <persName ref="#Giulia"
            >Giulia</persName> ready to wait on us.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-04-16" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-04-16">Monday, April 16.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>Quite a busy day - tea at the <name type="type" ref="#Residenza_Il_Villino"
            >Villino</name> - <persName ref="#Buttles_Mary">Mary</persName>, <persName
            ref="#Hardy_Jean">Jean</persName> and <persName ref="#Trefusis_Robert">Robert</persName>
          go off to <placeName ref="#Rome">Rome</placeName> tomorrow for a week.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-04-17" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-04-17">Tuesday, April 17.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>The children got off today. <persName ref="#Buttles_Lizzie">Lizzie</persName> not very
            well.<pb n="131"/>
          <persName ref="#Constantini_Mme">Mme. Costantini</persName> made me a visit this afternoon -
          looking remarkably well, and very smart - asked me to lunch for Saturday.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-04-18" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-04-18">Wednesday.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>Cold, disagreeable weather - at home most of the day.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-04-21" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-04-21">Saturday, April 21st.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>I have been in the house for 2 days - weather bad, and slight cold. <persName
            ref="#Constantini_David">David Costantini</persName> called and left the Ivories.
            <persName ref="#Berenson_Bernard">Mr. Berenson</persName> called. <persName
            ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I drove out today - and did some errands -
            <persName ref="#Buttles_Lizzie">Lizzie</persName> and she lunched with me - lovely day.
          The whole world is electrified by the horrible disaster in <placeName ref="#California"
            >California</placeName>. An earthquake has practically destroyed <placeName
            ref="#San_Francisco">San Francisco</placeName>! The accounts that have reached us from
          the wrecked and burning city seem too dreadful to be possible.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-05-04" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-05-04">May 4th. Saturday.</date>
          <placeName ref="#Florence">Florence</placeName>
        </dateline>
        <p>We have now been here for 3 weeks and two days - and will leave for <placeName
            ref="#Paris">Paris</placeName> tomorrow, where <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M"
            >Theodore</persName> and <persName ref="#Knagenhjelm_Eleanor">Eleanor</persName> are now
          waiting for us. With the exception of two or three days, we have had the worst kind of
          weather - rain, cold winds and several hail storms. Driving for pleasure has been out of
          the question. I have had constant pleasant visits from and with <persName
            ref="#Buttles_Lizzie">Lizzie</persName> and the girls. <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette"
            >Nettie</persName> and I lunched one day at <placeName ref="#La_Loggia">La
            Loggia</placeName>"" - the charming country home of the <personGrp ref="#Constantini"
            >Costantini</personGrp>'s - which they are thoroughly changing - making it as far
          <!--[unreadable]--> the 15th century. It will be an enchanting place. We had one of the
          very pleasant teas with the <personGrp ref="#Newman">Newmans</personGrp> which they always
          give us - and were to have lunched with the <personGrp ref="#Berenson"
            >Berenson</personGrp>'s at <placeName ref="#Villa_I_Tatti">I Tatti</placeName>, but the
          weather has been too cold.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-05-06" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-05-06">Monday, May 6th.</date>
          <placeName ref="#Paris">Paris</placeName>
          <name type="hotel" ref="#Hotel_Westminster">Hotel Westminster</name>
        </dateline>
        <p>We had quite a comfortable journey on - though in a very shabby carriage for a "train de
          luxe". <persName ref="#Buttles_Lizzie">Lizzie</persName> and the girls lunched with us -
            <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and <persName ref="#Buttles_Mary"
            >Mary</persName> went to the station with us. <persName ref="#Constantini_David"
            >Constantini</persName> kindly turned up to wish us goodbye. Arrived in <placeName
            ref="#Paris">Paris</placeName> on time! and found <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M"
            >Theo</persName>, <persName ref="#Knagenhjelm_Eleanor">Eleanor</persName> and <persName
            ref="#Jones_Daniel">Jones</persName> at the station. In our old rooms here.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-05-08" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-05-08">May 8th. Tuesday.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>Bad weather yesterday - in the house all day. This morning <persName ref="#Burgoyne_Amelie"
            >Amelie</persName> and I drove out to the <placeName ref="#Bois">Bois</placeName>.
          Charming - rained this afternoon.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1906-05-10" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1906-05-10">Thursday, May 10th.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>Continued bad weather - violent storms. Have so enjoyed <persName
            ref="#Knagenhjelm_Eleanor">Eleanor</persName>'s visit. Sorry that she goes back to
            <placeName ref="#Dresden">Dresden</placeName> tomorrow.</p>
      </div>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
