<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>Diary of Mrs. Emma B. Andrews. Volume 5 1897-1898</title>
        <author>
          <persName ref="#Andrews_Emma_B">Emma B. Andrews </persName>
        </author>
        <editor>
          <persName ref="SK">Sarah Ketchley </persName>
        </editor>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>
          <orgName ref="#Emma_B_Andrews_Diary_Project">Emma B. Andrews Diary Project</orgName>
        </publisher>
        <address>
          <addrLine>University of Washington, Seattle, WA</addrLine>
        </address>
        <availability>
          <licence target="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/">This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</licence>
        </availability>
        <date>2021-11-15</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <p><name ref="#American_Philosophical_Society_Philadelphia">American Philosophical Society, Philadelphia</name></p>
      </sourceDesc>
      <encodingStmt>
        <projectDesc>
          <p>Established in 2010, the goals of the <name ref="#Emma_B_Andrews_Diary_Project">Emma B. Andrews Diary Project</name> include the transcription and digitization of a wide range of primary historical material from the <orgName ref="#'Golden_Age'">'Golden Age'</orgName> of <orgName ref="#Egyptian">Egyptian</orgName> archaeology at the end of the 19th and beginning of the 20th centuries. A founding partner of <name ref="#Newbook_Digital_Texts">Newbook Digital Texts</name> (www.newbookdigitaltexts.org), the <name ref="#EBA_Diary_Project">EBA Diary Project</name> offers undergraduate and graduate digital humanities education and internships at the <name ref="#University_of_Washington">University of Washington.</name> <persName ref="#Andrews_Emma_B">Emma B. Andrews</persName> is best remembered for her association with the millionaire lawyer turned archaeologist/art and antiquities collector, <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore M. Davis.</persName> Traveling to <placeName ref="#Egypt">Egypt</placeName> with him between 1889 and 1912, she kept detailed journals of these voyages along the <orgName ref="#Nile">Nile,</orgName> including his important yet under-reported excavations of over 20 significant tombs in the <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">Valley of the Kings.</placeName> <persName ref="#Emma">Emma</persName> provides a vital commentary on the archaeology and pioneering Egyptologists of the time, painting a revealing picture of the lives of the colonial gentry and the cultural and scientific literati in at the dawn of the twentieth century. Analysis of the content of her diaries, along with a broad range of additional primary source material, will afford scholars information about important historical resources for the first time.</p>
        </projectDesc>
      </encodingStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-11-19" type="entry">
            <dateline><placeName ref="#New_York">New York</placeName> - <date when="1897-11-19">Nov. 19. <choice><sic>1997</sic><corr>1897</corr></choice></date>.</dateline>
            <p><pb n="134"/> (next page is duplicate 134) It is now 6 days since we sailed from <placeName ref="#New_York">New York</placeName> at 10 A.M. on Nov. 13 on the <name type="boat" ref="#Kaiser_Wilhelm_II">Kaiser Wilhelm II</name>. <placeName ref="#Beal_Montgomery">Montgomery Beal</placeName>, Mrs. Davis's nephew with us. We have had a pleasant passage though very little sun - pleasant passengers too, many friends and acquaintances. <persName ref="#Ward_Howe_Julia">Mrs. Julie Ward Howe</persName>, with her daughter <persName ref="#Elliot_Mrs">Mrs. John Elliot</persName>, and her husband. <persName ref="#Norman_Mrs">Mrs. Norman</persName>, with her daughter <persName ref="#Norman_Mable">Mable</persName>, and son <persName ref="#Norman_Reginald">Reginald</persName> from <placeName ref="#Newport">Newport</placeName>. <persName ref="#Freufanell-Cibo_Countess">Countess Freufanell&#233;-Cibo</persName> of <placeName ref="#Foligno">Foligno</placeName> - introduced to us by <placeName ref="#Cortazzo_Madame">Madame Cortazzo</placeName>. <persName ref="#Wilson_Mrs">Mrs. Wilson</persName> of <placeName ref="#Gibraltar">Gibraltar</placeName>, who crossed with us last year - a bride then, with her husband, <persName ref="#Wilson_Capt_Stewart">Capt. Stewart Wilson</persName> of the <orgName ref="#Royal_Engineers">Royal Engineers</orgName> - and <persName ref="#Rathbone_Marion_Lucy">Mrs. Robert Shaw Oliver</persName> with her 3 girls from <placeName ref="#Albany">Albany</placeName>, going out to <placeName ref="#Florence">Florence</placeName> for the winter. So that it was like a reception all the way over. Every afternoon they all came to tea with me in the saloon - and every evening <persName ref="#Ward_Howe_Julia">Mrs. Julia Ward Howe</persName> played whist with me and <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and <persName ref="#Whitehead_Mr">Mr. Whitehead</persName>, who with <persName ref="#Whitehead_Mrs">Mrs. W</persName>. is also on board, and a very good game the delightful old lady played. We have with us also, <persName ref="#Anderson_Hendrick">Hendrick Anderson</persName>, the young sculptor, going back to <persName ref="#Rome">Rome</persName>, who has been with us so much this summer. Today we passed the <placeName ref="#Azores">Azores</placeName> - not keeping to the south as we did last year, when we passed the large and important island of <placeName ref="#Sao_Miguel">San Miguel</placeName>. Today we passed in between <placeName ref="#Faial">Fayal</placeName> and <placeName ref="#Sao_Jose">San Jose</placeName> - then past <placeName ref="#Sao_Jorge">St. George</placeName>, and along the beautiful island of <placeName ref="Terciero">Tanicera</placeName>, <placeName ref="#Sao_Miguel">San Miguel</placeName> being just visible away to the south and east. We have very comfortable rooms and the ship is clean and comfortable - though she rolls even in these smooth seas. She has the nickname of Rolling Billy.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-11-19" type="entry">
            <dateline><placeName ref="#New_York">New York</placeName> - <date when="1897-11-19">Nov. 19. 1997</date>.</dateline>
            <p><pb n="134"/> (duplicate of the above page) Nov. 19. 1997. It is now 6 days since we sailed from <placeName ref="#New_York">New York</placeName> at 10 A.M. on Nov. 13 on the <name type="boat" ref="#Kaiser_Wilhelm_II">Kaiser Wilhelm II</name>. &#8230;...................... duplicate page 134</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-11-22" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1897-11-22">Monday. Nov. 22</date>.</dateline>
            <p><pb n="135"/> Arrived at 9:30 this morning - bright but with heavy squalls of wind. <persName ref="#Wilson_Capt_Stewart">Capt. Wilson</persName> came out to meet his wife - and the sea was so rough, she went off in the tug with all the others. I did not go, as past experience at <placeName ref="#Gibraltar">Gibraltar</placeName> in the rain, warned me not to venture. So the <persName ref="#Freufanell-Cibo_Countess">Countess</persName> and I wandered about and talked and grew weary enough before the others came back late for lunch.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-11-25" type="entry">
            <dateline><placeName ref="#Naples">Naples</placeName>. <date when="1897-11-25">Nov. 25</date>.</dateline>
            <p>Arrived at 7 A.M. the <placeName ref="#Mediterranean">Mediterranean</placeName> proving as quiet as the <placeName ref="#Atlantic_Ocean">Atlantic</placeName>. Came to the <name type="hotel" ref="#Grand_Hotel">Grand Hotel</name>, where we found <persName ref="#Buttles_Lizzie">Lizzie</persName>, <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and <persName ref="#Buttles_Mary">Mary</persName> waiting for us. After a comfortable breakfast before the fire in our pleasant sitting room overlooking the bay and <placeName ref="#Vesuvius">Vesuvius</placeName>, we sat about and talked and pleasantly idled away the hours, rejoicing to be on land once more. <placeName ref="#Vesuvius">Vesuvius</placeName>, after his late activity, is again quiet. The <persName ref="#Freufanell-Cibo_Countess">Countess</persName> came to lunch with us, and the <persName ref="#Oliver_family">Olivers</persName>. Then we all said goodbye, and they went off to <placeName ref="#Florence">Florence</placeName>.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-12-01" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1897-12-01">Dec. 1. Wednesday</date>.</dateline>
            <p>Our days in <placeName ref="#Naples">Naples</placeName> have been rather dull. Weather bad. <persName ref="#Buttles_Lizzie">Lizzie</persName> with a bad cold - <persName ref="#Buttles_Mary">Mary</persName> really ill with one - and <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> just recovering from a severe attack of influenza. <persName ref="#Anderson_Hendrick">Anderson</persName> went up to <placeName ref="#Rome">Rome</placeName> 2 days ago. We enjoyed going to the sculpture gallery of the museum with him. <persName ref="#Buttles_Lizzie">Lizzie</persName> and <persName ref="#Buttles_Mary">Mary</persName> took last nights train to <placeName ref="#Florence">Florence</placeName>. <persName ref="#Taylor_Mrs">Mrs. Taylor</persName> suddenly appeared this afternoon, having arrived from <placeName ref="#Genoa">Genoa</placeName> on the <name type="boat" ref="#SS_Konigin_Luise">K&#246;nigen Luise</name> <pb n="136"/> - came to the boat about 5 - found her crowded - I was bored - comfortable deck rooms - <persName ref="#Bend_Mrs">Mrs. Bend</persName>, <persName ref="#Bend_Amy">Amy</persName> and <persName ref="#Bend_Beatrice">Beatrice</persName> joined us last night.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-12-02" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1897-12-02">Thursday. Dec. 2d</date>.</dateline>
            <p>Passed <placeName ref="#Sicily">Sicily</placeName> this morning - <placeName ref="#Mt_Etna">Aetna</placeName> covered with snow - cold wind blowing - sea calm as a river.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-12-04" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1897-12-04">Saturday. Dec. 4</date>.</dateline>
            <p>We will reach <placeName ref="#Port_Said">Port Said</placeName> tonight. The <name type="boat" ref="#SS_Konigin_Luise">K&#246;nigen Luise</name> has beautiful great decks - but she is tremendously over crowded with passengers for <placeName ref="#Egypt">Egypt</placeName>. About 100 for <placeName ref="#Port_Said">Port Said</placeName> - we have decided some of us to go to <placeName ref="#Ismailia">Ismaelia</placeName> - the <persName ref="#Norman_family">Normans</persName> and <persName ref="#Bend_family">Bends</persName> never having seen the canal. <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> - <name type="hotel" ref="#Shepheards_Hotel">Shepheards Hotel</name>.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-12-07" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1897-12-07">Tuesday - Dec. 7</date>.</dateline>
            <p>We reached <placeName ref="#Port_Said">Port Said</placeName> Saturday at midnight - the usual fracas and disagreeable features of coaling all night. Ports, doors, everything closed - noise etc. - to my thinking there is nothing gained by going on to <placeName ref="#Ismailia">Ismailia</placeName> - better solve the unpleasant problem by quitting the steamer at any hour she arrives, and accepting anything that can be found at <placeName ref="#Port_Said">Port Said</placeName>. As it was, we slept little were very slow in getting through the canal next day, sticking several times, and did not reach <placeName ref="#Ismailia">Ismailia</placeName> until 7:30 - waited some time for the tender, and did not land before 9:30 - a passable supper - and bed rooms - <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and <pb n="137"/> I in one room - my bed so chill and damp, that I have suffered much from it - we reached <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> at 6 P.M. and were soon installed in our old corner rooms to the north - feeling very much at home. We drove down to the boat this morning - finding her almost in sailing condition. There remain however, all the stores to be unpacked, and a thousand little things to be arranged and settled.</p> 
        </div>
        <!--who is mattar? theorizing that he is a member of the crew like abdul and ibrahim-->
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-12-26" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1897-12-26">Sunday after Christmas. Dec. 26</date>. <placeName ref="#Bedouin">Beduin</placeName>. </dateline>
            <p>At last we are settled in this our delightful little winter home - and it would be entirely perfect had I only my dear <name type="#animal" ref="#Toby_Dog">Toby</name> here! How glad I am to quit all that entourage at <name type="hotel" ref="#Shepheards_Hotel">Shepheards</name>, I cannot even express to myself! I have had 10 days of real illness - several days in my bed. In all my life I have never been so ill - the winter is a bad one in <placeName ref="#Egypt">Egypt</placeName> - cold - high winds - and little sunshine. We kept a steady fire in our sitting room. Everyone has a cold. <persName ref="#Bend_Mrs">Mrs. Bend</persName> and <persName ref="#Norman_Mrs">Mrs. Norman</persName> half the time in their beds. We found our faithful <persName ref="#Salah_Mohammed">Mohammed Salah</persName> waiting for us at the station when we arrived, and <persName ref="#Abdul">Abdul</persName> and <persName ref="#Ibrahim">Ibrahim</persName>. We had our Xmas this morning, and gave the men all around, shawls and knives and cigarettes - good woolen underclothes for <persName ref="#Fuli_Rais">Rais Fuli</persName>, <persName ref="#Abdul">Abdul</persName>, <persName ref="#Mattar">Mattar</persName>, and <persName ref="#Ibrahim">Ibrahim</persName>. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> had bought for <persName ref="#Fuli_Rais">Rais Fuli</persName> in <placeName ref="#Paris">Paris</placeName> last spring a first class field glass - and has his name put in gilt letters on the case - and I had extra things for <persName ref="#Abdul">Abdul</persName>,<persName ref="#Mattar"> Mattar</persName> and <persName ref="#Ibrahim">Ibrahim</persName>. The men had - sheep - and I went into town this afternoon <pb n="138"/> to find all the shops closed. Last evening being Christmas night, <persName ref="#Bend_Mrs">Mrs. Bend</persName> and <persName ref="#Hardy_Jean #Wilson_Alice"> the girls</persName> dined with us. The first dinner of our new cook - and a very good dinner it was - quite admirable - they were quite impressed.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-12-27" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1897-12-27">Monday, Dec. 27</date>.</dateline>
            <p><persName ref="#Monty">Monty</persName> and I paid a hurried visit to <placeName ref="#Hatouns">Hatoun's</placeName> and <placeName ref="#Parvis">Parvis's</placeName> shops this morning, and hurried back - we got off at 12:30 in a very good wind and reached <placeName ref="#Al_Badrashayn">Bedrashein</placeName> in less than 3 hours - have dawdelled away much time in fear of our big sail, which proves too big. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> has decided to have it made smaller tomorrow, and to kill two birds with one stone by visiting <placeName ref="#Ṣaqqâra">Sakkarah</placeName>, which we did not intend doing until we come down - as I am not now very fit. So <persName ref="#Fuli_Rais">Rais Fuli</persName> took the 6 o'clock train to <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> to fetch the sail makers. Cold.</p> 
            <!--lol emma is obviously not a fan of the cold-->
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-12-28" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1897-12-28">Tuesday, Dec. <choice><sic>18</sic><corr>28</corr></choice></date>. </dateline>
            <p>They all made an early start for <persName ref="#Ṣaqqâra">Sakkarah</persName> this morning - even <persName ref="#Jones_Daniel">Jones</persName> and <persName ref="#Burgnoyne_Amelie">Amilie</persName>. I sent <persName ref="#Burgnoyne_Amelie">Amilie</persName> as she had never seen it. They all condoled with me on going off, because I was to be left all alone for the day. But after they got away, I smiled and began to enjoy myself! I mended 2 sponge bags - I explored the little store closet under the stairs, arranged and consensed it - put in order the linen closet and my dress closet, re-arranged <persName ref="#Abdul">Abdul's</persName> sideboard for him - the bookcase and all the small things - and after a delicious little lunch, with <persName ref="#Abdul">Abdul</persName> waiting upon me so quietly and faithfully, I took a book and stretch myself upon the divan in the saloon - where I could neither read or sleep <pb n="139"/> because of enjoying the delicious quiet and repose. The first quiet day I have had for almost a year! I enjoyed the occasional bursts of sunshine through the window, across the mossy green carpet, and the big green chair, making a delicate harmony with the line of young wheat growing on the bank - and the palms tossing their branches above. The <name type="boat" ref="#Ramesis_boat">Rameses</name> came up from <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> - on which are <persName ref="#Whitehead_Mr #Whitehead_Mrs">Mr. and Mrs. Whitehead</persName> - and <persName ref="#Whitehead_Mr">Mr. W</persName>. came over to make me a little visit - reporting <persName ref="#Whitehead_Mrs">Mrs. W</persName>. afraid to venture out in the cold, and only 35 passengers. I asked him why he had not gone to see wonderful <persName ref="#Ṣaqqâra">Sakkarah</persName>, and he said "he thought he would get enough of temples and pyramids before he got out of <placeName ref="#Egypt">Egypt</placeName>"! Our people came back about 5, raving about their delicious day. We find our little stoves most comfortable and cheerful - we could hardly exist without them. All day long, the big sail has been stretched on shore, with the men ripping and cutting - now she is pronounced to be all right and is again in place on the boom. Every inch of the boat outside and in, was painted last summer, in admirable fashion, making a great improvement in the <placeName ref="#Bedouin">Beduin</placeName>. I never saw more beautiful paint - the tints so perfect - and the finish like porcelain. We seem now to be quite perfect.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-12-29" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1897-12-29">Wednesday - Dec. 29</date>. </dateline> 
            <p>The day began cold, with a south wind which changed to north about one o'clock - and we sailed away until 4 P.M. when it veered to west, and we tied up, after having made 8 miles - the sail proves quite perfect. <pb n="140"/></p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-12-30" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1897-12-30">Dec. 30. Thursday</date>. </dateline>
            <p>We made an early start this morning before 7 - the wind good and strengthening all the time - at 1 o'clock we were driven on a sand bank - but pulled to the anchor and got away and sailed finely until about 6 P.M. when we stopped for the night near <placeName ref="#Al_Wasta">Wasta</placeName>, having made about 33 miles - very cold and windy. We are going to have a hard time on the river this year I fear, as it is so uncommonly low - and the current is running so strong. It has rained from time to time today.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-12-31" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1897-12-31">31 Dec. Friday evening</date>. </dateline>
            <p>We have been sitting about since dinner, talking and reading. I have been reading aloud in <bibl><author><persName ref="#Sayce_Archibald">Sayce</persName></author>'s "<title ref="#The_Egypt_of_the_Hebrews_and_Herodotos">Egypt of the Hebrews</title>"</bibl> then <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore<persName> read from <bibl><author><persName ref="#Tennyson_Alfred"></persName></author>"<title ref="#In_Memoriam_AHH">In Memoriam</title>"</bibl>. It is very still and quiet - not a sound to be heard outside - the men all asleep - not a sound - and I intend as I always do, to see the old year out. It is cold - but no wind - we had a great surprise this morning. I knew it was very cold, and <persName ref="#Jones_Daniel">Jones</persName> had come into my room and lighted my little stove, which made a cheerful light in my darkened room, it being hardly past 7 o'clock - when I heard <persName ref="#Monty">Monty</persName> asking if he could come in, that he had something to show me. So in he came, wrapped in his bathrobe with his hat on, and a little tray in his hand on which was heaped a little pile of snow, or more strictly speaking frost! He said the decks were white with it - that there was a dense fog, and the extreme cold had turned it to snow, wherever it touched. All the men were tremendously impressed - only one or two every having seen anything of the kind before. <pb n="141"/> It took the sun a long time to dissipate the fog - but at last the clearest and brightest day we have had since we came, evolved itself - and after a general cleaning and rubbing and drying of the decks, we sailed away in a very light wind which continued until nearly 8 o'clock - when we tied up. I have been on deck most of the time - air so delicious -dry - and with a real snap of cold in it. We have made about 12 miles.
            </persName>
            </persName></p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-01-01" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-01-01">January 1 - 1898</date>. </dateline>
            <p>The New Year dawned cold and dark - when I first looked out of my window, the river was as smooth as a mirror, and the clouds looked like snow. It was not until after 9 o'clock that the sun came out, and shown fitfully and dimly. The wind too was fitful - however we sailed as we could until nearly 7 o'clock - the moon being half full. Passed <placeName ref="#Benisoef">Benisoef</placeName> about noon and cannot be far from <placeName ref="#Fashen">Fashon</placeName> tonight - making about 11 miles.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-01-02" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-01-02">2d Sunday after Christmas. Jan. 2</date>. </dateline>
            <p>Have made 48 miles 0 and are now lying 2 miles south of <placeName ref="#Shaykh_Fadl">Sheik Fadl</placeName>. Still cold. The other afternoon I saw a large fox running along the waters edge - apparently disturbed at our nearness. However by the time <persName ref="#Jones_Daniel">Jones</persName> got his gun out he disappeared over the bank.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-01-03" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-01-03">Jan. 3. Monday</date>. </dateline>
            <p><pb n="142"/> We made 30 miles - starting at 7:30 and pulled up at <placeName ref="#Al_Minya">Minieh</placeName> at one o'clock. All of the rest went into the town for our mail and some shopping. The wind was so strong and the dust and sand so filled the air, that I stopped at home. Even the deck was impossible - and the wind increasing we have not moved.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-01-04" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-01-04">Tuesday. Jan. 4</date>. </dateline>
            <p>Started soon after 6:30 this A.M. a clear, brilliant morning, the wind good increasing to strong. We sailed splendidly without a break until 6 o'clock or thereabouts, making 55-1/2 miles. The air was softer, and the sun bright, the afternoon delicious. I was on deck from 11 A.M. to 5 P.M.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-01-05" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-01-05">Wednesday. 5 Jan</date>. </dateline>
            <p>Still cold, with light north wind growing stronger - we made 6 miles, when in the first great turn of the beginning of the <placeName ref="#Abu_Fudah_Jabal">Abufedah Mts</placeName>. we were obliged to furl our sail and anchor. The steamer <name type="boat" ref="#">Tewfik</name>, with Mr. <persName ref="#Vanderbilt_Cornelius">Cornelius Vanderbilt</persName> passed up - giving us a salute as he passed. We tracked later, for about a mile to a good place for the night. Passed <placeName ref="#Manfalût">Manfalout</placeName> about noon, and altogether made 9 miles. Cold with a little rain this evening. <pb n="143"/></p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-01-06" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-01-06">6 Jan. Thursday</date>. </dateline>
            <p>A cold day - the morning very quiet until nearly noon, when we pulled up our stakes and started among the crowd of working boats, only to find we had left one of our sailors on shore, who had been sent to find some vegetables. An exciting time for a few moments, when we finally got under way with a fair wind increasing to strong - and we did some splendid and difficult sailing - it was like yachting. We saw the minarets of <placeName ref="#Asyut">Assiut</placeName> all the afternoon appear and disappear - but as usual seemed to get no nearer to them. After we tied up, the wind began to blow, and rain poured smartly for half an hour. The sailors made a great row on deck, getting the furniture together and covered and the awnings up. Made 18 miles.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-01-07" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-01-07">7 Jan. Friday</date>. </dateline>
            <p>A beautiful day - almost warm - and almost like Egypt. Light winds and some tracking brought us early in the afternoon to <placeName ref="#Asyut">Assiut</placeName>. The <name type="boat" ref="#Nitocris">Nitassis</name> passed down. Got a big mail of papers and letters - and had, for the first time some positive information in regard to the sudden move of troops from <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> to the <placeName ref="#Sudan">Sudan</placeName>. It was at first reported that the emergency was so great, that most of <persName ref="#Cook_Thomas">Cook's</persName> steamers would be required, as he has the contract with Government to carry troops - but it seems that was an exaggeration. They go by rail to <placeName>Nag Hamadi,</placeName> and then are shipped. An officer told <persName>Theodore</persName> today, that the finishing of the railway between <placeName ref="#Naj_Hammadi">Nag Hamadi</placeName> and <placeName ref="#Aswan">Assouan</placeName>, was to be pushed on to rapid finish. <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I took a drive into <placeName ref="#Asyut">Assiut</placeName> this afternoon. A <pb n="144"/> very large and growing town - especially the European quarter - near the river, and <orgName ref="#American_Mission">American Mission College</orgName>. We waited some time at the gate of a garden, where <persName ref="#Abdul">Abdul</persName>, and a kind of rais belonging to the carriage, a mere bundle of rags, with a smiling yellow face above, who seemed to be the elder brother of the two wretched little horses, went to get me some flowers. We thought we had never seen so many varieties of humanity as passed and repassed continually - with many it would have been hard from appearance to have drawn the line between the beast and the human. The <name type="boat" ref="#Ramesis">Ramesis the Third</name> came to the landing near us, and a small Gage steamer, with <persName ref="#de_Bourdon_Henri_Prince">Prince Henri de Bourbon</persName> and party on board. We are having splendid nights - the moon just full. Made 10 miles today.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-01-08" type="entry">
            <dateline><placeName ref="#Asyut">Assiut</placeName>. <date when="1898-01-08">8 Jan. Saturday</date>. </dateline>
            <p>Still here - having devoted the day to a general cleaning - to getting something done to our oven - to doing a big wash - <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I took another drive this morning - into the town, and making the circuit of it. It is a holiday - being the 8th anniversary of the accession of the <persName ref="#Bey_Abbas_II_Helmy">Khodive</persName>. The town was therefore crowded - and we drove through solid masses of turbaned humanity. We had no one with us but our driver - but we did not meet with the slightess rudeness - though it was as well perhaps that we did not understand all that was said to us. The moon makes such beauty, rising above the splendid palm and scent groves, that line the shore of the river opposite <placeName ref="#Asyut">Assiut</placeName>. <pb n="145"/></p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-01-09" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-01-09">First Sunday after the Epiphany. 9th Jan</date>. </dateline>
            <p>We have had the warmest day of the year - and a very still one too - but have made <placeName ref="#Abu_Tij">Aboutig</placeName> where we are not lying, 15 miles from <placeName ref="#Asyut">Assiut</placeName> - <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and <persName ref="#Monty">Monty</persName> walked into the town, although it was almost dark when we tied up - and said it seemed very clean and charming. It always looks inviting, with its 2 handsome twin minarets showing above the trees. Made 15 miles.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-01-10" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-01-10">10 Jan. Monday</date>. </dateline>
            <p>We had slipped along under light winds today, until we are within a short distance of <placeName ref="#Tahta">Tahtah</placeName>, and suppose we have made 25 miles. Warmer - and splendid moonlight nights.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-01-11" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-01-11">Tuesday, 11 Jan</date>. </dateline>
            <p>We are lying at <placeName ref="#Sohag">Sohag</placeName> - after a fine day of difficult sailing - beginning about 10 o'clock. Very difficult bends of the river - we turn and turn upon our path - made 28 miles. <placeName ref="#Sohag">Sohag</placeName> is on a hight bank with its handsome river front with its very good houses; looks quite unique for Egypt. We will wait here for the man who has been sent up from <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName>, with the new wash bowl for my room.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-01-12" type="entry">
            <dateline><placeName ref="#Akhmim">Akmim</placeName>. <date when="1898-01-12">12 Jan</date>. </dateline>
            <p>We came the 5 miles from <placeName ref="#Sohag">Sohag</placeName> this afternoon, having waited all day for the plumber to finish his work in my room. We went for a <pb n="146"/> walk after breakfast, and seeing a little dahabeah flying the American flag, and hearing from one of our sailors that it was a "Hakim", we thought it might be some of the people of the <orgName ref="#American_Mission">American Mission School</orgName>, as we know they sometimes go out in this way - and wishing much to talk to them, we went down to call. But we found the "Hakim" was a dentist with a very Hebrew name, and his card bore the title of dentist to the <persName ref="#Bey_Abbas_II_Helmy">Khodive</persName>. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName>, asked him if he would like to see our boat, thereupon he came, bringing with him a most respectable citizen of <placeName ref="#Sohag">Sohag</placeName>, who he introduced as one of the "old Egyptian nobles" - whatever that might be. He then asked if he could bring the <persName ref="#Sohag_Mudir">Mudir</persName> of the district in the afternoon - and about 3 o'clock they came, in some state. The <persName ref="#Sohag_Mudir">Mudir</persName> was very well dressed in European fashion - and spoke admirable English - had a pleasant polished manner - and seemed much interested in the boat.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-01-13" type="entry">
            <dateline><placeName ref="#Belliana">Belliana</placeName>, <date when="1898-01-13">13 Jan</date>. </dateline> 
            <p>Had a good sailing day - the wind very strong at times. Struck a sand bank sharply - and had some difficulty in getting off. Passed <placeName ref="#Al_Manshāh">Monshieh</placeName> and <placeName ref="#Jirjā">Girgeh</placeName> - the day very cold - with high wind.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-01-14" type="entry">
            <dateline><placeName ref="#Naj_Hammadi">Nag Mamadi</placeName>. <date when="1898-01-14">14 Jan</date>. </dateline>
            <p>A fine warm day - wind light - reached this place at 4 o'clock - found the R.R. bridge closed - and after pulling up, heard that it would not open again today. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and the rest went for a walk - and met and talked with the Engineer of the bridge - an Englishman - who <pb n="147"/> said it was entirely in the hands of the Government lately - as trains were running all the times, carrying troops to <placeName ref="#Aswan">Assouan</placeName> and the front. They saw a large barge with horses, and about 5 camels, and ammunition cars, waiting for the Lancashire regiment that comes up tomorrow. The bridge opens at 6 in the morning, and we hope to get through at once. Made 18 miles.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-01-15" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-01-15">Saturday, 15 Jan</date>. </dateline>
            <p>Got through the bridge this morning at 8 o'clock by towing - arrangements there very good. A strong north wind was too much for us, and we had to stop sailing long before noon, and tied up to the bank. About half past 5 we started and slowly moved along in a light wind for 2 miles, when we stopped - judging we had made ruing the day 10 miles.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-01-16" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-01-16">2d Sunday after <name type="event" ref="#Epiphany">Epiphany</name>. 16 Jan</date>. </dateline>
            <p>High wind in morning - laid up most of the day - sailed at 4 o'clock for an hour some 3 miles below <placeName ref="#Keneh">Keneh</placeName> - warm and pleasant. Made 17 miles.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-01-17" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-01-17">Monday, 17 Jan</date>. </dateline>
            <p>Started early - light wind and tracking made <placeName ref="#Denderah">Denderah</placeName> at noon. The day warm and delicious. Rode out to the <placeName ref="#Temple_of_Dendera">Temple</placeName> after lunch. My new saddle a great success. We had excellent donkeys and enjoyed the ride immensely. <persName ref="#Petrie_William">Flinders Petrie</persName> is excavating near <placeName ref="#Denderah">Denderah</placeName>. We could see <pb n="148"/> the dust of the excavations - and the comfortable looking house he has built there. As we reached the river again, we saw the <name type="boat" ref="#Isis">Isis</name> with an English flag passing - and a few moments after, the <name type="boat" ref="#Alma">Alma</name> appeared, and we are lying just behind her tonight 5 miles above <placeName ref="#Keneh">Keneh</placeName>.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-01-18" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-01-18">Tuesday, 18 Jan</date>. <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName></dateline>
            <p>We reached <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName> at 6:30 this evening, having made a fine run of 44 miles. A rather exciting day too, as the <name type="boat" ref="#Isis">Isis</name> was just ahead, the <name type="boat" ref="#Alma">Alma</name> at our heels, and the <name type="boat" ref="#Gazelle">Gazelle</name> behind her. The wind was so light, it was hardly a zephyr and we stole along by the town like a ghost - and came into our old place just under the <placeName ref="#Temple_of_Dendera">Castle</placeName>.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-01-19" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-01-19">Wednesday, 19 Jan</date>. </dateline>
            <p>We have a very good plan to lie - in a little cove just under the <placeName ref="#Temple_of_Dendera">Castle</placeName> - where no one can pull in ahead of us. The <name type="boat" ref="#Alma">Alma</name> lies, above, around the corner - and the <name type="boat" ref="#Gazelle">Gazelle</name> behind us. The <name type="boat" ref="#Zet_el_Nil">Zenet-el Nil</name>, with her owner <persName ref="#Golenischeff_Vladimir">M. Goliniescheff</persName>, the <name type="Hyksos_steamer">Hyksos</name>, with the <persName ref="#Shephard_family">Shephards</persName> - and the <name type="boat" ref="#Gamilla">Gamilla</name> flying the German flag, are in port. <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName> looks cold, and quiet <persName ref="#Achmed_Rais">Achmed</persName> was waiting with his donkeys this morning, and we had just started, when we met <persName ref="#Whitehead_Mr #Whitehead_Mrs">Mr. and Mrs. Whitehead</persName> who are on the <name type="boat" ref="#Ramesis">Ramesis</name>, walking down to see us. Se we dismounted and walked back with them - as <persName ref="#Whitehead_Mrs">Mrs. W</persName>. had not seen the boat, and they were to leave for <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName>, at noon. Then we walked back to the <name type="hotel" ref="#Luxor_Hotel">Luxor Hotel</name> with them - there mounted our donkeys, <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and I, as <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and <persName ref="#Monty">Monty</persName> were visiting the <placeName ref="#Luxor_Temple">Luxor temple</placeName> <pb n="149"/>. We rode out towards <placeName ref="#Karnak">Karnak</placeName>, but it was too late to visit the temples, and stopping for a moment at the <name type="hotel" ref="#Luxor_Hotel">Hotel</name>, we got home just in time for lunch. I stayed at home in the afternoon - enjoying our delightful deck, and the matchless and unique view across the stretch of the river, and the plain beyond, of the mountains. All day, the river has been so smooth, that the mountains with their soft, yellow pink have been reflected in it. Mr. <persName ref="#Stokes_James">James Stokes</persName> called late in the afternoon. He is one of the unfortunate passengers on the <name type="boat" ref="#Ramesis">Rameses the Great</name> who were unexpectedly disembarked here for several days, while the steamer was ordered forward to pull off some barges aground, full of stores and ammunition for the army, and to tow them to <placeName ref="#Aswan">Assouan</placeName>.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-01-20" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-01-20">Thursday, 20 Jan</date>. </dateline>
            <p>This afternoon we all went to the Races - which were sufficiently amusing - saw the <persName ref="#Vanderbilt_family">Vanderbilts</persName> who are here on their steamer the "<name type="boat" ref="#Tewfik">Tewfik</name>" and met unexpectedly <persName ref="#Taylor_Florence">Florence Taylor</persName> - who with her mother are up the river with the <persName ref="#Thubron_family">Thubrons</persName> in the <name type="boat" ref="#Indiana_boat">Indiana</name>, of the <orgName ref="#American_Line">Anglo-American line</orgName>. They (the <persName ref="#Taylor_family">Taylors</persName>) came afterwards to the boat, with <persName ref="#Scott_John_Sir">Sir John Scott</persName>, and we asked <persName ref="#Taylor_Mrs">Mrs. T</persName>. and <persName ref="#Taylor_Florence">Florence</persName> to come back and dine with us - which they did, we sending the felucca for them. They were enchanted with our excellent dinner, poor starved things - a merry evening. They said for <placeName ref="#Nice">Nice</placeName>, Feb. 12.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-01-21" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-01-21">Friday, 21 Jan></date>. </dateline>
            <p>A delightful afternoon at <placeName ref="#Medinet_Habu">Medinet Habu</placeName>. The <placeName ref="#Temple_of_Ramesses_III">temple</placeName> always so <pb n="150"/> interesting is now swept and almost garnished - and completely excavated.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-01-22" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-01-22">Saturday, 22 Jan</date>. </dateline>
            <p><persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and <persName ref="#Monty">Monty</persName> went to <placeName ref="#Karnac">Karnac</placeName> this morning - <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I in the felucca to the <persName ref="#Wetzstein_Dr">German Consul</persName>s, to see his antiquities. In the afternoon we stayed at home for a quiet reading on deck, and <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and <persName ref="#Monty">Monty</persName> went to <placeName ref="#Der_el_Bahari">Der-el-Bahri</placeName> - the air misty - and slight clouds everywhere. Late in the afternoon we went to return a visit to the <name type="boat" ref="#Hyksos">Hyksos</name> - and also to call on the ladies (4 of them) on the <name type="boat" ref="#Alma">Alma</name>. <persName ref="#Broderick_Miss">Miss Broderick</persName>, whom I was very anxious to meet is one of them - and we fell to talking at once on the <orgName ref="#Egypt_Exploration_Society">Egypt Exploration Society's</orgName> affairs.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-01-23" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-01-23">3d Sunday after Epiphany. 23 Jan</date>. </dateline>
            <p>This afternoon <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName>, <persName ref="#Monty">Monty</persName> and I went up to <placeName ref="#Palmenburg">the Castle</placeName> to call - and after we got home, <persName ref="#Broderick_Miss">Miss Broderick</persName> and <persName ref="#Morton_Miss">Miss Morton</persName> came to tea - and young <persName ref="#Cutting">Cutting</persName>.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-01-24" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-01-24">24 Jan. Monday</date>. </dateline>
            <p>This morning <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I rode to <placeName ref="#Karnak">Carnac</placeName> - but unfortunately forgot our tickets and came home - stopping at the <orgName ref="#American_Mission">American Mission</orgName> book store, for the new <bibl><author><persName ref="#Baedeker_Karl">Baedeker</persName></author><title ref="#Baedekers_Egypt"></title></bibl> - <persName ref="#Huhatt_Mr #Huhatt_Mrs">Mr. and Mrs. Huhatt</persName> came to tea - and <persName ref="#Broderick_Miss">Miss Broderick</persName> and <persName ref="#Morton_Miss">Miss Morton</persName> to dinner. A pleasant evening. <name type="event" ref="#Ramadan">Ramadan</name> began today. <pb n="151"/></p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-01-25" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-01-25">Jan. 25. Tuesday</date>. </dateline>
            <p><persName ref="#Insinger_M #Insinger_Mme">M. and Mme. Insinger</persName> came this afternoon, and then sent down some beautiful flowers - <persName ref="#Dickson_Miss">Miss Dickson</persName> and <persName ref="#Kilburn_Miss">Miss Kilburn</persName> from the <name type="boat" ref="#Alma">Alma</name> came to tea. The start for <placeName ref="#Aswan">Assouan</placeName> tomorrow morning.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-01-26" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-01-26">Jan. 26. Wednesday</date>. </dateline>
            <p>A cold wind blowing all day - <persName ref="#Huhatt_Mr">Mr. Huhatt</persName> came to play chess with <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName>, and to stay to luncheon - after luncheon, as we were having coffee, <persName ref="#Somers_Clark_George">Mr. Somers-Clarke</persName> came in, having just arrived from <placeName ref="#El_Kab">El-Kab</placeName> with <persName ref="#Scott_John_Sir">Sir John Scott</persName> in his steamer. A pleasant visit - he telling about his new excavations at <placeName ref="#Kom_El_Ahmar">Kom el-Ahmar</placeName>, opposite <placeName ref="#El_Kab">El-Kab</placeName>, where they are finding tombs of great antiquity. He described a <objectName type="statue" ref="#Statue_of_Horus_of_Nekhen">hawk's head and body in bronze</objectName>, of finest workmanship. He has come for 2 days at <placeName ref="#Der_el_Bahari">El-Bahari</placeName>. This evening there is a real tempest going on - and additional ropes have been put out to the anchors - and it is cold.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-01-27" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-01-27">Thursday, Jan. 27</date>. </dateline>
            <p>A great blow last night - I never knew a harder one here - and for a long time I could not sleep. <persName ref="#Huhatt_Mr">Mr. Huhatt</persName> again came to play chess - <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I never put our heads out of the boat. All the canvass and awnings had to come down last night - <persName ref="#Shepheard_Miss">Miss Shephard</persName> and her friend came to tea. We shall be off tomorrow for <placeName ref="#Aswan">Assouan</placeName>. <pb n="152"/></p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-01-28" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-01-28">Friday, Jan. 28</date>. </dateline>
            <p>We got away about 9 this morning - but almost immediately the wind grew so strong that we soon took to the bank, and stayed until late in the afternoon - when we again started and made <placeName ref="#Erment">Erment</placeName> about dark. Cold.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-01-29" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-01-29">Saturday, Jan. 29</date>. </dateline>
            <p>Began tracking this morning at 8 - until we stopped at the <placeName ref="#Cook_Landing">Cook landing</placeName> to get the men we had sent off for milk and fruit. Then went on tracking for about 2 miles, and at noon began sailing, and brought up tonight at 6:30 5 miles above <placeName ref="#Esneh">Esneh</placeName> - having made 30 miles. A beautiful sail all the afternoon - part of the time in a crowd of gyassas, laden rails for the railway in the south - some of them with cattle. I was on deck all day - most lovely sunset effects - warmer, though cold enough.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-01-30" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-01-30">4th Sunday after Epiphany. Jan. 30</date>. <placeName ref="#Gebel_el_Silsila">Silsileh</placeName>. </dateline>
            <p>We have had a beautiful sailing day - and have made 52 miles. Yesterday we left the "<name type="boat" ref="#Gamilla">Gamilla</name>" lying at <placeName ref="#Esneh">Esneh</placeName> - soon after starting this morning we found her following us - and she is now lying ahead of us, having arrived soon after we did. Passed the "<name type="boat" ref="#Gazelle">Gazelle</name>" lying by. Passed <placeName ref="#El_Kab">El-Kab</placeName> about 11 o'clock and <placeName ref="#Edfu">Edfou</placeName> at one o'clock - and pulled up beyond <placeName ref="#Gebel_el_Silsila">Silsileh</placeName> at 6 o'clock. It has been warmer today, and is milder tonight. I have been on deck most of the day - such lovely colouring - and a sunset of of every colour of the rainbow - etherially delicate. Our moon is <pb n="153"/> now well on in her second quarter. The thermometer on my balcony this morning registered 36&#8304;.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-01-31" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-01-31">Monday. Jan. 31</date>. <placeName ref="#Aswan">Assouan</placeName>. </dateline>
            <p>Started about 8 o'clock, and sailed splendidly all day - arriving at 4;30. The river was so full of gyssas, all laden with railway materials and army supplies, that the sailing was exciting. Found <placeName ref="#Aswan">Assouan</placeName> so crowded with the same, and all the quay near the R.R. station given up to unloading - even <placeName ref="#Cook_Landing">Cook's landing</placeName> stage has been moved down by the barracks to avoid the noise and bustle. We did not know at first where we could land - but at last feeling our way along <placeName ref="#Elphantine">Elephantine</placeName>, we passed the <name type="boat" ref="#Alma">Alma</name>, and then the <name type="boat" ref="#Pocahantus">Pocahantus</name> - and pulled in behind the <name type="boat" ref="#Zenet-el-Nil">Zenet-el-Nil</name>, at the very beginning of the little sand gesireh - which is now indeed a very considerable island, so low is the river. However the bank is green with young wheat, and splendid palms above - and we congratulated ourselves, in spite of the fact that the <name type="boat" ref="#Osiris">Osiris</name> lies beyond the <name type="boat" ref="#Zenet-el-Nil">Zenet</name> - - then a great crowd of gyassas - then the <name type="boat" ref="#Isis">Isis</name> and <name type="boat" ref="#Gazelle">Gazelle</name> and then the <name type="boat" ref="#Istar">Istar</name>. Much warmer.</p> 
        </div>
        <!--church?-->
        <!--school-->
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-02-01" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-02-01">Tuesday, Feb. 1st</date>. </dateline>
            <p>Went over to the town this morning, and after sending a telegram, and getting our mail, we walked along the now really handsome quay, to the beginning of the barracks - where we found a new building - a <name>Catholic Church and School</name> - we walked into the <placeName>Church,</placeName> new and clean, and very good, with its marble floor, and arched roof - and sat down to <pb n="154"/> rest. Then to the Hotel to read the dispatches - I have never seen <placeName ref="#Aswan">Assouan</placeName> so busy - such crowds of boats, and business of unloading - such extraordinary crowds - much black, black faces. The long, well built quay now is really handsome - and many good new buildings. What a change from 10 years ago! To the <placeName ref="#Grenfell_Tomb">Grenfell tombs</placeName> - I waiting for the rest to clamber up and down, in the felucca with my book.</p> 
        </div>
        <!--temples??-->
        <!--book??-->
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-02-02" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-02-02">Wednesday, Feb. 2d</date>. </dateline>
            <p>This morning <persName ref="#Broderick_Miss">Miss Broderick</persName> and <persName ref="#Morton_Miss">Miss Morton</persName> came for a visit, and invited <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and me to dine on Friday evening. Then we went across the river to the <placeName ref="#Aswan_Bazaar">bazaar</placeName>. All the things looked rather tame to me. Met a whole procession of military camels - this afternoon <persName ref="#Sayce_Archibald">Mr. Sayce</persName> called - and as <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and <persName ref="#Monty">Monty</persName> were going for a drive, he asked <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and me to come to tea. So when the felucca came back from the other side, we went to the <name type="boat" ref="#Istar">Istar</name> - and had a pleasant visit -tea on deck - then down stairs to see his room, old fashioned boat - 22 ft. wide - while we are only 17-1/2. His saloon furnished in yellow brocatelle seemed enormous. We saw some good antiquities - and he showed us in the <orgName>French Expedition</orgName> book, the pictures of the <placeName ref="#Jewish_Temple_at_Elephantine">temples</placeName> on <placeName ref="#Elephantine">Elephantine</placeName>, which were destroyed by <persName ref="#Ali_Mohammed">Mohamet Ali</persName> to build a palace across the river, of which now no fragments remain. Invited <persName ref="#Sayce_Archibald">Prof. Sayce</persName> to dine on Saturday.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-02-03" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-02-03">Thursday, Feb. 3d</date>. </dateline>
            <p>To <placeName ref="#Philae">Philae</placeName> this morning - <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I, with <persName ref="#Abdul">Abdul</persName> in the train at 9 o'clock. Found all the <name type="boat" ref="#Alma">Alma</name> party at the <placeName ref="#Aswan_Train_Station">station</placeName> going too. The <pb n="155"/> <placeName ref="#Aswan_Train_Station">station</placeName> is rather difficult to get to now, so encumbered is all the territory around with military stores - and with railway materials waiting shipment for the <placeName ref="#Sudan">Soudan</placeName>. A jolting, rattling three quarters of an hour brought us to <placeName ref="#Shellal">Shellal</placeName> - where there is a military encampment and more supplies - and steamers and barges for shipping them. I found Little <persName ref="#Yemma">Yemma</persName> waiting at the <placeName ref="#Philae">Philae</placeName> landing - and he soon produced the delightful little <persName ref="#Dendowi">Dendowi</persName>, not much changed or grown. Found <persName ref="#Newman_Mr #Newman_Mrs">Mr. and Mrs. Newman</persName> in the long colannade - <persName ref="#Newman_Henry_Roderick">he</persName> painting as usual, and looking very well, both very kind and hospitable, and asked us down to their boat for coffee, and to see <persName ref="#Newman_Henry_Roderick">his</persName> Japanese sketches. After luncheon <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and I went down - and spent a very pleasant hour. Home in a cataract boat, bring <persName ref="#Broderick_Miss">Miss Broderick</persName> and <persName ref="#Dickson">Miss Dickson</persName> with us. It was more exciting this descent than I have ever known it. I suppose because the water is lower than usual.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-02-04" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-02-04">Friday Feb. 4</date>. </dateline>
            <p>Very warm all day - and tired with my expedition of yesterday I stayed at home all day. The rest went off late in the afternoon for a row around the island, and came home complaining of the heat. <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I went to dine with <persName ref="#Broderick_Miss">Miss Broderick</persName> on the <name type="boat" ref="#Alma">Alma</name> - and had a charming evening - with much music. <persName ref="#Kilburn_Miss">Miss Kilburn</persName> playing the violin admirable. The row down to their boat, and back again to ours in the wonderful moon-light was delightful. <pb n="156"/> (not numbered)</p> 
        </div>
        <!--ruins of convent-->
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-02-05" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-02-05">Saturday, Feb. 5</date>. </dateline>
            <p>At home all day until the afternoon, when I went with the rest in the felucca in the mountain of the <orgName>Coptic Dor.</orgName> I sat in the boat with my book, while the rest climbed through the hot sand, and found the ruined convent very interesting. <persName ref="#Sayce_Archibald">Mr. Sayce</persName> dined with us. He starts down tomorrow.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-02-06" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-02-06">Sunday. <name type="event" ref="#Septuagesima">Septuagesima</name>. Feb. 6</date>. </dateline>
            <p>It was so warm this morning that we none of us felt energetic and <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> proposed that we should sail up to the cataract, and get out on one of the islands. It was not much of a sail, as there was so little wind. But on coming to the first rapid water, we stopped at the nearest island of rock and sand, and walked about on the clean, hard sand, rifted over and over by the wind - and broken by huge masses of lovely rose granite. The <name type="boat" ref="#Istar">Istar</name> and the <name type="boat" ref="#Zenet_el_Nil">Zenet el-Nil</name> started down that afternoon.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-02-07" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-02-07">Monday, Feb. 7</date>. </dateline>
            <p>Warm and delightful all day. Did nothing. All the <name type="boat" ref="#Alma">Alma</name> people came to dine - and after dinner we went on deck to enjoy the wonderful moonlight. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> is growing anxious to get down the river, and talks of going on Thursday or Friday.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-02-08" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-02-08">Tuesday, Feb. 8</date>. </dateline>
            <p>The first thing <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> asked me as he came into breakfast this morning was "do you mind starting down today". I said "no", though I am always reluctant to leave <placeName ref="#Aswan">Assouan</placeName>. So after breakfast we crossed in the felucca to get our mail, pay a last visit to the <placeName ref="#Aswan_Bazaar">bazaar</placeName>, and send some telegrams, when we got back, we found the awnings being taken down and general preparations for the start. I wrote a hurried note to <persName ref="#Broderick_Miss">Miss Broderick</persName>, explaining our sudden change of plan - knowing that they had all gone to <placeName ref="#Philae">Philae</placeName> for the day. At 12;30 we were off, and a light south wind springing up we came along right merrily - when the wind failed - the head has been intense - 95&#8304; on my back balcony - but that has some reflection. Pulled up at 7 o'clock just as a sudden, howling wind came up and made our landing very difficult. Suppose we are about 5 miles from <placeName ref="#Kawm_Umbū">Kom Ombo</placeName>. The air is so charged with sand that the moon can just be seen, wan and almost green - and she has lost a little slice off her. Very warm tonight.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-02-09" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-02-09">Wednesday evening. Feb. 9</date>. </dateline>
            <p>We have only succeeded in making 2 miles today - when the N.W. wind increased so much we were forced to tie up, where we now lie. Since early this morning the same thick dust laden air of last evening - the sun showing dimly through it, like a pale full moon. Walking has been impossible - and we have stayed in doors.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-02-10" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-02-10">Thursday, Feb. 10</date>. </dateline>
            <p>We came down the 3 miles to <placeName ref="#Kawm_Umbū">Kom Ombo</placeName> where we now are. I wakened at 5 this morning, and found we were under way. After breakfast we went up to the <placeName ref="#Temple_Complex_at_Kom_Ombo">temple</placeName>, and spent two pleasant hours there - in <pb n="158"/> spite of high wind and the dust of the excavators outside the <placeName ref="#Temple_Complex_at_Kom_Ombo">temple</placeName> wall. While we were there the "<name type="boat" ref="#Horus_boat">Horus</name>" came up with a tug, flying the English flag, and pulled up ahead of us. The views from the <placeName ref="#Temple_Complex_at_Kom_Ombo">temple</placeName> plateau are so splendid, I never want to come away. While we were sitting at lunch the "<name type="boat" ref="#Cheops">Cheops</name>" appeared with tug, and English flag - but did not stop - and soon after the "<name type="boat" ref="#Philetus">Philetus</name>" came sailing up, also with the English flag - and stopped, and next appeared the "<name type="boat" ref="#Miriam">Miriam</name>" the <orgName ref="#Egyptian_Museum">Egyptian Museum</orgName> boat, with a tug, and stopped behind us - so that the settlement is a large one tonight. We had had a pleasant scheme for taking tea in the <placeName ref="#Temple_Complex_at_Kom_Ombo">temple</placeName> this afternoon - but the high wind, and all the people from the boats made it impossible.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-02-11" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-02-11">Friday, Feb. 11</date>. </dateline>
            <p>We are at a little mail station on the east bank called <placeName ref="#Iqlīt">El-Eglit</placeName> - about half way between <placeName ref="#Kawm_Umbū">Kom Kombo</placeName> and <placeName ref="#Gebel_el_Silsila">Silsileh</placeName> - and here we have stayed, prisoners of the North wind. The <name type="boat" ref="#Osiris">Osiris</name> is in sight.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-02-12" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-02-12">Saturday, Feb. 12</date>. </dateline>
            <p>All day at <placeName ref="#Iqlīt">El-Eglit</placeName> - a very stormy night - impossible to move - cold again.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-02-13" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-02-13">Sexigesina Sunday. Feb. 13</date>. </dateline>
            <p>Started early this morning, and at 12 o'clock made <placeName ref="#Silsilis">Silsilis</placeName>. Tremendous wind - with some difficulty made a landing on the West bank, and visited the different little shrines and Specs. Then got away, but <pb n="159"/>> were nearly blown upon the rocks, which make this part of the river dangerous - and dropped our anchor just in time to save us. Finally succeeded in making about a mile where we now are, with the <name type="boat" ref="#Osiris">Osiris</name> above us.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-02-14" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-02-14">Monday, Feb. 14</date>. </dateline>
            <p>Early start - struggled along until after 9 o'clock, when we tied up - wind blowing hard - and still blows. Made 4 miles.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-02-15" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-02-15">Tuesday, Feb. 15</date>. </dateline>
            <p>Started at 5:30 and stopped before 10 o'clock - wind so strong. <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I walked along the railway embankment for some distance - but the flying sand and dust we found very disagreeable. Began rowing about 7 o'clock with the wind falling - and rowed until 8:30. We have seen the zodiacal light for a long time.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-02-16" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-02-16">Wednesday, Feb. 16</date>. </dateline>
            <p>Began rowing at 6 o'clock - I looked out of my window, and saw a smooth water, a rosy, golden flush of dawn, and a waning moon high in the sky, reflected in the water. Brought up at <placeName ref="#Edfu">Edfou</placeName> at 8 o'clock - and found the <name type="boat" ref="#Mena">Mena</name> (Cook's boat) with <persName ref="#Hay_John_Col">Col. John Hay</persName>, our Minister at <placeName ref="#London">London</placeName>, and his party - and 2 other boats. Started soon after breakfast for <placeName ref="#Temple_of_Edfu">the temple</placeName> - where we stayed about 2 hours, and were back before lunch and off, and have been floating with a little rowing all day until 6:30 when we stopped. We are about 4 miles from <placeName ref="#El_Kab">El Kab</placeName>. <pb n="160"/></p> 
        </div>
        <!--hawk statue?-->
        <!--kneeling statue-->
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-02-17" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-02-17">Thursday, Feb. 17</date>. </dateline>
            <p>Reached <placeName ref="#El_Kab">El-Kab</placeName> at 8 o'clock - found the <name type="boat" ref="#Istar">Istar</name> lying in front of the <name type="boat" ref="#Antar">Antah</name> - and while we were seated at breakfast, <persName ref="#Somers_Clark_George">Mr. Somers-Clarke</persName> came in to see us, and to ask us to come to his boat to see the <objectName>Sacred Hawk</objectName> he had found at <placeName ref="#Kom_El_Ahmar">Kom el-Akmar</placeName>. After breakfast I mounted a donkey, while the rest walked, into the <placeName ref="#Kom_El_Ahmar_Fort">old fortress</placeName> and amongst its ruins, and then climbed the great wall 30 ft. or more thick, and I dismounted and walked on it - a rare view of desert, and river, and remains of former human habitation. Then we went to the <name type="boat" ref="#Antar">Antar</name> and saw the head and crown of the splendid <objectName>hawk</objectName> - as large as a big apple, of pure gold with a crown of gold 6 in. high, representing the <orgName>Osiris</orgName> feather crown - with eyes of obsidian - the workmanship fine and spirited. The body which we did not see, is of bronze, and much broken, but can be reconstructed. Then we were shown in the portico of the little house on shore, what is more interesting historically, a <objectName>kneeling figure in stone</objectName>, very crude and archaic, what <persName ref="#Somers_Clarke_George">Mr. S.-C</persName>. thinks belongs to the prehistoric time - also found at <placeName ref="#Kom_El_Ahmar">Kom El-Ahmar</placeName>, where <placeName ref="#Quibell_James">Mr. Quibell</placeName> is excavating. In the afternoon we all rode out to the little <placeName>temple of Amenophis III</placeName> in the desert and had tea - we had never seen this pretty and interesting temple which <persName ref="#Somers_Clarke_George">Mr. S.-C</persName>. has illustrated and described. The ride through the desert valley - with the great arid mountains around us, and the evening colours, was something to remember. Evidences of the water courses, which are sometimes fed by the rains in the mountains were interesting. <persName ref="#Sayce_Archibald">Mr. Sayce</persName>, and <persName ref="#Somers_Clarke_George">Mr. S.-C</persName>. came to dinner - a pleasant evening - talked over the <orgName ref="#Egypt_Exploration_Society">Egypt Exploration Fund Society</orgName>. <pb n="161"/></p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-02-18" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-02-18">Friday. Feb. 18</date>. </dateline>
            <p>Left <placeName ref="#El_Kab">El-Kab</placeName> at 8 this morning - stopped in a high wind about 11. Made 10 miles - horrid.</p> 
        </div>
        <!--dentist?-->
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-02-19" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-02-19">Saturday, Feb. 19</date>. </dateline>
            <p>Reached <placeName ref="#Esneh">Esneh</placeName> at 9 - having rowed since very early in the morning - <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> met the <persName>American dentist</persName>, who gave startling accounts of wind and cold below <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName>. Made about 20 miles - and are now at <placeName ref="#Gebelein">Gebelein</placeName>, 13 miles from <placeName ref="#Erment">Erment</placeName>.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-02-20" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-02-20">Quinqungesima Sunday, Feb. 20</date>. </dateline>
            <p>A day of hard work at rowing - until about 2 o'clock - this obstinate north wind stopped blowing - and in smooth water in a glory of beautiful colouring we came along, arriving at <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName> just after dark. We found the <name type="boat" ref="#Osiris">Osiris</name> lying in our old place, and brilliantly illuminated, fizzing rockets and fireworks - so we hope she is going off tomorrow, and we have pulled in just behind her, and will take her place when she goes.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-02-21" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-02-21">Monday, Feb. 21</date>. </dateline>
            <p><persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I walked into town - went to the <persName ref="#Wetzstein_Dr">German Consul</persName>s and looked at his curiosities. Sun warm, and much dirt.<persName ref="#Huhatt_Mr">Mr. Huhatt</persName> came to play chess with <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Mr. Davis</persName>, and stayed to lunch. <persName ref="#Insinger_Mr">Mr. Insinger</persName> called. <pb n="162"/></p> 
        </div>
        <!--Hamilton Fish-->
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-02-22" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-02-22">Tuesday, Feb. 22</date>. </dateline>
            <p>We have had up all our flag decorations in honor of the day. <persName ref="#Varley_Mr">Mr. Varley</persName> called. The <name>Hamilton Fisks</name> just down from <placeName ref="#Aswan">Assouan</placeName> in the steamer came to dine.</p> 
        </div>
        <!--gezireh??-->
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-02-23" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-02-23">Wednesday, Feb. 23</date>. </dateline>
            <p>The "<name type="boat" ref="#Olga">Olga</name>" with the <persName ref="#Ayer_family">Ayer family</persName> came down this morning and is near us. They came over at once to call. The "<name type="boat" ref="#Alma">Alma</name>" also arrived, and went across to the gezireh - and they all came over to see us. This afternoon we went over to the "<name type="boat" ref="#Seura">Seura</name>" <persName ref="#Varley_Mr">Varley</persName>'s boat, to see his <objectName ref="#Nile_Sketches">Nile sketches</objectName>. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> bought the 2 best. Then we went to the "<name type="boat" ref="#Hyksos">Hyksos</name>", to have tea with <persName ref="#Shepheard_Miss">Miss Shepheard</persName>.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-02-24" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-02-24">Thursday, Feb. 24</date>. </dateline>
            <p><persName ref="#Varley_Mr">Mr. Varley</persName> and <persName ref="#Hooker_Mr">Mr. Hooker</persName> came over and stayed a long time this morning - and a very pleasant morning it was. We were asked to the "<name type="boat" ref="#Alma">Alma</name>" for tea, but I did not feel well, and <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> went alone. <persName ref="#Huhatt_Mr #Huhatt_Mrs">Mr. and Mrs. Huhatt</persName> dined with us.</p> 
        </div>
        <!--Ayer daughter-->
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-02-25" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-02-25">Friday, 25 Feb</date>. </dateline>
            <p>A quiet morning on deck with my books - it has been hot for days - and grateful the heat is. <persName ref="#Broderick_Miss">Miss Broderick</persName> and <persName ref="#Morton_Miss">Miss Morton</persName> came to tea - and <persName ref="#Ayer_Mr #Ayer_Mrs">Mr. and Mrs. Ayer</persName>, and the daughter dined with us. <pb n="163"/></p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-02-26" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-02-26">Saturday, Feb. 26</date>. </dateline>
            <p>"<name type="boat" ref="#Istar">Istar</name>" came in early this morning - <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I went to tea with <persName ref="#Sayce_Archibald">Mr. Sayce</persName> - and the evening being so radiantly beautiful, we went out rowing all of us - and serenaded the "<name type="boat" ref="#Alma">Alma</name>" people.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-02-27" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-02-27">Sunday, Feb. 27</date>. </dateline>
            <p><persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I went to church this morning - over to the "<name type="boat" ref="#Olga">Olga</name>" for tea this afternoon with <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and <persName ref="#Monty">Monty</persName> - met <persName ref="#Fiske_Mr">Mr. Fiske</persName> of <placeName ref="#Florence">Florence</placeName> and <persName ref="#Sayce_Archibald">Mr. Sayce</persName> - as the latter had been asked to dine with us this evening we also asked <persName ref="#Fiske_Mr">Mr. Fiske</persName> - and had a charming evening.</p> 
        </div>
        <!--end of olivia's section-->
        <!--emma's section below-->
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-03-02" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-03-02">Wednesday, March 2d</date>. </dateline>
            <p>Have all been occupied with the <persName ref="#Bend_family">Bend family</persName>, who arrived on the steamer on Monday - they dined with us that night and last night. yesterday we all went to <placeName ref="#Karnak">Karnak</placeName> in the morning - heat and dust indescribable, the rest went over to <placeName ref="#Medinet_Habu">Medinet Habu</placeName> in the afternoon - I wisely stayed at home.  <persName ref="#Fiske_Mr">Mr. Fiske</persName> came to tea. Today all but <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName>, I and <persName ref="#Bend_Mr">Mr. Bend</persName>, went to the <placeName ref="#Bībān al-Mulūk">Tombs of the Kings</placeName> - we going over in the afternoon to meet them at <placeName ref="#Der_el_Bahari">Der el-Bahri</placeName> - first visiting <placeName ref="#Dayr_al_Madinah">Der el-Medinet</placeName> which I had never before seen - a charming little temple, in its desert gorge - coming home by moonlight - frightful wind and dust.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-03-03" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-03-03">Thursday, March 3d</date>. </dateline>
            <p>Yesterday the north wind got up early and strong and has blown without cessation all day. I did not go out this morning -<pb n="164"/> <name ref="#Bend_Mr">Mr. Bend</name> and <persName ref="#Bend_Beatrice">Beatrice</persName> to lunch - all went to the races in the afternoon - afterwards <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I to tea with <persName ref="#Huhatt_Mrs">Mrs. Huhatt</persName>, and farewell visits to <placeName ref="#Palmenburg">the Castle</placeName>, and to <persName ref="#Shepheard_Miss">Miss Shepheards</persName>. Then <persName ref="#Bend_family">the Bends</persName> came to dine, and all went on donkeys to <placeName ref="#Karnak">Karnak</placeName> by moonlight, except <persName ref="#Bend_Mr">Mr. Bend</persName>, <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I, who had not the courage to face the wind and dust. I have settle many little matters - and we hope to get off tomorrow - <persName ref="#Bend_family">the Bends</persName> going off in their steamer at 5 o'clock for <placeName ref="#Aswan">Assouan</placeName>. All the dahabeahs but ours have gone down.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-03-04" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-03-04">Friday March 4</date>. </dateline>
            <p>We got off this morning at last - but the wind a little dead against us. For a time we thought we would have to tie up at <placeName ref="#Karnak">Karnak</placeName>, but we have come along in spite of it to within a mile of <placeName ref="#Naqādah">Nagada</placeName> - and are lying in the splendid moonlight at a high bank crowned with the finest palm trees I have ever seen. The day fine - not too warm - on deck the whole day.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-03-05" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-03-05">Saturday, March 5</date>. </dateline>
            <p>The men began rowing at 5 o'clock this morning - and the morning was quiet until about noon when the north wind got up, and still stays up. It is now 9 o'clock - and we are anchored in mid river. The night is as bright as day. We made <placeName ref="#Keneh">Keneh</placeName> at 5 o'clock - and are now only a mile below. The "<name type="boat" ref="#Nephtys">Nephtys</name>" passed us this morning with her tug - and soon after we descried the "<name type="boat" ref="#Mimi">Mimi</name>" ahead of us - and found them both lying at <placeName ref="#Dandarah">Denderah</placeName>. The "<name type="boat" ref="#Tik">Tik</name>" at the <placeName ref="#Keneh">Keneh</placeName> landing. The day a little<pb n="165"/> cool. Three Dahabeahs have passed up today. Two of them flying the American flag. The "<name type="boat" ref="#Manhattan">Manhattan</name>", and the "<name type="boat" ref="#Queen_of_the_Nile">Queen of the Nile</name>", and this evening the "<name type="boat" ref="#Stella">Stella</name>" went up. It is a great year for dahabeahs. Made 25 miles.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-03-06" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-03-06">2d. Sunday in <name type="event" ref="#Lent">Lent</name>. March 6</date>. </dateline>
            <p>We think we have made about 12 miles - since noon the wind has been strong and north - and the fact that the "<name type="boat" ref="#Mimi">Mimi</name>" was so near us, induced our men to work hard in spite of the wind. The night is beautiful.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-03-07" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-03-07">Monday, March 7</date>. </dateline>
            <p>A beautiful quiet day - and we have made 38 miles - no wind, except the lightest breath from the north now and then. Our men have rowed valiantly for 12 hours - and we are now lying about 6 miles from <placeName ref="#Balyana_Al">Ballianeh</placeName>. The <name type="boat" ref="#Mimi">Mimi</name> has been just behind us until 5 o'clock, when she stopped where the "<name type="boat" ref="#Nephtys">Nephtys</name>" and "<name type="boat" ref="#Istar">Istar</name>" were lying this side of <placeName ref="#Naj_Hammadi">Nagh Hamadi</placeName>. We were just in time for the bridge at the latter place - which was just opening as we came up to it, and were the first to come through there being 3 steamers and the "<name type="boat" ref="#Mimi">Mimi</name>" - and in spite of <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName>'s nervousness we got quickly and quietly through.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-03-08" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-03-08">Tuesday, March 8</date>. </dateline>
            <p>Arrived at <placeName ref="#Balyana_Al">Balliana</placeName> about 9:30 - found the <name type="boat" ref="#Olga">Olga</name> and the <name type="boat" ref="#Alma">Alma</name> lying near each other. All their people had gone out to <placeName ref="#Abydos">Abydos</placeName>, and except <persName ref="#Broderick_Miss">Miss Broderick</persName> - who came over at once to see us. We started ourselves in half an hour - the morning being cool and cloudy - and although the 2 hours ride out there even with the worst donkeys in the world, was delightful over that wide cultivated country - the wheat quite grown and bearded - oats well formed, and the air full of blossoming clover - yet the coming home was tiring in the extreme - bad donkey boys, unpleasant, natives, and intolerable donkeys, almost spoiled the lovely face of nature. We could not go to the <name type="historical" ref="#Tomb_of_Osiris">tomb of Osiris</name> as no one could tell us where it was. We have been baking bread today for the crew - and get off early tomorrow. <name type="boat" ref="#Istar">Istar</name>, <name type="boat" ref="#Mimi">Mimi</name>, and <name type="boat" ref="#Nephtys">Nephtys</name> all here.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-03-09" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-03-09">Wednesday, March 9</date>. </dateline>
            <p>Began rowing at 5:30 - at 9 o'clock the north wind was so strong we gave it up and went to shore. It blew a gale until 7 o'clock when we dropped down 3 miles to <placeName ref="#Jirjā">Girgeh</placeName> - having made altogether the 8 miles between the two places. Passed 2 dahabeahs tonight - supposed to be the "<name type="boat" ref="#Istar">Istar</name>" and "<name type="boat" ref="#Alma">Alma</name>". The air has been so charged with dust, and still is that the sun looked just as the full moon looks tonight.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-03-10" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-03-10">Thursday, March 10</date>. </dateline>
            <p>High wind - made by rowing and drifting about 18 miles - and are very near <placeName ref="#Akhmīm">Akmim</placeName>.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-03-11" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-03-11">Friday, March 11</date>. </dateline>
            <p>Reached <placeName ref="#Sohag">Sohag</placeName> this morning and stopped for the mail. The <name type="boat" ref="#Alma">Alma</name> <pb n="167"/>just starting out, as we pulled in. We have made about 5 miles below <placeName ref="#Sohag">Sohag</placeName> - altogether 12 miles.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-03-12" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-03-12">Saturday, March 12</date>. </dateline>
            <p>A splendid day - began rowing in a calm at 4:30 A.M. when a gentle south wind came up, and carried us on to our victorious way until we reached <placeName ref="Asyut">Assiut</placeName> at 7 o'clock P.M. - having made 63 miles. <name type="boat" ref="#Olga">Olga</name>, <name type="boat" ref="#Alma">Alma</name> and <name type="boat" ref="#Istar">Istar</name> here. <persName ref="#Ayers_family">The Ayers</persName> came over and spent the evening - but I did not see them being very miserable in my bed.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-03-13" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-03-13">3d Sunday in Lent. March 13</date>. </dateline>
            <p>Have made 6 miles this day. Left the <name type="boat" ref="#Alma">Alma</name> and <name type="boat" ref="#Istar">Istar</name> at <placeName ref="Asyut">Assiut</placeName> looking after inscriptions in the Mountains I suppose. Overtook the <name type="boat" ref="#Olga">Olga</name>, but she has since floated out of sight.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-03-14" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-03-14">Monday, March 14</date>. </dateline>
            <p>Another slow day, with north wind. We have passed <placeName ref="#Manfalût">Manfalout</placeName>, making altogether we think about 22 miles.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-03-15" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-03-15">Tuesday, March 15</date>. </dateline>
            <p>An exasperating day. We started early and rowed around the two great turns between <placeName ref="#Manfalût">Manfalout</placeName> and half way past the <placeName ref="#Abu_Fudah_Jabal">Gebel Abou Feydah</placeName> chain - and were congratulating ourselves that we were going to pass it, when the north wind became so strong, we had to stop before making the last turn - as these dangerous cliffs come down quite to the<pb n="168"/> water - and here we are still, with the lights of another dahabeah showing a little above us - we do not know what. Every night now we have 3 or 4 Gaffirs or guards watching us - as this part of the river always has a bad reputation - and there is much excitement now over the sad murder a short time since at <placeName ref="#Maghaghah">Maghagah</placeName> of <persName ref="#Cowper_Lord">Lord Cowper</persName>'s valet, who left the dahabeah for the Post Ofice, and missing his way back, was decoyed it is supposed into the sugar cane. His body was found the same evening robbed - and he had been strangled after a violent struggle. This has made a great stir - especially as two murders of natives in the same vicinity have since taken place. The "<name type="boat" ref="#Mimi">Mimi</name>" passed us this afternoon in tow of a tug. Made about 8 miles.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-03-16" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-03-16">Wednesday, March 16</date>. </dateline>
            <p>In spite of the wind, we have come bravely along today - and are now just by <placeName ref="Mallawi">Melawi-el-Arieh</placeName>, having made 25 miles. This morning before 7 o'clock the <name type="boat" ref="#Herodotus_Boat">Herodotus</name> in tow passed down - and about 11 o'clock this morning we came upon her sticking tight in the sand. She must have been there a long time and we were just preparing to offer assistance, when she began to start. Too windy to be on deck today until about 4 o'clock when I went up - and we had tea there - and a beautiful sail, or row until dark - passing the end of the <placeName ref="#Jabal_Abū_Fūdah">Abu Feydah</placeName> chain - with a lovely bank of palm trees - villages - fields - cattle, sheep and the evening air of repose over all. There is a dahabeah just behind us, but too far for us to make her out. She is probably the <name type="boat" ref="#Alma">Alma</name>. <pb n="169"/></p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-03-17" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-03-17">Thursday, Mar. 17</date>. </dateline>
            <p>Early this morning I was wakened by hearing <persName>Jones</persName> saying to <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> in the hall that we were passing the <name type="boat" ref="#Olga">Olga</name> stuck in the sand, and raising my curtain I saw her plainly - her stern right in the bank and slightly tilted. None of the family visible - and she had the air of having adapted herself to the situation. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> sent word to ask if we could help her - but it seems she had been there for more than a day, and there was nothing but a tug - so after stopping a moment we came on. The <name type="boat" ref="#Mimi">Mimi</name> passed us in tow later on - and we floated and rowed making <placeName ref="#Pinieh">Pinieh</placeName> at 6:30, where we stopped for mail. Made 31-1/2 miles.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-03-18" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-03-18">Friday, Mar. 18</date>. </dateline>
            <p>Started early, <name type="boat" ref="#Mimi">Mimi</name> passed us as we pulled out and a good light wind has prevailed all day and we have come on splendidly. Passed <placeName>Gelassaneh</placeName>, <placeName ref="##Jirjā">abu Girgeh</placeName>, <placeName>Haghaha</placeName>, and are now about 2 miles above <placeName>Fasben</placeName> having made 62 miles. The river has been very difficult today in several places - we were on the sand for a few minutes - and I cannot imagine how the boats we left behind us can get through - as even we with our light draught find it so difficult. It rained gently for a little while today.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-03-19" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-03-19">Saturday, Mar. 19</date>. </dateline>
            <p>Made about 8 miles this morning and got as far as <placeName ref="#Biba">Bibeh</placeName>, when the north wind was so strong we had to drop our anchor to save ourselves <pb n="170"/>from being sent on to the rocky cliffs - and we have not moved since, except as the wind has swayed us. The ominous sky brought the storm just as we had finished dinner. It blew tremendously, and the rain fell in torrents. The boat proved very tight, the only leaks being in my room, where the roof is higher - and at this offset there were several leaks - and towels, cups and bowls were put in requisition. I took a volume of <bibl><title>McMasters History of the People of the United States</title></bibl> from the bookcases this evening, and chanced upon the interesting and pathetic history of the settlement of <placeName ref="#Galliopolis">Galliopolis</placeName> in <placeName ref="#Ohio">Ohio</placeName> - which I had never read before.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-03-20" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-03-20">4th Sunday in <name type="event" ref="#Lent">Lent</name>. Mar. 20</date>. </dateline>
            <p>I did not get to bed last night until nearly one o'clock. The storm which seemed to pass away in the evening, burst upon us again after eleven. All the family had gone to bed - so <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and I stayed up and again put in use the bowls, cups, and towels. For the first time, I really felt a little afraid as we were lying in the middle of the river - we had 3 anchors down, and the boat tugged at them most unpleasantly. Early this morning we pulled to the anchor to a safer place, and put out our 3 anchors on a little sand island, where we are still lying, the wind having blown great guns all day. The <name type="boat" ref="#Rameses">Ramses</name> passed us early - feeling her way very cautiously indeed. I went on deck for a few moments after tea - but it was too windy to be pleasant - though the air was soft and deliciously full of the fragrance of clover blossoms. Wrote my Sunday letter to <persName ref="#Titus_Mrs">Mrs. Titus</persName> - and one to <persName ref="#Buttles_Jennie">Jennie Buttles</persName> in <placeName ref="#Gambier">Gambier</placeName>. <pb n="171"/></p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-03-21" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-03-21">Monday, March 21</date>. </dateline>
            <p>We have had the most exciting day I ever passed o the <placeName ref="Nile">Nile</placeName>. We began the day early, with a light south wind - and found the river very difficult. About 10 o'clock we descried a Cook Steamer evidently stuck on the sand, ahead of us - and on coming up with her found her to be the <name type="boat" ref="#Ammartis">Ammartis</name>, which passed us yesterday. She was surrounded by gyasses, who were relieving her of some of her luggage. Not long after we passed the Steamer <name type="boat" ref="#Shellal">Shellal</name>, a complete wreck, and partly submerged. She was deserted and in the hands of the wreckers - having stove a hole in her bottom on some unsuspected stones in the river. Half an hour after sitting at luncheon, our boat gave a sudden lurch, and there was a grinding of stones under her bow. We all rushed on forward deck, fearing some real calamity; but examination showed no leak, and we came on our way rejoicing; but it was rather nervous work for awhile. Next we saw one of the large Gage steamers, empty, and abandoned, and left tied to the bank, to wait for higher water, so that she could get down the river. Then we came up the <name type="boat" ref="#Ammartis">Ammartis</name>, who had got off the sand, and passed us a short time before, transferring her passengers to the <name type="boat" ref="#Tewfik">Tewfik</name>, who was sending her to the <name type="boat" ref="#Ammartis">Ammartis</name> - the latter drawing less water. So when we found ourselves tonight 6 miles below <placeName ref="#Al_Wasta">Wasta</placeName> and having made 37 miles, and only touched sand once for a moment, we congratulated ourselves. A beautiful day and evening.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-03-22" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-03-22">Tuesday, Mar. 22</date>. </dateline>
            <p>We were off this morning in a light south wind, at 6 o'clock.<pb n="172"/> The wind shifted again and again, but at last came gently and steadily from the south, and we came rapidly along reaching <placeName ref="#Al_Badrashayn">Bedrasheen</placeName> at 4 o'clock, and making the last 15 miles from there to <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> or rather <placeName ref="#Giza">Ghizeh</placeName> at 6:30. Here we found the landing place all along in front of the <name type="historical" ref="#Museum_of_Egyptian_Antiquities">Museum</name>, crowded with dahabeahs - and with some difficulty we found a place. I have never seen so beautiful an approach to <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> - in the afternoon and evening light, the very picturesque scene of houses and trees at <name type="historical" ref="#Old_Cairo">Old Cairo</name>, and the <placeName ref="#Island_of_Rhoda">island of Rhoda</placeName>, dominated by the great <placeName ref="The_Citadel">Citadel</placeName> with the dome and slender minarets of the <placeName ref="#Mosque_of_Mohamet_Ali">mosque of Mohamet Ali</placeName> were wonderful.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-03-23" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-03-23">Wednesday, Mar. 23</date>. </dateline>
            <p>A warm, cloudless day - home all the morning, and driving with <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> this afternoon.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-03-24" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-03-24">Thursday, Mar. 24</date>. </dateline>
            <p>At home all day - very hot - high Kamseen wind. <name type="boat">Istar</name> came down tonight.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-03-25" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-03-25">Friday, Mar. 25</date>. </dateline>
            <p>Drove into <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> with <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> in the morning. In the afternoon we had a delicious drive almost quite to the <name type="hotel" ref="#Mena_House_Hotel">Mena House</name>. The air so cool - the fields so green. Alas! they are building a trolley line to <placeName ref="#Pyramids">the Pyramids</placeName> - and the avenue is very changed from what it was the first time I saw it. Now some disease seems to have attacked the lubbek trees<pb n="173"/> and they are rapidly dying, with no apparent effort to replant. Young <persName ref="#Bishop_Courtlandt">Courtlandt Bishop</persName> came to dine - and the two Ayers, father and son, came in to call - and told us about their troubles descending - having arrived yesterday morning. She was 2 days on the sand - and got off by employing a windlass and crew of a big gyassa passing. A new moon tonight.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-03-26" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-03-26">Saturday, Mar. 26</date>. </dateline>
            <p>The wind blew great guns last night - and made such a noise - the water dashing and splashing under the stern, and my very head - and when I wakened this morning, the rain was dashing against my windows. Fortunately it did not rain hard, or last long - <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> went in town to lunch with <persName ref="#Bend_family">the Bends</persName>, and play chess. <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I drove into <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> on some necessary affairs, bringing <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> home with us. <persName ref="#Monty">Monty</persName> off riding - weather cool and delightful now. We are quite anxious over the dispatches of the day, from the <placeName>United States.</placeName> That <persName ref="#McKinley_William">Pres. McKinley</persName>'s message says that the <name type="boat" ref="#Maine">Maine</name> was destroyed from outside torpedo and that the <placeName ref="#United_States_of_America">U.S.</placeName> had recognized the <orgName ref="#Cuban_Insurgents">Cuban insurgents</orgName> - very disquieting.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-03-27" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-03-27">5 Sunday in <name type="event" ref="#Lent">Lent</name>. Mar. 27</date>. </dateline>
            <p>To the <name type="historical" ref="#Museum_of_Egyptian_Antiquities">Museum</name> this morning. <persName ref="#Varley_Mr">Mr. Varley</persName>, <persName ref="#Royal_Judge">Judge Royal</persName>, and <persName ref="#Faviger_Mr">Mr. Faviger</persName> came to tea and made a long pleasant visit. <persName ref="#Bend_Amy">Amy Bend</persName> and <persName ref="#Bishop_Courtlandt">Mr. Bishop</persName> also turned up - and <persName ref="#Bend_Mr">Mr. Bend</persName> and the two girls came to dine. <persName ref="#Bend_Mrs">Mrs. Bend</persName> ill in her bed. <pb n="174"/></p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-03-28" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-03-28">Monday, Mar. 28</date>. </dateline>
            <p>Very hot all day - home in the morning - and at 5 o'clock in the afternoon <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I drove out to the <name type="hotel" ref="#Mena_House_Hotel">Mena House</name> and had tea, and home quite late.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-03-29" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-03-29">Tuesday, Mar 29</date>. </dateline>
            <p><persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName>, <persName ref="#Monty">Monty</persName> and I spent the morning at the Museum - principally in the rooms up stairs - and I came home well tired. Home all afternoon - very hot. <persName ref="#Ayer_James_Dr">Dr. James Ayer</persName> came to dine. Political news from home more reassuring.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-03-30" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-03-30">Wednesday, Mar. 30</date>. </dateline>
            <p>The hottest day I ever spent on the <placeName ref="Nile">Nile</placeName>. My room, always the coolest on the heat, had a temperature of 80&#8304; and the Cabana 90&#8304;.  <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and I drove into town to see <persName ref="#Bend_family">the Bends</persName> this morning. Home, and busy this afternoon with preparations for packing.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-03-31" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-03-31">Thursday, Mar. 31</date>. </dateline>
            <p>An uncomfortable day - hot - strong wind - a busy day of packing and dismantling - the last night is always sade.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-04-01" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-04-01">Friday, April 1</date>. </dateline>
            <p>Came to the <name type="historical" ref="#Ghezireh_Palace">Ghesireh Palace</name> this afternoon - found the grand apartment formerly used by <persName ref="#Ismail_Pacha">Ismail Pacha</persName> ready for us - the rooms enormous - richly furnished and decorated, the salon and my room looking on the river - and seeming very cool and comfortable this hot night.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-04-02" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-04-02">Saturday, April 2</date>. </dateline>
            <p>Drove to the dahabeah this morning and then went to the <name type="historical" ref="#Museum_of_Egyptian_Antiquities">Museum</name> - where it was cool and delightful. Coming out the heat was so intense, that even in a covered carriage it seemed really terrifying. Late in the afternoon <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I drove into town to shops and looked after many things. We keep the enormous windows of our rooms closed from early morning - until seven o'clock at night when they are opened for the cool air - and they admit also mosquitoes and bats.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-04-03" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-04-03">Sunday, April 3</date>. </dateline>
            <p>Palm Sunday. I have not had the courage to move out of the house until at 6 o'clock, after having had a cup of tea, <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and I went over to <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> to pay some farewell visits. In cross the bridge, the reflected heat from the iron at the sides, was like a blast from a furnace. We found <persName ref="#Sandwith_Mrs">Mrs. Sandwith</persName> in the garden with the children - she said the thermometer stood an hour before at 97&#8304;.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-04-04" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-04-04">Monday, April 4</date>. </dateline>
            <p>A farewell visit to the boat this morning, and a visit to <persName ref="#Phillips_Mr">Phillips</persName> the antiquity dealer in <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> afterwards. Very hot - with the same high, hot Khamseen wind we have had for 2 days. <persName ref="#Sopher_Mme">Mme. Sopher</persName> came over this afternoon to shampoo our heads. Our last preparations are all made - and we shall be off tomorrow - <persName ref="#Fuli_Rais">Rais Fuli</persName> and <persName ref="#Abdul">Abdul</persName> came<pb n="176"/> this evening to see the magnificence of the <name type="historical" ref="#Ghezireh_Palace">Palace</name>. It was amusing to see their impressions.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-04-09" type="entry">
            <dateline><name type="hotel" ref="#Hotel_Bernini_Bristol">Hotel Bristol</name>. <placeName ref="#Rome">Rome</placeName> -  <date when="1898-04-09">Saturday, April 9th</date>. </dateline>
            <p>Arrived last night - after a very good and comfortable voyage in the Rubitine Steamer <name type="boat" ref="#Regina_Margherita">Regina Margherita</name>. Left <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> the morning of Tuesday April 5, early - weather having so entirely changed, that we were cold in driving to the station. <persName ref="#Fuli_Rais">Rais Fuli</persName>, <persName ref="#Abdul">Abdul</persName>, <persName ref="#Ebrahim">Ebrahim</persName>, the <persName ref="#Cook_Thomas">Cook</persName>, and <persName ref="Dervish_Mohammed">Mohamet Dervish</persName>, and our good <persName ref="#Salah_Mohammed">Salah</persName>, were all waiting at the station for us. As <persName ref="#Ali_Mohammed_Prince">Prince Mohamet Ali</persName> and the <persName>wife of the French Minister</persName> were all going by the same train, there was a very smart gathering of people - especially of red fezs - even <persName ref="#Cromer_Lord">Lord Cromer</persName> was there. <persName ref="#Ayers_family">The Ayers</persName> also crossed with us. The steamer was very clean and comfortable - I had a deck room, with a double bed, so delightful, with a good window by day, and an electric light by night, that I stopped in bed until 5 o'clock of the last day - with my books - and had a beautiful rest. Reached <placeName ref="#Naples">Naples</placeName> and landed by 8 o'clock - had breakfast at the <name type="hotel" ref="#Grand_Hotel">Grand</name> - and then a charming drive up the hill and over to <placeName ref="#Posolippo">Posillippo</placeName>, and then back in time for early lunch, and off for <placeName ref="#Rome">Rome</placeName> by one o'clock - which we reached for dinner in our pleasant sitting room at 7:30. Found piles of letter waiting. Very serious news as to probably war with <placeName ref="#Spain">Spain</placeName> - and accounts of the brilliant and decisive battle fought by <persName>Kitchener</persName>, the <orgName>Sirdar</orgName> in the <placeName>Soudan</placeName> - great loss of dervishes. <persName>Mahomet</persName> the general captured. We have the corresponding rooms, only<pb n="177"/> one storey higher, than those we had last year. Drove to <name type="historical" ref="#St_Peters_Basilica">St. Peters</name> this morning and to <placeName ref="#Villa_Borghese">Villa Borghese</placeName> this afternoon. <persName ref="#Anderson_Hendrick">Hendrick Andersen</persName> dined with us - looking well and happy - last night and tonight. This morning to his pleasant studio - and were charmed and astonished at the vigor and originality of his work.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-04-10" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-04-10">Easter Sunday, April 10</date>. </dateline>
            <p>Splendid weather, and services at <placeName ref="#St_John_of_Lateran">St. John of Lateran</placeName> this morning, and <name type="historical" ref="#St_Peters_Basilica">St. Peters</name> in the afternoon - delightful music - and what effects in the <name type="historical" ref="#St_Peters_Basilica">St. Peters</name>! <persName ref="#Bronson_Mrs #Bronson_Miss">Mrs. and Miss Bronson</persName> to dine with us.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-04-11" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-04-11">Monday, April 11</date>. </dateline>
            <p>To the <name type="historical" ref="#Museo_Nazionale_Romano">Museo delle Terme</name> this morning with <persName ref="#Anderson_Hendrick">Anderson</persName>. To drive in the <placeName ref="#Villa_Borghese">Borhese</placeName> in the afternoon.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-04-12" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-04-12">Tuesday, April 12</date>. </dateline>
            <p><placeName ref="#Vatican_City">Vatican</placeName> with <persName ref="#Anderson_Hendrick">Anderson</persName>. <persName ref="#Whitehead_family">Whiteheads</persName> turned up this evening.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-04-13" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-04-13">Wednesday, April 13</date>. </dateline>
            <p>To the <name type="historical" ref="#Vatican_Pinacoteca">Vatican Pinacotheca</name> - <persName ref="#House_Mrs">Mrs. House</persName>, <persName ref="#Elliot_Mr #Elliot_Mrs">Mr. and Mrs. Elliot</persName> to dinner <persName ref="#Richter_Dr">Dr. Richter</persName> called - interesting.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-04-14" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-04-14">Thursday, April 14</date>. </dateline>
            <p>To various churches this morning - to a reception at <persName ref="#Elliot_Mrs">Mrs. Elliotts</persName> in the afternoon. <persName ref="#Bull_Dr">Dr. Bull</persName> to dine with us. <persName ref="#Richter_Dr">Dr. Richter</persName> came DUPLICATE PAGE 177 PAGE 178</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-04-15" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-04-15">Friday, April 15</date>. </dateline>
            <p>To the <placeName ref="#Villa_Doria_Pamphili">Doria Pamfili</placeName> this morning and then to the <placeName ref="#St_John_of_Lateran">Lateren</placeName>. In the afternoon drove in the beautiful <placeName ref="#Villa_Doria_Pamphili">Doria Pamfili</placeName> gardens.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-04-16" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-04-16">Saturday, April 16</date>. </dateline>
            <p>Rain all day and in the house. <persName ref="#Ayer_Mr">Mr. Ayer</persName> called.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-04-17" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-04-17">Sunday, April 17</date>. </dateline>
            <p><persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and I drove out on the <placeName ref="#Via_Appia">Appian way</placeName> this morning - air deliciously warm and soft - but the wind so high and grew so violent we had to have the top of the carriage up - beautiful storm effects on that wide <placeName ref="#Campagna">Campagna</placeName>, with the tops of the Mts. white with snow. <persName ref="#Norman_Mrs">Mrs. Norman</persName> and <persName ref="#Norman_Mable">Mabel</persName> came to dine.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-04-18" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-04-18">Monday, April 18</date>. </dateline>
            <p><persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and I have been nosing about in the various shops of an old man who deals in frames in the <name type="historical" ref="#Via_Gregoriana">Via Gergoriana</name>. There were such beauties, it was hard to decide. Chose one of the best for a mirror to be placed in the hall over the hat table. <persName ref="#Richter_Dr">Dr. Richter</persName> came to lunch - conversation about <persName type="historical" ref="#Da_Vinci_Leonardo">Leonardo</persName>, <persName ref="#Botticelli_Sandro">Boticelli</persName>, and other artists, and discussion of various pictures. Then we drove wwith them to visit by appointment the house of <persName ref="#Minghetti_Donna_Laura">Donna Laura Minghetti</persName>, to see the famous <objectName type="painting" ref="#Portrait_of_a_Girl">leonardo da Vinci</objectName>. A charming house, and an even more charming and hospitable hostess - and the beautiful picture was a sensation indeed. The <persName ref="#Elliot_family">Elliots</persName> called this evening.<pb n="179"/></p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-04-19" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-04-19">Tuesday, April 19</date>. </dateline>
            <p>With the old frame man in <name type="historical" ref="#Via_Gregoriana">Via Gregoriana</name> this morning again and a charming drive, <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName>, <persName ref="#Monty">Monty</persName>, <persName ref="#Anderson_Hendrick">Anderson</persName> and I had in the <placeName ref="#Villa_Doria_Pamphili">Doria Pamphili</placeName> gardens this afternoon. They were not open to the public, but for some reason or other we were allowed to enter, and had all the drives and beautiful avenues to ourselves. <persName ref="#Ayer_Mrs">Mrs. Ayer</persName>, the <persName ref="#Norman_family">Normans</persName> to tea - and <persName ref="#Richter_Dr">Dr. Richter</persName> to dinner - and we do not go to <placeName ref="#Florence">Florence</placeName> tomorrow but the next day - for <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> is trying to get a precious picture.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-04-20" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-04-20">Wednesday, April 20</date>. </dateline>
            <p>Miserable weather. Poked into the old frame shop this morning with <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName>, and out in the rain for half an hour with <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> though I did not leave the carriage. <persName ref="#Richter_Dr">Dr. Richter</persName> to lunch - and then a very exciting afternoon - he and <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> went off at 3 o'clock in a closed carriage to <persName ref="#Minghetti_Donna_Laura">Donna Laura Minghetti</persName>'s to actually bring home in great secrecy, into our own possession, the incomparable <objectName type="painting" ref="#Portrait_of_a_Girl">Leonardo</objectName>, to which we thought it such a privilege only a few days since, to be allowed to see. It is hard to realize that we have actually acquired it, it seems almost as if we have bought the <name type="historical" ref="#Apostolic_Palace">Vatican</name> or <name type="historical" ref="#St_Peters_Basilica">St. Peters</name>! If we can only get it out of italy without arousing suspicion! <persName ref="#Richter_Dr">Dr. R.</persName> to dinner.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-04-29" type="entry">
            <dateline><name type="hotel" ref="#Hotel_Cavour">Hotel Cavour</name>. <placeName ref="#Milan">Milan</placeName>. <date when="1898-04-29">April 29</date>. </dateline>
            <p>We have made a great stride on our blessed way home to <name type="animal" ref="#Toby_Dog">Toby</name> <pb n="180"/>and <placeName ref="#The_Reef">the Reef</placeName>. Was having been declared, <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> naturally began to feel uneasy, and to my great satisfaction decided to give up <placeName ref="#Venice">Venice</placeName>, and go home on the <name type="boat" ref="#Kaiser_Wilhelm_der_Grosse">Kaiser der Grosse</name> the 25 May. Sent <persName ref="#Monty">Monty</persName> over to <placeName ref="#Venice">Venice</placeName> for 3 days there, and picked him up at <placeName ref="#Bologna">Bologne</placeName> yesterday as we came through. I lost all our short stay of a week at <placeName ref="#Florence">Florence</placeName> - as I took to my bed at once with a sharp attack of influenza and did not leave it until the day we came away. <persName ref="#Baldwin_Dr">Dr. Baldwin</persName> in attendance twice a day. The cold still hangs on - and I feel really shattered. <persName ref="#Anderson_Hendrick">Anderson</persName> came from <placeName ref="#Rome">Rome</placeName> with the <persName ref="#Norman_family">Normans</persName> on Monday - and it was delightful to have him again. <persName ref="#Berenson_Bernard">Berenson</persName> and <persName ref="#Castello_Mrs">mrs. Castello</persName> to dine the night before we left and I got up for the dinner. I was furious that I could not go with <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> to lunch with them, and see their pretty houses, which <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> raved about. It rained all the time we were in <placeName ref="#Florence">Florence</placeName>, and is still at it, The weather very heavy and discouraging.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-04-30" type="entry">
            <dateline><placeName ref="#Lucerne">Lucerne</placeName> - <date when="1898-04-30">April 30</date>. <name type="hotel" ref="#Grand_Hotel_National">Hotel National</name>. </dateline>
            <p>A perfect day for that incomparable journey over the <placeName ref="#Alps">Alps</placeName> from <placeName ref="#Milan">Milan</placeName> here. We seem to have left all the rain behind us. Arrived at 7 o'clock leaving <placeName ref="#Milan">Milan</placeName> at 12:30 and found delightful rooms overlooking the lake.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-05-01" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-05-01">Sunday, May 1st</date>. </dateline>
            <p>The brilliant sunshine looked into my room this morning and the views across the lake were glorious with the snow capped mountains, and the green hills enclosing the heavenly blue lake. Drove for 2 hours<pb n="181"/> this morning among the hills and around the lake. All the country is full of blossoming cherry trees - meadows gay with flowers - the hum of bees and the song of birds. I heard the nightingales at 4 o'clock this morning. Wrote letters this afternoon and we had tea out on our balcony. Magnificent sunset effects - rosy snow mts. and clouds - reflected in the blue lake!</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-05-02" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-05-02">Monday, May 2</date>. </dateline>
            <p>Another fine day - walking, driving and hunting over <name type="historical" ref="#Bossards_Antiquity_Shop">Bossards antiquity shop</name> . Such a delight to think that next month at this time we ought to be at home - off tomorrow early for <placeName ref="#Paris">Paris</placeName>.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-05-04" type="entry">
            <dateline><name type="hotel" ref="#Hotel_Westminster">Hotel Westminster</name>. <placeName ref="#Paris">Paris</placeName>, <date when="1898-05-04">Wednesday, May. 4</date>. </dateline>
            <p>We left <placeName ref="#Luzern">Lucerne</placeName> yesterday at 7:30 A.M. in clouds and rain, which continued all day - and arrived here at 6 o'clock. Came to our old quarters - most homelike - with the smiling familiar faces of the <persName ref="#Hotel_Westminster_Concierge">Concierge</persName> and his <persName ref="#Hotel_Westminster_Concierge_Wife">wife</persName> - <persName ref="#Emil">Emil</persName> the waiter, and the kind, deprecating <persName ref="#Hotel_Westminster_Femme_De_Chambre">femme de chambre</persName> - news of the successful battle at <placeName ref="#Manila">Manilla</placeName>, and the triumph of <persName ref="#Dewey_George_Commodore">Commodore Dewey</persName>. Poor <placeName ref="#Spain">Spain</placeName> - I am full of sympathy for the brave <persName ref="#Queen_Christina">Queen Christina</persName> who has done all she could to rule and direct the troublesome country. Today it has been storming violently, with bursts of alternate sunshine. <persName ref="#Buttles_Mary">Mary</persName> and I were settling ourselves this morning - and began with gowns and shopping this afternoon. She has gone to the Circus with <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and <persName ref="#Monty">Monty</persName> this evening - and I am keeping our cheerful salon company, with a bright wood fire.<pb n="182"/></p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-05-14" type="entry">
            <dateline><placeName ref="#Paris">Paris</placeName> <date when="1898-05-14">May 14</date>. </dateline>
            <p>Since my last entry there has been nothing to write, except curses - deep and loud, against the weather. It has rained every day, persistently and continuously. I have not been out since the 4th, until yesterday, when I drove to <orgName ref="#Maison_Paquins">Paquins</orgName> a few doors off, and back. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> has had a great success with his <objectName type="painting" ref="#Portrait_of_a_Girl">Leonardo</objectName>. She was invited to the <placeName ref="#Louvre">Louvre</placeName>, and compared with the <objectName type="painting" ref="#Mona_Lisa">Mona Lisa</objectName> and the <objectName type="painting" ref="#Virgin_of_the_Rocks">Madonna of the rocks</objectName>. <persName ref="#Braun">Braun</persName> has photographed her magnificently - and <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> has given him the privilege of selling the photographs. <persName>Mary</persName> goes back home this morning. <persName ref="#Jones_Daniel">Jones</persName> and <persName ref="#Burgnoyne_Amelie">Amilie</persName> take her to the train, she has a compartment in the sleeping car which she does not leave until she reaches <placeName ref="#Pisa">Pisa</placeName> tomorrow night at 11 o'clock - where <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> meets her, and spends the night, and the have most of the day together there before going back to <placeName ref="#Florence">Florence</placeName>. We go at 11 o'clock tomorrow via <placeName ref="#Calais">Calais</placeName> to <placeName ref="#London">London</placeName>.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-05-17" type="entry">
            <dateline><name type="#hotel" ref="#Grand_Hotel_Bristol">Hotel Bristol</name>. <placeName ref="#London">London</placeName>. <date when="1898-05-17">May 17th</date>. </dateline>
            <p>We came over very comfortably from <placeName ref="#Paris">Paris</placeName> on Sunday - in spite of the rain. Fortunately it held up as we were getting on and off the boat, or it would have gone hard with me, as there is no protection whatever in the way of a roof. I had a nice little cabin, and laid down and slept most of the way - and the sea was smooth. Found our old quarters at this most comfortable of all hotels - and the weather has been good. Shopped a little and drove in the Park yesterday and today.<pb n="183"/> This afternoon went with <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> around to the <orgName ref="#Burlington_Fine_Arts_Club">Burlington Arts Club</orgName> to see the collection of Milanese paintings - quite charming and interesting. Found the photograph of our <objectName type="painting" ref="#Portrait_of_a_Girl">Leonardo</objectName> there opposite the <objectName type="painting" ref="#Mona_Lisa">Mona Lisa</objectName>. We have had visits from <persName ref="#Farrar_family">the Farrars</persName>, <persName ref="#Denbigh_family">Denbighs</persName>, <persName ref="#Rathbone_William_Gair">Mr. Rathbone</persName> and <persName>Fielding</persName> - all the rest off to the theatre, as they were last night. I do not risk the exposure. <persName ref="#Emmons_Mr">Mr. Emmons</persName> here today - they sail tomorrow on the <name type="boat" ref="#Teutonic">Teutonic</name>.
            </p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-05-22" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-05-22">Sunday, May 22</date>. </dateline>
            <p>The week has been rather quiet. I have had not dining out, no theatres or operas - as I do not go out in the evening. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> has been busy doing all of these things - and I scarcely see him, except at breakfast. The weather has been bad - today it is mending. I have had almost a daily drive in the <placeName>Park</placeName> - and yesterday I lunched with <persName ref="#Denbigh_Lady">Lady Denbigh</persName> - and met some pleasant people. Tonight <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> dines with <placeName>Lord Denbigh</placeName> - a man's dinner for <persName ref="#Denbigh_Lady">Lady D.</persName> has gone down to <placeName ref="#Nuneham">Nuneham</placeName> to her family of 8 children. <persName>Fielding</persName> came early yesterday, and he and <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> knocked about to galleries and shops in the morning, and he came to lunch and went with us afterward to the Military Tournament; came back to tea - and went home and dressed, came back and ined, and he and <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> had an old fashioned game of chess. I have just got home from a solitary drive in the <orgName>Part</orgName> - having first gone to tea with <persName ref="#Farrer_Miss">Miss Farrer</persName>. <placeName>The Park</placeName> lovely, backward as is the season, the trees are well out now, and the thorns beginning to show their flowers. <persName ref="#Bridgman_Dr">Dr. Bridgman</persName> called after lunch and made me a visit - telling me all about<pb n="184"/> our war! how the Spaniards had a disciplined navy, and we had not - how much cleverer and quicker they were than we - what an unrighteous war it was - but that in the end we must win, for they (England) intended standing by us!</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-05-24" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-05-24">Tuesday, May 24</date>. </dateline>
            <p>Our last evening in <placeName ref="#London">London</placeName> - and these two last days have been very busy - between friends and affairs. The weather still uncertain - we made the acquaintance of <persName ref="#Colvin_Sydney">Mr. Sydney Colvin</persName> this afternoon. He came to see the <objectName type="painting" ref="#Portrait_of_a_Girl">Leonardo</objectName> - and I talked a little with him about <persName ref="#Stevenson_Louis_Robert">Stevenson</persName>. He looks rather a hard, dry fellow. <persName ref="#Rathbone_William_Gair">Mr. Rathbone</persName> and <persName ref="#Farrar_William_Sir">Farrar</persName> here too. Last agonies of packing going on in all our rooms.</p> 
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1898-06-01" type="entry">
            <dateline><date when="1898-06-01">Tuesday, June 1st</date>. <placeName ref="#Holland_Hotel">Holland House</placeName>. </dateline>
            <p>Just one week ago tonight I made the last entry - and it is hard to realize - and now we are here again, after a very comfortable and monotonous voyage. The <name type="boat" ref="#Kaiser_Wilhelm_der_Grosse">Kaiser Wilhelm der Grosse</name> is the finest ship I have ever sailed on. Such comfort, luxury, cleanliness - good service, and the best and most profuse table I ever saw. <persName ref="#Rathbone_William_Gair">Mr. Rathbone</persName> and <persName>Fielding</persName> were at the station to say goodbye, the morning we left London. A quick and pleasant ride to <placeName ref="#Southhampton">Southhampton</placeName>, and as we ran along the big dock, with the <name type="boat" ref="#Kaiser_Wilhelm_der_Grosse">Kaiser</name> lying close to it, she looked enormous from the train. On three consecutive days we made 560 miles - and the voyage would have made a record, had we not 2 days before reaching<pb n="185"/> <placeName ref="#New_York">New York</placeName>, broke one or the blades of one of the screws. However, we were in our slip by 10:30 this morning. END vol 5 11</p>
      </div>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
