<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>Diary of Mrs. Emma B. Andrews. Volume 7 1899-1900</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>
          <orgName ref="#Emma_B_Andrews_Diary_Project">Emma B. Andrews Diary Project</orgName>
        </publisher>
        <address>
          <addrLine>University of Washington, Seattle, WA</addrLine>
        </address>
        <availability>
          <licence target="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/">This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</licence>
        </availability>
        <date>2021-01-12</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <p><name ref="#American_Philosophical_Society_Philadelphia">American Philosophical Society, Philadelphia</name></p>
      </sourceDesc>
      <encodingStmt>
        <projectDesc>
          <p>Established in 2010, the goals of the <name ref="#Emma_B_Andrews_Diary_Project">Emma B. Andrews Diary Project</name> include the transcription and digitization of a wide range of primary historical material from the <orgName ref="#'Golden_Age'">'Golden Age'</orgName> of <orgName ref="#Egyptian">Egyptian</orgName> archaeology at the end of the 19th and beginning of the 20th centuries. A founding partner of <name ref="#Newbook_Digital">Newbook Digital</name> Texts (www.newbookdigitaltexts.org), the <name ref="#EBA_Diary_Project">EBA Diary Project</name> offers undergraduate and graduate digital humanities education and internships at the <name ref="#University_of_Washington">University of Washington.</name> <persName ref="#Andrews_Emma_B">Emma B. Andrews</persName> is best remembered for her association with the millionaire lawyer turned archaeologist/art and antiquities collector, <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore M. Davis.</persName> Traveling to <placeName ref="#Egypt">Egypt</placeName> with him between 1889 and 1912, she kept detailed journals of these voyages along the <orgName ref="#Nile">Nile,</orgName> including his important yet under-reported excavations of over 20 significant tombs in the Valley of the Kings. <persName ref="#Emma">Emma</persName> provides a vital commentary on the archaeology and pioneering Egyptologists of the time, painting a revealing picture of the lives of the colonial gentry and the cultural and scientific literati in at the dawn of the twentieth century. Analysis of the content of her diaries, along with a broad range of additional primary source material, will afford scholars information about important historical resources for the first time.</p>
        </projectDesc>
      </encodingStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1899-11-26">
        <dateline>
          <pb n="65"/>Sunday, <date when="1899-11-26">Nov. 26, 1899</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>On the 18th at 11 o'clock, Saturday morning, we sailed from <placeName ref="#New_York">New York</placeName> on the <name type="boat" ref="#SS_Furst_Bismark">F&#369;rst Bismark</name> - the fourth voyage I have made in this boat - twice across the Northern <placeName ref="#Atlantic_Ocean">Atlantic</placeName>, and once, now 5 years ago, on this southern voyage. <persName ref="#Wilson_Clarence">Clarence Wilson</persName>, and <persName ref="#Amory_Howard">Howard Amory</persName> came to see us off. We have had a wonderful voyage - until tonight there has been no movement - we might have been travelling on a placid river. Now since leaving <placeName ref="#Gibraltar">Gibraltar</placeName> a few hours ago, the sea has been growing heavy and I find writing difficult. It has been very warm too - and I have as yet not worn any of my winter clothes. I have had a bad cold too - one of my old fashioned croupy colds, and stayed in bed 2 days. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> too, has had a cold, and does not get over it - because he won't be careful. I have been most comfortable - having the <persName ref="#Albers_Adolph">Captain's</persName> room and have enjoyed my little sitting room much, where we have our friends to tea. This afternoon we had <persName ref="#Woodworth_Mrs">Mrs. Woodworth</persName> and <persName ref="#Woodworth_Fanny">her daughter</persName> and <persName ref="#Maitland_Tom">Mr. Tom Maitland</persName>. They had been ashore at <placeName ref="#Gibraltar">Gibraltar</placeName> in the wet, and were glad enough to come in for a cup of good tea. For it began to pour with rain this morning and by 9 o'clock when we dropped anchor at <placeName ref="#Gibraltar">Gib.</placeName> it was almost invisible because of the rain. We had hoped to see or hear something of the <persName ref="#Wilsons">Wilsons</persName> - but if they were there, they could not face the weather. I discovered an old <placeName ref="#Columbus">Columbus</placeName> friend on board this after- noon - <persName ref="#Bates_Mary">Mary Bates</persName>! and she has been spending an hour or so with me this evening - and we have been talking of old times and people - <pb n="66"/>how many are gone! and how few remain!</p>
          </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1899-11-28">
        <dateline>
          Tuesday, <date when="1899-11-28">Nov. 28</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>The last day of this long voyage has come - and I begin to feel more cheerful. The weather very squally for 2 days - but still warm. I sat out in my chair all the afternoon yesterday - dozing and watching the magnificent pageant of the clouds - such splendid marshalling of strange grand shapes - and such constant vivid effects of light and shade - until I was driven in as everyone else by a very sharp squall of wind and rain. We are due early tomorrow morning at <placeName ref="#Naples">Naples</placeName>.</p> 
          </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1899-11-29">
        <dateline>
          Wednesday, <date when="1899-11-29">Nov. 29</date>. <name type="hotel" ref="#Grand_Hotel">Grand Hotel</name>. <placeName ref="#Naples">Naples</placeName>.
        </dateline>
          <p>True to our schedule we arrived early this morning. There was such a stir on deck and about the boat all night that I did not sleep well, and in spite of my determination not to get up early, and have the usual dreary waiting to land, I gladly heard the anchor go down at 5:30 and was up and for breakfast by 7 o'clock. I caught a splendid view of <placeName ref="#Vesuvius">Vesuvius</placeName> as we slowly steamed in, while dressing, - the sun was rising, but had only touched a long, level line of smoke from its crater, turning it to gold - while all the rest of the world was in semi darkness. By 9 o'clock we were seated at breakfast before a little cackling wood fire in our sitting room here, with <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and <persName ref="#Wilson_Alice">Alice Wilson</persName>. Soon after, young <persName ref="#Constantine">Costantine</persName> from <placeName ref="#Rome">Rome</placeName> turned up. The <pb n="67"/> rest went for the <name ref="#Posolippo">Posillipo</name> drive - and this afternoon leaving <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> to rest and take care of his cold, we drove to <placeName ref="#Sant_Anna_dei_Lombardi">S. Olivato</placeName>, but found it closed, and then to <placeName ref="#Santa_Chiara">Santa Chiarra</placeName> to see the Gothic tombs of the Angevine kings. The church cold and deserted, except for an old priest tottering down the aisle with his cat dancing behind. Sat in the palm garden after dinner and talked to <persName ref="#Woodward_Haven_Mrs">Mrs. Woodward</persName> and the <persName ref="#Morton_Girls">Morton girls</persName>.</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1899-12-01">
        <dateline>
          Friday <date when="1899-12-01">Dec. 1st</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>We had a long pleasant morning at <placeName ref="#National_Archeological_Musuem_Naples">the museum</placeName> yesterday - some shopping in the afternoon. This morning <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and I took the <placeName ref="#Posolippo">Posillipo</placeName> drive. <persName ref="#Costantini_David">Constantini</persName> and the girls going to <placeName ref="#Pompeii">Pompeii</placeName>. The morning heavenly beautiful and calm. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> has been wretched with his cold - and with a bad boil on his cheek, which developed at sea, and which it has been difficult to heal - so we had <persName ref="#Malbranc_Dr">Dr. Malbrane</persName> after getting here, who lanced and dressed it - it is now much better.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1899-12-03">
        <dateline>
          Sunday, <date when="1899-12-03">Dec. 3d</date>. <name type="hotel" ref="#Hotel_International">Hotel Internationale</name> - <placeName ref="#Brindisi">Brindisi</placeName>.
        </dateline>
          <p>Left <placeName ref="#Naples">Naples</placeName> yesterday at noon - arrived here at 10:30 last night, well tired. Ordered fires in all the rooms at once, had the beds pulled to pieces, and the very damp sheets and pillow cases dried before the fire - while we went down to the chill coffee room and had some good hot chocolate. The house and everything in it seems so damp - as it is so close to the water. Today, until 3 o'clock, it has rained - now it is clear and cool. We have just had some tea before <pb n="68"/> the fire in our big gold and red sitting room. The <name type="boat" ref="#Osiris">Osiris</name> lies at the quay, just opposite the <name type="hotel" ref="#Hotel_International">hotel</name>, and we go on board of her tonight after dinner.</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1899-12-07">
        <dateline>
          <name type="hotel" ref="#Shepheards_Hotel">Shepheards Hotel</name>. <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName>. <date when="1899-12-07">Dec. 7th</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>We arrived last evening at 7 o'clock - having reached <placeName ref="#Port_Said">Port Said</placeName> at 8 o'clock in the morning. The three nights and two days we were on the <name type="boat" ref="#Osiris">Osiris</name> were dismal and wretched - a clean, pretty, well arranged and comfortable boat when at rest, she is the very evil one when in motion. We left <placeName ref="#Brindisi">Brindisi</placeName> at midnight. I had gone comfortably to sleep in my clean, roomy cheerful cabin, but wakened with the stir of starting and as soon as we got outside we met the heavy sea which the high wind had promised us all day - and between the shrieking of the wind, the tramping of the sailors overhead, and the heavy rolling, sleep went far away from me. I only spent part of one afternoon on the deck and appeared once at dinner - and although not ill, I preferred staying in bed to being knocked and rolled about - so there I did stay until the morning we reached <placeName ref="#Port_Said">Port Said</placeName> - <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> had fallen in with <persName ref="#Red_Rennell_Sir">Sir Rennell Red</persName> in the smoking room, and made friends on the strength of mutual tastes, and common friends. We were too late for the morning train to <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName>, but the mail train had a saloon car attached for <persName ref="#Red_Rennell_Sir">Sir Rennell</persName>, who kindly asked us to share it with him, which we gladly did. We have charming rooms here to the garden, on the 3d floor where we have never been before. This morning <persName ref="#Salah_Mohammed">Salah</persName> came, and we went to see the <name type="boat" ref="#Beduin">Beduin</name> and her crew. She is at the <placeName ref="#Giza_Museum_Landing">Museum landing</placeName>, and is <pb n="69"/> almost ready for us - and I heartily wished we could have stayed on her - <persName ref="#Abdul">Abdul</persName> and <persName ref="#Fuli_Rais">Fuli</persName>, and all our men were so glad to see us. The river is discouragingly low - all our friends have gone up.</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1899-12-08">
        <dateline>
          Friday, <date when="1899-12-08">Dec. 8th</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p><persName ref="#Wilson_Alice">Alice</persName> met some friends from <placeName ref="#Copenhagen">Copenhagen</placeName> in the dining room last evening - <persName ref="#Trauttenberg_Baron #Trauttenberg_Baroness">Baron and Baroness Trantenburg</persName>. He is the Austrian delegate on the <orgName ref="#Caisse_de_la_Dette">Caisse de la Debttes</orgName>, and she is Russian - agreeable, full of talk, gesticulation and demonstration. He a charming elderly man of very decided parts. <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> has had quite a shock since arriving. <persName ref="#Hassan">Hassan</persName> who came over about 3 months ago, has been very ill, and is in <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName>. She went with <persName ref="#Salah_Mohammed">Salah</persName> to see him yesterday, at the house of his uncle <persName ref="#Rais_Mahommed">Rais Mahommed</persName> and found him in a lamentable state in the noise and dirt of an ordinary mud village - and so ill and dazed with fever and medicine that he did not know her - she came home in great distress and telling <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> about it, and he said at once, "come, and we will go to the German Hospital and try and get him in there". And by 7 o'clock the poor fellow was comfortaby installed as second class patient in that excellent hospital. The Doctor pronounces it consumption and we fear it is.</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1899-12-09">
        <dateline>
          Saturday, <date when="1899-12-09">Dec. 9</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>At the <name type="boat" ref="#Beduin">dahabeah</name>, driving and shopping all day. <persName ref="#Red_Rennell_Sir">Sir Rennell Rod</persName> called, and <persName ref="#Sandwith_Dr">Dr. Sandwith</persName>. After dinner <persName ref="#Frantenberg_Mr">the Frantenbergs</persName> and we sat and talked in the big new hall which is such an improvement to <pb n="70"/> <name type="hotel" ref="#Shepheards_Hotel">Shepherds</name>. We are so busy we can do no sight seeing, as we are very anxious to get off on Thursday of next week.</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1899-12-12">
        <dateline>
          Tuesday, <date when="1899-12-12">Dec. 12</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>At the <name type="boat" ref="#Beduin">dab.</name> most of the day - and are now in very good shape and ready for the first north wind that comes along.</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1899-12-13">
        <dateline>
          Wednesday, <date when="1899-12-13">Dec. 13</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>We spent the morning at <placeName ref="#Egyptian_Museum">the Museum</placeName> - and had <persName ref="#Mitchell_Dr #Mitchell_Mrs">Dr. and Mrs. Mitchell</persName>, Scotch people, with whom <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> struck up an acquaintance on the <name type="boat" ref="#Osiris">Osiris</name> to lunch. The <persName ref="#Mitchell_Dr">Dr.</persName> is a well known Edinboro divine, very pleasant and interesting. They are going up the river with <persName ref="#Ashburton_Lady">Lady Ashburton</persName> in her best. <persName ref="#von_Bissing_Baron">Baron von Bissing</persName> came to dine - and told us many things about Egyptian things. Every one is so charmed to have <persName ref="#Maspero_Gaston">Maspero</persName> again at the head of the antiquities dep. and to be rid of <persName ref="#Loret_M">Loret</persName>. Indeed the French were given to understand by <persName ref="#Cromer_Lord">Lord Cromer</persName> that if they did not send <persName ref="#Maspero_Gaston">Maspero</persName>, the administration would go out of their hands. There have been two inspectors appointed - a new office. <persName ref="#Quibell_James">Quibell</persName> is inspector of Lower Egypt, and <persName ref="#Carter_Howard">Howard Carter</persName> for Upper Egypt. Why <persName ref="#Carter_Howard">Carter</persName>, who doesn't know hieroglyphs, should have been appointed no one can say. And <persName ref="#Newberry_Percy">Newberry</persName> is in <placeName ref="#England">England</placeName>, with no appointment, for which we are very sorry - and which no one with a sense of fitness can understand.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1899-12-14">
        <dateline>
          Thursday, <date when="1899-12-14">Dec. 14</date>. <name type="boat" ref="#Beduin">Beduin</name>.
        </dateline>
          <p>Came on board this morning. <persName ref="#Quibell_James">Mr. Quibell</persName> came to lunch - such <pb n="71"/>. a pleasant visit - very busy all the afternoon settling. No wind and could not move - are still at <placeName ref="#Giza_Museum_Landing">the Museum landing</placeName> - but so pleased to be once more in this charming little floating home -the very abode of peace and repose.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1899-12-15">
        <dateline>
          Friday, <date when="1899-12-15">Dec. 15</date>. 12 miles.
        </dateline>
          <p>Again very busy putting things in order. The rest drove into <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> - <persName ref="#von_Bissing_Baron">Baron V. Bissing</persName> came to lunch - and a slight south wind having come up, after lunch, we gladly spread our sails and started, with <persName ref="#von_Bissing_Baron">v. Bissing</persName> and <persName ref="#Salah_Mohammed">Salah</persName> saying goodbye from the shore. It was 2 o'clock and we came along slowly and gently, until just as the sun set most gloriously behind a forest of grand palms, the wind seemed to die out; but with the <name type="boat" ref="#Beduin">Beduins</name> mysterious power of slipping along with no wind, we moved silently on the broad light of a full moon, until we tied up at 7 o'clock - about 3 miles below <placeName ref="#Al_Badrashayn">Bedrescheen</placeName>.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1899-12-16">
        <dateline>
          Saturday, <date when="1899-12-16">Dec. 16</date>. 12 miles.
        </dateline>
          <p>A very warm still morning - we did not move. Had the awning up - and sat on deck all day - very hot - we went for a walk after breakfast, but found too much dust and too many flies, and were driven home by the too ardent sun. About 2 o'clock a light wind came up, and we moved off - and were passing <placeName ref="#Hulwan">Helouan</placeName> at 4 o'clock - the river wide and very difficult - and many working boats about - we did not touch bottom once - and sailed until 8 o'clock <pb n="72"/> occasionally as the wind died away, the men polled. We had tea on deck, and I came down soon after, and had a beautiful hour and a half on my sofa, looking out at the gloriously soft moonlight, the passing shores, and the silvered sails of the boats past which we glided - and we are now lying against a bank on which splendid palms are growing having made 12 miles - and being just 3 miles ahead of this day last year.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1899-12-17">
        <dateline>
          3d Sunday in <name type="event" ref="#Advent">Advent</name>, <date when="1899-12-17">Dec. 17</date>. 5 miles.
        </dateline>
          <p>A perfectly calm day - I have been quite miserable all day. Our men tracked for a long time, and we thus made 5 miles -very hot.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1899-12-18">
        <dateline>
          Monday, <date when="1899-12-18">Dec. 18th</date>. 39 miles.
        </dateline>
          <p>I was quite happy this morning to hear before 7 o'clock the stir of preparation for sailing - and when my shutters were opened and I saw that we were under sail with quite a fair wind, and the sun shone soft and bright into my room, and I felt quite well, I was happy and thankful. The wind fell very light after awhile, and for an hour and a half our men polled, but since that we have been coming along in a steady, strong wind, and when we pulled up at 7 o'clock this evening, we had made 39 miles. Passed <placeName ref="#Al_Wasta">Wasta</placeName> at four o'clock, at which time we were sitting on deck, without wraps - which was not a bad thing to do on the 18th of Dec! We are tied up to the same island we were last year. It has been a most delightful day - and <pb n="73"/> it is a most delightful night. I stood at the window tonight looking at the moonlighted water and at <name type="constellation" ref="#Orion">Orion</name> and <name type="constellation" ref="#Sirius">Sirius</name>, wonderfully bright. I have always been so sorry we did not call our boat "Sirius" or "Saphis". <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> began reading aloud this evening, "<objectName ref="#England_in_the_19th_Century">England in the Nineteenth Century</objectName>" by <persName ref="#Oman_Charles">Oman</persName>. I am enchanted with <objectName ref="#Stevensons_Letter">Stevenson's letters</objectName>, by <persName ref="#Calvin_Sydney">Sydney Calvin</persName>, just published. I have almost finished the 1st volume.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1899-12-19">
        <dateline>
          Tuesday, <date when="1899-12-19">Dec. 19th</date>. 8 miles.
        </dateline>
          <p>An unsatisfactory day, we have made only 8 miles. The morning was absolutely placid - the water without a wrinkle. About 2 o'clock, we began sailing in a light wind, which after awhile grew fitful, and then very strong - and the river being now so uncertain we did not dare keep on, but took refuge under a high bank for an hour. Then we polled and tracked and finally at 7 o'clock pulled up to the landing at <placeName ref="#Benisoef">Benisoef</placeName> - making 8 miles.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1899-12-20">
        <dateline>
          Wednesday, <date when="1899-12-20">Dec. 20th</date>. 29 miles.
        </dateline>
          <p>Another placid morning - the wind coming up about noon, and lasting until about 6 o'clock - about 12 o'clock we saw the smoke of the <name type="boat" ref="#Rameses"><choice><sic>Hameses the Great</sic><corr>Rameses the Great</corr></choice></name> - but she did not catch us until 5:30, as she was not making fast time, owing to the low water. <persName ref="#Fearing_Dan #Fearing_Mrs">Mr. and Mrs. Dan Fearing</persName> were on her - we had all hoped to meet in <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> but they arrived the very day we left - and we hoped to catch them this evening at <placeName ref="#Maghaghah">Maghagah</placeName> - but our wind failed us, and we had to tie up four miles below <placeName ref="#Maghaghah">Maghagah</placeName>. <pb n="74"/></p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1899-12-21">
        <dateline>
          Thursday, <date when="1899-12-21">Dec. 21st</date>. 22 miles.
        </dateline>
          <p>No wind until noon - a very light one however, lasting until after 5 o'clock - we have pulled to the anchor and polled a good deal - and are now within 2 miles of <placeName ref="#el_Sheikh_Fadl">Sheik Fadl</placeName>. For two or three days there has been a little nip of winter in the air, which with the bright sunlight, has made a delicious air. Tonight it is very dark - many cloud about, and not even the "cold light of stars". We are tonight 56 miles in advance of this day last year - and it is just one week today since we started.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1899-12-22">
        <dateline>
          Friday, <date when="1899-12-22">Dec. 22d</date>. 6 miles.
        </dateline>
          <p>The morning was cloudy with wind from the south. When my blinds were opened, I found we were lying at a board kind of beach, with a short herbage growing on it, and knowing we would not move until the wind went down, I sent word to have the fowls let out, and from my window I could see the whole performance which I always enjoy. The pair of sacred geese went first, and took at once to the water. Then the pet cock Dick, and his three white hens and then the turkeys, bedraggled indeed, the doves, and the rabbits. Dick remembers me very well, and when <persName ref="#Burgnoyne_Amelie">Amelie</persName> opened the window and I called to him, he came at once, and would have been in the room, had we not closed the window. About 10, the wind fell somewhat and we pulled to the anchor, and then sailed for an hour or so, until a difficult bend in the river brought the wind in our face - so we pulled up for the night at a beautiful low, broad sand bank, where we are <pb n="75"/> now lying, with the smoke of <placeName ref="#Galassaneh">Galassaneh</placeName> just around the corner - brining us within 25 miles of <placeName ref="#Al_Minya">Minieh</placeName>, where we got our first mail. We feel very anxious to have news of the war - all our English friends in <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> were very sad and anxious. We had a wonderful sunset - splendid clouds touched into pink and crimson, against a brilliant blue sky; and in the midst of it, a little pitiful funeral cortege came across the sand, the few men bearing the wooden bier or box in which the dead man was laid, sewed up the coarse cloth - and the women crying and throwing dust upon their heads - they all got into a boat and were rowed across the river to the western shore where we could see the white mounds of acropolis. Two Egyptian gentlemen with a village sheik walked down to the boat to look at her, and <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> sent <persName ref="#Abdul">Abdul</persName> out to ask if they would like to come inside and see her, which they gladly did - and after making their obeisances to us on deck, <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> took them below, and they were mightily pleased. They only spoke Arabic - so <persName ref="#Abdul">Abdul</persName> acted as an interpreter.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1899-12-23">
        <dateline>
          Saturday, <date when="1899-12-23">Dec. 23</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>A miserable day so far as getting on is concerned - though it has been charming indoors where I have spent the day. It has been cold, with constant high south wind - and we have not stirred an inch, fortunately we are lying at a peasant place.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1899-12-24">
        <dateline>
          Fourth Sunday in <name type="event" ref="#Advent">Advent</name>. <date when="1899-12-24">Dec. 24</date>. 4 miles.
        </dateline>
          <p>Wind still south - clear and cool. We <pb n="76"/> tracked about 4 miles - and have a very high bank on one side of us. Busy this afternoon and evening with little <name type="event" ref="#Christmas">Xmas</name> preparations.</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1899-12-25">
        <dateline>
          <name type="event" ref="#Christmas">Christmas</name>, <date when="1899-12-25">Dec. 25</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>A beautiful cold morning, with south west wind which continued all day. The air has been deliciously pure and pleasant. We had a Merry breakfast and afterwards distributed our gifts to the men- which is always such a pleasant thing to do - they are such happy children on such occasions. Then we went on deck to see our display there. <persName ref="#Jones_Daniel">Jones</persName> and the men had been busy with it since 5 o'clock this morning, and it was entirely charming - with palm branches and other green things with bunches of mandarins - and all the flags and pennants flying. The thermometer on my cabana went to 41 last night - as against 66 at midday.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1899-12-26">
        <dateline>
          Tuesday, <date when="1899-12-26">Dec. 26</date>. 13 miles. (12 miles)
        </dateline>
          <p>Which we have made mostly this afternoon - the wind all this morning was very shifting - and cool, below <placeName ref="#Al_Minya">Minieh</placeName> - and cloudy. We hope to reach <placeName ref="#Al_Minya">Minieh</placeName> tomorrow.</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1899-12-27">
        <dateline>
          Wednesday, <date when="1889-12-27">Dec. 27.</date> 14 miles.
        </dateline>
          <p>Another perfectly calm morning and very cold, the 2 above <placeName ref="#Al_Minya">Minia</placeName> mercury last night at 37 degrees. Once last year, we had it at 38 degrees - about 11 o'clock a light wind began and we reached <placeName ref="#Al_Minya">Minia</placeName> at 3:30. Sent ashore for mail, and posted a heap of letters, and then <pb n="77"/> started on, but only made about 2 miles, when the wind failed us. Saw the "<name type="boat" ref="#Mâat"><choice><sic>Mast</sic><corr>Maat</corr></choice></name>" at <placeName ref="#Al_Minya">Minia</placeName> - <persName ref="#Northampton_Marquis">Lord Northampton</persName> so our <persName ref="#Fuli_Rais">Rais</persName> reported, is making some excavations near <placeName ref="#Al_Minya">Minia</placeName>. We have <choice><sic>given</sic><corr>given up</corr></choice> reading <persName ref="#d'Este_Isabella">Isabella d'Esta</persName> it is so garrulous and so confused - and we have begun "<name type="book" ref="#Italian_Unity">Italian Unity</name>" a charming concise and clear little history - "<name type="book" ref="#England_in_the_Nineteenth_Century">England in the 19th Century</name>", by <persName ref="#Oman_Charles">Oman</persName>, whom we met last spring in <placeName ref="#Oxford">Oxford</placeName> when we lunched with <persName ref="#Sayce_Archibald">Mr. Sayce</persName>. We received a huge mail today, good news from all our letters - but distressing accounts of affairs at the seat of war in South Africa. <persName ref="#Roberts_Lord">Lord Roberts</persName> has been sent down as Commander in Chief with <persName ref="#Kitchener_Herbert">Lord Kitchener</persName> as his Chief of Staff. The latter has resigned, and bidden farewell to the <orgName ref="#Egyptian_Army">Egyptian Army</orgName>, and is happily on his way to <placeName ref="#Africa">Africa</placeName>. A sad incident was <persName ref="#Roberts_Lord">Lord Roberts</persName> receiving on the day of his appointment news of the death in battle of his only son! We are tonight 74 miles ahead of last year.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1899-12-28">
        <dateline>
          Thursday, <date when="1899-12-28">Dec. 28</date>. 13-1/2 miles. <placeName ref="#Bani_Hasan">Beni Hassan</placeName>
        </dateline>
          <p>No wind until 11 o'clock - then slight - day cold and often cloudy - quite a mist tonight on the river - tracked and sailed, and are lying about a mile above <placeName ref="#Al_Minya">Minia</placeName>.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1899-12-29">
        <dateline>
          Friday, <date when="1899-12-29">Dec. 29</date>. 20 miles.
        </dateline>
          <p>Began tracking at 8 o'clock this morning and kept it up for two hours. At noon the wind began, and we have sailed slowly and steadily along - bringing up 3 miles below <pb n="78"/> <placeName ref="#Hag_Kandil">Hadji Kanduh</placeName> at 6 o'clock. Stuck upon a sand bank for 5 minutes. Beautiful day, cool and bright.</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1899-12-30">
        <dateline>
          Saturday, <date when="1899-12-30">Dec. 30</date>. 17 miles.
        </dateline>
          <p>When I drew aside my curtain this morning at 7 o'clock, I found the fog so thick that I could not see the water - occasionally a pale ghost of sun would show itself, to disappear in a moment - and it was not until 10 o'clock that the fog moved off so that we could track - and pulling to an anchor and tracking we got on until noon, when a light wind came, and carried us on until 6 o'clock - at which time we pulled up for the night, just at the long turning that leads to the <placeName ref="#Gebel_Abu_Foda">Gebel Abufeyda</placeName> cliffs - of which the Captains are always so afraid.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1899-12-31">
        <dateline>
          First Sunday after <name type="event" ref="#Christmas">Christmas</name>. <date when="1899-12-31">Dec. 31</date>. 30 miles.
        </dateline>
          <p>Another heavy fog prevailed this morning - and we were not off until nearly 10 o'clock - tracked and sailed until about 2 o'clock, when in a strong wind we sailed until 6 o'clock - bringing us within 10 miles of <placeName ref="#Asyut">Assiut</placeName>. The day has been beautiful. Passed the <placeName ref="#Gebel_Abu_Foda">Gebel Abufeda</placeName> - and <placeName ref="#Manfalût">Manfalout</placeName>.</p>
          </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-01-01">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1900-01-01">January 1st</date>. 1900! <placeName ref="#Asyut">Assiut</placeName>. 10 miles.
        </dateline>
          <p>The beginning of a new century is really thrilling! so much do our arbitrary divisions of time influence our feeling and sentiment - we have been discussing the true beginning of the <pb n="79"/> century - whether it is today, or not until 1901. There seems to be a wide difference of opinion about this - and the papers are full of it. We received news on our arrival here, of poor <persName ref="#Hassan">Hassan's</persName> death - on the 27th of Dec. and we feel very sad over it. <!-- Do I tag this? --><persName>The Sister</persName> from the <!-- Unknown --><placeName>Hospital</placeName> wrote that he sank rapidly from weakness, and died quietly in possession of all his faculties. It will be a great loss to my <!-- Do I tag this? --><persName>sister-in-law</persName>'s family. We have had a great blow from the North all day - and have taken until 3 o'clock to make the great bends in the river before reaching <placeName ref="#Asyut">Assiut</placeName>. It is an interesting spectacle the work on the great dam here - and much seems to have been accomplished since we saw it last March. We are lying at a very high bank - and the dust is flying everywhere.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-01-02">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1900-01-02">Jan. 2</date>. Tuesday. 32 miles.
        </dateline>
          <p>We began sailing at 7 o'clock this morning in a very good wind, and soon after breakfast had passed <placeName ref="#Abu_Tij">Aboutig</placeName>, and are now about 10 miles above <placeName ref="#Tahta">Tahtah</placeName>. Unfortunately the wind increased to a gale, and at 12 o'clock - in a difficult turn, we had to furl our sails, and anchor until 5:30 when we were able to get off, and did not stop until after 6 o'clock. If we could have made the turn, where we came to grief, we would have been able to sail the whole day, and would have made a record journey. The evening was beautiful - and just under Venus, the palest little crescent of a new moon was seen - at which our sailors looked with much interest, as <name type="event" ref="#Ramadam">Ramadan</name>, The Mahommedan Lent, begins the day after the first appearance <pb n="80"/> of a new moon following the first day of their lunar year.</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-01-03">
        <dateline>
          Wednesday, <date when="1900-01-03">Jan. 3d</date>. 40-1/2 miles.
        </dateline>
          <p>Started early in a fair wind, making <placeName ref="#Sohag">Sohag</placeName> at about 2:30 - where we pulled up a few moments to get our mail - and managed by tracking and polling to make the awkward turn to <placeName ref="#Akhmīm">Akmim</placeName> - 5 miles from <placeName ref="#Sohag">Sohag</placeName>.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-01-04">
        <dateline>
          Thursday, <date when="1900-01-04">Jan. 4th</date>. 27-1/2 miles.
        </dateline>
          <p>We have been hoping to reach <placeName ref="#Balyana_Al">Balliana</placeName> either last night or this morning to meet the <persName ref="#Fearing_Dan #Fearing_Mrs">Fearings</persName> who are on the <name type="boat" ref="#Rameses">Rameses the III</name>. But the wind failed us all the morning - and to our great disappointment when within 2 miles of <placeName ref="#Balyana_Al">Balliana</placeName>, we met the <name type="boat" ref="#Rameses">Rameses</name> on her way down, though she was scheduled not to sail until tomorrow morning. We could only shout our mutual regrets to each other. We were so anxious to show them the <name type="boat" ref="#Beduin">Beduin</name>, and they equally anxious to see it.</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-01-05">
        <dateline>
          Friday, <date when="1900-01-05">Jan. 5th</date>. <placeName ref="#Balyana_Al">Balliana</placeName>.
        </dateline>
          <p>Still lying where we pulled up last night - <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and <persName ref="#Wilson_Alice">Alice</persName> went out to <placeName ref="#Abydos">Abydos</placeName> this morning - lunching there, reaching home before 5 o'clock. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> reports that the road has been greatly improved in view of the visit of <persName ref="#Cromer_Lord">Lord Cromer</persName> - and that they had good donkeys - 2 things hardly to be believed of <placeName ref="#Abydos">Abydos</placeName> - the day quite cool. <pb n="81"/></p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-01-06">
        <dateline>
          Saturday, <date when="1900-01-06">Jan. 6</date>. 5 miles.
        </dateline>
          <p>A dead calm all day - only moved by tracking and polling.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-01-07">
        <dateline>
          Sunday, <date when="1900-01-07">Jan. 7</date>. <name type="event" ref="#Epiphany">Epiphany</name>. 8 miles.
        </dateline>
          <p>Another calm day - and very warm, -84&#176; on the cabana and the really first warm evening we have had. Our young moon begins to make the nights beautiful.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-01-07">
        <dateline>
          Monday, <date when="1900-01-07">Jan. 8</date>. 3 miles.
        </dateline>
          <p>Calm day, with occasional gusts of strong south wind, made our 3 little miles by dint of patient tracking and poling.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-01-07">
        <dateline>
          Tuesday, <date when="1900-01-07">Jan. 9</date>. 10 miles.
        </dateline>
          <p>No wind this morning - but tracking and pulling to anchor we reached <placeName ref="#Naj_Hammadi">Nagh-Hamadi</placeName> to see the bridge just closing - and had to wait until 3 o'clock. We went through in beautiful style reaching <placeName ref="#Qasr_es_Sayyad">Kasr es Sayd</placeName> and tying up just above it.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-01-10">
        <dateline>
          Wednesday, <date when="1900-01-10">Jan. 10</date>. 38 miles.
        </dateline>
          <p>Started out this morning at 7 o'clock with a side wind, rather strong, and came dangerously near making a wreck of ourselves in about half an hour - going full sail on to some rocks quite concealed by the water. It made a frightful row; <pb n="82"/> I was reading in bed, and found myself standing in the middle of the room shouting, "Good heavens! what have we done!" Everything and everybody was in an uproar, the sails were dropped - hatches up, and the bottom of the boat carefully searched - but no opening found and no leakage - but there we stuck. Fortunately we were not far from <placeName ref="#Qasr_es_Sayyad">Kasr es Sayd</placeName> - and the <!-- Unknown --><persName>Reis</persName> sent the felucca to shore for help. Two trips of her, brought about 20 men, with the <persName ref="#Sheik">Sheik</persName> of the village - and they immediately with our men went overboard, and after much grunting and heaving, swung the boat around, and afloat again. It was a cold morning, and a high wind blowing - and after I was dressed I went on deck and we were pulling to the anchor to make a difficult turn, and land the men. They were a rough looking lot - and one of them more nearly like a monkey than any human being I ever saw. He was a savage buffoon - and full of capers - grimaces and always shouting. We were glad to get rid of them and they were excessively pleased at the 21. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> gave the <persName ref="#Sheik">Sheik</persName> to be distributed among them. Then our men set vigourously to work to clean and wash the deck where they had been - we are now lying a little above <placeName ref="#Keneh">Keneh</placeName>.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-01-11">
        <dateline>
          Thursday, <date when="1900-01-11">Jan. 11</date>. 27 miles.
        </dateline>
          <p>Contrary winds and alternate calms have made sailing very difficult today. Beautiful weather. Five miles above <placeName ref="#Naqādah">Nagada</placeName>.</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-01-12">
        <dateline>
          Friday, <date when="1900-01-12">Jan. 12</date>. 17-1/2 miles. <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName>.
        </dateline>
          <p>We arrived today at 3:30. Found only the <pb n="83"/> "<name type="boat" ref="#Gazelle">Gaselle</name>" and the "<name type="boat" ref="#Miriam">Miriam</name>" here. <persName ref="#Maspero_Gaston">M. Maspero</persName> is on the "<name type="boat" ref="#Miriam">Miriam</name>". We are most anxious to know him. We have made the trip from <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> here, staying one day at <placeName ref="#Abydos">Abydos</placeName>, in 28 days. Came to our old place under the <!-- Unknown --><placeName>Castle</placeName> - where <persName ref="#Insinger_Mr">Mr. Insinger</persName> is renewing his river front in a very substantial manner.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-01-13">
        <dateline>
          Saturday, <date when="1900-01-13">Jan. 13</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>To <placeName ref="#Karnak">Karnak</placeName> this morning - a delightful ride. They are still excavating and finding some good things there. But the fall last summer of the 10 columns in the great hall, makes a melancholy spectacle. They are now being raised. Saw <persName ref="#Carter_Howard">Mr. Carter</persName> yesterday - <persName ref="#Huhatt_Mr">Mr. Huhatt</persName> to lunch.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-01-14">
        <dateline>
          Second Sunday after <name type="event" ref="#Epiphany">Epiphany</name>. <date when="1900-01-14">Jan. 14</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p><persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I went to church today, the little chapel looking more attractive than usual. The hotel is virtually empty - and the congregation was small. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and <persName ref="#Wilson_Alice">Alice</persName> went to <placeName ref="#Karnak"><choice><sic>Kanah</sic><corr>Karnak</corr></choice></placeName>. <persName ref="#Maspero_Gaston #Masspero_Louise">M. and Mme. Maspero</persName> called soon after lunch. We were delighted to meet them. He speaks excellent English, but she, only French. He has promised to send us over under <persName ref="#Carter_Howard">Mr. Carter's</persName> guidance to see the great <name type="historical" ref="#Tomb_of_Amenhotep_II">Amenhotep II tomb</name>, which <persName ref="#Loret_M">Loret</persName> discovered last winter - and on the "<name type="boat" ref="#Miriam">Miriam</name>" ready to go down to <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName>, is an immensely interesting cargo - no less than nine royal mummies, found in that tomb - and making a splendid sequence with those found years ago at <placeName ref="#Der_el_Bahari">Derl el Bahri</placeName>, of the kings and members of their families. We invited the <persName ref="#Maspero_Gaston #Maspero_Louise">Masperos</persName> with their niece to dine <pb n="84"/> next Tuesday. Last evening <persName ref="#Murch_Chauncey">Mr. Murch</persName> called - as large as life, and even larger than last year. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and <persName ref="#Wilson_Alice">Alice</persName> after the <persName ref="#Maspero_Gaston #Maspero_Louise">Masperos</persName> left this afternoon, rode over to <name type="historical" ref="#Temple_of_Hatshepsut">Hatshepaut's temple</name> - reporting it very disagreeable, because of the construction of some protecting roofs and colonnades.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-01-15">
        <dateline>
          Monday, <date when="1900-01-15">Jan. 15</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>A very quiet, cool day - overcast. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and <persName ref="#Wilson_Alice">Alice</persName> went this afternoon to <name type="historical" ref="#Medinet_Habu_Temple">Medinet Habu</name>. They report the country on the other side of the river quite desolate and uncultivated back from the river. <persName ref="#Insinger_Mr #Insinger_Miss">Mr. and Mrs. Insinger</persName> called and had tea with us - and sent flowers.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-01-16">
        <dateline>
          Tuesday, <date when="1900-01-16">Jan. 16</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>Rode into the town this morning and went to see <persName ref="#Murch_Dr">Dr. Murch</persName> - stayed until nearly one o'clock looking at scarabs. <persName ref="#Alexander_Dr #Alexander_Mrs">Dr. Alexander and wife</persName> from <placeName ref="#Asyut">Assiut</placeName> who are on the <!--unknown--><name type="boat" ref="">Mission boat</name>, that we passed coming up, came in - and we asked them all to tea. <persName ref="#Huhatt_Mr">Mr. Huleatt</persName> to lunch, and chess afterwards, and the <persName ref="#Maspero_Gaston #Maspero_Louise">Masperos</persName> at dinner. They stayed late, and we had a charming evening. He is so interesting - simple, and agreeable. He looks German, was born in <placeName ref="#Milan">Milan</placeName>, and has spent a year or more in <placeName ref="#United_States_of_America">America</placeName> and is said to possess the most varied learning - and talks well on every subject. After giving us the most interesting information on Egyptian matters, in the most unpretentious way, he fell into talk with <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> after she had been singing, on music - and she says she never met anyone who knew so much about it, and seemed so much to love it. Al- Repeat of Page 66-74 <pb n="85"/> together it has been one of those evenings which stand out in memory - as individual, and altogether valuable. Cool and cloudy.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-01-17">
        <dateline>
          Wednesday, <date when="1900-01-17">Jan. 17</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>Another cool, clouded morning - which was most favorable for our visit to the <placeName>Tombs of the Kings</placeName>. Yesterday the "<name type="boat" ref="#Thames">Thames</name>" with <persName ref="#Kidder_Mr">Mr. Kidder</persName> of <placeName ref="#Boston">Boston</placeName> on board, came up and took the <!-- Unknown --><persName ref="">Miriams</persName> place behind us; and <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> sent a note asking if he would like to join us at the tombs, and see that of <name type="historical" ref="#Tomb_of_Amenhotep_II">Amenhotep II</name> with us. Poor <persName ref="#Wilson_Alice">Alice</persName> was so ill with a bad headache she could not go. I went in my chair - though I was sorry that I did not try my good little donkey - as donkeys in the chair did not work well together. The ride through the cliffs, and into the <name type="historical" ref="#Bībān_al_Mulūk">valley of the Tombs</name> was most delightful. I never saw the sky so blue, or the cliffs so deeply yellow - and occasionally a few light fleecy clouds, sailing up over the blue. Most of our little company were in advance of me - so that I had the beautiful great silence all to myself - we went first into the <name type="historical" ref="#Tomb_of_Ramesses_VI">tomb of Rameses VI</name> and then had lunch at the entrance to the <name type="historical" ref="#Tomb_of_Ramesses_XI">tomb of Rameses XI</name>. <persName ref="#Carter_Howard">Mr. Carter</persName> joined us at lunch, and <persName ref="#Kidder_Mr">Mr. Kidder</persName> and his friend appeared just as we had finished. So we started out to see the <name type="historical" ref="#Tomb_of_Amenhotep_II">Amenhotep tomb</name>, the sun was tremendously hot, and we ought not to have ventured out in such heat so soon after eating. It was quite a climb, and once or twice my heart and my strength failed me. A sharp incline led to the mouth of a tomb where a heavy iron gate had been placed. <persName ref="#Carter_Howard">Mr. Carter</persName> advised all the men to <pb n="86"/> take off their coats - we were each given lighted candles, and began a steep descent or staircase of broken stones, along which a rope had been stretched for safety - then over some beams across a deep shaft, and then down another impossible stairway, so low that we could not stand upright, and then came into the great funeral hall - supported by square pillars - the ceiling, the walls and surfaces of the pillars painted and decorated in very chaste style - and as fresh as when it was done almost 4000 years ago - and at the end of this great hall but on a lower level was the enormous red granite sarcophagus of the king with some very delicate decorations of hieroglyphs and figures - the corners well rounded. The lid had been taken off and broken off by some ancient despoilers, but the body remains untouched - probably protected <persName ref="#Carter_Howard">Mr. Carter</persName> told us by the curse pronounced in the band of hieroglyphs around the top of the sarcophagus upon any marauding hands. The beautifully decorated coffin lay on some support almost at the level of the sarcophagus and <persName ref="#Jones_Daniel">Jones</persName> standing at one end, and <persName ref="#Carter_Howard">Mr. Carter</persName> at the other lifted the lid, and the mummy was there just as it had been originally laid - swathed entirely in its mummy garments, with 3 or 4 rows of wreaths of Minosa or Sunt blossoms about the neck, and on the breast a bunch of the same. This is the first instance of a king being found in his own coffin, undisturbed in his own tomb - and it has wisely been decided to leave him as he lies. It was really an impressive sight. Afterwards we went into a small chamber on a higher level, and saw the body of a man bound to a painted boat, and not mummified - but the flesh hardened upon the bones - a gaping wound in the breast - and in another <pb n="87"/> chamber 3 bodies of a man, his wife, and child lying side by side, with the same wounds, and in the same position. It was at first thought that this pointed to the practice of human sacrifice at the burial of a king; but <persName ref="#Maspero_Gaston">M. Maspero</persName> the other evening seemed rather undecided about this. We were not long down in the tomb, as the heat was great, over 100&#176; - and we found the air of 4000 years ago ill adapted to our modern lungs - so climbing the rough stairs, we were glad to emerge into fresh air, and the light of common day. But we had no sooner got out, than <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> frightened us half to death by fainting away and sinking to the ground. Our only restorative was water, until <persName ref="#Carter_Howard">Mr. Carter</persName> sent a swift messenger over the cliffs to his house at <placeName ref="#Der_el_Bahari">Der el Bahri</placeName> for some brandy. He soon revived, and insisted on standing on his feet, when again he went off, and this time I was thoroughly alarmed, as I feared he had received a sun stroke. But the brandy made him all right - and we decided that a hearty lunch, followed by a stiff climb in a broiling sun immediately after, and the bad air of the tomb were the cause of this unusual behavior on his part. After a nap of nearly an hour in the shade in my carrying chair, he mounted his donkey and we all came home - and very thankful I was to reach the rest and comfort of the boat. We are all mightily tired tonight. After this weary expedition I always resolve never to go again.</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-01-18">
        <dateline>
          Thursday, <date when="1900-01-18">Jan. 18</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>Today we have been quiet - only a visit to our old friend's, <!-- Unknown --><persName ref="">Mohammed Mohassib's</persName>, to see his curios - <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> bought some very fine <pb n="88"/> things. There are so many good things offered quietly for sale here now, that the Arab thieves must have found some rich tomb to plunder. This afternoon we went to the races - and a Scotch clergyman the <persName ref="#Macdonald_Rev">Rev. Mr. Macdonald</persName> afterwards came to play chess with <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName>. The "<name type="boat" ref="#Thames">Thames</name>" started for <placeName ref="#Aswan">Asw&#226;n</placeName> today. Very cool, even cold. Called on <persName ref="#Insinger_Mr #Insinger_Miss">the Insingers</persName>.</p> 
          </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-01-19">
        <dateline>
          Friday, <date when="1900-01-19">Jan. 19</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>Very cool, cloudy and quiet all day - stayed at home. <persName ref="#Huhatt_Mr">Mr. Huleatt</persName> at lunch. <persName ref="#Tytus_Mrs">Mrs. Tytus</persName> and <persName ref="#Tytus_Bob">her son</persName>, <persName ref="#Day_Mrs">Mrs. Day</persName>, and young <!-- Unknown --><persName ref="">Terry</persName> the people who are on the "<name type="boat" ref="#Tih">Tih</name>" came to tea this afternoon - very pleasant people - the two young men so unaffectedly enthusiastic about <placeName ref="#Egypt">Egypt</placeName>. How exquisite the view of the mountains opposite us. I look and admire from the earliest morning hour, sometimes before 7 o'clock, when their reflection in the river is etherially lovely - until the last thing before going to bed, I look out of my window and still see, for we have the brilliant light of stars, though our moon has gone, their soft yellow shadow in the water. We notice a fall of several inches in the river since we have been here.</p>
          </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-01-20">
        <dateline>
          Saturday, <date when="1900-01-20">Jan. 20</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>To town on my donkey this morning to see <persName ref="#Mohassib_Mohammed">Mohammed Mohassib</persName> - who gave me a most interesting gold ring, which just fitted my little finger - with the cartouche of a royal mother on it. He gave it to me with such a pretty manner, and said it was to bring me luck! He came again this evening to see us and say goodbye - such a shrewd, wise, <pb n="89"/> humorous old Arab - speaking English so quaintly. He talked of such interesting things - antiques - excavations - the low Nile and its consequences - the history of <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName>, etc. A dear old man! <persName ref="#Carter_Howard">Mr. Carter</persName> came to lunch. He was much struck with some scarabs and things <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> showed him which we has bought since we came, and said he knew that some rich and important tomb was being robbed - and that he was on the scent of it. He is the Inspector of Antiquities for Upper Egypt. <persName ref="#Huhatt_Mr">Mr. Huleatt</persName> came to play chess - we start up the river tomorrow if we have wind - and get our coke, which is due on the steamer tomorrow.</p> 
          </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-01-21">
        <dateline>
          Sunday, 3d Sunday after <name type="event" ref="#Epiphany">Epiphany</name>. <date when="1900-01-21">Jan. 21</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p><persName ref="#Jones_Daniel">Jones</persName> came in while we were at breakfast to say that the "<name type="boat" ref="#Istar">Istar</name>" was coming down and looking out of the window we saw her just heading for shore, and she pulled up just behind the "<name type="boat" ref="#Mâat">Maat</name>" which came up just behind us yesterday. After breakfast <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> went over to see <persName ref="#Sayce_Archibald">Mr. Sayce</persName> and asked him to lunch with us. He came looking very well and so fussy and amusing about the dangers of the present state of the river. He went no farther than <placeName ref="#El_Kab">El Kab</placeName> - and seems very anxious to get down soon and safely. Our coke arrived - and at 3 o'clock we were taking down our awnings and getting ready to sail. <persName ref="#Insinger_Mr">Mr. Insinger</persName> came with some flowers to say goodbye, at 3:30 we were off and reached <placeName ref="#Armant">Erment</placeName> in a very light wind, just as daylight failed. <pb n="90"/></p>
          </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-01-22">
        <dateline>
          Monday, <date when="1900-01-22">Jan. 22</date>. 27 miles.
        </dateline>
          <p>We are lying tonight one mile above <placeName ref="#Esneh">Esneh</placeName>. I have been miserable all day - but came out to dinner tonight. The wind grew so strong we were forced to come to the bank about 5 o'clock - which we did with a bang - and now we are securely and doubly anchored - and a howling gale going on - the hardest I ever saw on the Nile - and there is such a dashing of water and noise that writing is difficult, and I fear sleep will be as difficult.</p> 
          </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-01-23">
        <dateline>
          Tuesday, <date when="1900-01-23">Jan. 23d</date>. 56 miles.
        </dateline>
          <p>The gale lasted though with lessening violence all night, and enough of it left today to bring us finely on our way to <placeName ref=
          "#Gebel_el_Silsila">Silsileh</placeName> tonight. Passed the "<name type="boat" ref="#Antar">Antar</name>" with <persName ref="#Somers_Clarke_George">Mr. Somers-Clarke</persName>, who waved a greeting as we went by, about 12 miles above <placeName ref="#El_Kab"><choice><sic>El Aab</sic><corr>El Kab</corr></choice></placeName>.</p> 
          </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-01-24">
        <dateline>
          Wednesday, <date when="1900-01-24">Jan. 24</date>. 41 miles. <placeName ref="#Aswan">Asw&#226;n</placeName>.
        </dateline>
          <p>We have made a good run today, bringing up here at 5 o'clock. Passed the <name type="boat" ref="#Tih">Tih</name> early in the forenoon, in difficulty with a sand bank - but she got away in 2 hours after us. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> has scouted at all the stories we have heard of the river here - but we were more and more amazed as we drew near. <persName ref="#Sayce_Archibald">Mr. Sayce</persName> had told us we could not reach our old landing place without going around the island of <placeName ref="#Elephantine">Elephantine</placeName>, which we never do - but things looked so bad, that we pulled up just before reaching <placeName ref="#Grenfell_Tomb">Grenfell's tombs</placeName> just opposite 2 fine sycamores. A lovely spot indeed, with its stretches <pb n="91"/> of yellow sand. <placeName ref="#Elephantine">Elephantine</placeName> is almost connected with <placeName ref="#Aswan">Asw&#226;n</placeName> by the sand and oh! how very intrusive and out of place the new hotel, built by that objectionable Anglo-American Co. on the lovely island of <placeName ref="#Elephantine">Elephantine</placeName> looks. It stands just where the old hospital buildings stood. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and the girls went immediately into town with the felucca, and did not get back until dark, - having had to walk over a great stretch of sand. The air is lovely - cool, quieting, life giving. Just 3 days and 2 hours coming from <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName>.</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-01-25">
        <dateline>
          Thursday, <date when="1900-01-25">Jan. 25</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>The wind was blowing such a gale from the north all the morning, and the sand flying so suffocatingly, that none of us stirred out of the boat. We got a great mail this morning. Good news from everywhere by letter, but sad news of war and suffering in S. Africa. Our sympathies are deeply enlisted for the English in this hour of deep tribulation. This afternoon we went out in the felucca, paid first, a visit to the <persName ref="#Bird_Mr #Bird_Mrs">Birds</persName> on the <name type="boat" ref="#Gazelle">Gazelle</name>, but did not find them - then stopped at the new <!-- Unknown --><placeName ref="">Cook's Hotel</placeName>, the "<name type="hotel" ref="#Cataract_Hotel">Cataract Hotel</name>"" to see it. It is hardly yet finished though there are many guests already there. It stands high above the river, opposite the southern end of <placeName ref="#Elephantine">Elephantine</placeName> - a well built, well furnished, and with open fireplaces everywhere - a large covered terrace in front, and many balconies and verandahs give splendid views of all the beautiful features of the river here. We were delighted with it. And what air! delicious and inspiriting. It is a tangible as pleasure <pb n="92"/> to breathe this air, as to eat when hungry. Then we called at the "<name type="boat" ref="#Tih">Tih</name>" to see <persName ref="#Tytus_Mrs">Mrs. Tytus</persName> and <persName ref="#Day_Mrs">Mrs. Day</persName> - and after quite a visit, went over to the town - the Post Office, Telegraph office etc. Then walked to the extreme end of the town, to the great stretch of sand almost filling the river on this side, and found the felucca waiting for us - and with great dfficulty got across to our <name type="boat" ref="#Beduin">Beduin</name>. But it will take only a day of two to make even this impossible - and leave us only the long pull around the southern part of the island.</p>
          </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-01-26">
        <dateline>
          Friday, <date when="1900-01-26">Jan. 26</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>Went around the island and over to <placeName ref="#Aswan">Asw&#226;n</placeName> this morning. Beautiful weather, but a little cool. Bought some very unusual old baskets from the <placeName ref="#Sudan">Sudan</placeName>, - the manner of making which and their patterns suggested our Indian basket work from <placeName ref="#Alaska">Alaska</placeName> and the South West. Went into the <!-- Unknown --><name type="hotel" ref="">Asw&#226;n Hotel</name> to read the despatches - news from <placeName ref="#Africa">Africa</placeName> more encouraging. <persName ref="#Roberts_Lord">Lord Roberts,</persName> and <persName ref="#Kitchener_Herbert">Lord Kitchener</persName> had arrived. Then through the <placeName>Bazar</placeName> and home. The river front of <placeName ref="#Aswan">Aswan</placeName> is really charming when one reached it, but the climb through long stretches of sand, or up the steep stairs dripping with water from the water skins of the carriers makes it very discouraging. A delicious row home through the splendid air. After lunch I devoted myself to past arrears of writing, until after tea, when <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName>, <persName ref="#Wilson_Alice">Alice</persName> and I went for a walk on <placeName ref="#Elephantine">Elephantine</placeName>. This morning early, we pulled up to a little cove opposite the southern island of <persName ref="#Kitchener_Herbert">Kitchener's</persName> and are lying in an ideal spot where in a deep curve of the <placeName ref="#Elephantine">Elephantine</placeName> bank, a low sand bank has <pb n="93"/> formed. Splendid trees on the shore, and the steep cliffs opposite away across the river, shrouded in golden red sand, and further along the chaotic rocks of the <placeName ref="#First_Cataract">Cataract</placeName>, make fine features. I have never been in a more lovely spot.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-01-27">
        <dateline>
          Saturday, <date when="1900-01-27">Jan. 27</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>We have had a tiring day, which I am glad is over. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> hired a special train to take us to <placeName ref="#Philae">Philae</placeName>, and we asked the "<name type="boat" ref="#Tih">Tih</name>" people to go with us - which they gladly did. We left our boat at 10 minutes before 10 o'clock, and left <placeName ref="#Aswan">Asw&#226;n</placeName> in the funny little train at 10:30. <placeName ref="#Shellal">Shellal</placeName> is now a vast workshop - with shops and booths, tents and railway trains. Anything in greater contrast to the verdant, barbaric spot we first knew it, could not well be imagined. We found <persName ref="#Imam">Imam</persName>, <persName ref="#Dendowi">Dendowi,</persName> and all the rest of our old friends waiting for us - and after the steep climb up to the temples, found <persName ref="#Newman_Henry_Roderick #Newman_Mrs">Mr. and Mrs. Newman</persName> in their usual corner in the <placeName ref="#Great_Hypostyle_Hall">Hall of Columns</placeName>. I stayed a long time talking to them, for there is really nothing of much interest in any of the temples themselves and we had been so often - and we all agreed with <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> when he said the oftener he came to <placeName ref="#Philae">Philae</placeName>, the less he wanted to come again. We had lunch and a very pretty, good one - our ample lunch panniers are so satisfactory, in the eastern colonnade as usual, among the flies and the hovering, clamorous natives, who are always trying to offer some service, in order to establish some claim to baksheesh. Of course <persName ref="#Imam">Imam</persName> and <persName ref="#Dendowi">Dendowi</persName> were our personal attendants. After <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> had finished his cigar, we took a cataract boat, and went down the river as <pb n="94"/> far as it is permitted, to see what we could of the barrage - which was not much or impressive, then to make a visit on the <persName ref="#Newman_Henry_Roderick #Newman_Mrs">Newmans</persName>, and look at his pictures, and then to the train, where we had to sit and wait some time. What a sight was the motley crowd - every manner of savage, in every kind of rags and clothing - a weary half hour in the jolting, dusty little train - another weary tramp across the sands to our felucca into which we thankfully got, and said "khalas Philas"! A delicious row home - tea waiting for us on the shaded deck - quiet, cleanliness and peace! and alas! the big boom down. The big white sail furled and packed on it - not to be used again until next year.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-01-28">
        <dateline>
          Sunday, <date when="1900-01-28">Jan. 28th</date>. Fourth Sunday after <name type="event" ref="#Epiphany">Epiphany</name>.
        </dateline>
          <p>A quiet beautiful day at home - reading and writing. It is a physical pleasure to breathe here at <placeName ref="#Aswan">Asw&#226;n</placeName>. After tea we went in the felucca, sailing up and rowing down, towards the cataract. A heavenly thing to do at that hour -  <persName ref="#Bird_Mr #Bird_Mrs">Mr. and Mrs. Bird</persName>, from the <name type="boat" ref="#Gazelle">Gazelle</name>, came to dine.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-01-29">
        <dateline>
          Monday, <date when="1900-01-29">Jan. 29th</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>I spent the morning on deck - <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> at home writing - <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and <persName ref="#Wilson_Alice">Alice</persName> at the bazar - still the north wind blowing - river perceptibly falling each day - I am in no hurry to leave <placeName ref="#Aswan">Asw&#226;n</placeName> - we are so charmingly placed here in this little cove, with its small pretty beach just large enough for it - and the grand palms on the island, through which the wind soughs so strangely and pleasantly. I love it <pb n="95"/> all - and it is such a good place for our fowls. Our two pet geese are enchanted with it - they sail about from window to window, asking for attention and food - we had such good news from home - all well, and tranquil. At 5 o'clock we went for tea on the <name type="boat" ref="#Gazelle">Gazelle</name>, with the <persName ref="#Bird_Mr #Bird_Mrs">Birds</persName>, and had a pleasant visit. We have such a delightful little savage, who has made himself quite at home on the boat. <!-- Unknown --><persName ref="">Little Hassoun</persName>, the son of <persName ref="#Hassoun"><choice><sic>Hassoum</sic><corr>Hassoun</corr></choice></persName> the sailor, who has been one of our principal sailors for 4 years. He lives on the island just above us. He was sweet and attractive last year - but is much more so now - and is the most interesting child I ever saw - and very clean. We may get off tomorrow if the wind allows us.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-01-30">
        <dateline>
          Tuesday, <date when="1900-01-30">Jan. 30th</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>The wind did not allow us - and as the bread arrived late in the morning, we decided to wait until tomorrow. A beautiful day - but cool - the <persName ref="#Bird_Mr #Bird_Mrs">Birds</persName> came to say goodbye. We went for a sail at 5 o'clock - enchanting.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-01-31">
        <dateline>
          Wednesday, <date when="1900-01-31">Jan. 31st</date>. 3 miles.
        </dateline>
          <p>Got off about 9:30 this morning - north wind rather light at the time - said goodbye to our little <!-- Unknown --><persName ref="">Hassoun</persName> and <placeName ref="#Aswan">Asw&#226;n</placeName> with real regret. As soon as we got out on the main river, the wind was so strong we were driven to the long stretch of sand, just opposite our landing a week ago - near the sycamores under <placeName ref="#Grenfell_Tomb">Grenfell's tombs</placeName>. Towards evening the wind falling, we went down about 2 miles. <pb n="96"/></p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-02-01">
        <dateline>
          Thursday, <date when="1900-02-01">February 1st</date>. 18 miles.
        </dateline>
          <p>We were still within sight of <placeName ref="#Aswan">Asw&#226;n</placeName> this morning - and the north wind has blown all day - but the men have rowed, and with the current we have made about 18 miles, and are within 5 miles of <placeName ref="#Kawm_Umbū">Kom Ombo</placeName>. Day warm - it is pleasant to be on the move again, and to be restricted to the life of the boat. Yesterday was the last day of <name type="event" ref="#Ramadam">Ramadam</name> - and today is the <name type="event" ref="#Id_al_Fitr">feast of Baerain</name> - and as soon as we appeared on deck, all our men came in procession to shake hands, and give congratulations and wishes, much as we do at <name type="event" ref="#New_Years">New Years</name> The young moon was visible this evening - the merest thread of a crescent.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-02-02">
        <dateline>
          Friday, <date when="1900-02-02">Feb. 2</date>. 2 miles.
        </dateline>
          <p>The men began rowing at 6 o'clock A.M. and by 9 o'clock when we had finished breakfast we had pulled up under the <placeName ref="#Temple_of_Kawm_Umbū">Kom Ombo temple</placeName>. We paid a rather short visit to it, as we wanted to go on. It was only to show it to <persName ref="#Wilson_Alice">Alice</persName> - but the wind was so strong that in a difficult curve of the river below <placeName ref="#Kawm_Umbū">Kom Ombo</placeName>, we had to go to the sand bank on the opposite side of the river, where we laid until 6 o'clock - when the wind falling, we dropped down two miles. It has been the warmest day we have had - so that we forsook the deck until 5 o'clock. The geese were let out this morning, and have been all day crazy with delight, splashing in the water, and sailing round and round the boat, stopping at certain windows where they are accustomed to be fed, and begging for food. When at 6 o'clock we moved off, they declined being caught - and we thought they would follow the boat. <pb n="97"/> The felucca with one sailor followed to keep watch of them - but the night came so soon, that we sent back the chicken boat with two men to help, and only about two hours after the boats returned, bringing only the geese - the gander - a handsome young bird, could not be caught. We hope he may come during the night.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-02-03">
        <dateline>
          Saturday, <date when="1900-02-03">Feb. 3d</date>. 21 miles.
        </dateline>
          <p>A rather quiet day enabled the men to row most of the time. We made <placeName ref="#Silsilis">Silsilis</placeName> just at one o'clock. After lunch in spite of the heat, <persName ref="#Wilson_Alice">Alice</persName>, with <persName ref="#Jones_Daniel">Jones</persName> as an escort, went across to the quarries - and afterwards joined <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> at the <placeName ref="#KV57">grotto of Horemheb</placeName>. After leaving <placeName ref="#Silsilis">Silsilis</placeName> we came to the same difficult part of the river that we passed Jan. 23d. There was a fresh wreck to be seen this afternoon - another gyassa - with its mast above water - and the stretches of sand were wider than they were then. The wreck of a steamer that went down in the first year of the war of the Soudan is now showing a little - and is a very dangerous obstacle to navigation. Passed the <name type="boat" ref="#Rameses">Rameses the Great</name> going up. We were on deck until 7 o'clock. The night was so beautiful and soft. But we already miss the delicious pure <placeName ref="#Aswan">Asw&#226;n</placeName> air. I have never heard anything equal to the frogs that we hear now in the evening. Such great basso-profundo voices: It must be the low water.</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-02-04">
        <dateline>
          Sunday, 5th Sunday after <name type="event" ref="#Epiphany">Epiphany</name>. <date when="1900-02-04">Feb. 4</date>. 16 miles.
        </dateline>
          <p>We had got to within 4 miles of <placeName ref="#Edfu">Adfu</placeName>, this morning <pb n="98"/> about 11 o'clock - when the north wind began in an instant to blow almost a gale, and we came to a low green bank, where we are still lying, wind very strong. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and <persName ref="#Wilson_Alice">Alice</persName> went for a walk about 5 o'clock and <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I had our tea alone - and afterwards walked on deck. Dahabeah <name type="boat" ref="#Gamilla">Gamila</name> passed up - <name type="boat" ref="#Rameses">Rameses the Great</name> also.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-02-05">
        <dateline>
          Monday, <date when="1900-02-05">Feb. 5th</date>. 10 miles.
        </dateline>
          <p>Came to <placeName ref="#Edfu">Edfu</placeName> at 9 o'clock - and went to the <placeName ref="#Temple_of_Edfu">temple</placeName>. After two or three visits it becomes uninteresting this temple. I had the best donkey I ever had in <placeName ref="#Egypt">Egypt</placeName> - rather big and black. Wind blew from the north all day. Have managed to get down about 6 or 7 miles.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-02-06">
        <dateline>
          Tuesday, <date when="1900-02-06">Feb. 6</date>. 28 miles.
        </dateline>
          <p>A beautiful calm day - reached <placeName ref="#El_Kab">El-Kab</placeName> at 8:30 in the morning. The rest walked up to the temple - all the dogs were waiting to be fed - and my old woman soon appeared, looking more like a mummy than ever. She was trembling with delight on seeing me - I gave her some warm clothes, money, and things to eat - and she stayed crouching on the bank among the beans, mumbling her rolls and butter, and calling down blessings upon me, until we moved off. She brought me a long white bead, as a gift! Touching! Reached <placeName ref="#Esneh">Esna</placeName> where we did not stop about 7 o'clock. "<name type="boat" ref="#Herodotus">Herodotus</name>" and <persName ref="#Somers_Clarke_George">Mr. Somers-Clarke</persName> there. <pb n="99"/></p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-02-07">
        <dateline>
          Wednesday, <date when="1900-02-07">Feb. 7th</date>. 12 miles.
        </dateline>
          <p>We began the day in a beautiful manner, with a gentle south wind, and hoped to make a record day, and reach <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName> tonight. But suddenly, in the twinkling of an eye, all was changed. I saw the <persName ref="#Fuli_Rais">Rais</persName> give the order to furl the sails - and we all exclaimed in wonder, "what can he mean" when I saw the sand coming - and in a moment it was on us! We gathered up all our belongings and scurried below - windows, doors, and tambooshes were closed, and the north wind howled all day, and we were obliged to tie up at once two or three miles below <placeName ref="#Gebelein">Gebelen</placeName>.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-02-08">
        <dateline>
          Thursday, <date when="1900-02-08">Feb. 8th</date>. 19-1/2 miles.
        </dateline>
          <p>We have made today reaching <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName> at 2:30. Came to our old landing under the <!-- Unknown --><placeName ref="">Castle</placeName>. Found the <name type="boat" ref="#Thames">Thames</name> and the <name type="boat" ref="#Sunshine">Sunshine</name> here and the <name type="boat" ref="#Herodotus">Herodotus</name> arrived late this afternoon.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-02-09">
        <dateline>
          Friday, <date when="1900-02-09">Feb. 9</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>Home all day. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I went across to <placeName ref="#Medinet_Habu">Medinet Habu</placeName> and took tea and over to <placeName ref="#Dayr_al_Madinah">Der el Medinet</placeName>. Charming effects coming home. <persName ref="#Somers_Clarke_Mrs">Mrs. Somers-Clarke</persName> dined with us.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-02-10">
        <dateline>
          Saturday, <date when="1900-02-10">Feb. 10</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>Went to town on my donkey with <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName>. To <!-- Unknown --><persName ref="">Mahasaibs</persName>, where we saw a few most interesting things. Then to all on <persName ref="#Murch_Mrs">Mrs. Murch</persName>, where <pb n="100"/> it looked so cool and clean. It is the only pleasant spot I know at <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName> - in the town! <persName ref="#Mohassib_Mohammed">Mohassib</persName> made us a visit this evening.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-02-11">
        <dateline>
          Sunday, <name type="event" ref="#Septuagesima">Septuagesima</name>. <date when="1900-02-11">Feb. 11</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>This being the only day that <persName ref="#Carter_Howard">Mr. Carter</persName> could show <persName ref="#Wilson_Alice">Alice</persName> the <name type="historical" ref="#Tomb_of_Amenhotep_II">tomb of Amenhotep II</name>, she, with <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName>, <persName ref="#Burgoyne_Amelie">Amelie</persName> and <persName ref="#Jones_Daniel">Jones</persName> - lunch baskets my carrying chair, donkeys and many sailors started about 10:30. I would not go again and <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> I think hardly dared to go in the heat. But he and I went across and rode to <persName ref="#Carter_Howard">Mr. Carter's</persName> house to meet them and have tea. We found <persName ref="#Somers_Clarke_George">Mr. Somers-Clarke</persName> with them. We admired the little house, and the pretty garden within the enclosing walls. There was a real avenue of scent trees. Rode home by the brilliant moonlight - <persName ref="#Wilson_Alice">Alice</persName> and <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> well tired, but reporting a most interesting and delightful day. 3 dahabeahs arrived up today.</p>
          </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-02-12">
        <dateline>
          Monday, <date when="1900-02-12">Feb. 12th</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>A tremendous gale from the north has been blowing all day - and although we had all the awnings up and tightly secured, it was so cold and the dust so bad we deserted the deck. <persName ref="#Huhatt_Mr">Mr. Huhatt</persName> came to play chess with <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore,</persName> and afterwards the wind having fallen a little, <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and <persName ref="#Wilson_Alice">Alice</persName> went over to <placeName ref="#Dayr_al_Madinah">Der el Medinet</placeName>. <persName ref="#Carter_Howard">Mr. Carter</persName> came to dine, and we had a pleasant evening.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-02-13">
        <dateline>
          Tuesday, <date when="1900-02-13">Feb. 13</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>Much warmer today, but a high wind still. Home all day. <pb n="101"/> <!-- Unknown --><persName ref="">Young Terry</persName> and <!-- Unknown --><persName ref="">Tytus</persName> from the <name type="boat" ref="#Tih">Tih</name>, came to dine with us. They are just down from <placeName ref="#Khartoum">Khartoum</placeName> - and told us many interesting things. Wise boys!</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-02-14">
        <dateline>
          Wednesday, <date when="1900-02-14">Feb. 14</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p><persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and I went into <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName> this morning, to see about various things - went to say goodbye to <persName ref="#Murch_Mrs">Mrs. Murch</persName>. <persName ref="#Huhatt_Mr">Mr. Huhatt</persName> again to play chess, and then we all went over to <placeName ref="#Der_el_Bahari">Der el Bahri</placeName> and had tea. It was a charming afternoon - and the ride home with the splendid full moon was delightful. It was interesting to see the admirable manner in which the temple is being protected by walls and partial roofing. There are now 9 dahabeahs here - saw <persName ref="#Carter_Howard">Carter</persName> and said goodbye.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-02-15">
        <dateline>
          Thursday, <date when="1900-02-15">Feb. 15</date>. 32 miles.
        </dateline>
          <p><persName ref="#Murch_Chauncey">Mr. Murch</persName> came to breakfast and I sent some little delicacies up to the castle and a book to <persName ref="#Insinger_Mr">Mr. Insinger</persName> who has had a sharp attack. To my surprise he came down to the boat - looking ghastly and hardly able to move or breathe, - speaking very frankly and almost defiantly of his condition. Then we got off - and very glad I was to quit those high, evil smelling <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName> banks - which the low water has made very disagreeable. We had a good south wind - and the day has been very warm. Passed <placeName ref="#Naqādah">Nagada</placeName>, and are now lying at a low sand bank opposite <placeName ref="#Qifṭ">Kuft</placeName>, the ancient <placeName ref="#Coptos">Koptos</placeName>, which we intend visiting tomorrow, to see <persName ref="#Reisner_George #Reisner_Mrs">the Reisners</persName>, and the work <persName ref="#Reisner_George">Mr. Reisner</persName> is doing there. On deck until 7 o'clock - to see the full moon rise <pb n="102"/> splendidly. Passed <persName ref="#Somers_Clarke_George">Mr. Somers-Clarke</persName> who is at <placeName ref="#Karnak">Karnac</placeName>.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-02-16">
        <dateline>
          Friday, <date when="1900-02-16">Feb. 16</date>. <placeName ref="#Qifṭ">Kuft</placeName>.
        </dateline>
          <p>We are still lying where we were last night. After breakfast we went across the river, and took the best donkeys we could find at the landing place, which were inexpressibly bad. They were the ordinary little working animals, and our saddles were all too big for them - and they stumbled and grunted along a highway running through rich fields, where were the best crops I have seen this winter. After having ridden a mile or more we came to the old town, entirely in ruins - mostly of mud brick walls of Roman or Coptic times - with some inscribed remains of the time of <persName ref="#Intef_V">Antef V</persName> and <persName ref="#Thotmes_III">Thothmes III</persName>. We could not find <persName ref="#Reisner_George #Reisner_Mrs">the Reisners</persName>, or hear anything of them, the natives saying only that he was working in the mountains, which were two hours at least farther on. So we gave it up, and <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and <persName ref="#Jones_Daniel">Jones</persName> walked home rather than ride their poor little beasts. Some drops of rain fell two or three times - and by the time we got back to the boat, a furious north wind was making the sand fly, and the sailors were putting out all our anchors. It is now quiet, and the night brilliant.</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-02-17">
        <dateline>
          Saturday, <date when="1900-02-17">Feb. 17th</date>. 9 miles.
        </dateline>
          <p>The men began rowing this morning soon after four o'clock, but by 8 o'clock the north wind was so strong we were forced to anchor near a sand bank, where we are now reposing, within sight of <placeName ref="#Keneh">Keneh</placeName>, where we intend stopping. Life on deck <pb n="103"/> has been impossible today, except for walking - and that was not agreeable because of the sand and wind. It is quiet now. A busy, nice indoors day.</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-02-18">
        <dateline>
          Sunday, <date when="1900-02-18">Feb. 18</date>. 10 miles.
        </dateline>
          <p>Brought up at <placeName ref="#Keneh">Keneh</placeName> about 8 o'clock this morning, and after breakfast <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and I, with <persName ref="#Burgnoyne_Amlie">Amelie</persName> and <persName ref="#Jones_Daniel">Jones</persName> rode into <placeName ref="#Keneh">Keneh</placeName>, just because the day was so fine, and the town rather worth seeing. Donkeys always good, and reads good - a charming ride - everything, town and all, looking as if they came out of the Arabian Nights. After lunch we crossed the river to <placeName ref="#Dandarah">Denderah</placeName> - and went out to the temple. <name type="boat" ref="#Rameses">Rameses the Third</name>, and dahabeah <name type="boat" ref="#Tih">Tih</name> passed down today. Moved off at 5 o'clock and made several miles.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-02-19">
        <dateline>
          Monday, <date when="1900-02-19">Feb. 19th</date>. 15 miles.
        </dateline>
          <p>A beautiful day, but a strong north wind. We passed <placeName ref="#Dishnā">Dishnah</placeName> at 11 o'clock - but had to go to a sand bank at one o'clock - where we are still lying - with the north wind carousing as usual.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-02-20">
        <dateline>
          Tuesday, <date when="1900-02-20">Feb. 20</date>. 5 miles.
        </dateline>
          <p>A light head wind this morning carried us along for an hour or two, when we had to take to the bank - where we stayed until 6 o'clock, when we made a little progress - altogether about 5 miles we think. A cold wind raged all day - and we <pb n="104"/> had to stay below. <name type="boat" ref="#Gazelle">Gazelle</name> seen in the distance behind us.</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-02-21">
        <dateline>
          Wednesday, <date when="1900-02-21">Feb. 21</date>. 20 miles.
        </dateline>
          <p>Started at 7 o'clock, and by steady rowing passed <placeName ref="#Qasr_es_Sayyad">Kasr as Sayd</placeName> at 9 o'clock. The place where we came to grief on the stones was plainly visible today. Sand and loose stones were showing in many places - passed <placeName ref="#Hiw">Hou</placeName> at 10:30 that wretched village, with its ruinous mosque high up on its bank, and falling to pieces in the river. Arrived at <placeName ref="#Naj_Hammadi">Nagh Hamadi</placeName> too late - the bridge closing at 12 o'clock - and had to wait until 3 o'clock for it to open. we drew up against the barge close to the bridge and waited, sending for our mail. Good news from everywhere - especially from South Africa - a despatch announcing the relief of <persName ref="#Kimberly">Kimberly</persName> under <persName ref="#Roberts_Lord">Lord Roberts</persName>. The sun very hot all day, but wind cold. Sat on deck all the afternoon, enjoying the beauty of the river, and the great mountain mass of <placeName ref="#Gebel_el_Tarif">Gebel et Taif</placeName>, below <placeName ref="#Naj_Hammadi">Nagh Hamadi</placeName>. Came through the bridge at 3 o'clock, and made 8 miles.</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-02-22">
        <dateline>
          Thursday, <date when="1900-02-22">Feb. 22d</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>A very still warm morning, with occasionally a very light wind. Drew up to <placeName ref="#Balyana_Al">Balliana</placeName> about 12 o'clock and found the "<name type="boat" ref="#Zet_el_Nil">Zenet-el Nile</name>". lying there with the American flag, and a <persName ref="#Thorn_Mr">Mr. Thorn</persName> and family from <placeName ref="#Tacoma">Tacoma</placeName>, state of <placeName ref="#Washington">Washington</placeName> - and the "<name type="boat" ref="#Tih">Tih</name>" just putting out. She dropped her anchor on seeing us, and the boys came over in their felucca to get the scarabs <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> got for them the other day in <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName>, with <pb n="105"/> which they were delighted. After lunch, in spite of the heat, <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and <persName ref="#Wilson_Alice">Alice</persName> went out to <placeName ref="#Abydos"><choice><sic>Abydes</sic><corr>Abydos</corr></choice></placeName> to see <persName ref="#Petrie_William">Fr. Flinders Petrie</persName> and the tombs of the I dynasty he has found. They did not find it as interesting as they had hoped, and came home after 6 o'clock desperately tired with their bad donkeys - and thinking it had not paid, and we lost the fine south wind which blew all the afternoon, and the fun of going down with the "<name type="boat" ref="#Tih">Tiy</name>". <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I tried to stay on deck, but found it so hot, and the flies intolerable, and the noisy natives and children were insufferable. <placeName ref="#Abydos">Abydos</placeName> is a detestable place at which to lie - I feel so chagrined that I forget that today was <persName ref="#Washington_George">Washington's</persName> birthday. I have thought of it for several days - and have said to myself, "now don't forget to give the order to have the ship dressed, and an extra dinner", - and then I proceeded to forget it!</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-02-23">
        <dateline>
          Friday, <date when="1900-02-23">Feb. 23</date>. 5 miles.
        </dateline>
          <p>We made but little progress today - for the north wind got up in a furious manner, and about 9 o'clock we were driven to a sand bank where we had to stay until 6 o'clock - when we managed to move across the river to a better anchorage, and tied up for the night. It was impossible to go on deck, and I never saw the sand so bad - it came in through every crack and crevice.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-02-24">
        <dateline>
          Saturday, <date when="1900-02-24">Feb. 24</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>We are lying just where we did last night, having been held here by one of the worst gales I ever saw on the river. We were fortunately Page 106 more out of the reach of the sand than yesterday. The waves have been like those of a moderate sea - and the boat so shaken by the wind that writing was difficult. All is quiet now, and we hope to get off tomorrow.</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-02-25">
        <dateline>
          Quinquagesima Sunday, <date when="1900-02-25">Feb. 25</date>. 3 miles.
        </dateline>
          <p>We got within a mile of <placeName ref="#Girgeh">Girgeh</placeName> this morning by 10 o'clock. A cold north wind still blowing. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName>,<persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and <persName ref="#Wilson_Alice">Alice</persName> walked into the town. I preferred our own clean deck for my exercise - and found the wind very cold. We could not move until 6 o'clock when we dropped to a nice little beach two miles below the town.</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-02-26">
        <dateline>
          Monday, <date when="1900-02-26">Feb. 26</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>Are lying just where we brought up last night. North wind howling all day - clouds very black and threatening. It rained last night hard, and there was a leak in my room. Quiet tonight, and we hope for a change of weather tomorrow.</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-02-27">
        <dateline>
          Tuesday, <date when="1900-02-27">Feb. 27</date>. 15 miles.
        </dateline>
          <p>Got off early this morning - quite in the night in fact. The wind came up as usual with the light - and floating, rowing and lying by, we brought up within 2 miles of <placeName ref="#Akhmīm">Akmim.</placeName> Cool. Page 107</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-02-28">
        <dateline>
          Wednesday, <date when="1900-02-28">Feb. 28</date>. Ash Wednesday. 14 miles.
        </dateline>
          <p>Again we made an early start some time in the night, and pulled up to <placeName ref="Sohag">Sohag</placeName> at 6 o'clock. We got our mail and were off after breakfast - and stopped at 6 o'clock - river very bad. Shocked to read of <!-- Unknown --><persName ref="">Mr.Bond's</persName> death in the papers - pneumonia. My mind has been full of that bereaved family all day. Cold.</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-03-01">
        <dateline>
          Thursday, <date when="1900-03-01">March 1st</date>. 43 miles.
        </dateline>
          <p>A charming day - men began rowing at 5 o'clock this morning - and at 8 o'clock a light sound wind began and has lasted with intervals of intense calm all day. The sun has been hot, but such a delicious cool air, that life was a pleasure. I have been on deck all day. We have had a double awning spread. Passed <placeName ref="Tahtah">Tahtah</placeName> at 10 o'clock - 15 miles from our stopping place of last night. Passed <!-- Unknown --><placeName ref="">Gaou</placeName> at 2 o'clock, 12-1/2 miles, and came to <placeName ref="#Abu_Tij">Aboutig</placeName> by 6:30, - 14-1/2 miles. We have had some exciting moments today. I was wakened at 6 this morning by a great bump on the sand, but we stuck only a moment. I got up and looked out of my window and saw a pink and red river, with such a network of sand banks, that a way through them seemed impossible. Indeed the spectacle of the river today has been astounding. In one place the natives were bringing their camels to the river with huge water skins on their backs - and one hardly sees the women with their water jars now - so far have the villages retired from the water. Came up with the "Tih" about 3 o'clock - sticking in the sand, and young <!-- Unknown --><persName ref="">Terry</persName> and <persName ref="#Tytus_Bob">Tytus</persName> out shooting pigeons on the sand. We are lying anchored almost in the middle of the river which I like very much.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-03-02">
        <dateline>
          Friday, <date when="1900-03-02">March 2</date>. 19 miles.
        </dateline>
          <p>This has been our warmest and stillest day. We reached <placeName ref="#Asyut">Assiut</placeName> at noon - having come through many a difficult place, without touching. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and <persName ref="#Wilson_Alice">Alice</persName> rode into the town to the P.O. We had to wait for oil, butter, yeast, etc. and could not get off until 6 o'clock, when we came 4 miles - getting safe away from the smoke and noise of the barrage works. A great stretch of sand lies before <placeName ref="#Asyut">Assiut</placeName> - so that boats cannot directly approach her now - a handsome river front the town has. <name type="boat" ref="#Rameses">Ramesis the Great</name> came down, and stayed awhile. The <name type="boat" ref="#Antar">"Antar"</name> appeared, <persName ref="#Somers_Clarke_George">Mr.Somers-Clarke</persName> having gone by rail to <placeName ref="#Aswan">Asw&#226;n,</placeName> and will rejoin his boat at <placeName ref="#Asyut">Assiut.</placeName> And the "Tih" appeared just as we were leaving. It has been very hot all day - and the flies vicious - though none in the boat. The new moon appeared this evening.</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-03-04">
        <dateline>
          Sunday, 1st in Lent. <date when="1900-03-04">March 4th</date>. 40 miles.
        </dateline>
          <p>The hottest day we have had this year 93&#176; on my cabana. A good south wind all day - too strong at times for the dangerous condition of the river. Passed <placeName ref="#Hag_Kandil">Hadji Kandul<placeName>, <!-- Unknown --><placeName ref="">Tel el Amazna</placeName>,<placeName ref="#Mallawi">Melawi</placeName>, and <placeName ref="">Kodah</placeName> about 6 o'clock, having been detained a mile above it, by the high wind. The <name type="boat" ref="#Antar">Antar,</name> having a keel, was able to hold up against it, sailed past us, and was lost to sight. It is getting rather unpleasant on the river, the banks are so high, we see <orgName>Page 109</orgName> but little of the country. And the enormous stretches of sand everywhere. Just after leaving <placeName ref="#Ar_Rawḍah">Redah</placeName> we saw a strange sight. The channel was narrow, and a cast stretch of sand, on which there lay the remains of a large iron boat, that our <persName ref="#Fuli_Rais">Rais</persName> told us was lost 20 years ago, during <persName ref="#Pashaz_Ismail">Ismail Pasha's</persName> life time. All the sailors travelling up and down the <placeName ref="Nile">Nile</placeName> have known the whereabouts of this wreck, but it has never been seen until the last two or three weeks! In fact the bottom of the river can be seen everywhere - piles of rocks cropping up here and there, and various wrecks revealed. A beautiful cool evening, after the heat of the day - and a nice little moon, already giving much light and with Venus resplendent very near her.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-03-05">
        <dateline>
          Monday, <date when="1900-03-05">Mar. 5th</date>. 7 miles.
        </dateline>
          <p>We found ourselves nearer <persName ref="#Bani_Hasan">Beni Hassan</persName> this morning than we supposed last night, for starting at 7 o'clock, we found ourselves at <placeName ref="#Bani_Hasan">Beni HAssan</placeName> at 8 o'clock - but did not stop as the morning was hot and calm - but before we had gone a mile from the landing, the sky clouded, the wind came out from the north and we were forced to seek the shelter of a high bank, from which we did not stir until 6 o'clock.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-03-06">
        <dateline>
          Tuesday, <date when="1900-03-06">Mar. 6th</date>. Collossaneh. 32 miles.
        </dateline>
          <p>One of the warmest days we have had - reached <placeName ref="#Al_Minya">Minieh</placeName> at 11 o'clock - had to anchor out in the river, as a great stretch of sand lies far out from shore. All the rest went into town for mail and Page 110 provisions. I preferred the quiet boat all to myself, and the time seemed short before they were all back again, and we were off - reaching <!-- Unknown --><placeName ref="">Collossaneh</placeName> about 7 - our moon now gives a beautiul light.</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-03-07">
        <dateline>
          Wednesday, <date when="1900-03-07">Mar. 7th</date>. 12-1/2 miles.
        </dateline>
          <p>The very hottest day I have known - the glass at 93 and not a clear atmosphere - very like a <persName ref="">Ramseen</persName> though the wind was not from the south. Overtook the <name type="boat" ref="#Mâat">"Maat"</name> and the <name type="boat" ref="#Antar">"Antar"</name> above <orgName ref="">Shekh Fadl.</orgName> <persName ref="#Somers_Clarke_George">Mr.Somers-Clarke</persName> still in <placeName ref="#Aswan">Asw&#226;</placeName>n. Came to <placeName ref="Jirjā">Abu Girga</placeName> soon after 6 o'clock.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-03-08">
        <dateline>
          Thursday, <date when="1900-03-08">Mar. 8</date>. 22-1/2 miles.
        </dateline>
          <p>The day began very still and hot and we thought we would have rain or a Ramseen. The wind grew so strong that we had to drop both anchors about 10:30 to save us from a stony bank. Lost sight of the <!-- Unknown --><orgName ref="">Faat.</orgName> <name type="boat" ref="#Antar">Antar</name> pulled into shore just behind us. We lay in the water, the wind buffeting us about, the sand flying over us until 6 o'clock when we were able to pull by an anchor in to shore. Wind still howling from the north, and cooler. A perfect procession of gyassas bound up, whizzing past us.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-03-09">
        <dateline>
          Friday, <date when="1900-03-09">March 9th</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>Still lying where we were last night - sand drifting over us - wind howling - a great gale from the north going on. We hope for a change tomorrow. Page 111</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-03-10">
        <dateline>
          Saturday, <date when="1900-03-10">March 10th</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>The most dreadful day I have ever spent in <placeName ref="#Egypt">Egypt</placeName>! we are still lying where we brought up day before yesterday. The wind is still howling, though not quite as bad as during the day. It has rained lightly much of the time, which with the dust, made everything outside very dirty. Have not had my nose out of the door.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-03-11">
        <dateline>
          2d Sunday in Lent. <date when="1900-03-11">Mar. 11th</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>Still lying where we have spent the last 3 days and the storm has been even more severe, -for we dragged our anchors. Our little stoves have come again into welcome use.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-03-12">
        <dateline>
          Monday, <date when="1900-03-12">March 12</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>We made a mile early this morning, when the wind again burst upon us and we had to pull up: in a better place however, as we have had little sand. The sun very bright all day, but wind cold - with a touch of early spring day in the north, which was very pleasant. On Saturday we sent the <persNam ref="#Dervish_Mohammed">Dervish,</persName> our third officer as we called him, a splendid blue black <orgName ref="#Nubians">Nubian</orgName> from <placeName ref="#Aswan">Asw&#226;n</placeName> who has been with us for four years, down to <placeName ref="#Al_Wasta">Wasta</placeName> for our mail; he did not get back until late yesterday, something being wrong with the trains. He must have suffered with the cold, as he had to sleep on the steamer landing, with no warm coverings. Again, good and reassuring news from S. Africa. One stronghold after another giving way before <persName ref="#Roberts_Lord">Lord Roberts</persName>, and the <!-- Unknown --><orgName ref="">Beers</orgName> retreating towards their own borders. Page 112</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-03-13">
        <dateline>
          Tuesday, <date when="1900-03-13">March. 13</date>. 22 miles.
        </dateline>
          <p>Quite the most exciting day I ever spent on the <placeName ref="Nile">Nile</placeName>. The men began rowing at 3 o'clock, the moon being almost full. A little after 4 o'clock we struck the sand with a good whack, and then the boat swung about over the sand slowly, seeming as if she would grind her bottom off. It must have been 5 minutes before she settled. Then another 5 or 10 minutes before the sailors swung her off. I got up and looked out of my window, and there were the men knee deep in the water pushing and struggling. Then we anchored until daylight. I dosed and wakened, and at 6:30 get up and looked out. We were passing <!-- Unknown --><placeName ref="">Feshen</placeName> - and I saw one of <orgName ref="#Thomas_Cook_and_Son">Cooks</orgName> large steamers lying at the town, closed and abandoned until the inundation comes. I could not see her name, as we were swinging round - but then there was a sight! We were almost on top of the <name type="boat" ref="#Mayflower">Mayflower</name> of the <orgName ref="#American_Line">Anglo-American line</orgName>, which was fast aground in the middle of the river - and between 20 and 30 gyassas all aground here and there - and a little farther on, the "Ramses the Third" fast on the sand, and quite in the Channel. I I called <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> to come and look, it was such an extraordinary spectacle. Very little sand showing - the river very broad and channel very doubtful. Then I found that the "Tih", the <name type="boat" ref="#Mâat">"Maat"</name> and the <name type="boat" ref="#Antar">"Antar"</name> had come behind us, and were all waiting to find a way. It did not take us long, and we got safely by them all - when <persName ref="#Burgnoyne_Amelie">Amelie</persName> brought me my tea at 7:30 she told me that the little tug waiting near was for the <name type="boat" ref="#Mâat">Maat</name> - that the <name type="boat" ref="#Mayflower">Mayflower</name> had been aground some hours, and the <name type="boat" ref="#Rameses">"Rameses the Third"</name> had been there two days - having spent 3 days on the sand near <placeName ref="#Al_Wasta">Wasta.</placeName> A Page 113 gentle south wind was blowing, and we went on very well, until making a difficult turn about a long sand bank protruding almost across the river about 11 o'clock- the wind which had grown strong and fitful carried us on the sand and held us there for 3 hours, - blowing very hard. About 1 o'clock the <name type="boat" ref="#Mâat">Maat</name> and her tug passed us and soon disappeared, and we began to regret that we had not ordered a tug on Sunday, when we sent to <placeName ref="#Al_Wasta">Wasta</placeName> for our mail. Just over the bank near us one of the big <orgName>Imfikiah</orgName> steamers lay up almost high and dry on the sand, closed and deserted. At 5 o'clock we got away and kept on until 7 - when we pulled up in sight of <orgName>Benisoef.</orgName> The river has been a spectacle today - a woful one. Beautiful air - colour effects - and radiant night - did not leave the deck until 7 o'clock.</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-03-14">
        <dateline>
          Wednesday, <date when="1900-03-14">March 14</date>. 27 miles.
        </dateline>
          <p>We have done today what I have seen done in descending the river - the men have towed! The wind has been light and fitful - the river very dubious - and many gyassas - and our progress has been difficult and wearying. At breakfast time we were going so finely that we expected to make <placeName ref="#Al_Wasta">Wasta</placeName> by 12 o'clock. We did not reach it until 4 o'clock - <persName>Jones</persName> went off in the felucca to get out mail, and <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> sent a telegram to <persName>Cook</persName> and <persName>Son,</persName> for a tug. For the first time I feel a little tired of the river - not of the pleasant placid life we lead in this delightful little boat, but of the delays the dangers and anxieties that this condition of the river brings. We are having the most heavenly nights, with a full moon. My windows are all <orgName>Page 114</orgName> left unshaded, and I revel in the moonlight, and the desert scenes. Cold this A.M. in my room - 52 at 7 o'clock.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-03-15">
        <dateline>
          Thursday, <date when="1900-03-15">March 15</date>. 
        </dateline>
          <p>30 miles before tug arrived. 20 "	with tug to Cairo. A warm day, with wind from <placeName>South</placeName> - coming out north about noon. At 3:20 we saw the tug coming, but were uncertain if she was coming for us. We found our little old <persName>Rais Achmed</persName> on her, our old Captain of the <placeName>Nubia</placeName> - who gladly hailed us. Our men put away their oars with smiles and great alacrity - and we were soon rushing along free from painful outlooking. We were within sight of <persName>Helouan,</persName> but it was nearly and hour before we reached it - and tied up awhile to make a visit to Mr. <persName>Sayce,</persName> who is lying there. We found him and <persName>Professor Schweinfurth</persName> on the bank, and they both came aboard and had tea with us. The latter is staying at <placeName>Helwan</placeName> - and told us such interesting things. We reached <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> at 7:30 - and found our old place at the <placeName>Museum</placeName> vacant. Mr. <persName>Sayce</persName> told us of a such a sad and painful thing which occurred on the <name type="boat" ref="#Mâat">Maat</name>, <orgName>Lord Northampton's</orgName> boat, the morning after we left them at <placeName>Maghagha</placeName> - the young Doctor he had with him, was found dead in his bed!</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-03-16">
        <dateline>
          Friday, <date when="1900-03-16">March 16</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>At home all day, busy and interested - a good mail arrived this morning, with no bad news - and splendid news from <placeName>S. Africa.</placeName> <persName ref="#Roberts_Lord">Lord Roberts</persName> is relieving one place after another, and the <name>Boers</name> everywhere retreating. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M"</persName> at the Museum this morning, and the girls in town.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-03-17">
        <dateline>
          Saturday, <date when="1900-03-17">March 17</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>Busy this morning with <persName ref="#Burgnoyne_Amelie">Amelie</persName> over the trunks which arrived from <placeName>Shepheards</placeName> this morning. Mr. and Mrs. <persName>Joe Smith</persName> to lunch. <persName ref="#Wilson_Alice">Alice</persName> and I drove almost to the <placeName>Mena House</placeName> this afternoon. The air most delicious with the fragrance of the blossoming alfalfa - but the wind very cold. A lovely night.</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-03-18">
        <dateline>
          Sunday, 3d in Lent. <date when="1900-03-18">March 18th</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>At home all the morning. <persName>Baron von Bissing</persName> came to lunch. He told us very interesting things of <orgName>Petrie's</orgName> discovered at <placeName>Abydos,</placeName> tombs of the I dynasty - which confirm the fact of the tomb discovered at <placeName>Nagada</placeName> supposed to be that of <persName>Menes</persName> to be really that. This afternoon <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and I drove into town to have tea with <persName>Dean</persName> and <persName>Mrs. Butcher.</persName> Found Mr. <persName>Sayce</persName> there, and had tea in the garden behind the church. Then we drove to <persName>Shepheards,</persName> and got out mail, and a pail of ice cream and then the <placeName>Ghizereh Palace</placeName> to see about rooms for Wednesday. We decided on our old <placeName>Khedivial</placeName> apartment. The men are having a great concert tonight. I have been walking on deck in the superb moonlight, and looking down at them as they sat about on the deck, with their darabookras, and tamborines, <persName>Salah</persName> the singer making great effects: The little stove burning, and the lamp hanging over <placeName>Sulyman's</placeName> table where he is ironing. Such a nice scene. Page 116</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-03-19">
        <dateline>
          Monday, <date when="1900-03-19">Mar. 19th</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>Home all day. Mr. <persName>Sayce</persName> came to lunch and did not leave until late - a pleasant visit - <persName>Nettie</persName> and <persName ref="#Wilson_Alice">Alice</persName> drove out to the <placeName>Mena House</placeName> for tea - and <persName>Monsieur Maspere</persName> and his wife came to tea, and sat very late until <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> returned from his ride. Very busy between times arranging and getting ready to have the packing done. The <name>Tranttenbergs</name> also called.</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-03-20">
        <dateline>
          Tuesday, <date when="1900-03-20">March 20</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>Packing all day. Mr. and Mrs. <persName>John Bancroft,</persName> who have been staying a long time at <placeName>Helouan</placeName> came to lunch and were delighted with the boat and our accounts of life on the river. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and I spent a pleasant morning at the Museum. <name>Brugsch Bay</name> paid us a visit in the afternoon. Our last evening on the dear <placeName>Beduin</placeName> for this season - always a melancholy thing.</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-03-21">
        <dateline>
          Wednesday, <date when="1900-03-21">March 21st</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>We are again installed in the vast <orgName>Khedivial</orgName> appartment at the <placeName>Ghezireh</placeName> - having arrived this afternoon in time for tea - just after breakfast <persName>Baron</persName> and <persName>Baroness Tranttenberg</persName> arrived at the boat, and invited us for dinner on Saturday. It has been warm today, and I am quite tired with all the parting arrangements at the dahabeah.</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-03-22">
        <dateline>
          Thursday, <date when="1900-03-22">March 22</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>At home all this morning writing letters - ad in the afternoon <orgName>Page 117</orgName> we all drove out to the Pyramids. The day was a grey one, and not warm, an ideal day for the desert - there was no glare from the sand - and the effects were fine - I never saw the <name>Sphinx</name> to such advantage. Tea at the <orgName>Mena House,</orgName> which was filed with officers - as the yearly encampment is now in the desert beyond the <placeName>Pyramids</placeName> - so that the scene on the terrace was very gay. The ride home was charming. <persName>Mrs. Tytys</persName> and her son, and young <!-- Unknown --><persName ref="">Terry</persName> came over from <persName>Shepheards,</persName> to dine with us, and were greatly amused and interested in our regal appartments.</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-03-23">
        <dateline>
          Friday, <date when="1900-03-23">March 23</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>Drove into town with <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore,</persName> and tried to do a little shopping. No one dares now to go into the bazaar, because of the rumours of small pox. <persName ref="#Wilson_Alice">Alice</persName> and <persName>Nettie</persName> went early in to town to see the dervishes and <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and I drove out beyond <placeName>Koubbeh</placeName> - where I have not been for years, <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> has grown enormously winthin the last few years in this direction. The <placeName>Fhedives</placeName> palace at <placeName>Koubbeh</placeName> seems a simple affair surrounded by large grounds apparently under fine cultivations - and beautiful green fields of wheat, barley, and alfalfa stretching away as far as one could see - the finest crops I have seen in <placeName>Egypt</placeName> this year. It was a delicious afternoon. We stopped at <placeName>Shepheard's</placeName> for the mail, and it being late had tea there - and then drove back to the <placeName>Ghezireh Palace,</placeName> and well pleased we were to exchange the pure air here for the bad air of Cairo. Page 118</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-03-24">
        <dateline>
          Saturday, <date when="1900-03-24">March 24</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>Drove with <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> to the <placeName>dahabeah</placeName> this morning to arrange some things. <persName>Jones</persName> and <persName ref="#Burgnoyne_Amelie">Amelie</persName> have been busy there for days - so that all inside the boat is in its summer condition. How I hated to leave the little boat - and then came the final parting with the men, who were all on the lower deck - standing and waiting. I shook hands with everyone of them, and said many "ma salams". We are quite distressed with <persName>Hais Fuli,</persName> who has not been well all winter - <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> sent him to <persName>Dr. Sandwith</persName> with a note. We have been dining with the <name>Tranttenbergs</name> - many charming things in their house. I like much the <persName>Baron</persName> - who is the <orgName>Austrian</orgName> representative in the <placeName>Cours de la Dette</placeName> for Egypt. There were many beautiful things in their appartment in the way of bric-a-brac and some really good things of the <orgName>Baroness's</orgName> who is something of a genius as a deller. What an extraordinary character she is - a cordial, enthusiastic most likely insincere woman of the world, <orgName>Russian</orgName> by birth, with a married daughter and grandchildren, and with very remarkable manners to our thinking.</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-03-25">
        <dateline>
          Sunday, 4th in Lent. <date when="1900-03-25">March 25</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>The day has been very hot - <persName>Khamsiny</persName> - with a wonderful marching of clouds and dissolving mists. I have not been out - having some writing to do - and feeling the heaviness of the atmosphere. some arrangements for packing, writing and reading occupied the morning. Every one else was out - and I had our vast salon all to myself - morning and afternoon. It is 40 x 45 feet - very lofty and magnificent <orgName>Page 119</orgName> with five great windows - 3 of them spaning on a balcony, overlooking the river. After the man left this side of the house, I set them wide open all the 5 of them - and it was indeed charming - the garden seemed to have entered into the house - and I enjoyed it immensely, and had quite a walk up and down, after finishing my letters. The room is splendidly furnished in true <orgName>Oriental</orgName> magnificence - all the rich, velvet and satin furniture with the <orgName>Khedivial</orgName> crown is mounted in gild elaborately . The chimney piece reaching to the ceiling is of alabaster, onyx-malachite and gilt, enornous mirrors, and everything to correspond. My bed room adjoining is all in red fluted silk - walls, ceiling and all. The bedroom that <persName>Nettie</persName> and <persName ref="#Wilson_Alice">Alice</persName> share together is equally huge, and was the <orgName>Khedivo's</orgName> - and his bathroom adjoining, has a great tin tub, made to represent silver, with his crown - all the rest of the rooms correspond. It was built by the <persName>Khedivo Ismail,</persName> of evil memory, the grandfather of the present <persName>Abbas II</persName> and is not owned by the <name>International Hotel Co.</name> His full length portrait adorns the salon - I must say the appartment is a bit "eerie", for certain mysterious crimes are associated with the palace. <persName>Baron von Bissing</persName> dined with us - and young <persName>Tytus</persName> and <!-- Unknown --><persName ref="">Terry</persName> came to say goodbye. We leave at 9 o'clock tomorrow morning for <persName>Alexandrea,</persName> and sail at 4 o'clock for <persName>Naples,</persName> an the <orgName>Kaiser Wilhelm II.</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-03-30">
        <dateline>
          Hotel Bristol. Rome. <date when="1900-03-30">March 30th</date>.
        </dateline>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-03-31">
        <dateline>
          Saturday, <date when="1900-03-31">March 31st</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>It stormed all night and was raining at intervals this morning so I did not go out until the afternoon, when the rain ceased. We drove to the <placeName>Villa Berghese,</placeName> and had a delightful afternoon with the pictures. I came away chilled to the bone, and was glad to reach home and a fire and a hot cup of tea.</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-04-01">
        <dateline>
          Sunday, <date when="1900-04-01">April 1st</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>The rain poured all night, with much thunder and lightning - and the morning was so bad, <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> would not go out - nor did I venture <orgName>Page 121</orgName> The girls took the carriage and drove to the <placeName>Lateran</placeName> and <orgName>Maggiori.</orgName> The afternoon was better, and at 4 o'clock we drove over to <placeName>St. Peters.</placeName> I don't know when I have enjoyed <persName>St. Peters</persName> so much - though music was not so good as usual. As <persName>Leo XIII,</persName> the present <persName>Pope</persName> celebrates this year his 90th birthday, the city is full of pilgrimages - and it is said that <placeName>Rome</placeName> never was so full. The church had more people in it than I had ever before known - and among them a band of pilgrims from <placeName>Moravia,</placeName> in their picturesque costumes - the women with skirts to their knees, and high boots like the men - their heads tied up in bright handkerchiefs. The men were splendid, stalwart looking fellows - a hardy, rather refined looking race - very cold today.</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-04-02">
        <dateline>
          Monday, <date when="1900-04-02">April 2d</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>We have had a whole beautiful day, and we celebrated the morning by driving out on the <placeName>Appian Way.</placeName> The air was so crisp - so almost wintry - and had such an effect of being washed so clean, that I realized I had not felt anything like it for 5 years. The larks were singing up in the sky - and the blackbirds on the trees - and the deep blue <placeName>Alban Mountains</placeName> and <placeName>Mt.</placeName> Soracte, covered with snow were beautiful. After luncheon I went out with the girls for a while, and then <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> took them to drive in the <persName>Doria Pamfili</persName> grounds. Lady <persName>Agnes de Trafford</persName> and <persName>Mr. de Trafford,</persName> wiht his sister <persName>Miss de Trafford,</persName> dined with us - and we had a merry dinner. Page 122</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-04-03">
        <dateline>
          Tuesday, <date when="1900-04-03">April 3d</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>Another cold, very cold showery day. We drove over to the <placeName>Vatican</placeName> to the sculptures - and spent the whole morning there, coming home petrified. Met the <persName>de Traffords</persName> there. This afternoon after a heavy shower, the sun coming out, we ventured forth to the <orgName>Patheon,</orgName> which was closed. By that time the rain began again, but we tried the interesting church of <persName>S. Maria Sopea Minerva</persName> - but found it too dark to see.Then we drove to <placeName>Santa Cecilia</placeName> - but found that closed, as they are doing a great deal of excavating there - of most interesting character. Then we drove back, and tried one or two antiquity shops, and then in disgust came home, and had tea in our pleasant sitting room, before a little wood fire, and watched a splendid sunset. tonight the 3 days old moon is resplendent in a clear sky - and <persName>Venus</persName> brilliantly beautiful near her.</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-04-04">
        <dateline>
          Wednesday, <date when="1900-04-04">April 4th</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>To the <placeName>Capitol Museum</placeName> this morning, where we stayed until we were petrified with the cold. Then we went into the <placeName>Ara Coeli,</placeName> which is always impressive with its beautiful old pavement, its <orgName>Cosmatesque</orgName> pulpits and its many curious grave slabs. In the afternoon in spite of the cold threatening weather, we drove out to <persName>S. Paolo fuora le Mura.</persName> I sat in the carriage while the others went into church, whose chill I did not feel like risking. Coming back we stopped at the very curious little church of <persName>S. Maria</persName> in <placeName>Cosmedin</placeName> - and to what is generally called the <orgName>Temple of Vesta,</orgName> the circular church of <persName>S. Maria</persName> in <placeName>Sola;</placeName> then drove <orgName>Page 123</orgName> to the old fram men's in <placeName>Via Gregorians</placeName> to settle with him about 4 lovely old frames <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> has bought of him. Then we drove to the <placeName>Palasse Borghese</placeName> to have tea with <persName>Mrs. Bronson.</persName> Mrs. <persName>Woodsworth</persName> had also invited us - but we had accepted Mrs. <orgName>Bronson's</orgName> invitation.</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-04-05">
        <dateline>
          Thursday, <date when="1900-04-05">April 5th</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>The morning being fine, we availed ourselves of the permits Lady <persName>Agnes</persName> had sent us, and went to the <placeName>Vatican Gardens</placeName> - and had a good walk there. They have always been mysterious in their attraction, and I was very glad to see them. But sadly disappointed we were. We met the <persName>de Traffords</persName> with some others there. Did a little shopping on our way home. Did not go out this afternoon. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> took <persName ref="#Wilson_Alice">Alice</persName> to various places. Young Mr. <persName>Watmore</persName> came to tea. It has rained at intervals today., coldy tonight.</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-04-06">
        <dateline>
          Friday, <date when="1900-04-06">April 6th</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>Went out into the rain this morning with <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> to see a <orgName>Sienese</orgName> painting that <persName>Monsieur Imbert</persName> wishes <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> to buy - a <persName>Matteo di Gualdo</persName> - a triptych - a very charming picture, not entirely in good condition - possibly <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> will buy it. Then we drove to the church of <persName>S. Pietro</persName> in <placeName>Vincolo</placeName> - and had a lovely look at the "Moses" by <placeName>Michelangelo.</placeName> Then to the <persName>Doria</persName> gallery to see the great <orgName>Velasquox.</orgName> At home all the afternoon, rain and cold winds. <persName>Ethel Bronson</persName> came to say boodgye - and so did Mr. <persName>de Trafford</persName> and <persName>Lady Agnes.</persName> Mr. <persName>John Parsons Page</persName> 124 of <placeName>New York</placeName> and <persName>Mary,</persName> who arrived today came in to see us this evening. They succeed to our rooms tomorrow.</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-04-07">
        <dateline>
          Saturday, <date when="1900-04-07">April 7th</date>. Grand Bretagne. Florence.
        </dateline>
          <p>A cold wet morning - left <placeName>Rome</placeName> at 9:30 arrived at 2:30 - and went to the <placeName>Grand Hotel</placeName> where we had engaged rooms, but found them so impossible that we declined them and came here, where we are most comfortably settled in our old rooms. Went to have tea with <persName>Lizzie</persName> and the girls - and enjoyed ourselves much. Rex wild with delight to see <persName>Nettie</persName> again.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-04-08">
        <dateline>
          Sunday - before Easter. <date when="1900-04-08">April 8th</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p><persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and I went by engagement up to <persName>Mrs. Costellar's</persName> place for lunch - leaving <persName ref="#Wilson_Alice">Alice</persName> at <placeName>Lizzie's.</placeName> A cold wet morning, with occasional bursts of sunshine, which about noon dispelled the clouds. We found <persName>Miss Berenson, Mr. Pearsall-Smith,</persName> and an <orgName>English</orgName> lady and gentleman with <persName>Mrs. Costellar</persName> and <persName>Berenson.</persName> A delicious lunch - and much pleasant talk. <persName>Mrs. Costellar</persName> never looked as well and womanly. She and <persName>Berenson</persName> announced their engagement, and will be married in the autumn. <persName>Mary</persName> and <persName ref="#Wilson_Alice">Alice</persName> came to fetch us, about 4 - and we walked over to <placeName>Berenson's</placeName> house to see all his choice and pretty things. Stopped at the <placeName>Villino,</placeName> and had tea with <persName>Lizzie</persName> - and she and <persName>Mary</persName> came to dine with us, <persName>Nettie</persName> having a bad cold. Page 125</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-04-09">
        <dateline>
          Monday, <date when="1900-04-09">April 9th</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>I went by appointment to the dentist's this morning - and then drove about a little. <persName>Berenson</persName> took us after lunch to see some pictures on loan, at the exposition of modern art. A small room beautifully hung with tapestries, had a few beautiful pictures - and a most charming <persName>Desiderio</persName> of an infant <persName>Christ</persName> and <placeName>St. John.</placeName> A interesting <persName>Crivelli</persName> and a most exquisite <persName>Madonna</persName> and Child labelled <persName>"Pur della Francesca"</persName> but which <persName>Berenson</persName> said was by <orgName>Baldevivetti.</orgName> Then we drove to an antiquity shop - and then to <orgName>Constantini's</orgName> and then to tea with <persName>Lizzie.</persName> <persName>Berenson</persName> and his sister dined with us.</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-04-10">
        <dateline>
          Tuesday, <date when="1900-04-10">April 10th</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p><persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName>, <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I went to the <placeName>Bargelle</placeName> this morning and stayed nearly 2 hours - coming out quite petrified. It is to me always one of the most delightful things to do in <placeName>Florence,</placeName> - the marbles are so delightful. <persName>Berenson</persName> came to lunch. Afterwards we drove to <persName>Brauer's</persName> one of the most artistic and interesting antiquaries I have ever seen. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> bought 2 beautiful quatre cento bronzes - and an ivory <persName>Madonna</persName> and <persName>Child</persName> - said to have been made by <persName>Nino de Pisano.</persName> Afterwards to <name>Lizzie's</name> for tea. <persName>Young Constantini</persName> dining with us tonight.</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-04-11">
        <dateline>
          Wednesday, <date when="1900-04-11">April 11th</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>I went up with the carriage to <persName>Lizzie's</persName> this morning after it had been taken <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and <persName ref="#Wilson_Alice">Alice</persName> to the <persName>Pitti,</persName> intending to take <persName>Nettie</persName> and <persName>Rex</persName> to drive - but found them all out. Then I did some shopping - <orgName>Page 126</orgName> and ran across <placeName>Mary.</placeName> <persName>Berenson</persName> and his sister came to lunch - then we went to <placeName>Bardini's</placeName> - the <persName>Berensons, Nettie</persName> and I, and then came back for <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and went to <placeName>Ban Lorenze</placeName> - to the Church and old <placeName>Saeriety</placeName> - then up to <placeName>Berensons</placeName> place and had tea - a lovely, clear day.</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-04-12">
        <dateline>
          Thursday, <date when="1900-04-12">April 12</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>At home this morning - Mrs. <persName>Pearsall-Smith</persName> and his friend from <placeName>Oxford,</placeName> Mr. <persName>Meller</persName> came to lunch. Afterwards we went to <persName>Brauers</persName> and spent a long time there, looking at his treasures - stopped at <placeName>Lizzie's</placeName> for tea - Mr. <persName>Cadman</persName> came from <placeName>Rome</placeName> to see <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore,</persName> and he and <persName>Constantini</persName> dined with us - I have a cold, and am thoroughly tired.</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-04-14">
        <dateline>
          Saturday, <date when="1900-04-14">April 14th</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>I spent all day yesterday in bed with one of my usual bronchial attacks - and have not been out of the house today. The weather is charming too - and I feel very cross about staying in. Since the noon gun fired today, the bells all over the city have been ringing their melodious chimes much of the time. I so love their sweet sounds, and never tire of it. The moon is full tonight and makes the river, and the old bridge and the towers and picturesque houses opposite beautiful. <persName>Constantini</persName> dined with us, and is now playing chose with  <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore.</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-04-15">
        <dateline>
          Easter Sunday, <date when="1900-04-15">April 15</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>A most lovely Easter day this has been - <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and I went up to <placeName>San Minato</placeName> this morning, and sat there a long time in the sun, <orgName>Page 127</orgName> which was really too warm. I did not dare venture into the church, much as I wanted - because of my cold. We had the place quite to ourselves, only a few faithful ones with wreathes and flowers crossing before the church to the graveyard beyond. A heavenly peace over everything. This afternoon I made a stupid drive and excursion under <orgName>Constantini's</orgName> suggestion, and visited a certain villa, which is to be sold and which <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> was anxious to see. I had expected to see an <orgName>Italian</orgName> villa - but my disappointment was great when I found a big, pretentious place, with little that was <orgName>Italian</orgName> about it - overlaid and crammed with things in bad <placeName>French,</placeName> and <orgName>Chinese.</orgName> It belongs to a rich <orgName>Russian,</orgName> who has lavished thousands upon it - and I did not see a thing I would have had, and nothing would induce me to live in such a house. <persName>Berenson</persName> dined here, and has just gone home. Mr. and <persName>Mrs. Stevens</persName> lunched with us.</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-04-16">
        <dateline>
          Monday, <date when="1900-04-16">April 16th</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>Stayed in the house all day - my cold no better. Miss <persName>Berenson</persName> came to say goodbye, and dear <persName>Lizzie</persName> came and had tea with me. <persName>Mary</persName> also, has been in bed for two days - so that we have not been able to say goodbye. <persName>Nettie</persName> goes with us to <persName>London,</persName> for which we are so glad, <persName>Mary</persName> not being able to travel with is. Mr. and Mrs. <persName>Stevens</persName> came to say goodbye.</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-04-17">
        <dateline>
          Tuesday, <date when="1900-04-17">April 17th</date>. Hotel Brittania - Venice.
        </dateline>
          <p>We left <placeName>Florence</placeName> in a rain at 11:30 and it poured harder and <orgName>Page 128</orgName> harder as the day went on. It was impossible to see out of the windows; arrived in <placeName>Venice</placeName> at 6 o'clock - fortunately the rain had stopped though everything was dripping - this has not improved my cold. We were greatly annoyed to find that we could not get into our appartment until tomorrow morning, as the people ( princely offenders) had decided to spend another day- and we are now distributed about the hotel.</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-04-18">
        <dateline>
          Wednesday, <date when="1900-04-18">April 18</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>A wretched day in the house - we got into our regal rooms this morning and are very comfortable. The salon is a gorgeous room in red silk and gold - all the world abroad, except myself.</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-04-19">
        <dateline>
          Thursday, <date when="1900-04-19">April 19</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>Again in the house, while everyone else is sight seeing, - the sun shines, but the winds are very strong - and cold. The house resounds with sneezing and coughing. We find our next door neighbors are Mr. and Mrs. <persName>Lanfear Norrie</persName> - she came in this afternoon to see me.</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-04-20">
        <dateline>
          Friday, <date when="1900-04-20">April 20th</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>Still in-doors, but much better, and hope to be out tomorrow. It has been a beautiful day, but with a cold wind. I was out in the sunshine on our balcony for awhile this morning - and I have been entranced watching the beautiful life of this most entrancing city. I have stared until my eyes were tired - the big steamers entering and leaving port, for we are just opposite the <placeName>Custom House</placeName> - the picturesque <orgName>Page 129</orgName> red and orange sails of the boats - the countless gondolas swiftly slipping about, propelled by the graceful sweet of the gondeliers - and as the day declined, the exquisite reflections on the water, the palaces and the boats. What a lovely spectacle <persName>S. Maria Maggiori</persName> with its tall pink campanile, all seeming to grow out of the sea. The rest of the family are all down stairs listening to a concert of classical music given in the big dining room - and outside, the usual strumming of guitars and singing and impassioned, cracked quavering voices - though the boats are pretty enough with their coloured lights.</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-04-21">
        <dateline>
          Saturday, <date when="1900-04-21">April 21st</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>Went out this morning with <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> to see some marbles - a strong wind blowing. We walked home, and lost our way and I was very tired. In the afternoon <persName ref="#Wilson_Alice">Alice</persName> and I went to <placeName>San Marco</placeName> - and stayed a long time - then had chocolate in a little shop. Quite tired out.</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-04-22">
        <dateline>
          Sunday, <date when="1900-04-22">April 22d</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>Stayed at home all day - feeling so little temptation to go out. The rest went to see the <placeName>Bensons</placeName> this afternoon and brought me some lovely flowers.</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-04-23">
        <dateline>
          Monday, <date when="1900-04-23">April 23d</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>A summers day - we went to the church of <persName>S. Francesco della Vigna</persName> to see the beautiful <persName>Negroponte Madonna</persName> again - and a lovely <persName>Gian Bellini</persName> - hidden away behind glass and iron gauze - in a dark sacristy Page 130 What a pity it is that pictures of world wide interest, of inexpressible value and beauty, cannot be placed in safety and in a good light, and in accessible places. The church was so frigid, that I did not stay long, but went outside into the little <placeName>Campo</placeName> - where the children came to bother and beg, and try all their little arts of pleasing upon me - presently out from the church came a priest and acolyte bearing a censer and crucifix, followed by 2 men bearing a bier with such a little coffin which immediately diverted the children, and I was left to saunter up and down in peace in the sunshine. Then we went to <persName>S. Giovanni</persName> in <placeName>Braggors,</placeName> and passing on the way the little <placeName>Schiavonis Church</placeName> we heard music and found that this was the feast of <placeName>St. George,</placeName> and that a service was being held in the upper church - so we stopped and went in, and assisted for awhile at a domestic little service, with one splendid voice in the choir. Then we kept on our way to the <placeName>Bragora</placeName> through the evil smelling canals. There we found the church on festa, with a very good light upon the splendid <orgName>Cima,</orgName> above the altar, and the beautiful <orgName>Ressurection</orgName> of <persName>Alvise Vivarini's</persName> and the <persName>Bartolomeo Vivarini Madonna</persName> with <placeName>Chile</placeName> sad Angels. The tide was very low this morning and the smells were inconceivable - indeed it seems to me <placeName>Venice</placeName> smells more vilely than usual. It is impossible to keep windows opened at night. This afternoon we had a delightful row in the <placeName>Ginduca</placeName> - which always interests me so - the place looks in a way so deserted, and the <persName>Riva</persName> so lonely with its strange big houses and their peculiar look. We turned into the charming little canal leading along the <placeName>Fondamenta della Croce</placeName> - and then back again Page 131 the people in their picturesque little houses living outside along the quiet street. One almost wished to be poor and live among them. I avoided the great cold <placeName>Redentore</placeName> church, and we kept on to the charming church of <placeName>San Sebastiano</placeName> where I was not allowed to stay very long, as the chill was deadly. <persName>Paul Veronese</persName> lies buried there, and the church and <placeName>Sacristy</placeName> are filled with his paintings. I walked about in the warm air along the pretty calle and watched the life about me - afterwards the rest went to the <placeName>Piazetta</placeName> for tea, but I wisely stopped at the hotel, and had tea alone.</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-04-24">
        <dateline>
          Tuesday, <date when="1900-04-24">April 24th</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>In the house all the morning - <persName>Doctor</persName> came to see <persName ref="#Wilson_Alice">Alice</persName> who has a bad cold - we went out together in the afternoon and walked about the <placeName>Piazetta</placeName> and into <placeName>St. Marks,</placeName> and had tea a Florians.</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-04-25">
        <dateline>
          Wednesday, <date when="1900-04-25">April 25</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p><persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and I went out to see some marbles and stuffs this morning. It was cold and sometimes a soft rain fell. A beautiful regatta on the <placeName>Grand Canal</placeName> in honour of <placeName>St. Marks</placeName> day, which it is - <persName>Nettie</persName> and I went out early this afternoon to the <placeName>Cathedral,</placeName> all in festival attire it was. What a splendour of richness, or sumptuousness, of effect, of art this wonderful church is! The crowd this afternoon so picturesque, the lights so mellow and illuminating. There is nothing like it in the world - and what a quaint little exhibitions of human character I saw! Afterward we took up <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and went to see the <orgName>Bensons.</orgName> Found them <orgName>Page 132</orgName> in the garden, which was a lovely wonder of tulips, forget-me-nots, and cherry blossoms - and old world surroundings of marbles, statues, and porticoes! The poor old lady so interesting, so full of enjoyment of her flowers. It is about the one pleasure she has left in life - lame, her arms and hands crippled with rheumatism, one eye destroyed from the effect of an accident years ago, she is most charming - with the espieglerie and manner of an old time woman of the world. She was so delighted with the seeds I sent her last year. Then we mounted to their appartment, and saw once more their charming rooms - full of beautiful things, such a grand hall - 135 ft. in length. It was cold and damp coming home.</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-04-26">
        <dateline>
          Thursday, <date when="1900-04-26">April 26</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>In doors all day - really ill - <persName ref="#Wilson_Alice">Alice</persName> in bed - doctor here. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and <persName>Nettie</persName> gone on that beautiful expedition to <placeName>Castel France</placeName> to see the great <orgName>Giorgione</orgName> - and I raging with disappointment at not being able to go with them. A heavy thunder shower last night - and very high cold winds today.</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-04-27">
        <dateline>
          Friday, <date when="1900-04-27">April 27</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>Still indoors - but <persName ref="#Wilson_Alice">Alice</persName> and I are both up and in our big salon. Very dark, gray, stormy sky. We get off tomorrow for <persName>Milan.</persName> So glad, as I am tired staying here, and not doing the thousand charming things there are to do. Page 133</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-04-29">
        <dateline>
          Sunday, <date when="1900-04-29">April 29th</date>. Milan - Hotel Cavour.
        </dateline>
          <p>We were all glad to quite <placeName>Venice</placeName> yesterday. I was tired of staying indoors in a place where there were so many ravishing things I wanted to see - and the weather was hopelessly bad. It was such a great disappointment for me not to be able to go to the <persName>Frori</persName> and to <persName>S. Giovanni</persName> a <persName>Paolo</persName> - where are the interesting tombs I have been reading about, and making notes of, for a year past. I had looked forward to seeing these with <persName>Nettie,</persName> in a more discriminating way than I had ever before seen them. But these 2 churches are the dampest and most frigid of any in <placeName>Venice:</placeName> and I could not go to them. Then there was <persName>Verona,</persName> with all its charms, and its own <orgName>Gothic</orgName> tombs. This visit which we had intended making, also had to be given up. We hope to get to <placeName>Pavia</placeName> from here for half a day at least. The journey yesterday by way of <persName>Padua, Vicenza, Verona,</persName> along the lower end of <placeName>Lago di Garda, Brescia</placeName> to <persName>Milan,</persName> was through a garden of <placeName>Paradise,</placeName> - hills, mountains, picturesque towns, formed a setting for the delicious landscape in dress of vivid greens - an fruit trees in blossom. Arrive at 7 o'clock - and are in our old rooms at this most excellent of all hotels. <persName ref="#Wilson_Alice">Alice</persName> and I have again spent the day in the house as it has been raining much of the time.</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-04-30">
        <dateline>
          Monday, <date when="1900-04-30">April 30th</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>It stormed heavily last night, and has been raining hard at times today. We leave tomorrow for <persName>Lucerne,</persName> and are anxiously hoping <orgName>Page 134</orgName> that we may have good weather for that incomparable journey. We all went to the <placeName>Poldi-Pezzoli</placeName> this morning and revelled among the pictures. The garden was exquisite this morning as seen from the windows. After lunch <persName>Nettie</persName> and I went out in a comfortable landau - and did some charming things - bringing up in the arcade of our favorite photographers and I got a lot of views of <placeName>Verona,</placeName> and especially of its churches and tombs. It rained and the wind blew hard as we came home. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> with the girls then went off to a sacred concert given by <persName>Don Lorenzo Perosi,</persName> a priest, and a composer of beautiful music - and it was in the church of <placeName>S. M. Bella Pace,</placeName> which has been converted into a kind of oratory for his music. It was an <orgName>Oratorio of Christ's Entry</orgName> into Jerusalem. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and <persName>Nettie</persName> enchanted with the music - I was too tired to go.</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-05-02">
        <dateline>
          Hotel National. Lucerne. Wednesday, <date when="1900-05-02">May 2d</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>A very favourable day yesterday for the incomparable journey over the <placeName>St. Gotthard.</placeName> But it is always tiring - the attention is all the time so divided between so many wonderful sights. <persName ref="#Wilson_Alice">Alice</persName> was very ill last evening - and we felt very anxious, but she is much better today, and in the sitting room this evening. We have the same rooms we had last year, fronting the lake. My pleasant room at the corner of the house looking towards <placeName>Mt.</placeName> <persName>Pilatus</persName> - and the very same yellow bellied blackbird, sits on the same tree outside, and sings in the same delicious manner. The weather not quite clear - a great deal of snow on the mts. which under a hot sun always makes a misty atmosphere. Page 135</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-05-03">
        <dateline>
          Lucerne. Thursday, <date when="1900-05-03">May 3d</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>My sister-in-law <persName>Mary Rogers</persName> came over from <placeName>Berne</placeName> where she and <persName>Marie Clockure</persName> are staying, to spend the day and night with me. A great pleasure to both of us. It rained heavily, with thunder and lightning this afternoon - so that going out was impossible, though <persName>Mary</persName> and I had a walk of an hour before the hotel and along the quay. A wonderful light on the Mts. and lake - all in dark, dark blue. I never saw anything finer. Last evening we saw a light burning on Mt. <persName>Pilatus</persName> from the little house there I suppose.</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-05-04">
        <dateline>
          Basle. Friday, <date when="1900-05-04">May 4th</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p><persName>Mary Rodgers</persName> went back to <placeName>Berne</placeName> this morning. Then <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> , <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I went to <placeName>Bossaras,</placeName> where <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> bought a most charming and interesting little painted wooden figure, which came from the <placeName>Cathedral of Burgos</placeName> in <placeName>Spain</placeName> - and bought the companion <orgName>Spanish</orgName> mirror of his own, to give to Mr. <persName>Ayer</persName> for his new house building in <placeName>Boston.</placeName> An early lunch, and then we started for <placeName>Basle</placeName> which we reached at 5 o'clock - coming to the "Trois <persName>Rois"</persName> where we are occupying an appartment at the corner of the house on the first floor which we had about 15 years ago. The <persName>Baroness von Overbeck, Alice's</persName> friend, came over from <placeName>Freibourg</placeName> to see her and dined with her. <persName ref="#Wilson_Alice">Alice</persName> will probably decide to stay with her until her father comes over next month. The river is very high and rapid. Page 136</p>  
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-05-06">
        <dateline>
          Hotel Bristol. Sunday evening. London, <date when="1900-05-06">May 6th.</date>
        </dateline>
          <p>Yesterday morning we spent at the <placeName>Museums and Cathedral</placeName> and walked on the terrace - after lunch, which Mme. <persName>v. Overback</persName> took with us, <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and I went for a long drive along the river 12 miles away to the <placeName>Hotel des Salines,</placeName> where we had tea and walked about the grounds. The hotel is handsome and comfortable, the grounds rather <orgName>German</orgName> and small. <persName>Nettie</persName> too tired to drive, and <persName ref="#Wilson_Alice">Alice</persName> getting ready to go to <placeName>Fribourg</placeName> with her friend, we left them at home. The drive home on the <orgName>German</orgName> side of the river very charming. Mme. <persName>v. Overbeck,</persName> who was <persName>Miss Romain Goddard</persName> of <persName>Zanesville, Ohio,</persName> dined with us, and then she and <persName ref="#Wilson_Alice">Alice</persName> departed, and at 10 o'clock we drove to the station and took a very comfortable sleeping car for <placeName>London</placeName> - where we arrived at 6 o'clock this P.M. well tired and covered with dust, the crossing most comfortable. Are in our favorite appartment here on the 2d floor.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-05-07">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1900-05-07">May 7th</date>. Monday.
        </dateline>
          <p>Busy all day with tailors et cet. <persName>Mathilde Boal</persName> arrived from <placeName>Paris</placeName> this morning to stay until Friday. Mr. <persName>Gaspard Farrer</persName> called.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-05-08">
        <dateline>
          Tuesday, <date when="1900-05-08">May 8th</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>A delightful evening at the <placeName>Majesty Theatre</placeName> this evening. Midsummer Nights' Dream - and quite a perfect representation of the play. <persName>Everard Fielding</persName> here this afternoon for tea. Page 137</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-05-09">
        <dateline>
          Wednesday, <date when="1900-05-09">May 9th</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>A dismal, erude, rainy day. <persName>Nettie</persName> and I went to the <placeName>Strand Theatre</placeName> this afternoon to see a play written by <persName>Bernhard Shaw</persName> - "You can never tell". Very clever and amusing - and well played.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-05-11">
        <dateline>
          Friday, <date when="1900-05-11">May 11th</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p><persName>Mathilde</persName> went back to <placeName>Paris</placeName> this morning - nothing of interest to chronicle for 2 days. <persName>Fielding</persName> dined tonight with us. Weather wretched and cold.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-05-12">
        <dateline>
          Saturday, <date when="1900-05-12">May 12</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p><persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> has gone with <persName>Fielding</persName> to the <name>Newnham Paddox</name> to spend Sunday with <persName>Lord Denbigh.</persName> We shopped this morning - and went to the <placeName>National Gallery</placeName> which was frigid. Mr. <persName>Hathbone</persName> came in the afternoon. The evening was dismally lonely without <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore.</persName></p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-05-14">
        <dateline>
          Monday, <date when="1900-05-14">14 May</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p><persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> came home with a bad cold. The day has been wintry.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-05-19">
        <dateline>
          Saturday, <date when="1900-05-19">May 19th</date>. Royal Anchor Hotel. Liphook.
        </dateline>
          <p>We decided to come here again to spend Sunday - as <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> has not seen it, and we were sure of the comforts of this little Inn. <persName>Gaspard Farrer</persName> came in time for dinner. We got down for lunch, and afterwards drove to Hindhead. No sunshine, and heavy clouds - view not Page 138 distinct of course. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> delighted with the drive, and with the grand views, that even the misty dull atmosphere gave. Comfortable, even pretty dinner in our cheerful sitting room. Little to chronicle of our movements during the week. All with bad colds - yet we have taken tea (having declined dinner) with the <orgName>Hathbones</orgName> - declined dinner at Sir Tm. Farrers - and gone with <persName>Gaspard Farrer</persName> to the most delightful concert I ever heard - one of the <placeName>Philharmonics</placeName> with <persName>Isayc</persName> as violinist - an inspired genius - with a touch that put one directly into paradise - delicious orchestra - well lead. Last night <persName>Fielding</persName> was dining with us - with a hoarse, coughing cold. About half past nine o'clock we heard some cries and calls in the street, and we distinguished the word Mafeking. In a moment we were all on our feet at the windows - and sure enough, the shouts were taken up, and grew into a rear, "relief of Mafeking". <persName>Fielding</persName> hastily said goodnight, after vainly begging us all to go out with him - and just as we were going to bed, after 11 o'clock, came back, saying the town was wild, - that it was a spectacle not to be missed etc. We made him sit down and have some beer and biscuits, and then he was out again. This morning we heard from <persName>Jones,</persName> who was out most of the night, of all the excitement, and it makes one's heart thrill, to think of that long besieged and suffering town, being relieved, and of that brave, resourceful hero - <persName>Col. Baden-Powell</persName> at last rescued. as enormous crowd last night besieged the house of mother-in-law, where his wife is living, and spent hours in cheering. It gives one a clutch at the heart to think of it! Page 139</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-05-21">
        <dateline>
          Monday, <date when="1900-05-21">May 21st</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>We came back from <placeName>Liphook</placeName> today - leaving on the 9:57 train. <persName>Nettie</persName> and I stepped over in <placeName>Guildford,</placeName> and made a visit to Mr. <persName>Leenard</persName> and his private <orgName>Alpine</orgName> garden - which I so enjoyed - took the 12 o'clock train to <placeName>London,</placeName> and home just in time for luncheon. Mr. <persName>Rathbone</persName> and his daughter lunched with us - and Sir <persName>William Farrer</persName> and his daughter came for tea - so that we are rather tired - <placeName>London</placeName> still wild with excitement - houses decorated with flags - illuminations and torch light processions.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-05-22">
        <dateline>
          Tuesday, <date when="1900-05-22">May 22d</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>Very busy alldday - <persName>Nettie</persName> went with <persName ref="#Burgnoyne_Amelie">Amelie</persName> and <persName>Jones</persName> to the <orgName>Military Tournament</orgName> - was delighted - we went to the <orgName>Criterion</orgName> and saw a most amusing play - <name>"Lady Huntford's Experiment"</name> - well played. Rain yesterday and today.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-05-23">
        <dateline>
          Wednesday, <date when="1900-05-23">May 23d</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>Another day of gloom and rain - <persName>Nettie</persName> and <persName>Fielding</persName> off on some lark this afternoon to see a <orgName>Japanese</orgName> play. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and I went to tea with <persName>Miss Luling</persName> - after seeing the <orgName>Temple Flower Show.</orgName> Nettie's last day.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-05-24">
        <dateline>
          Thursday, <date when="1900-05-24">May 24</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p><persName>Nettie</persName> off early this <orgName>A.M.</orgName> Rain all day - very busy. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and I had an hour this afternoon at the <placeName>National Gallery</placeName> - and I spent <orgName>Page 140</orgName> almost the whole morning at the <orgName>Flower Show</orgName> - where I met Sir Wm. <persName>Farrer</persName> in his wheel chair with his two girls - what a show it was! and what colour! fruit, flower, foliage - and how admirably shown! We are off tomorrow ourselves! how glad I am to go! all confusion tonight with last things - still raining. <persName>S.S. Kaiser Freidrich.</persName></p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-05-31">
        <dateline>
          Thursday, <date when="1900-05-31">May 31st</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>Just a week ago since I made my last entry - a weary week - with long days and nights - and many hours to each one of the them! It was a cold and misty morning last Thursday when after an early breakfast <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and I drove in a hanson for <placeName>Waterloo</placeName> station. <persName ref="#Burgnoyne_Amelie">Amelie</persName> and <persName>Jones</persName> having preceeded us with luggage. <placeName>London</placeName> had not wakened up - though on our way down the <persName>Mall,</persName> under the trees, we met a nice <orgName>English</orgName> girl, followed by her groom, out for a morning drive. Quite a distance on the tender from <name>Southampton</name> to the steamer - and almost no passengers. The ship looked enormous as we came up to her. She is very large - and well arranged - her furniture and fittings in heavy <orgName>German</orgName> taste. I have a spacious, pleasant cabin, to which I feel not the slightest attachment, and am happy to think this is the last night I shall pass in it. The weather has been windy and wet - no incentive to be on deck - I have spent every day in my room until yesterday, I turned out for lunch and dinner - and again today. On deck a few moments this A.M. and then came in and wandered about, trying to decide which was the least loathly place to sit. Some old acquaintances of <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore's</persName> from <placeName>Milwaukee</placeName> are at our table - a brother of <persName>Mrs. Hagerman</persName> and his wife, daughter and father-in-law. We hoped to be in tomorrow morning, but it will not be possible - even had not the fog descended on us at noon as it did - and the fog horn is going constantly. It is a dismal sound - and I am putting off going to bed as late as I can. I count the days spent at sea as so much out of life! I hardly know how I would have dragged through these days without a book of <orgName>Rider</orgName> <persName>Haggards, "A Norfolk Farmer"</persName> - being a practical relation of years farming operations on his own farms - and things pertaining to the life of a country gentleman - a thoughtful, charming book - I have enjoyed every page. A great contrast to his novels, for which I do not care. I love everything connected with land, its interests and cultivation.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-06-03">
        <dateline>
          Newport -Whit. Sunday. <date when="1900-06-03">June 3d, 1900</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>Once more at home, thankful and well! We got to our dock on Friday the 1st by 2 o'clock. It was a sickeningly hot day - with an atmosphere so thick, that the fog whistle constantly sounded, though it was not a fog. <persName>Mary Newberry</persName> met us - and she and I went at once to the <persName>Holland,</persName> leaving <persName ref="#Burgnoyne_Amelie">Amelie</persName> and <persName>Jones</persName> with <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and the luggage and the Custom officers. There was no trouble or delay. We found <placeName>Fifth Avenue</placeName> given up to the <orgName>Policemen's Parade</orgName> - and I found great difficulty in going about - the carriage being constantly blocked on <placeName>6th Avenue</placeName> or <placeName>Madison Avenue</placeName> by the unusual traffic thrown upon them. The luggage did not get up in time for dinner, so we dined in our sitting room, in Page 142 our winter clothes! with <persName>John Froster</persName> and <persName>Mary M.</persName> and came here by the one o'clock train on Saturday. The country looked so charming - its peculiar <placeName>New England</placeName> features such a contrast to what we had just seen in <placeName>Old England.</placeName> There are so many quiet little farm houses, at the end of the estuaries putting in from the sea, standing with dignity under the shade of the great elms, which always attract me - and the homely orchards - the meadows - the trees - and as one gets into <placeName>Rhode Island,</placeName> the neighborhood of the sea, the great stretches of low birch, oak and other trees - with masses of rhododendrons and <orgName>Kalinias</orgName> in bloom. Our home coming was rather saddened by finding that the precious <persName>Toby</persName> had been taken 3 days before with a severe attack of rheumatism, and the Vet. had physicked him so mercilessly that he could only stir a feeble tail in recognition. I sent at once for Dr. <persName>Stanton,</persName> who put him on a course of rhus which even now seems to have helped him. The great excitement on getting home was to see the garden. The bills of labor and material had been so enormous that we were anxious to see how they were justified by results - and I don't think <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> or I had dared communicate our fears to each other. It was so late last night when we got here, that we could see nothing - and this morning at 5 o'clock, being awakened by <persName>Toby,</persName> I slipped into my wrapper, and unlocking my door quietly, made the tour of the upper rooms to see it all - I could see enough to allay all my fears. How delicious the first dainty breakfast was, in the beautiful room - how glad everyone was to see us, how perfect and orderly the house was! as soon as we could we went out for a tour of inspection - and <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> all prepared to come heavily <orgName>Page 143</orgName> (double) down on <persName>Brunton,</persName> was so enchanted that he could only pour forth congratulations and praise. The meadow has been in part transformed - I have a forest almost! everything judiciously associated - and I could only in the deepest depth of my heart, wish one or two things changed. It is a happy, bright thought all the time and I grudge the time I must give to other things. The weather is dark, cold and dull - a great deal of humidity in the air, and none in the earth - which is desperately in need of rain. I am wearing winter clothes - and we have fries in the library, hall, and dining room. Delicious to smell the fragrance of the wood smoke once more.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-06-05">
        <dateline>
          Tuesday, <date when="1900-06-05">June 5th</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>Still cool - with fog. Thermometer went down to 45 last night.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-06-07">
        <dateline>
          Thursday, <date when="1900-06-07">June 7</date>.
        </dateline>
          <p>A lovely, bright day, which I have literally spend out of doors. Drove in to town yesterday afternoon - and saw Mrs. <persName>Norman</persName> and <persName>Mabel.</persName> <persName>Margaret La Farge</persName> came to tea - and this afternoon Mrs. <placeName>Huntingdon</placeName> - and walked about the place afterwards. Very damp, after 5 o'clock. The pictures came down from <placeName>Worcester</placeName> night before last, and <persName>Gus</persName> has them now all again in place. <persName>Mrs. Busk</persName> and <persName>Daisy</persName> to tea.</p> 
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-07-01">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1900-07-01">July 1st</date>. Sunday.
        </dateline>
          <p>The season is truly extraordinary - cold, windy, and no rain. The local showers have hardly touched us. I fear it will go hard with <persName>Page</persName> 144 us in the garden. Our strawberries are still lasting - the first picking on June 12, - magnificent. On the 24th we had our first peas. <persName>Mrs. Tytus</persName> and <persName>Miss Kulen</persName> arrived on the 8th and stayed 8 days. Mr. <persName>Dean</persName> here for 2 days. <persName ref="Whaling_Bessie">Bessie Whaling</persName> arrived on the 15th June.</p>
        </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1900-07-10">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1900-07-10">July 10</date>, Tuesday.
        </dateline>
          <p>We have had some warm weather lately - and a touch of several storms - very severe ones - which passed us by going up the bay. Still the drought holds - and all hands are busy at the hose - I fear for our new planting. The "4th" was a delicious day, warm and rather quiet, with a drynorth air coming from miles and miles of waste land of pines and birches and bayberry and other sweet things. It is <orgName>Newport's</orgName> most delicious feature - and I always feel like living out of doors while it lasts. <persName ref="#Whaling_Bessie">Bessie</persName> and I dined with <persName ref="#Parsons_Lellie">Lellie Parsons</persName> on Friday - a big, formal, dreary banquet. <persName ref="#Agassig_Mr">Mr.Agassig</persName> and <persName ref="#Wolcott_Dr">Dr. Wolcott</persName> of <placeName ref="#Boston">Boston</placeName> dined here Sunday evening. I am busy these days at the dentists - and begrudge the time I have to spend driving in an out. 14 14</p>
      </div>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
