<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>Diary of Mrs. Emma B. Andrews. Volume 3 1894-1895</title> <!-- replace with correct volume -->
        <author>
          <persName ref="#Andrews_Emma_B">Emma B. Andrews</persName>
        </author>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Originally prepared by</resp>
          <persName ref="#SLK">Sarah L. Ketchley</persName>
        </respStmt>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>TEIPublisher development</resp>
          <persName ref="#EF">Emma Fritzberg</persName>
        </respStmt>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>Historical Markup Tool development</resp>
          <persName ref="#AH">Audrey Holmes</persName>
        </respStmt>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>transcription</resp>
          <persName>name name</persName> <!-- replace with correct names -->
        </respStmt>
        <respStmt>
          <resp>proofreading and tagging</resp>
          <persName ref="#SK">Sarah Ketchley</persName>
          <persName ref="#IS">Isabelle Schelegel</persName>
          <persName ref="#IW">Izzy Wiebe</persName> 
          <persName ref="#BL">Benjamin Lewis</persName>
          <persName ref="#SB">Selma El-Badawi</persName>
        </respStmt>
         <respStmt>
                    <resp>biographical research and writing</resp>
                    <persName ref="#SK">Sarah Ketchley</persName>
                    <persName ref="#JJ">Jasmine Jones</persName>
                    <persName ref="#JC">Jasmine Choi</persName>
                    <persName ref="#SR">Samuel Roller</persName>
                    <persName ref="#AAD">Avery Dahl</persName>
                    <persName ref="#AD">Avneet Dhaliwal</persName>
                    <persName ref="#IH">Iona Hillman</persName>
                    <persName ref="#LK">Lexi Kinzer</persName>
                    <persName ref="#PH">Priya Hariharan</persName>
                </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>
          <orgName ref="#EBA_Diary_Project">Emma B. Andrews Diary Project</orgName>
        </publisher>
        <address>
          <addrLine>University of Washington, Seattle, WA</addrLine>
        </address>
        <availability>
          <licence target="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/">This work is
            licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International
            License.</licence>
        </availability>
        <date>08-2020</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <p><orgName ref="#American_Philosophical_Society">American Philosophical
          Society</orgName>,<placeName ref="#Philadelphia">Philadelphia</placeName></p>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>Established in 2010, the goals of the <orgName ref="#EBA_Diary_Project">Emma B.
          Andrews Diary Project</orgName> include the transcription and digitization of a
          wide range of primary historical material from the 'Golden Age' of Egyptian
          archaeology at the end of the 19th and beginning of the 20th centuries. A founding
          partner of <orgName ref="#Newbook_Digital_Texts">Newbook Digital Texts</orgName>
          (www.newbookdigitaltexts.org), the <orgName ref="#EBA_Diary_Project">EBA Diary
            Project</orgName> offers undergraduate and graduate digital humanities education
          and internships at the <orgName ref="#University_of_Washington">University of
            Washington</orgName>.
          <persName ref="#Andrews_Emma_B">Emma B. Andrews</persName> is best remembered for her
          association with the millionaire lawyer turned archaeologist/art and antiquities
          collector, <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore M. Davis</persName>. Traveling
          to <placeName ref="#Egypt">Egypt</placeName> with him between 1889 and 1913, she kept
          detailed journals of these voyages along the <placeName ref="#Nile">Nile</placeName>,
          including his important yet under-reported excavations of over 20 significant tombs
          in the <placeName ref="#Bībān al-Mulūk">Valley of the Kings</placeName>.
          <persName ref="#Andrews_Emma_B">Emma</persName> provides a vital commentary on the
          archaeology and pioneering Egyptologists of the time, painting a revealing picture of
          the lives of the colonial gentry and the cultural and scientific literati in at the
          dawn of the twentieth century. Analysis of the content of her diaries, along with a
          broad range of additional primary source material, will afford scholars information
          about important historical resources for the first time.</p>
      </projectDesc>
      <editorialDecl>
        <correction>
          <p>Obvious misspellings (eg place names and people's names) which are misreadings of original handwritten diary are corrected
            with choice, sic and corr.</p>
        </correction>
        <normalization>
          <p>Original spelling and typography is otherwise retained.</p>
        </normalization>
      </editorialDecl>
    </encodingDesc>
    <revisionDesc> <!-- update this with major revision list-->
      <list>
        <item>
          <date when="2021-05-08">8 May 2021</date> Last checked by SLK. Updated header, fixed
          placeName and name tags.</item>
      </list>
    </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
    <text>
      <body>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1896-11-17" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <name type="boat" ref="#SS_Gens">S.S. Gens.</name> <date when="1896-11-17">Nov. 17, 1896</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p><pb n="73"/>We sailed at 10 o'clock on Saturday the 14th - <persName ref="#Convers_Mr">Mr. Convers</persName>, <persName ref="#Luling_Mr">Mr. Luling</persName> and <persName ref="#Jevons_Mr">Mr. Jevons</persName> were down to see us off. A cold bright morning - and the cold lasted until yesterday - everyone congealed - but we are now in warmer waters - and constant sunshine - I have a large bright room - at a table in which I am writing. The sun looks into my port by day, and the moon by night -for we have fortunately fallen upon the second quarter of the moon. The last thing I do, after having turned out the light at night, is to climb up on the sofa, and take a look at the night, and the wide waste: of blue black water, in which our ship makes its great furrow of dashing white foam - what a beautiful immensity it is, and a grand picture to carry into the oblivion of the night.</p>
          <p>There are comparatively few passangers - and I have never known such pleasant ones. The <persName ref="#Hamilton_Fisks_Group">Hamilton Fisks</persName> of <placeName ref="#New_York">New York</placeName> - <persName ref="#Doty_Dr">Dr. Doty</persName>, the Health Officer of the <placeName ref="#New_York_Port">N. Y. Port</placeName>, <persName ref="#Ward_Howe_Elliot">Mrs. Ward Howe Elliot,</persName> the daughter of <persName ref="#Ward_Howe_Julia">Mrs. Julia Ward Howe</persName> - and a <persName ref="#Pratt_Edward">Mr. Pratt</persName> - now American Consul General at <placeName ref="#Singapore">Singapore,</placeName> and for five years our Minister to <placeName ref="#Persia">Persia</placeName> - a really cultivated man. We all have tea together in the afternoon, and make very merry - and we have <persName ref="#Bend_Beatrice">Mrs. Bend</persName> of <placeName ref="#New_York">New York</placeName> and her two daughters at our table. I asked <persName ref="#Pratt_Edward">Mr. Pratt</persName> how long <persName ref="#Benjamin_Samuel">Benjamin,</persName> former Minister to <placeName ref="#Persia">Persia,</placeName> had lived in that country, and he said 3 years. I said that was rather a short time acquaintance with a country about which to write an exhaustive work. He tole me <persName ref="#Benjamin_Samuel">Benjamin</persName> had given great offence to the Shela, and others in his book - and that he had seen absolutely nothing of parts of <placeName ref="#Persia">Persia</placeName> about which he writes.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1896-11-27" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1896-11-27">Nov. 27</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p><pb n="74"/> We will reach <placeName ref="#Genoa">Genoa</placeName> in a few hours, and I will gladly say au revoir to the sea for 3 or 4 days. It is very cold this morning, but clear. Until we reached <placeName ref="#Gibraltar">Gibraltar</placeName> our beautiful balmy weather lasted. We passed the <placeName ref="#Azores">Azoros</placeName> on the 20th - running very close to the large island of <placeName ref="#Sao_Miguel">San Miguel</placeName> - very picturesque with its background of mountains, and the steep slopes, some of them quite cultivated to the top - its pleasant looking houses and villages - and the miles of low grass houses, where immense quantities of pineapples are cultivated. On Monday morning the 23d we reached <placeName ref="#Gibraltar">Gibraltar,</placeName> and went ashore, despite of some threatening clouds. We took <persName ref="#Bend_Beatrice">Beatrice Bend</persName> in our carriage and went as far as <placeName ref="#Europa_Point">Europa Point,</placeName> but before we again reached the town, rain began to fall, and there was nothing to do but stop at the wretched <name type="hotel" ref="#Hotel_Royal">Hotel Royal,</name> and wait until it was time to go back to the steamer - and there we waited staring out on the same little square where I spent so many hours doing the same thing two years ago. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> went out and bought 3 umbrellas - a pair of overshoes for me, and 3 yards of macintosh cloth for us to sit upon on the wet, unprotected decks of the little tender. From that time until last night the gale has raged - and 3 miserable nights have I spent and 2 days in my forward cabin, tossed up and down. Yesterday morning early the 26, we dropped our anchor in the bay of <placeName ref="#Naples">Naples</placeName> - and in spite of some rain and a high wind, I went ashore with the rest, and spent a pleasant day. The two Bend girls we took immediately to the <name type="hotel" ref="#Grand_Hotel">Grand Hotel,</name> and found pleasant rooms for them, and by the time <persName ref="#Bend_Beatrice">Mrs. Bend</persName> arrived from the <pb n="75"/> <name type="historical" ref="#Custom_House">Custom House,</name> we had ordered luncheon, and made a short visit to the Aquarium. How good that lunch was, and how good the stable land was! Then we said goodbye to our friends, and started back to the steamer - stopping a few moments at <name type="historical" ref="#Squadriblis">Squadriblis</name> to buy some shell things. We have had a quiet night, and are running smoothly this morning.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1896-12-06" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <name type="boat" ref="#SS_Friedrich_der_Grosse">S.S. Freiderick der Grosser</name>. near <placeName ref="#Port_Said">Port Said</placeName>. <date when="1896-12-06">Dec. 6</date>
          </dateline>
          <p>I am so thankful that this long voyage has almost come to an end - and that we will arrive at <placeName ref="#Port_Said">Port Said</placeName> early tomorrow morning - we reached <placeName ref="#Genoa">Genoa</placeName> on the 27 Nov. just too late to catch the only train to <placeName ref="#Florence">Florence</placeName> at noon - and after a slight delay at the <name type="historical" ref="#Custom_House">Custom House</name>, made a long journey through the streets of the town to the <name type="hotel" ref="#Hotel_du_Pare">"Hotel du Pare"</name> a rather attractive looking ancient Villa standing in large grounds with trees, which might be cheerful on a summers day, but on that chill afternoon, dripping with rain, was truly disconsolate. The palatial rooms and halls, with their tiny fires and enormous windows shaking and rattling in the gale, made us thankful we were only going to stop for the night. The next day we were off for <placeName ref="#Florence">Florence</placeName> at 12 o'clock - which we reached at 7 P.M. - a weary ride - slow and rough, through never ending tunnels. The girls and <persName ref="#Hassan">Hassan</persName> were waiting for us, and went with us to the <name type="#hotel" ref="#Hotel_Royal_Grande_Bretagne">Grande Bretagne</name>, where we were installed in our old appartment. <placeName ref="#Florence">Florence</placeName> the next day was cold, but bright. I spent the Sunday morning with <persName ref="#Parsons_Mary">Mary</persName> shopping - I found her chattering Italian like a native. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> went to the <name type="historical" ref="#Uffizi_Gallery">Uffizzi</name> - <pb n="76"/> <persName ref="#Clarence">Clarence</persName> and <persName ref="#Jones_Daniel">Jones</persName> to do as much of the town as they could. <persName ref="#Buttles_Lizzie">Lizzie</persName> and both girls came to breakfast, and the girls stopped to lunch - after which a drive to <placeName ref="#Fiesole">Fiesole</placeName>, and the rest of the time with <persName ref="#Buttles_Lizzie">Lizzie</persName> in their pretty little appartment, 2 Via Venezia, and then all came home with us to dinner. <persName ref="#Berenson_Bernard">Berenson</persName> also came to dinner, looking very well. The next day we were off to <placeName ref="#Genoa">Genoa</placeName> again, with <persName ref="#Parsons_Mary">Mary</persName> along and went for the night to the <name type="hotel" ref="#Hotel_Isotta">"Hotel Isotta",</name> much more comfortable than the other. At 2 o'clock the next day we went out to the Frederick the Great - and after enormous trouble and anxiety, through the insufficiency and want of order of the North German Lloyd Co. we succeeded at last in getting all our 30 pieces of luggage out of the <name type="historical" ref="#Custom_House">Custom House</name> and aboard the steamer - and sailed about 5 o'clock the next morning for <placeName ref="#Naples">Naples.</placeName> We found the steamer very pleasant, but rather durious in her arrangement. Large as she is she only carries 120 first class passengers - but she carries enormous freight to <placeName ref="#Australia">Australia</placeName> - her decks are charming - the service and the food very poor. Reached <placeName ref="#Naples">Naples</placeName> the next morning - rain pouring - everyone else went ashore - I stayed at home - <persName ref="#Peabody_Dr">Dr. Peabody</persName> and family, <persName ref="#Pratt_Edward">Mr. Pratt</persName> and <persName ref="#Doty_Dr">Dr. Doty</persName> arrived in the afternoon. So did the <name type="boat" ref="#Kaiser_Wilhelm_II">Kaiser Wilhelm,</name> just from <placeName ref="#New_York">New York,</placeName> a week later than ourselves. We were at last off on the home stretch for <placeName ref="#Egypt">Egypt</placeName> at 6 P.M. Since then the weather has been bad, and heavy seas until today - which is lovely. In my room during most of the voyage from <placeName ref="#Genoa">Genoa.</placeName></p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1896-12-09" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <name type="hotel" ref="#">Shepheards Hotel</name>. <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName>. <date when="1896-12-09">Dec. 9 - 96</date>
          </dateline>
          <p><pb n="77"/> We arrived day before yesterday the 7th at 6 P.M. and took possession of our pleasant old appartment facing the street no. 120 et suite. On the evening of the 6th we passed the <name type="historical" ref="#Damietta_Lighthouse">Damietta</name> light, and the ship steamed slowly and almost imperceptibly along until she dropped anchor at <placeName ref="#Port_Said">Port Said</placeName> about 2 o'clock A.M. There was but little sleep to be had - what with the coaling, the babbling and shrieking outside, and the stir inside - and as the night was warm, and all the doors and ports closed because of the coaling, sleep was far from every one. At 6 o'clock <persName ref="#Burgnoyne_Amelie">Amilie</persName> came to call me, and I was glad to give up the struggle and get up. We had little trouble at the <name type="historical" ref="#Custom_House">Custom House,</name> and were soon in a clean and very comfortable railway carriage for <placeName ref="#Ismailia">Ismailia,</placeName> where we got an excellent lunch at the new hotel established lately by <persName ref="#Shepheards_Group">Shepheards,</persName> and waited for the <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> train. We find <name type="hotel" ref="#Shepheards_Hotel">Shepheards</name> practically empty - and this season is to be a bad one for <placeName ref="#Egypt">Egypt</placeName> I fear. The next morning we had a grand disappointment in finding that our boat was a month behind time - painters and carpenters still at work - the boom not raised, and general helplessness. The English foreman of <persName ref="#Thubron_Ernest">Thubron</persName> is quite ineffectual - and <persName ref="#Thubron_Ernest">Thubron</persName> has shown gross negligence and carelessness. Instead of the boat ready, and in sailing order for the 1st of Dec. as the contract calls for - <persName ref="#Thubron_Ernest">Thubron</persName> has evidently given his whole attention to building gunboats up the river. He has been at <placeName ref="#Dongola">Dongola</placeName> for 3 months - and has allowed the <name type="boat" ref="#Beduin">Beduin</name> to care for herself. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> with admirable patience made <pb n="78"/> himself master of facts through the dire confusion of falsehoods and incompetency, and then he went for <persName ref="#Thubron_Ernest">Thubron</persName> and his foreman, with such well directed effort and so much energetic talking, that the foreman is scared out of his life, and the workmen are jumping about like monkeys. I am busy all the time now with an hundred practical details.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1896-12-13" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1896-12-13">Sunday, Dec. 13</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p><persName ref="#Parsons_Mary">Mary</persName> and <persName ref="#Clarence">Clarence</persName> have gone off in the carriage with <persName ref="#Salah_Mohammed">Salah</persName> to see the Tombs of the <name type="historical" ref="#Tombs_of_the_Mameluks">Mameluks</name> and the <name type="historical" ref="#Tombs_of_the_Khalifs">Khalifs</name> - <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore,</persName> <persName ref="#Doty_Dr">Dr. Doty</persName> and <persName ref="#Peabody_Dr">Dr. Peabody</persName> have gone on donkeys to see the dahabeah. We go every day to the boat to watch and direct its progress - and we hope to be able to get off by the 1st of January. The great trouble now is that the furniture was not shipped from <placeName ref="#England">England</placeName> until the 6th of Dec.! We have engaged our old cook <persName ref="#Ibrahim_Hanna">Hanna</persName> - poor <persName ref="#Selim">Selim</persName> having died here not more than a month ago - <persName ref="#Ibrahim_Hanna">Hanna</persName> speaks no French or English, but as we have engaged a very promising young Nubian as waiter whom <persName ref="#Salah_Mohammed">Salah</persName> knows very well, and who has lived for years in <placeName ref="#England">England,</placeName> we can get on very well. <persName ref="#Ibrahim_Hanna">Ibrahim</persName> too is engaged as 2d man and laundress - and my <!--Is this the same person as Ibrahim Hanna?--><persName ref="#Ibrahim_Mohammed">Mohammed Ibrahim</persName> is going in no capacity that I can think of, except to learn more English, and if he can, to wait and do domestic work. It is impossible now to tell how much English he knows, as he is so shy and frightened when he trys to speak </p>
          <p><persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> gave a dinner last night, and had <persName ref="#Sandwith_Dr">Dr. Sandwith</persName> and <persName ref="#Peabody_Dr">Peabody</persName> and <persName ref="#Doty_Dr">Doty</persName>. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and I had a delicious drive yesterday in the afternoon to the <name type="historical" ref="#Ghezireh_Palace">Ghezireh Palace,</name> and walked about the shady avenues <pb n="79"/> and among the flowers - stopping to return the visit of <persName ref="#Sandwith_Dr">Dr. Sandwith</persName> and <persName ref="#Sandwith_Mrs">Mrs. Sandwith</persName> on our way home.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1896-12-27" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <name type="hotel" ref="#Ghizereh_Palace_Hotel">Ghesireh Palace Hotel</name>. <date when="1896-12-27">Dec. 27</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>We left <name type="hotel" ref="#Shepheards_Hotel">Shepheards</name> this morning and came over here, to escape the smells and noise of <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> and are so enchanted with the delicious air and space - our rooms are really palatial - and look out on the beautiful garden - and the sitting room opens on a balcony, which the present hot weather makes quite delightful. The sun was so hot this afternoon that the awning was necessary. The house is practically empty - and it is so enormous, that only in the evening after dinner, when everyone congregated in the big hall, that there seems to be anyone here. We are so busy, trying to help along the boat - and there are so many vexatious delays, that our patience is fairly exhausted. I am amazed at <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore's</persName> apparent patience with <persName ref="#Thubron_Ernest">Thubron</persName> and his unprincipled inefficiency. I have never been so long in <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> before - and I think I am tired of it - if not of <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo,</placeName> certainly of the life of hotels - and the dreary people. It is nice to see the interest and enjoyment of <persName ref="#Clarence">Clarence</persName> and <persName ref="#Parsons_Mary">Mary</persName> in everything. I am well - and quite free from cold for the first time in Cairo.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-01-03" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            Second Sunday after Christmas. <date when="1897-01-03">Jan. 3</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>Still waiting impatiently to get off - some progress has been made during the past week to be sure. The obscure and troublesome - <pb n="80"/> Jan. 9th - what I intended saying when I began that last sentence, quite a week ago, I have now not the faintest idea. Each day since has been so busy, with tiresome occupations, driving down to the dahabeah through that squalid <placeName ref="#Boulak_Ramleh">Boulak-Ramleh</placeName> quarter - until I am fairly sick with the sight of so much misery that no one can relieve. The long delayed furniture came yesterday - and with much trepidation I saw it unpacked, and if my worst fears were not realized, there were enough disappointments to make it almost unbearable. Chairs too large for the rooms - everything a little too big, or a little too small - the side board entirely forgotten - and I had to get into the carriage with <persName ref="#Thubron_Ernest">Thubron,</persName> and drive to 3 different furniture places before I found a little second hand buffet that freshened and polished, will answer for this winter - then I bought finger bowls, caraffes - liqeur glasses - candlesticks - match boxes - soap dishes etc. etc. etc. Still with all these drawbacks the <name type="boat" ref="#Beduin">Beduin</name> is so comfortable and so convenient and pretty, that we are thoroughly happy that on Monday morning we will take possession of her, and at last start up the river. We have had real <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> winter weather for 10 days - high winds, clouds, occasional sharp rains. These things would not be unbearable - were it not for the discomfort of indoors in such weather. We would never think it possible at home to sit in a room where the thermometer stood at 62&#176; only. But my thermometer has been just there for several days. There is in each of our big rooms, a tiny, ornamented accidental fireplace, between two of the big windows - these are strictly ornamental, and are almost hidden by the magnificent satin draperies of the windows. But two or <pb n="81"/> three days ago when the wind was high and cold, I asked the waiter if we could have a fire, and it was made, much to the cost of our comfort, for the only draught was out into the room - and if the fuel had been anything but charcoal, the consequences might have been disastrous - as it was, all the wooden mantle was scorched, and the windows had to be opened to clear the room. We learned afterwards that there were no openings at the top to these chimneys - so that the fireplaces were purely pieces of ornamental furniture.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-01-11" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            Dahabeah "<name type="boat" ref="#Beduin">Beduin</name>". <date when="1897-01-11">Monday, Jan. 11. 1897</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>We are actually in possession - have started - and made <measure type="distance">15 miles</measure> to <placeName ref="#Al_Badrashayn">Bedrasheen,</placeName> where we are now lying. <persName ref="#Parsons_Mary">Mary</persName> and I flew about this morning doing last things - we lunched at the <name type="historical" ref="#Ghezireh Palace">Gesireh,</name> but went down before lunch on the terrace, to see the <name type="boat" ref="#Beduin">Beduin,</name> under convoy of the tug, go by, on her way to above the bridge, which opens at one o'clock. Just as we reached the terrace, I saw away down the river, the tug pulling out, and our "<name type="boat" ref="#Beduin">Beduin</name>" stately, tall, and shapely in her tow. Several people gathered on the terrace to see her go by - and I heard her pronounced the "handsomest craft on the river". Immediately after lunch, when poor <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> had finished all his backsheeshs, we drove above the bridge, and went aboard. There was hurry and scrambling for 15 minutes, as our trunks were literally turned upside down, and sent back empty to the hotel to be kept for us, until we came down. In the midst of it, <!--Proper convention?--><persName ref="#Taylor_Mrs">Mrs.</persName> and <persName ref="#Taylor_Miss">Miss Taylor</persName> arrived for a parting visit. Then there was the "debbil to pay" as dear old <persName ref="#Salah_Mohammed">Salah</persName> would say, as <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> <pb n="82"/> discovered that the men on the tug did not know that they were to go further than above the bridge, and were aghast at the idea of taking us as far as <placeName ref="#Asyut">Assiut;</placeName> they had no food - no blankets - no preparations, but go they had to, and with many a heartfelt blessing from us all to the impossible <persName ref="#Thubron_Ernest">Thubron,</persName> we started at 3:40 this P.M. I have been working like a slave all the afternoon, and am too tired to see or think, but we are happy, if not yet in order.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-01-12" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-01-12">Jan. 12</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>We have made about <measure type="distance">18 miles</measure> - and are somewhere between <placeName ref="#Badrashin">Bedreschein</placeName> and <placeName ref="#Al_Wasta">Wasta.</placeName> The tug proves a worthless thing. She can make about <measure type="distance">2 miles</measure> with us, an hour, without any assistance from us - but if we have a wind that at all fills our sails, we sail right on to her and she has to cast off. Various "d&#233;sagr&#233;mens" have developed themselves, the most important of which is old <persName ref="#Henna">Henna,</persName> our cook, who was with us for 2 winters on the <name type="boat" ref="#Herodotus_Boat">Herodotus</name> has taken fright at the range in his kitchen, and thinks he can do nothing with it, although he makes much better bread with it, than I have ever known him do before. And, we greatly need the forgotten sideboard - and many rather necessary things have been overlooked. However, we are so pretty and convenient, that we are quite ashamed of ourselves in complaining of anything. My room is entirely charming - and so are all the bedrooms in their pretty chintzs and simple fittings - and the saloon would be a charming interior anywhere - with its Morris green brocades and art fabrics. Then the big upper deck is entirely perfection, with its pretty rugs, its big brown <pb n="83"/> wicker hooded chairs and easy chairs, with their bright yellow and black cushions and pillows in bandana stuffs. But best of all, the <name type="boat" ref="#Beduin">Beduin</name> has proved a rattling good sailor, and there can be no happier man on earth than our <persName ref="#Fuli_Rais">Rais Fuli,</persName> who for the first time in his life is 1st Captain. He has been twice with us as 2d Captain and we have always said he should be captain of our dahabeah when it was built. He is such a fine specimen of a calm, serene <orgName ref="#Mohammedan">Mohammedan,</orgName> and has a gentle personal dignity I have never seen equalled. He is a <orgName ref="#Nubian">Nubian</orgName>, knows the river thoroughly, and we could trust him with everything we have. The boat will now be his house summer as well as winter - and he will get &#65505;3. a month and during the summer feed himself - I think I am as pleased as he is. He has chosen an admirable crew - I never saw so good a one on the <placeName ref="#Nile">Nile</placeName> - and in their brown cardigans with "<name type="boat" ref="#Beduin">Beduin</name>" in blue letters across the breast, they look very well.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-01-13" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-01-13">Jan. 13</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>Made <measure type="distance">23 miles</measure> - are now lying near <placeName ref="#Al_Wasta">Wasta</placeName> - day calm, with some head wind - heavy storm of wind during the night - very busy settling.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-01-14" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-01-14">Jan. 14</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>Beautiful warm weather - though my self-registering barometer on my little verandah went down to 40&#176; during the night. Passed <placeName ref="#Benisoef">Benisoef</placeName> about noon - ran until 8 o'clock this evening, - made <measure type="distance">23 miles</measure> today.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-01-15" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-01-15">Jan. 15</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p><pb n="84"/> A long run today - starting at 6 A.M. and bringing up at 7 o'clock P.M. within <measure type="distance">3 miles</measure> of <!--Couldn't figure out--><placeName>Golasseheh</placeName> - busy all day - made <measure type="distance">57 miles</measure>.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-01-16" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-01-16">Jan. 16</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>I wakened before it was light this morning and heard the rippling of the water that showed how fast we were slipping along - but, a little after 7 o'clock we ran into a dense fog - I never saw such a sight before on the <placeName ref="#Nile">Nile</placeName> - and we pulled up awhile until the hot sun had dissipated it. We passed <placeName ref="#Al_Minya">Minieh</placeName> at 11 o'clock - and <name type="historical" ref="#Beni_Hasan">Beni Hassan</name> this afternoon and are now lying at <!--Not rhoda island but unsure--><placeName>Rhodah</placeName> having made <measure type="distance">51 miles</measure>. Some high wind today from the right quarter - and we have had to cast the tug off, but the wind has been fitful. Have passed such lovely palm fringed shores. This morning the usual begging saint from <placeName ref="#Gabal_al_Tayr">Der el-Tayr</placeName>, or Mountain of the Bird, swam out to us - and demanded the usual toll. The boat is now in perfect order - and I am now resting from my labors. Thermometer registered last night 45&#176; and today at 2 o'clock 72&#176;. I had my little stove lighted and brought into my room for the first time this morning.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-01-17" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-01-17">Jan. 17</date> Second Sunday after <name type="event" ref="#Epiphany">Epiphany</name>.
          </dateline>
          <p>We have only made <measure type="distance">20 miles</measure> today. There has been but little wind, and what there was, from the wrong quarter. Something was the matter with the tug, and we had to stop for 3 hours to have her tickered. <pb n="85"/> We are now within <measure type="distance">4 miles</measure> of <placeName ref="#Gebel_Abu_Foda">Gebel Abou Fedah</placeName> - day has been overcast, and a little cool. Thermometer last night 42&#176; - today 72&#176;. A remarkable sunset - really the most wonderful and gorgeous in its beauty I ever saw.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-01-18" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-01-18">Jan. 18</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>A very disappointing day. <persName ref="#Thubron_Ernest">Thubrons</persName> wretched little tug has given out entirely, and been abandoned by us. The Engineer reported early this morning a leak in the boiler - but as that has been the case for several days, it seemed to be no reason that we should not go on in the same slow way. So <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> went aboard the tug - found that the engineer in order to "see in the boiler" as he said, had taken off the cylinder head, and then found a loose nut kicking about somewhere, and said if he moved their lives would be in danger. There was nothing to do but to leave her, which we did, declining to give the man 2 oars as he wished us to do, to paddle back to <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo.</placeName> Day warm and beautiful - sailed for nearly 2 hours in a very light wind and think we have made about 10 miles. On deck until nearly 7 o'clock, watching the radiant moon-rise and the colors on the <placeName ref="#Gebel_Abu_Foda">Gebel Abu-Fedah</placeName> chain.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-01-19" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-01-19">Jan. 19</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>We began tracking a little after seven o'clock this morning - a very little south wind made it hard work for our poor fellows - but in spite of it, we have made <measure type="distance">9 or 10 miles</measure>. The English dahabeah <name type="boat" ref="#Thames">Thames</name> passed us in tow about dark. Our people inquired about our tug, and <pb n="86"/> they answered they had passed her near <placeName ref="#Hag_Kandil">Hager Kandil,</placeName> floating down to <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo.</placeName> A pleasant little walk this A.M. along the banks of the <placeName ref="#Bahr_Yussef">Bar Jusef</placeName> canal - larks singing - wheat to my knees.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-01-20" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-01-20">Jan. 20</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>A trying day as far as getting on - warm, still and a haze that about noon assumed a rather threatening look. Our fellows have tracked and pulled to the anchor - and in this fashion we have been creeping past the <placeName ref="#Gebel_Abu_Foda">Abu Fedah</placeName> cliffs this afternoon. A strong north wind sprang up and helped us along, though the weather was so threatening we did not dare hoist a sail. About 6 o'clock the gale broke upon us - but no rain, and we are safely tied up for the night under the lee of a high bank. The air has cleared and the moon shows faintly from a veil of light clouds.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-01-21" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-01-21">Jan. 21</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>We began sailing at 8 o'clock this morning with a strong north wind - and the <name type="boat" ref="#Beduin">Beduin</name> had her first good opportunity to test her true sailing qualities. She behaved splendidly to the great delight of her Captain and her crew, to say nothing of her owner. She sailed on the wind in so fine a fashion, that the crew were enthusiastic. I found the wind too strong on deck, and went below to the entrance deck, where I stood sometime watching the sailors, who were laughing and cheering apostrophising the wind - then the boat - then shaking hands in congratulation. We careered and made more motion than I have ever felt on the <pb n="87"/> <placeName ref="Nile">Nile</placeName>.- but then we had never sailed like that in such a wind before. In the midst of our triumphal progress in making a difficult bend of the river we came in collision with a working or ferry boat, anchored just at the point. Her boom scraped our sides a little to the great distress of <persName ref="#Fuli_Rais">Rais Fuli</persName> - but no real harm done. In swinging round to avoid as much as possible the shock of the contact, we went aground on the sand - and it was 3 hours before we got off, so that we did not reach <placeName ref="#Asyut">Assiut</placeName> until after 5 P.M. - too late to go into the town - <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore,</persName> <persName ref="#Clarence">Clarence</persName> and <persName ref="#Jones_Daniel">Jones</persName> set off for the P.O. We found waiting for us, the 2 tables from <name type="historical" ref="#Hatoun">Hatoun's</name> for which we had written - and the box of table linen from Paris. The "<name type="boat" ref="#Thames">Thames</name>" lying opposite <placeName ref="#Asyut">Assiut.</placeName> We made about <measure type="distance">30 miles</measure> today.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-01-22" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-01-22">Jan. 22</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p><persName ref="#Parsons_Mary">Mary</persName> and I took <persName ref="#Abdul">Abdul</persName> this morning, and rowed down to the town, and took a carriage there. We made a few little purchases - drove through the bazaars, to the imminent risk it seemed to me of the lives of everybody there - certainly to their great discomfort. These carriages are an innovation. I have never seen them before. In trying to find some flower pots, I came across a young Egyptian in European dress, who got into the carriage with us, and took us to his garden, where he gave us everything that was in bloom, which was not much, as the gardens are at this season practically dead as to flowers. Among other things he gave us 2 remarkable fruits I had never seen before, which he called "Kishta" or cream. It seems it is an imported delicacy <pb n="88"/> from the <placeName ref="#West_Indies">West Indies</placeName> - the Anona squamosa. I got my pots - but we were not allowed to pay for anything - our young host being an amateur gardiner, and as polite and kind as he could be. After many thanks, we left him and came home, it being too late to go to the <!--Unsure what college this is built so early--><name>American College</name> as I had intended, to inquire about the 2 American women doctors who have lately arrived and about whom I wish to know something. There was no wind to get away - in the afternoon the "<name type="boat" ref="#Rameses">Ramesis the Great</name>" from up the river, and the "<name type="boat" ref="#Ramesis_boat">Ramesis</name>" from <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> arrived, and were near us. On the former were the <persName ref="#Case_Group">Case family</persName> from <placeName ref="#Boston">Boston,</placeName> people who were on the <name type="boat" ref="#SS_Gens">Gens,</name> and whom <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> knew. They came aboard to see the <name type="boat" ref="#Beduin">Beduin</name>. An evening of wonderful beauty and color - with a late full moon rising over the placid water. There are splendid trees - palms and scents all about <placeName ref="#Asyut">Assiut.</placeName></p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-01-23" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-01-23">Jan. 23d</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>We are still in sight of <placeName ref="#Asyut">Assiut</placeName> - though we have made <measure type="distance">5 miles</measure> by tracking and pulling to the anchor - the wind when there was any, being dead ahead. <persName ref="#Parsons_Mary">Mary</persName> and I have been spending the afternoon on my pleasant little verandah - reading and working.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-01-24" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-01-24">Jan. 24</date>. Third Sunday after <name type="event" ref="#Epiphany">Epiphany.</name>
          </dateline>
          <p>A day of almost perfect calm - by tracking and polling and using the occasional little puffs of wind, we have made <measure type="distance">15 miles</measure>. Such beautiful opalescent effects all day - the whole world done in pearly, pink, gray heat. <pb n="89"/></p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-01-25" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-01-25">Jan. 25</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>Another day like yesterday - until about 6 o'clock the wind came up, and we got about an hour's sailing - which with the pulling to anchor, tracking and poling, brought us within <measure type="distance">10 miles</measure> of <placeName ref="#Tahta">Tahtah</placeName> - making <measure type="distance">12 miles</measure> altogether. The <name type="historical" ref="#Mena">Mena,</name> flying the English flag - and the <name type="boat" ref="#Elephantine">Elephantine</name> flying the French flag, passed us today - and tonight we are tied up just above the latter. Mercury today - 80&#176;.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-01-26" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-01-26">Jan. 26</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>A more successful day - a good wind this afternoon having brought us <measure type="distance">30 miles</measure> and we are tonight <measure type="distance">5 miles</measure> from <placeName ref="#Sohag">Sohag</placeName> - passed <placeName ref="#Tahta">Tahtah</placeName> at 3 this afternoon - I have been the whole day on deck - very hot, very bright - flies tormenting - but an air, pure, warm and exhilerating, that seems to renew one's life - and such colouring! The great cliffs of <placeName ref="#Gebel_Harêdi">El Haradeh</placeName> have been near us all day - their soft yellow, with heliotrope, and ashes of roses shadows. It seems a bad employment of time to read, or work, or look at anything but this strange country - with its simplicity of feature, the changing life of the banks of the river, - one of the most interesting things is the ferry boats - with their loads of men, women, children, and every description of animal. They are common working sail boats - their sails sometimes so tattered and chiffonn&#233;e that one wonders there can be any propelling power about them. Then they cannot often approach the low shores, and men and women unceremoniously kilt up their clothes and wade to shore, driving their animals before them, or dragging them <pb n="90"/> after. It is no unusual thing to see donkeys lifted bodily into these boats and the other day we were much diverted by seeing 3 camels, scolding their protests, lifted in as it were in sections, - one leg at a time.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-01-27" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-01-27">Jan. 27</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>Started this morning in a strong wind and came to <placeName ref="#Sohag">Sohag</placeName> just as breakfast was ready. Most of the male population of this good looking thriving town were ranged along the bank above us - we had to stop for mail and butter, which took about an hour - and in the mean time we bought some of the bright <placeName ref="#Akhmīm">Akmim</placeName> cloths which a merchant was displaying on the bank. They used to be made in <placeName ref="#Akhmīm">Akmim,</placeName> but I suspect they more often now, come from <placeName ref="#Birmingham">Birmingham, England.</placeName> The river here makes a very bad turn, and north and south seem to change places. We came to grief here once before in the <name type="boat" ref="#Herodotus_Boat">Herodotus</name> - and again this morning, our delay of an hour resulted in staying all day near <placeName ref="#Sohag">Sohag</placeName> - for the strong wind at last found us on shore about <measure type="distance">2 miles</measure> above the town - and opposite <placeName ref="#Akhmīm">Akmim.</placeName> The wind blew a hurricane all day - and all windows and doors had to be closed to keep out the driving fine sand. Towards evening we pulled to the anchor across the river near <placeName ref="#Akhmīm">Akmim</placeName> - and would rather have been above than below the town - as the cholera raged at this place during the summer. Made <measure type="distance">9 miles</measure>.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-01-28" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-01-28">Jan. 28</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>We have made <measure type="distance">35 miles</measure> today - beginning at 6:30 o'clock with a <pb n="91"/> fair wind that grew so strong we had to lie by at <placeName ref="#Balyana_Al">Balliana</placeName> for more than 2 hours.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-01-29" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-01-29">Jan. 29</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>With the exception of Jan. 15, we have made today our best record - <measure type="distance">49 miles</measure> - and are lying tonight near <placeName ref="#Keneh">Keneh.</placeName> Passed the <name type="boat" ref="#Philetus">Philetus</name> - like a dream.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-01-30" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-01-30">Jan. 30</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>A good wind this morning then sailed and tracked until we tied up for the night, having made <measure type="distance">32 miles</measure>.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-01-31" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-01-31">Jan. 31</date>. <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName>. Fourth Sunday after <name type="event" ref="#Epiphany">Epiphany</name>.
          </dateline>
          <p>We made the intervening <measure type="distance">12 miles</measure> between our landing place of last night and <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName> at 4:30 - having had a variable light wind all day - sometimes no wind, when we tracked and poled. About 11 o'clock, we descried the streamer of a dahabieh in the distance - then her sails, and the sails of 3 more - to our great delight as we have been thirsting for a foe worthy of our steel. We crept slowly along towards them, making <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName> the same time as the <name type="boat" ref="#Manhattan">Manhattan,</name> and just behind the <name type="boat" ref="#Zenet-el-Nil">Zenet-el Nil,</name> <name type="boat" ref="#Sesostris">the Sesostris</name> and the <name type="boat" ref="#Ammon_Ra">Ammon Ra</name> - in front of which last we tied up, just below the <!--Double check--><name type="boat" ref="#Castle">Castle.</name> The rest went into the town, and I stayed to enjoy the quiet of our dahabeah and our beautiful deck - and the wonders of the setting sun - and the shadows creeping over the mountains. Heaps of letters and newspapers. <pb n="92"/></p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-02-03" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-02-03">Feb. 3</date>. <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName>.
          </dateline>
          <p>We have had a tremendously high wind for 2 days - yesterday neither <persName ref="#Parsons_Mary">Mary</persName> nor I stirred from the boat. Although protected by the high bank, we were really buffetted about and the waves race high - everything was kept closed - doors, windows, screens and tambooshes - but in spite of all the dust penetrated everywhere - though to a much less degree than in any other boat I have been on. Across the river, the sand obscured the sight of the mountains at times - and I was sorry for the <!--This is a group of people probs but who?--><persName>Cookites,</persName> who were swarming on the sands, starting for their various excursions - for 2 or 3 steamers are in - and of course their passengers cannot wait for more favorable weather. <persName ref="#Parsons_Mary">Mary</persName> and I this morning climbed up the high bank, with the intention of walking back into the country - but our skirts blew over our heads, our hats off our heads - and our eyes were blinded with sand - so that we soon gave up the contest and came home, glad to finish our walk on the sheltered deck. <persName ref="#Salah_Mohammed">Salah</persName> came to see us soon after our arrival, very proud of us, and of our sailing record. He is almost willing to let us beat his <name type="boat" ref="#Zenet-el-Nil">Zenet-el Nil</name> - <persName ref="#Golenischeff_Vladimir">M. Goleinschief's</persName> boat, of which he has charge. Old <persName ref="#Mohassib_Mohammed">Mohammed Mohassib</persName> also came one evening - excessively pleased - and we presented our little gifts to him. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> reports <name type="historical" ref="#Karnak">Karnak</name> in the hands of the Excavation Society - I have not yet seen it. <persName ref="#Baldwin_Mr">Mr. Baldwin</persName> who is on the <name type="boat" ref="#Ammon_Ra">Ammon-Ra,</name> with his wife, and son-in-law, <persName ref="#Grinell_Dr">Dr. Grinell</persName> - was here today. <persName ref="#Baldwin_Mrs">Mrs. Baldwin</persName> is very wretched since she came on the river. They want us to start for <placeName ref="#Aswan">Assouan</placeName> when they do. The Fell party on the <name type="boat" ref="#Zenet-el-Nil">Zenet-el-Fil</name> go back to <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> from here - much to <persName ref="#Salah_Mohammed">Salah's</persName> <pb n="93"/> disgust. This morning we had a visit from <persName ref="#Huhatt_Mr">Rev. Mr. Huhatt</persName> - the English clergyman at <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor,</placeName> and <persName ref="#Coulson_Mr">Mr. Coulson</persName> - they begged us to go to the <name type="hotel" ref="#Luxor_Hotel">Luxor Hotel</name> to a "Cinderella Fancy Dress" Ball for the benefit of the little Hospital here. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> made no promises, but took several tickets. <name type="event" ref="#Ramadan">Ramadan</name> begins today - very early this year.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-02-05" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName>. <date when="1897-02-05">Feb. 5</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>Yesterday afternoon we rode over to <name type="historical" ref="#Medinet_Habu_Temple">Medinet Habout</name> - very warm going - this splendid temple has been much excavated since I saw it last. Today we had our photographs taken by old <persName ref="#Beato_Felice">Beato,</persName> who afterwards came into the boat to see it - and was loud in praises of it. Then we pulled across the river to the gizereh, and went again to <name type="historical" ref="#Medinet_Habu_Temple">Medinet,</name> where we had lunch - and afterwards rode over the burning desert to <placeName ref="#Der_el_Bahari">Der el Bahari</placeName> -leaving <persName ref="#Parsons_Mary">Mary</persName> at <name type="historical" ref="#Medinet_Habu_Temple">Medinet</name> to finish her sketches It was very hot - and I am well tired tonight.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-02-06" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-02-06">Feb. 6</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>We did not much want to leave <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName> this morning - but as <persName ref="#Baldwin_Mrs">Mrs. Baldwin</persName> has religious scruples about starting on Sunday - it was today or next week - and as <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> is anxious to test the sailing qualities of the <name type="boat" ref="#Beduin">Beduin</name> with the <name type="boat" ref="#Ammon_Ra">Ammon-Re,</name> <!--Need to identify later--><persName>Cooks</persName> best and largest boat, we left about noon, twenty minutes or more after they were under way - the wind was very light, but in an hour we had easily overtaken and passed her, to the intense disgust of her men, and the delight of our own. Indeed <persName ref="#Fuli_Rais">Rais Fuli,</persName> with his calm, serene manner repressed the too <pb n="94"/> exultant manner of our men - though it must have been the triumph of his own life. About 6 o'clock after much tracking we pulled up near <placeName ref="#Armant">Erment</placeName> where we now are. I was rather sorry to leave <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName> so soon. We had one very busy day while there - to <name type="historical" ref="#Karnak">Karnak</name> in the morning - the races in the afternoon - <persName ref="#Huhatt_Group">Mr. and Mrs. Huhatt,</persName> <persName ref="#Brown_Group">Mr. and Mrs. Brown</persName> - <persName ref="#Scott_Elliot_Miss">Miss Scott</persName> - and <persName ref="#Norton_Miss">Miss Norton,</persName> to tea at 5 o'clock, and <persName ref="#Bilings_Laura">Laura Billings</persName> and her sister and <persName ref="#Fahnestock_Harris">Mr. Fahenstock</persName> of <placeName ref="#New_York">New York</placeName> to dine in the evening. We had a lovely dinner - and I had some splendid red roses from the <name type="hotel" ref="#Luxor_Hotel">Luxor Hotel.</name> This morning before leaving, I went to the Roman Catholic Italian Convent, to see if it were possible to arrange for <persName ref="#Zenobia">Zenobia,</persName> my little arab child here in whom we have been much interested, to enter the school. I had an interview with the Mother Superior, or rather <persName ref="#Parsons_Mary">Mary</persName> had, for she could speak only Italian. We found the cleanest, quietest place I have ever seen in <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName> - pleasant airy courts, good gardens - and everything so spotlessly clean - <choice><sic>the the</sic><corr>the</corr></choice> Superior herself, clean, fat and sweet as she could be - and strongly reminding us of <name type="object" ref="#The_Abbess">"The Abbess"</name> of <persName ref="#Moroni_Giovanni ">Moroni</persName> - a photograph of which I brought with me from home. <persName ref="#Zenobia">Zenobia,</persName> her father, and her sister, now married - the sweet child of 2 years ago, were at the boat this morning. The sister well clothed, in the usual Arab fashion - veiled as becomes a married woman - and <persName ref="#Zenobia">Zenobia</persName> as pretty and taking, and round and brown, as she used to be. I fear it will be impossible to get her into the Italian school - but I may succeed with the American Mission school when I go down. I would like to lift the child somewhat out of her dirt and poverty. For the first time at <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor,</placeName> I rode in one of the carriages, <pb n="95"/> 2 or 3 of which are supplied by the Hotel - and I felt almost ashamed of myself - one doesn't like to see such unnecessary innovations.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-02-07" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-02-07">Feb. 7.</date> Fifth Sunday after <name type="event" ref="#Epiphany">Epiphany</name>.
          </dateline>
          <p>We stopped a short time at the <placeName ref="#Armant">Erment</placeName> garden to get oranges and lemons this morning, and the <name type="boat" ref="#Ammon_Ra">Ammon-Ra</name> passed ahead - light wind and calms most of the day. We overtook the <name type="boat" ref="#Ammon_Ra">Ammon-Ra</name> and sailed her out of sight. Tied up at <placeName ref="#Esneh">Esneh</placeName> at 7:30 - but the wind coming out strong at 9 o'clock, we pulled up our stakes, and were off and did not stop until one o'clock, when we pulled up at <placeName ref="#El_Kab">Al-Kab</placeName> having made in all <measure type="distance">41 miles</measure>. The nights have now a wonderful beauty. A little new moon appeared 3 nights ago - and Venus is resplendent - and so is Sirius. Yesterday and today warm.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-02-08" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-02-08">Feb. 8th</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>Did not sail early this morning - and as we began tracking about 11, the <name type="boat" ref="#Ammon_Ra">Ammon-Ra</name> appeared in sight. At 2 o'clock we pulled up at <placeName ref="#El_Kab">Al-Kab,</placeName> to see <persName ref="#Somers_Clarke_George">Mr. Somers-Clarke</persName> - who is living there on his dahabeah at work at excavations. He came on the <name type="boat" ref="#Beduin">Beduin</name> for a short visit, and it was quite an hour before we got away, the <name type="boat" ref="#Ammon_Ra">A.R.</name> being by that time more than a <measure type="distance">mile</measure> in advance - before an hour had gone by, we had caught and passed her. Passed <placeName ref="#Idfu">Edfou</placeName> about 5 o'clock - what beautiful wide country - what splendid great domes of sycamore trees! We have come about <measure type="distance">5 miles</measure> above <placeName ref="#Idfu">Edfou</placeName> - and have made <measure type="distance">24 miles</measure> today. The <name type="boat" ref="#Beduin">Beduin</name> seems to sail almost without wind - so smoothly she glided along <pb n="96"/> mile after mile this evening, through the glittering moon lit water, without a ripple, other than she made.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-02-09" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-02-09">Feb. 9</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>I do not know how we have made <measure type="distance">23 miles</measure> today - it has been so calm with so little wind - but at 7 o'clock we passed <placeName ref="#Silsilis">Silsilis,</placeName> and are now lying <measure type="distance">2 miles</measure> above - such a perfect night and so warm. We crept silently along by the dangerous <placeName ref="#Silsilis">Silsileh</placeName> rocks, as it was growing dark, and I never saw a more beautiful scene - the water without a ripple - everything bathed in moonlight - and Venus almost as bright as the moon. <name type="boat" ref="#Ammon_Ra">Ammon-Ra</name> came up later and tied up behind us - and before we had finished dinner <!--Ask about appropiate name for group tags--><persName ref="#Grinell_Group">Dr. and Mrs. Grinell</persName> came over. Busy all day, writing and working, having succeeded in rousing myself out of my long indolence.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-02-10" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-02-10">Feb. 10</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>A hot calm day - a little tracking this A.M. then laid up, with the <name type="boat" ref="#Ammon_Ra">Ammon-Ra</name> just behind us. Thermometer at 86&#176; in the afternoon. At 7 came a good wind and we were off, and sailed until 9 o'clock - <measure type="distance">2 miles</measure> above <placeName ref="#Kawm_Umbū">Kom Ombo</placeName> which was beautiful as we passed it in the moonlight - made <measure type="distance">15 miles</measure>.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-02-11" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-02-11">Feb. 11. Thuesday.</date> <placeName ref="#Aswan">Assouan.</placeName>
          </dateline>
          <p>Arrived at 10:30 this morning - having started at 6 o'clock, with the <name type="boat" ref="#Ammon_Ra">Ammon-Ra</name> and <name type="boat" ref="#Manhattan">Manhattan</name> within sight behind us - and made <measure type="distance">23 miles</measure> in 4 hours - having lost sight of both boats. Passed the <name type="boat" ref="#Gazelle">Gazelle</name> <pb n="97"/> just below <placeName ref="#Aswan">Assouan</placeName> on her way down. Found the "<name type="boat" ref="#Sesostris">Sesestris",</name> "<name type="boat" ref="#Istar">Istar</name>", "<name type="boat" ref="#Philetus">Philetus</name>" and "<name type="boat" ref="#Thames">Thames</name>" here at <name type="boat" ref="#Elephantine">Elephantine</name> - and now that the <name type="boat" ref="#Ammon_Ra">"Ammon-Ra"</name> and "<name type="boat" ref="#Manhattan">Manhattan</name>" have arrived, we make 7 dahabeahs here. The <name type="boat" ref="#Philetus">Philetus</name> started this afternoon for the ascent of the Cataract. Sailed in the felucca towards the Cataract, rowing home. This scenery and these rocks never lose in vividness of expression - and the same beautiful afterglow, that I always associate with <placeName ref="#Aswan">Assouan.</placeName></p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-02-12" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-02-12">Feb. 12</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>Went over to <placeName ref="#Philae">Philae</placeName> by train - <persName ref="#Parsons_Mary">Mary</persName> and I - with all our entourage of servants and sailors and hampers - <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and <persName ref="#Clarence">Clarence</persName> following later on their donkeys, in time for lunch. I found <persName ref="#Yemma">Yemma</persName> waiting for me, having heard through one of our sailors that we would arrive. He is little grown - and is really a very efficient little guide - <persName ref="#Dendowi">Dendowi</persName> too, the unapproachable - who appropriated <persName ref="#Parsons_Mary">Mary</persName> for the day. <persName ref="#Newman_Group">Newmans</persName> not here this year. <persName ref="#Parsons_Mary">Mary</persName> at once selected an eligible spot for painting and set to work - and after wandering about and photographing all the children and <persName ref="#Mohammet">Mohammet</persName> the sailor, I established myself in the long colonnade near <persName ref="#Parsons_Mary">Mary,</persName> out of the sun, and wind - and read - while <persName ref="#Jones_Daniel">Jones</persName> and <!--Which ibrahim is this?--><persName>Ibrahim</persName> got the lunch ready - I made <persName ref="#Yemma">Yemma</persName> and the children sing for me - and when I grew tired of their shouting, I begged them to sing me something soft and low - and they sang squatted on the ground about me, the song I always call the cataract song - as one hears it about here all the time - they sang it softly - in a constantly recurring refrain, putting their heads on their hand to express <pb n="98"/> sleep - I asked <persName ref="#Yemma">Yemma</persName> what the song was, and they all replied that it was the "Dongola" song - and when I asked what it meant, <persName ref="#Yemma">Yemma</persName> replied that it was a slumber song (though of course these are not his words) that the mother was singing the baby to sleep - and was telling him not to be afraid, although there was war and fighting in <placeName ref="#Dongola">Dongola,</placeName> here it was safe and quiet - to sleep and not fear. I thought it very pretty, but I believe one song is used for various words. After lunch we walked about, and climbed to the roof of the temple - where of course the views were delicious - and the birds eye view of the island gave a very good idea of the extent of <persName ref="#Lyons_Capt">Capt. Lyons</persName> work and explorations of last year. <persName ref="#Grinell_Group">Dr. and Mrs. Grinnell</persName> also lunched out there but they were in Pharaoh's Bed. We came home by one of the Cataract boats - bringing <persName ref="#Yemma">Yemma</persName> and <persName ref="#Dendowi">Dendowi</persName> with us to show them the boat - then sent them back. They were such amusing little guests.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-02-17" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-02-17">Feb. 17</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>Before 5 o'clock this morning, I heard the preparations for departure. Our splendid big boom was taken down the day we spent at <placeName ref="#Philae">Philae</placeName> - and for 2 or 3 days the boat has been getting ready for her downward journey. We have had a lovely week at <placeName ref="#Aswan">Assouan</placeName> - the pleasantest I have ever known - at our same old landing, with the same views before us, we felt quite at home. <placeName ref="#Aswan">Assouan</placeName> has greatly improved since we were here, the river front has been faced with stone, and steps made here and there to the water. The main street following the river bank is now clean, and quite well built, with some good government houses, <pb n="99"/> which with the hotel, give a very bright, clean look. It is very quiet almost no soldiers at the garrison - all having gone to the front. I like the air here better than any place along the river - it is so pure and so entirely from the desert, there being so little vegetation here. A day or two after we arrived, <persName ref="#Sayce_Archibald">Prof. Sayce</persName> and <persName ref="#Fitz_Hardinge_Lord">Lord Fitz-Hardinge</persName> came to call. The <persName ref="#Fitz_Hardinge_Group">Fitz-Hardinges</persName> have the little <name type="boat" ref="#Thames">Thames</name> which they built years ago - and <persName ref="#Sayce_Archibald">Prof. Sayce</persName> on his <name type="boat" ref="#Istar">Istar,</name> was just behind us. A nice, entertaining young fellow with the <persName ref="#Fitz_Hardinge_Group">Fitz-Hardinges,</persName> <persName ref="#Bridgman_Dr">Dr. Bridgman,</persName> who found him an enthusiastic gardener, and the only person I ever met who could tell me anything about horticulture in <placeName ref="#Egypt">Egypt.</placeName> We had <persName ref="#Sayce_Archibald">Prof. Sayce</persName> one evening to dinner - and found him very interesting - telling us a great many things we wanted to know. We left <persName ref="#Fitz_Hardinge_Lord">Lord Fitz-Hardinge</persName> very ill - with threatened pneumonia. He has during the past year succeeded to the title, we having formerly known of him as <persName ref="#Fitz_Hardinge_Lord">Hon. Mr. Berkeley.</persName> With this title which is one of the oldest in <placeName ref="#England">England,</placeName> dating from the time of <persName ref="#Stephen_King">King Stephen,</persName> he has become owner of <name type="historical" ref="#Berkeley_Castle">Berkeley Castle</name> one of the most interesting historical Castles of England, and also to an income of &#65505;70,000 a year. He has no children, he and his wife are past 60 - have very quiet tastes - devoted to church work - schools and charities, and terribly depressed by this change of fortune, which breaks up old habits, and entails so much state and responsibility for which they have no liking. The next heir, is <persName ref="#Berkeley_Lord">Lord Berkeley</persName> of <placeName ref="#Oxford">Oxford</placeName> - a man no longer young - no children, and who cares only for chemistry and geology - and devoutly dreads the day when he shall succeed. - Next to him is an unmarried woman not young, the oldest of 9 children of a clergyman, who has just 600 &#65505;s <pb n="100"/> to spend a year! <persName ref="#Sayce_Archibald">Prof. Sayce</persName> on the <name type="boat" ref="#Istar">Istar,</name> started down at the same time we did this morning - but he told us yesterday, that he would float faster than we could, as his boat is heavy, with a keel - one of the heavy, old fashioned wooden boats, which would not have the ghost of a chance with us in sailing. We have floated against the wind, but with so little progress that at 7 this morning we stopped judging we have made about <measure type="distance">15 miles</measure>. We are lying in the cove of the bend of the river, at anchor, some distance from shore, with the "<name type="boat" ref="#Istar">Istar</name>" near below, her lights showing hospitably against this desert shore. The night most resplendent, the moon full and the great yellow sand drifts over the mountain sides, glowing with almost as much color as they do by day. I would not have my blinds closed, and slept with all the curtains back from the windows that I might get all the outside beauty possible - and waking several times during the night, I sat up in my bed and looked out at it all. What beautiful, resplendent loneliness!</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-02-18" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-02-18">Feb. 18</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>We made about <measure type="distance">3 miles</measure>, starting at half past 6 this morning, but this wretched north wind increasing we gave it up, and lay again in the stream as the shore was so sandy - the <name type="boat" ref="#Istar">Istar</name> almost a <measure type="distance">mile</measure> below us. <persName ref="#Sayce_Archibald">Prof. Sayce</persName> sent over a note, asking us to come to tea - which we did going down in the felucca - very hard rowing against the wind, even with the current, and there really were waves. We had a charming visit <persName ref="#S_Showing_Prof">Prof. S. Showing</persName> us some of his interesting works on <placeName ref="#Egypt">Egypt</placeName> - <persName ref="#Belzoni_Giovanni">Belzoni's</persName> splendid great volume, with hand painted pictures of the temples and <pb n="101"/> tombs - his rendering of the hieroglyphs, being remarkably accurate, though at that time there was no key to them - and of course he was ignorant of their meaning - and it was like copying any other detail of decoration. The great Napeonic work, of the French Scientific Expedition which I had never seen before - the travels of <!--Unsure who this is--><persName>Ligh,</persName> the Englishman a copy of which <persName ref="#Amory_Howard">Howard Amory</persName> gave me from his grandfather's library, and others - one an account of travel written by an Italian <persName ref="#Valle_Della_Pietro">"del Valle"</persName> in 16     <!--Empty space in diary-->. The <name type="boat" ref="#Istar">Istar</name> is a big, old fashioned boat, and looked most comfortable - 20 ft. wide. We and <persName>Cooks</persName> new boats are 17 ft. This width gives her a beautiful saloon, and a wide corridor to the stern cabin, which is also very large, and fitted as a library - with bookcases to the ceiling - a charming, scholarly room - and here <persName ref="#S_Showing_Prof">Prof. S.</persName> says he really does his work for the whole year. Another wonderful night but the wind as strong as ever - and we are rocking uncomfortably - indeed I never rocked so much on the river as we have been doing all day.</p>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-02-19" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-02-19">Friday. Feb. 19</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>We began the morning very early with a light wind, but it soon changed into a big blow - and we were soon driven upon the lee bank, where we pounded up and down in the sand, until <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> suggested an anchor put out at the stern when we were more comfortable. I have just finished reading <bibl><author><persName ref="#Stevenson_Louis_Robert">Stevenson</persName></author>'s <title>"South-Sea Sketches"</title></bibl>, and a second reading of his <bibl><title>Vailima Letters</title></bibl> - and are now going to read <!--tag for book just title?--><bibl><title>Ebb Tide</title></bibl>. A great blow going on. <pb n="102"/></p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-02-20" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-02-20">Feb. 20</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>I had quite an attack of neuralgia or rheumatism in my back and chest last night, which kept me from sleeping - and finding when my morning cup of tea was brought me at 7 o'clock - that the gale was still blowing and the boat rocking, I decided after having my bath to go back to bed, and have my breakfast. Wind continued all day, and weather hopeless. I began reading <bibl><author><persName ref="#Sayce_Archibald">Prof. Sayce</persName></author>'s <title>"Egypt of the Hebrews"</title></bibl>. Last night we got away from our lee shore, and took refuge on the opposite side of the river, where we are now lying, more quietly. Read aloud a long time in <bibl><author><persName ref="#Milner_Alfred">Milner</persName></author>'s <title>"England in Egypt"</title></bibl>.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-02-21" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-02-21">Feb. 21</date>. <name type="event" ref="#Sexagesima">Sexagesima</name> Sunday.
          </dateline>
          <p>The men rowed, or we floated all the latter part of the night until 7 this morning, when I saw <placeName ref="#Kawm_Umbū">Kom Ombo</placeName> directly in front of us. A fine all around view of it, perched so high on its cliff - we pulled up soon, and after breakfast went up to the Temple - it is charming in its height, though not specially interesting; and is certainly very much swept and garnished. The wind falling, we decided not to linger, but pushed off, just as Gage's Steamer "<name type="boat" ref="#Memphis">Memphis</name>" was coming up to her landing. Passed the <name type="boat" ref="#Istar">Istar</name> lying by a little below <placeName ref="#Kawm_Umbū">Kom Ombo.</placeName> This is our 5th day from <placeName ref="#Aswan">Assouan,</placeName> and we have only covered <measure type="distance">29 miles</measure>.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-02-22" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-02-22">Feb. 22. Monday</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>We were off before 6 o'clock this morning - rowing - and in the face of the north wind which still holds with more or less fitfullness - <pb n="103"/> we passed <placeName ref="#Silsilis">Silsilis</placeName> about 3 o'clock - but did not stop, as we are so belated. About an hour afterwards we had gained very much upon the <name type="boat" ref="#Istar">Istar</name> - and our men were pulling lustily - when the order from the <persName>Rais</persName> was suddenly given to stop, and in a moment after, we went rather hard upon a sand bank - which delayed us about an hour - when we went on until 7 o'clock - apparently by the light of Venus, almost as good as a moon. We tied up at a pleasant bank under some scent trees, having come between <measure type="distance">3 and 4 miles</measure> below <placeName ref="#Silsilis">Silsilis</placeName> - making today <measure type="distance">15 miles</measure>. It is so easy to tell who is keeping <name type="event" ref="#Ramadan">Ramadan.</name> Quite a proportion of crew are and they are so solemn and melancholy. Our nice <persName ref="#Mathar">Mathar,</persName> the 2d captain, hasn't even a smile - <persName ref="#Fuli_Rais">Rais Fuli,</persName> and he, and 5 or 6 of the crew, are carefully keeping it.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-02-23" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-02-23">Tuesday Feb. 23</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>We have allowed ourselves just a month from today to reach <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> - there will be so much to do there about changes in the boat, and getting her ready to leave her, that the 10 days between March 23 and April 3d when we leave for <placeName ref="#Brindisi">Brindisi</placeName> will not be more than we need. But this north wind must cease blowing! This morning we started out before 6 - and when <persName ref="#Ainely">Ainely</persName> came to my room, she reported the <name type="boat" ref="#Istar">Istar</name> some distance in advance of us, and another dahabeah. We are wondering if it can be the <name type="boat" ref="#Gazelle">Gazelle</name>, which left <placeName ref="#Aswan">Assouan</placeName>, the day we arrived. Yesterday the <name type="boat" ref="#Nephtys">Nephtis</name> passed up, with the <persName ref="#Hamilton_Duke">Duke of Hamilton</persName> on board. His own flag I suppose at the mast, yellow, with a grimping lion - very effective. He has only lately succeeded to the title we were told - and jumped from <pb n="104"/> a lieutenant in the navy to his present titles and possessions. A pleasant thing. Reached <placeName ref="#El_Kab">El Kab</placeName> - <measure type="distance">36 miles</measure>.</p>
          <!--End Thurston-->
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-02-24" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-02-24">Wednesday. Feb. 24</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>Morning calm - did not start until 10 o'clock - as we had hoped to see <persName ref="#Somers_Clarke_George">Mr. Somers-Clarke</persName>. I wanted very much to see his boat. But we found he and <persName ref="#Sayce_Archibald">Prof. Sayce</persName> had gone early to the tombs, so after a little inspection of the old town, we came away - and have with difficulty, against a head wind made <measure type="distance">15 miles</measure>.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-02-25" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-02-25">Thursday Feb. 25</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>We floated down 2 miles to <placeName ref="#Esneh">Esneh</placeName> early this morning - and all the rest went off in the felucca to see the temple - which I don't care for - <persName ref="#Jones_Daniel">Jones</persName> and <persName ref="#Henna">Henna</persName> went marketing - and they all joined us again at the end of the town. Our men have rowed tremendously this afternoon, hoping to bring us to <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName> tonight - but at 11 o'clock the wind grew so strong that we tied up within sight of the <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName> lights - having made <measure type="distance">36 miles</measure>.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-02-26" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-02-26">Friday Feb. 26</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>We came to our old place near the <placeName ref="#Carter_Castle">Castle</placeName> early this morning. High wind has been blowing all day, and I did not ride out to <placeName ref="#Karnak">Karnac</placeName> with them this afternoon - though we walked into town, and I went to the <orgName ref="#American_Mission">American Mission</orgName> to ask about the little arab girl "<persName ref="#Nubia">Nubia</persName>" and the chances of sending her to school. I saw <persName ref="#Nichols_Mrs">Mrs. Nichols</persName> in her pleasant <pb n="105"/> clean rooms - and she could not give me any encouragement. Asked her and <persName ref="#Nichols_Mr">Mr. Nichols</persName> to come to tea this afternoon - and had a very pleasant visit. They are soon going to <placeName ref="#United_States_of_America">America</placeName> for a vacation year, having spent 7 years here. Only 4 dahabeahs here - the <name type="boat" ref="#Hyksos_steamer">Hyksos</name>, <name type="boat" ref="#Anna">Anna</name>, <name type="boat" ref="#Gamilla">Gamilla</name>, and one other. <persName ref="#Huhatt_Mr">Mr. Huhatt</persName> came to play chess.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-02-27" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-02-27">Saturday, Feb. 27</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>Today the <name type="boat" ref="#Cheops">Cheops</name>, <name type="boat" ref="#Columbia">Columbia</name> and <name type="boat" ref="#Ammon_Ra">Ammon-Ra</name> came down. All went over early to the <placeName ref="#Bībān al-Mulūk">Tombs of the Kings</placeName> for the day - I could not face the idea of such a long excursion in this heat - so stayed on the boat all day - and had a rest and did all manner of delightful little independent things. Intensely hot - I had "<persName ref="#Nubia">Nubia</persName>" part of the morning with me, but she was such a restless little colt, I had to send her away at 12 o'clock - quite happy with numerous possessions - the chief of which was a pair of red shoes - which <persName ref="Schaiyeh_Mohammed">Mohammed Schaiyeh</persName>, my singer, bought for her in the town. The family came back at 6:30 -powdered with dust, and tired, and clamouring for lemonade and tea - having had a delightful day. The <name type="boat" ref="#Osiris">Osiris</name> came in this afternoon and is lying close behind us.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-02-28" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <name type="event" ref="#Quinguagesima">Quinguagesima</name> <date when="1897-02-28">Sunday. Feb. 28</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>We had thought of getting off today, but there was no wind, and <persName ref="#Baldwin_Mr">Mr. Baldwin</persName> wants us to wait for him tomorrow. I did not leave the boat, in the afternoon the wind very high. <persName ref="#Read_Constantine_Mrs">Mrs. Constantine Read</persName> and her cousin made us a visit, and <persName ref="#Shephard_Mr">Mr. Shephard</persName> and <persName>his sister</persName> of the <pb n="106"/> <name type="boat" ref="#Hyksos">Hyksos</name> also came. He, the Engineer of the new railroad. <persName ref="#Mohassib_Mohammed">Mohammed Mohassib</persName> also came.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-03-01" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-03-01">March 1st. Monday</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>We did not get away until 7 o'clock this morning - and had not lost sight of the town when a very hard north wind sprang up, and after trying to float, gave it up and anchored, until about 4 o'clock, when it came out a little to the south, and we gladly spread our sails, and had soon come to a big turn in the river which brought the wind on our side, so that we could not keep off the bank. Found here tied up, under the same circumstances, the <name type="boat" ref="#Osiris">Osiris</name> which left <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName> the day before us, and the <name type="boat" ref="#Ammon_Ra">Ammon-Ra</name> who got away an hour before us this morning - and here we all are for the night. Two Mecca pilgrims going to <placeName ref="#Mecca">Mecca</placeName> stopped on the bank above us after the sun had gone down, to break the long fast of the day and eat their evening meal. They were dressed entirely in white, and had a donkey, carrying their luggage.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-03-02" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-03-02">March 2d. Tuesday</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>A very early start this morning and rowing and floating in company with the <name type="boat" ref="#Ammon_Ra">Ammon-Ra</name> and the <name type="boat" ref="#Osiris">Osiris,</name> we reached <placeName ref="#Keneh">Keneh</placeName> about 3 o'clock, and the rest started in the felucca, before we reached the opposite landing for <placeName ref="#Temple_of_Dendera">Denderah</placeName>, and we floated down below and waited for them. Very hot for 2 hours - found the <name type="boat" ref="#Columbia">Columbia</name> at <placeName ref="#Temple_of_Dendera">Denderah</placeName>. They reported on coming home, very unruly donkey boys, and very exciting rows with them. All the morning we were just in advance of the <name type="boat" ref="#Osiris">Osiris</name>, <pb n="107"/>and she floated most unpleasantly near us - two or three times we were actually in collision side by side, and great commotion among the crews. <persName ref="#Oswald_St_Lord">Lord St. Oswald</persName> is on her. They all came back in an hour and a half, and we floated and rowed 3 or 4 miles farther down - and tied up with strong wind blowing from the north, at 6:30. I enjoyed a walk on deck while they were away - looking at the splendid desert mountains across the river beyond <placeName ref="#Keneh">Keneh</placeName>. What a hot, desolate spot <placeName ref="#Keneh">Keneh</placeName> must have been last summer, when the cholera raged so violently! I have never been in the town but once - and it lies so back from the river that it cannot be well seen. I suppose just now the Mecca pilgrims are crowding them on their way to <placeName ref="#Mecca">Mecca</placeName> - I should like to have ridden into the town today, and out a way upon the <placeName ref="#Koser">Koser</placeName> road. The descriptions of this desert route have always fascinated me. We think we have made <measure type="distance">31 miles</measure> today.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-03-03" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-03-03">Wednesday. March 3</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>This is <name type="event" ref="#Ash_Wednesday">Ash Wednesday</name> - and the last of the 30 days of <name type="event" ref="#Ramadan">Ramadan</name> - for which we are truly thankful - for <persName ref="#Fuli_Rais">Rais Fuli</persName> - 2 Rais Mattar - <persName ref="#Moomond">Moomond</persName> the big Mohammed, and <persName ref="#Baken">Baken</persName> the little sailor, all keep it rigourously. They represent the very pick of the crew - and things will now be more cheerful. This had been a distracting day. Such a mix as we, the <name type="boat" ref="#Osiris">Osiris,</name> the <name type="boat" ref="#Ammon_Ra">Ammon-Ra</name>, the <name type="boat" ref="#Columbia">Columbia</name> and several large working boats have been in most of the day. I have never known such an experience - the wind has been from the north most of the time. Our crew have worked splendidly at their oars, and beaten all the others <pb n="108"/> out and out. It was a splendid triumph. The gale increased and at 5 o'clock we tied up, followed by all the others - and we are strung along the bank, within 2 or 3 miles of <placeName ref="#Kasr_el_Sayd">Kasr-el Sayd</placeName>. After we landed we went to visit the <persName ref="#Baldwin_Mr #Baldwin_Mrs">Baldwins</persName>. We have made <measure type="distance">25 miles</measure> - and are rolling a little uneasily in the wind.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-03-04" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-03-04">Thursday. March 4</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>Made about <measure type="distance">5 miles</measure> early this morning - heavy gale from the north has made it impossible to stir since 8 o'clock. We are <measure type="distance">3 miles</measure> below <placeName ref="#Kasr_el_Sayd">Kasr el-Sayd</placeName>.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-03-05" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-03-05">Friday. March 5</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>Started at 5 o'clock this morning - and before I got up, while enjoying my book and cup of tea, we passed the bridge at <placeName ref="#Naj_Hammadi">Nagh-el-Hamadi</placeName>. <name type="boat" ref="#Ammon_Ra">Ammon-Ra</name> and <name type="boat" ref="#Osiris">Osiris</name> ahead of us.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-03-06" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-03-06">Saturday. March 6</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>Our men began rowing at 1 o'clock this morning - reached <placeName ref="#Balyana_Al">Balliana</placeName> at 10:30 and started immediately for <placeName ref="#Abydos">Abydos</placeName>. That pleasant ride of 7 miles out and 7 back, never seemed so tiresome - for the very worst donkeys of all the notorious bad donkeys of <placeName ref="#Abydos">Abydos</placeName> or rather <placeName ref="#Balyana_Al">Balliana</placeName> fell to our lot. The day was tremendously hot - the natives specially tormenting. I arrived at the temple more dead than alive - and by 3:30 we were in our saddles again - and I came home resolving <pb n="109"/> never to do that expedition again. The <name type="boat" ref="#Ammon_Ra">Ammon-Ra</name> and <name type="boat" ref="#Osiris">Osiris</name> did not stop - but the <name type="boat" ref="#Chonsu"><choice><sic>Chensu</sic><corr>Chonsu</corr></choice></name> (English) and the <name type="boat" ref="#Columbia">Columbia</name> (American Jews) did, and went to the <placeName ref="#Temple_of_Dendera">Temple</placeName>. We are having the most beautiful little new moon imaginable. For the first two nights it had the resplendent beams almost within its bow. The last winter we were here on the river we used constantly to see the Zodiacal lights - but I have not seen it this time. I saw in the <placeName ref="#Abydos">Abydos</placeName> fields today, the most beautiful light vivid green birds - large as our robin, but more slender and elegant.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-03-07" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            1st Sunday in <name type="event" ref="#Lent">Lent</name>. <date when="1897-03-07">March 7</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>Made from 6 A.M. to 8 P.M. 27-1/2 miles - are now at <placeName ref="#Akmim">Akmim</placeName>.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-03-08" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-03-08">Monday. March 8</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>Started early, and made <placeName ref="#Sohag">Sohag</placeName> by 9 o'clock - where we stopped to get coal and provisions and our mail. By 11 o'clock P.M. had come <measure type="distance">6 miles</measure> below <placeName ref="#Sohag">Sohag</placeName> - making the whole day <measure type="distance">11 miles</measure>. North wind.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-03-09" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-03-09">Tuesday. March 9</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>Made <measure type="distance">2 miles</measure> today early - tied up since in a gale - wind a little west of north - so that we are hoping it may move around to the south. We would like so much to have one record day of gentle south wind! <name type="boat" ref="#Chonsu">Chonsu</name> passed us, being so heavy, she floats fast. <name type="boat" ref="#Columbia">Columbia</name> still behind. Had a row in the felucca. <pb n="110"/></p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-03-10" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-03-10">Wednesday. March 10</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>Early this morning, we managed to make about 10 yards - but the wind increasing we tied up again - and now lying just as we did all day yesterday at the mercy of the wind, blowing across miles of sand. For days the sky has been full of clouds and last evening they were so ominous, that I hoped the night would bring rain, and perhaps break this deadly magic spell of north wind - but it has been even worse today. We have had the boat as tightly closed as possible, but the air everywhere has been thick with this fine, impalpable sand.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-03-11" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-03-11">Thursday. March 11</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>Still lying at the same spot, and a gale still blowing - impossible to be on deck except for a walk near sunset - so much sand still flying - rugs cushions etc. all folded and packed away.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-03-12" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-03-12">Friday. March 12</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>Got away at 6 o'clock and rowed and floated until about 10 - when the wind grew into such a sudden gale, we pulled with difficulty to the shore - where some work boats had taken refuge. Soon after the <name type="boat" ref="#Nephtys">Nephtys</name>, with the <name ref="#Hamilton_Duke">Duke of Hamilton</name>, and a tug came down the river, and came to the shore just below us. <measure type="distance">3 miles</measure> today.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-03-13" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-03-13">Saturday. March 13</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>Started in a light wind at 6 A.M. at 11 it was blowing such a gale that we tied up at the high cliffs about 2 miles above and opposite <pb n="111"/> <placeName ref="#Tahta">Tahtah</placeName>. Just where there is a group of palms - and the white little mosque against the yellow cliffs. Luckily it was not a hot day, or the reflection from those towering limestone cliffs would have been insufferable. But how the wind has blown - in our sheltered position however we got no sand. The canvass on the river side, and over the deck, and at the back were put up - leaving the land side with its pretty sights open - and under the hooded seats, the deck was charming for sitting. All the others went to walk, but I took mine on the clean deck. The <name type="boat" ref="#Columbia">Columbia</name> came in sight this morning, and drew up just above us. At 6:30 we both went off, in the bright moonlight, the wind having fallen very much - and the men are still rowing. (They rowed until 12:30, thus making <measure type="distance">27 miles</measure>).
        </p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-03-14" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            Second Sunday in <placeName ref="#Lent">Lent</placeName>. <date when="1897-03-14">March 14</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>Started early rowing. North wind strong most of the day. We are now tied up <measure type="distance">2 miles</measure> above <placeName ref="#Asyut">Assiut</placeName> - the lights of the town plainly to be seen. <name type="boat" ref="#Columbia">Columbia</name> near us. A superb sunset.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-03-15" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-03-15"><choice><sic>Monda</sic><corr>Monday</corr></choice>. March 15</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>Between marketing, getting in coke, and the mail, we were at <placeName ref="#Asyut">Assiut</placeName>, until after one o'clock. The afternoon a regular gale blowing, made <measure type="distance">2 miles</measure> at 8 o'clock. <pb n="112"/></p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-03-16" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-03-16">Tuesday. March 16</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>We are now beginning to calculate the distance made from 1:30 P.M. of each day. Since that time last night we have made <measure type="distance">32 miles</measure> - and have passed the troublesome <placeName ref="#Jabal_Abū_Fūdah">Gebel Abufedah</placeName>, and are anchored in the stream. We have an almost full moon now, and lovely effects this evening.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-03-17" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-03-17">Wednesday. March 17</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>Made <measure type="distance">21 miles</measure> - were blown ashore in the strong wind early in the afternoon near <placeName ref="#Hag_Kandil">Haggi Kandul</placeName> - and a lot of noisy children and rough looking men hung about the boat making it hideous with their clamour. We got away from that unpleasant neighborhood and floated down until 10 o'clock. Such a radiant night!</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-03-18" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-03-18">Thursday. March 18</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>We have made <measure type="distance">25 miles</measure> in the last 24 hours - the day being the calmest we have had and the hottest. We were all driven down stairs after luncheon by the heat. Passed <name type="historical" ref="#Beni_Hasan">Beni Hassan</name> at one o'clock - but did not stop - as we are so belated. Every day <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> says "tomorrow" I shall telegraph for a tug, if the south sind doesn't come. Each day we hopefully look for it - and we would even welcome a Khamseen. We reached <placeName ref="#Al_Minya">Minieh</placeName> at 7 o'clock and got our mail, and will lie here all night. The full moon was wonderfully beautiful and the night so soft. A heavy mist however lying along the river. <pb n="113"/></p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-03-19" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-03-19">Friday. March 19</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>An early start, and rowing and occasional sailing, or lying by when the wind was too strong, has brought us to within 3 miles of <placeName ref="#Al_Fashn">Fashen</placeName> - making since 1:30, <measure type="distance">44 miles</measure>, or 61-1/2 from <placeName ref="#Al_Minya">Minieh</placeName> this morning - a strange, wonderful sunset - and a cloudy night.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-03-20" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-03-20">Saturday - March 20</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>Started at 6 A.M. made <placeName ref="#Benisoef">Benisoef</placeName> about 1:30 - and a drifting and sailing delightfully along before a light wind, all the afternoon, we are now lying <measure type="distance">7 miles</measure> from <placeName ref="#Al_Wasta">Wasta</placeName>, - <measure type="distance">54-1/2 miles</measure> since 1:30 yesterday, and 25 miles since 1:30 today. <placeName ref="#Medamud">Medum</placeName> in sight.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-03-21" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            Third Sunday in <name type="event" ref="#Lent">Lent</name>. <date when="1897-03-21">March 21st</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>An early start in a good wind brought us along so surprisingly that we were near <placeName ref="#Al_Badrashayn">Bedrascheen</placeName> at 10:30, having discovered some minutes before that beautiful view of the dome and slender minarets of <persName ref="#Ali_Mohammed">Mohammed Ali</persName> - shining in the sun above the thick haze, looking like some enchanted palace. The sailing was so fine, and the <name type="boat" ref="#Beduin">Beduin</name> showing her paces so splendidly, that we suddenly decided we would not stop for the visit to <placeName ref="#Ṣaqqâra">Sakkarah</placeName>, and kept on for the <placeName>Museum</placeName> landing at <placeName ref="#Giza">Ghizeh</placeName>. The sky being full of great clouds, very unlike <placeName ref="#Egypt">Egypt</placeName> - all the morning the blue sky making such delightful contrasts with their great swelling white domes, and the pyramids of <placeName ref="#Al_Lisht">Lisht</placeName>, <placeName ref="#Dahshūr">Dashur</placeName>, and <placeName ref="#Ṣaqqâra">Sakkarah</placeName> showing splendidly - until quite in a moment the clouds grew dirty and the atmosphere thick, the wind increased, and we were blown to the bank, with <pb n="114"/> great effort escaping collision with the rocky foundation of a big sakiyeh on the top of which as usual a blindfolded bullock was walking round and round his wheel. Here we have been ever since, the wind growing into a gale, and the opposite shore almost hidden by the clouds of sand blowing across its sandy waste. We are quite sheltered here from it, though we get enough of it as the atmosphere is so charged with it and when in the afternoon it began softly to rain, the drops seemed like mud, and made a fine mess of our clean windows. The waves beat so high and roughly on the lee shore against which we lay, that the two feluccas, were in danger, and our men worked almost stripped, for 2 hours before they were bailed and lifted to a place of safety. In my stern room the uproar was tremendous - <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and <persName ref="#Clarence">Clarence</persName> went for a walk, but were driven home by the wind and rain, and there was a great fracas on deck, getting everything under canvass, safe from the wet. The men are always so funny with a rain - like children with a snow storm, and never seem quite to know what to do - <measure type="distance">67 miles</measure> to 1:30 today. At 11 o'clock this evening, I saw two or three stars showing.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-03-22" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-03-22">Monday, March 22</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>We attempted to get on this A.M. at 6 o'clock and succeeded only in making a start and were driven to shore about <placeName ref="#Cairo">Old Cairo</placeName> - tremendous wind, and rain almost amounting to hail in the afternoon - and with our new decks so warped, we came to great grief - the boat leaking in many places - so that when <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and <persName ref="#Clarence">Clarence</persName> came back from <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName>, where they went and had lunch and came back late in the <pb n="115"/> afternoon - they found us with curtains taken down from the windows, and bowls and pans standing about everywhere. They were so pleased to get home - they were ineffably amiable - said it seemed after <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> like Paradise.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-03-23" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-03-23">Tuesday. March 23</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>We made the <placeName>Museum</placeName> landing at <placeName ref="#Giza">Ghizeh</placeName> this morning early - and fortunately we were to have accomplished it - for the wind has increased in violence - it has been a gale all day - and it is cold and disagreeable - a bad March day for any part of the world. We spent a pleasant morning however at the <placeName>Museum</placeName> - and had it all to ourselves. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and <persName ref="#Clarence">Clarence</persName> have been into <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName>, and report it dismal.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-03-24" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-03-24">Wednesday. March 24</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>A gale all day - with rain now and then. Morning at the <placeName>Museum</placeName> - <persName ref="#Salah_Mohammed">Salah</persName> came out to see us.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-03-25" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-03-25">Thursday. March 25</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>Very busy all the morning with the various work people coming to the boat. Carpenters, painters, upholsterer, sail makers. <persName ref="#Parsons_Mary">Mary</persName> and I drove in the afternoon - charming and warmer - <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> very pretty with flowering shrubs and vines - very quiet and empty. Poor <persName ref="#Abdul">Abdul</persName> had been quite ill for some days, and so suffering that we sent for <persName ref="#Sandwith_Dr">Dr. Sandwith</persName> yesterday, who said he must go to the hospital for a few days. So this <pb n="116"/> morning the men with <persName ref="#Jones_Daniel">Jones</persName>, took him down in the felucca- being able to go quite to its doors in the boat. He is a great loss to us just at present not being simply the valued servant, but interpreter. Fortunately we have fallen back on <persName ref="#Salah_Mohammed">Salah</persName>, who fortunately has no engagement just now, and comes out to us every day. Excessively warm. I have never been in <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> when so warm.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-03-26" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-03-26">Friday. March 26</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p><persName ref="#Taylor_Mrs">Mrs. Taylor</persName> and <persName ref="#Taylor_Florence">Florence</persName> came this morning and made a visit, and were very pleasant - putting us en rapport with everything in and about <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> - asking us to dine on Saturday with them at the <name type="historical" ref="#Ghezireh_Palace">Gesireh</name> to meet <persName ref="#Scott_John_Sir">Sir John Scott</persName>, who wants to know <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName>, and whom <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> is very keen to meet. <persName ref="#Scott_John_Sir">Sir John</persName> is Judicial Advisor to the <persName ref="#Abbad_II">Khedive</persName>, and did excellent work in <placeName ref="#India">India</placeName> before coming here to help straighten out Egyptian affairs. In the afternoon went to the races - which were rather slow - met <persName ref="#Lang_Hamilton_Mrs">Mrs. Hamilton Lang</persName> and her daughter - saw <persName ref="#Kitchener_Herbert">Gen. Kitchener</persName>, the Sirdâr and other notables. </p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-03-28" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <name type="event" ref="#Laetare_Sunday">Fourth Sunday in Lent</name>. <date when="1897-03-28">March 28</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>I was ill all day yesterday, and could not go to dinner with <persName ref="#Taylor_Mrs">Mrs. Taylor</persName> - which was reported very pleasant. This afternoon <persName ref="#Sandwith_Dr #Sandwith_Mrs">Dr. and Mrs. Sandwith</persName> came to tea - and <persName ref="#Taylor_Mrs">Mrs. Taylor</persName> and <persName ref="#Taylor_Florence">Florence</persName>, and her fiancé <persName ref="#Morice_Mr">Mr. Morice</persName> to dine. We had a nice evening. <pb n="117"/></p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-03-30" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-03-30">Tuesday. March 30</date>. <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName>.
          </dateline>
          <p>We came over to <name type="hotel" ref="#Shepheards_Hotel">Shepheards</name> this afternoon - and are in the corner room we had 5 years ago, when <persName ref="#Fielding_Mr">Fielding</persName> was with us. Then it was cold and we had a fire in the big sitting room. Now it is so hot, that we have all the windows open at night and shut during the day to keep out the heat. But it is very noisy and smelly. I do not like it, although my balcony opens on the pretty garden. <name type="hotel" ref="#Shepheards_Hotel">Hotel</name> quite empty - very tired from yesterday - packing and arranging.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-03-31" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-03-31">Wednesday, March 31</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>Over at the boat which still lies at <placeName ref="#Giza">Ghizeh</placeName> - and where our <persName ref="#Fuli_Rais">Rais</persName> intends to stay all summer because it is so much cooler. Delightful drive in the afternoon.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-04-01" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-04-11">Thursday, April 1st</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p><persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and <persName ref="#Clarence">Clarence</persName> went to the <placeName ref="#Courts_of_Justice">Courts of Justice</placeName> this morning with <persName ref="#Scott_John_Sir">Sir John Scott</persName> and<persName ref="#Morice_Mr">Mr. Morice</persName>, and were much interested. <persName ref="#Abdul">Abdul</persName> came back from the hospital, very weak and thin, but almost well. A bothersome time for days getting all the carpets, curtains, stuffs, etc. of the boat safely packed away from dangers of moths and vermin. The boat reeks with the smell of Naphthaline and Camphor. The poor <name type="boat" ref="#Beduin">Beduin</name>, so changed - closed and dark, with her thick brown summer awnings enshrouding her - all the men gone but <persName ref="#Fuli_Rais">Rais Fuli</persName>, and <persName ref="#Arbuk">Arbuk</persName>, the nice little crew cook, who stays with <persName>the Captain</persName> - and <persName ref="#Abdul">Abdul</persName>, who will live with <persName ref="#Fuli_Rais">Fuli</persName> on the boat, and look after the inside cleaning - as he <pb n="118"/> reads and writes English, it will be very convenient for us - and <persName ref="#Fuli_Rais">Rais Fuli</persName> is immensely glad to have him. <name ref="#Taylor_Florence #Taylor_Mrs">The Taylors</name> sailed for <placeName ref="#Marseilles">Marseilles</placeName> today in the <name type="boat" ref="#Clyde">Clyde</name>.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-04-02" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-04-02">Friday, April 2d</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>We were obliged to go again to the boat to confer with the old French painter as to the colours for the outside. Then goodbye to all - and a delightful drive. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and <persName ref="#Clarence">Clarence</persName> on their horses with us most of the way. The air has been quite delightful for 2 days - all our friends beg us to stay for the charming April weather. We are off tomorrow morning for <placeName ref="#Alexandria">Alexandria</placeName> and sail for <placeName ref="#Brindisi">Brindisi</placeName> in the afternoon.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-04-15" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <placeName ref="#Rome">Rome</placeName>. <name type="hotel" ref="#Hotel_Bristol">Bristol Hotel</name>. <date when="1897-04-15">April 15</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>A long interval in this journal. We left <placeName ref="#Alexandria">Alexandria</placeName> the afternoon of the 3d in the fine new <name type="boat" ref="#SS_Bohemia">S.S. Bohemia</name> for <placeName ref="#Brindisi">Brindisi</placeName>. Weather very warm - and we were glad of the welcome change which two or three hours at sea brought. Boat very comfortable - but passage rough - almost every one in his bed - I stayed in mine Sunday and Monday - and we landed at <placeName ref="#Brindisi">Brindisi</placeName> at 5 o'clock and made our train, because they were complaisant enough to hold our train 40 minutes for us. The long ride to <placeName ref="#Naples">Naples</placeName> was not so tiring, and seemed more pleasant than usual. So delightful the country seemed in its fresh spring greenness - and the huge vegetable garden which stretches as far as the eye can see, without boundaries, for miles before reaching <placeName ref="#Naples">Naples</placeName>, is something quite wonderful. Everything planted under the thin foliaged trees, with their garlands <pb n="119"/> of vines stretching from tree to tree. We found pleasant rooms at the <name type="hotel" ref="#Grand_Hotel">Grand Hotel</name>, but <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> had taken a cold in crossing, which developed into a light form of grippe, which gave him much suffering and restlessness - and he had the <persName ref="#Malbranc_Dr">Doctor (Malbrane)</persName> who is always so simple and helpful, and stayed in the room all the time, and one day in bed. As the weather was not good, clouds everywhere, <placeName ref="#Vesuvius">Vesuvius</placeName> and the islands hidden from view most of the time, I stayed at home with <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> - and on Saturday the 10th he was well enough to come on here - <persName ref="#Clarence">Clarence</persName>, <persName ref="#Parsons_Mary">Mary</persName>, <persName ref="#Burgnoyne_Amelie">Amilie</persName> and <persName ref="#Jones_Daniel">Jones</persName> spent one day at <placeName ref="#Pompeii">Pompeii</placeName>, and <persName ref="#Clarence">Clarence</persName> the next day at <placeName ref="#Vesuvius">Vesuvius</placeName>. We had rooms engaged at the <name type="hotel" ref="#Hotel_Quirinale">Quirinal</name>, but found them much too small and fortunately having had an offer from the <name type="hotel" ref="#Hotel_Bernini_Bristol">Bristol</name> we came here, which is always my favorite hotel in <placeName ref="#Rome">Rome</placeName>. But alas, I have since coming here developed the grippe also - and have been in bed and in the house all the time until yesterday, as uncomfortable as I ever remember of being - with <persName ref="#Bull_Dr">Dr. Bull</persName> in daily attendance. All the world more or less is in <placeName ref="#Rome">Rome</placeName> - and to my thinking <name type="event" ref="#Holy_Week">Holy Week</name> is not the time to visit <placeName ref="#Rome">Rome</placeName>, unless one is interested in church ceremonies. The pictures in churches covered, many galleries closed etc.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-04-22" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <name type="hotel" ref="#Hotel_Royal_Grande_Bretagne">Hotel Grande Bretagne</name>. <placeName ref="#Florence">Florence</placeName>. <date when="1897-04-22"> April 22</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>We got away from <placeName ref="#Rome">Rome</placeName> Tuesday the 20th at 9 o'clock in the morning - I was glad to leave - for <persName ref="#Parsons_Mary">Mary</persName> had taken cold, and we were all under the weather. On <name type="event" ref="#Easter_Sunday">Easter Sunday</name>, I was able to drive out <measure type="distance">7 miles</measure> on the <placeName ref="#Campania">Campagna</placeName> to the <name type="historical" ref="#Villa_Livia">Villa Livia</name>, where we met by invitation <persName ref="Elliot_Mrs">Mrs. Elliott</persName>, who had asked some of her friends to take tea with us there. <pb n="120"/> <persName ref="#Stillman_Mrs">Mrs. Stillman</persName>, the once favorite beauty was there - <persName ref="#Anderson_Larz_Mr">Mr. Larz Anderson</persName> - the young Swedish American sculptor <persName ref="#Anderson_Larz_Mr">Anderson</persName>, whose mother lives in <placeName ref="#Newport">Newport</placeName> was there and others. It was not quite my idea of enjoyment - sitting at 5 o'clock P.M. on rugs on the ground at the top of a windy hill - but <persName ref="#Elliot_Mrs">Mrs. Elliott's</persName> intention was good and kind. The next morning, <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName>, <persName ref="#Parsons_Mary">Mary</persName> and I went to <name type="historical" ref="#St_Peters_Basilica">St. Peters</name> and saw the lovely <persName ref="#da_Forli_Melozzo">Melozzo</persName> angels and frescoes in the inner sacristy - then drove to the <name type="historical" ref="#Colosseum">Colosseum</name> and along the <placeName ref="#Via_San_Gregorio">Via S. Gregorio</placeName>, the morning being quite warm and beautiful. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> went to lunch with the <persName ref="#Elliot_John #Elliot_Mrs">Elliotts</persName>, and in the afternoon <persName ref="#Parsons_Mary">Mary</persName> and I drove to the <name type="historical" ref="#Villa_Doria_Pamphili">Villa Doria Pamphilia</name>, the lovely grounds of which were full of people, it being <name type="event" ref="#Easter_Sunday">Easter Monday</name> and a holiday. But the weather had changed and the wind was cold - so we drove to the <name type="historical" ref="#Piazza_Rusticucci">Piazzo Rusticucci</name> to say goodbye to <persName ref="#Elliot_Mrs">Mrs. Elliott</persName> and had a pleasant visit - meeting for the first time <persName ref="#Elliot_John">Mr. Elliott</persName> - a handsome, rather invalid looking man, whom I liked - especially when he took me on to his roof garden which he cultivates entirely himself, and which has charming views of <placeName ref="#San_Pietro">S. Pietro</placeName> and the whole quarter. It was gay with vines and climbing roses and flowers and quite fascinating. <persName ref="#Clarence">Clarence</persName> met us there, and after tea we all drove home. <persName ref="#Elliot_Mrs">Mrs. Elliott</persName> and her cousin <persName ref="#Ralem_Von_Miss">Miss Von Ralem</persName> having dined with us the night before. We had a pleasant ride to <placeName ref="#Florence">Florence</placeName>, found <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> waiting for us, and who soon went off with <persName ref="#Parsons_Mary">Mary</persName>. We have pleasant rooms here overlooking the <placeName ref="#Arno">Arno</placeName> and <name type="historical" ref="#Ponte_Vecchio">Ponto Vecchio</name>, and we, that is <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and I, have decided to stay here and not go to <placeName ref="#Venice">Venice</placeName> - <persName ref="#Clarence">Clarence</persName> will go alone. <pb n="121"/></p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-04-24" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-04-24">April 24. Saturday</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>We are having a rainy day - <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I however went for a little shopping this morning - before the rain began - the wind was blowing and the dust flying however. We brought up at <placeName>Pelotti's</placeName> where we met <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName>, and looked at many enticing things. <persName ref="#Berenson_Bernard">Mr. Berenson</persName> came to lunch - and after <persName ref="#Niblock_Lieutenant">Lieutenant Niblock</persName> called - home all the afternoon the rain pouring. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> still has a troublesome cold, and I have quite mended. Yesterday morning, <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName>, <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and I drove a long time in the lovely <placeName ref="#Parco_delle_Cascine">Cascine</placeName>. In the afternoon a visit to the <placeName ref="#Palazzo_Mozzi">Bardini palace</placeName> with its fascinating collection, and then a visit to <persName ref="#Buttles_Lizzie">Lizzie</persName> - <persName ref="#Parsons_Mary">Mary</persName> and <persName ref="#Clarence">Clarence</persName> have been busy each day doing <placeName ref="#Florence">Florence</placeName>. This afternoon <persName ref="#Clarence">Clarence</persName> went off alone to <placeName ref="#Venice">Venice</placeName>, charged with the precious things and the mission to the Armenian convent of <placeName ref="#San_Lazzaro_degli_Armeni">St. Lazarre</placeName>. We have done the <name type="historical" ref="#Uffizi_Gallery">Uffizzi</name> and <name type="historical" ref="#Gallerie_dell_Accademia">Academia</name>, and had a lovely afternoon at <placeName ref="#San_Miniato">San Miniato</placeName>. Wednesday evening <persName ref="#Bend_Mrs">Mrs. Bend</persName> and <persName ref="#Bend_Amy #Bend_Beatrice">her daughters</persName> dined with us, and on Thursday <persName ref="#Costellar_Mrs">Mrs. Costellar</persName> and <persName ref="#Berenson_Bernard">Berenson</persName>.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-04-25" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <name type="event" ref="#Second_Sunday_of_Easter">Sunday after Easter</name>. <date when="1897-04-25">April 25</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>We are just home from the <placeName ref="#Royal_Victoria_Hotel">Victoria Hotel</placeName>, where we have been dining with <persName ref="#Bend_Mrs">Mrs. Bend</persName> and spent a pleasant evening with her and <persName ref="#Bend_Amy #Bend_Beatrice">her two pretty girls</persName>. The day has been lovely - <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I had a delicious morning together at the <name type="historical" ref="#Palazzo_Pitti">Pitti</name> - and afterwards went to the church of the <name type="historical" ref="#Santa_Maria_del_Carmine">Carmine</name> to see the <persName ref="#Masaccio">Masaccio</persName> frescoes - which I knew well from my photographs - and could therefore intelligently enjoy in detail, despite the darkness of the little chapel where they are, and their faded condition. <pb n="122"/> <persName ref="#Buttles_Lizzie">Lizzie Buttles</persName> and both girls came to lunch, and stayed to tea. After they had gone, <persName ref="#Baldwin_Mrs">Mrs. Baldwin</persName> called. I found her simple, pleasant and unaffected - and I enjoyed talking to her. She has asked us to lunch on Tuesday.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-04-26" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-04-26">Monday. April 26</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>After a morning with <persName ref="#Parsons_Mary">Mary</persName> and <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> at the <placeName ref="#Museo_Nazionale_del_Bargello">Bargello</placeName>, among the <persName ref="#Della_Robbia_Giovanni">della Robias</persName> and <persName ref="#Donatello">Donatellos</persName> - <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and I drove out to the <placeName ref="#Villa_Rosa">Villa Rosa</placeName> at <placeName ref="#Fiesole">Fiesole</placeName> to lunch with <persName ref="#Costellar_Mrs">Mrs. Costellar</persName> and <persName ref="#Berenson_Bernard">Berenson</persName>. A nice scotch woman was there - a <persName ref="#Breenner_Christina">Miss Christina Breenner</persName> - worker in and writer on education of women. A pleasant visit, and much talking - and a charming drive down the hill and a turn in the <placeName ref="#Parco_delle_Cascine">Cascine</placeName> which was quite too lovely - none of the gay throng having arrived - the air so delicious - the birds singing like mad. We had to hurry home, for <persName ref="#Bend_Mrs">Mrs. Bend</persName> and <persName ref="#Bend_Amy #Bend_Beatrice">her girls</persName> were coming to tea to meet <persName ref="#Buttles_Lizzie">Lizzie</persName> and the girls. <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName>, poor child, detained at home with one of her bad neuralgia headaches - <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and I dined alone - and have had a quiet evening, writing letters.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-04-27" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-04-27">Tuesday, April 27</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>Such a busy day - shopping this morning - lunching at <persName ref="#Baldwin_Dr">Dr. Baldwins</persName> - where we had a delightful visit - and a beautiful luncheon, the house charming - home to meet <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> for some searching of photographs at <placeName ref="#Fratelli_Alinari">Alinaris</placeName> - then to <persName ref="#Buttles_Lizzie">Lizzies</persName> to tea - and <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> sang for us in splendid voice. Then a drive with <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and <persName ref="#Parsons_Mary">Mary</persName> in the <placeName ref="#Parco_delle_Cascine">Cascine</placeName>. <persName ref="#Parsons_Mary">Mary</persName> came to dine, and <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> came for her with <persName ref="#Hassan">Hassan</persName> in the evening. <pb n="123"/> Afterwards <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and I went up to <persName ref="#Woodward_Haven_Mrs">Mrs. Woodward Haven</persName>'s rooms to pay a visit and say goodbye. Weather very warm - off tomorrow for <placeName ref="#Milan">Milan</placeName>.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-04-28" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-04-28">Wednesday. April 28th</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>A very busy morning with <persName ref="#Parsons_Mary">Mary</persName> - <persName ref="#Buttles_Lizzie">Lizzie</persName> and the girls came to lunch - and at 2 o'clock we had to say goodbye to <persName ref="#Buttles_Lizzie">Lizzie</persName> and <persName ref="#Parsons_Mary">Mary</persName> - and <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName>, <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and I started for <placeName ref="#Milan">Milan</placeName>, which we reached comfortably enough at 10 o'clock - taking possession of our old, pleasant rooms at this <placeName type="hotel" ref="#Hotel_Cavour">Hotel Cavour</placeName>.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-04-29" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-04-29">Thursday. April 29</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p><persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName>, <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I started out at 10 o'clock for the <placeName>Brera</placeName> - where we stayed quite 2 hours - this afternoon <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I drove to the other end of everywhere, to the interesting little church of <name type="historical" ref="#Basilica_of_Sant_Eustorgio">S. Eustorgio</name>. We found it was a festa, and the little piazza in front of the church full of bazaars and peasants. As the especial picture we wanted to see was near the entrance, we got the wife of the Sacristan to open it for us - the <name type="object" ref="#Madonna_between_ss_James_and_Henry">picture</name> is a lovely one of the Madonna enthroned by <persName ref="#Bergognone_Ambrogio">Borgognone</persName>. The 3 different entrances to the church were lined with collections of blind, lame and halt, and the poor things all begging. Then we drove along distance to <placeName ref="#Basilica_of_Sant_Ambrogio">S. Ambrogio</placeName>, which I saw some years ago. Here there was a great service going on, and we could see nothing. So we came home, stopping on the way to buy some flowers. What a contrast to <placeName ref="#Florence">Florence</placeName> - which was literally lined with flowers and roses. Here not a flower for sale on the streets, and hardly any <pb n="124"/> shops to be found of them. The streets of <placeName ref="#Milan">Milan</placeName> are now so intersected by tramways that driving is impossible and uncomfortable. We found <persName ref="#Fitz_Hardinge_Lord">Lord Fitzhardinge</persName> and his party here just on their way up from <placeName ref="#Egypt">Egypt</placeName>, and <persName ref="#Bridgman_Dr">Dr. Bridgman</persName> came to dine with us - and stayed until nearly 12 o'clock - talking continually in his amusing way. They go tomorrow direct to <placeName ref="#London">London</placeName> - <persName ref="#Clarence">Clarence</persName> came back from <placeName ref="#Venice">Venice</placeName>, enthusiastic, in time for dinner.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-04-30" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-04-30">Friday. April 30</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>This morning we spent at the <name type="historical" ref="#Museo_Poldi_Pezzoli">Poldo Pozzoli</name>, and <name type="historical" ref="#Biblioteca_Ambrosiana">Ambrosiana</name> - delightful but tiring. In the afternoon <persName ref="#Bridgman_Dr">Dr. Bridgman</persName> and <persName ref="#Clarence">Clarence</persName> and <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> went to the <placeName ref="#Brera">Brera</placeName> - afterwards to the <name type="historical" ref="#Duomo_di_Milano">Cathedral</name> - and back in time for lunch. It was so pleasant in our sitting room with its big windows opening to the Park, and the sweet fragrant air pouring in, that after tea we walked over, and looked at the trees, and the swans and pheasants. A beautiful soft evening, with great masses of clouds, touched with rosy light, giving promise of rain tomorrow. We start for <placeName ref="#Turin">Turin</placeName> at 11:30 tomorrow morning.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-05-01" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-05-01">Saturday. May 1st</date>. <placeName ref="#Turin">Turin</placeName>. <name type="hotel" ref="#Grand_Hotel_de_Turin">Grand Hotel de Turin</name>.
          </dateline>
          <p>We left <placeName ref="#Milan">Milan</placeName> at 10:30 this morning and arrived here at 2 P.M. After lunch we went immediately to the <name type="historical" ref="#Palazzo_dell_Accademia_delle_Scienze">Mus&#233;e</name>, to see the Egyptian things we had so long wanted to see. After climbing 2 huge stone staircases we came to the <placeName ref="#Museo_Egizio">Egyptian department</placeName>, and looked in for a moment, and then <pb n="125"/> went on to the next floor very foolishly to see the paintings. Not much that is interesting, though we were much interested in seeing <name type="object" ref="#The_Holy_Family_with_the_Infant_St_John_the_Baptist">the Bugiardini</name> with the little St. John, almost the exact counterpart of the St. John in <placeName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore's</placeName> <name type="object" ref="#The_Virgin_and_Child_with_the_young_Saint_John_the_Baptist_and_an_angel">so called Francia</name>. The subject was the Madonna and Child, adored by the infant St. John and a lovely picture it was. <persName ref="#Berenson_Bernard">Berenson</persName> had written <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> a year or more ago, that his picture was a <persName ref="#Bugiardini_Giuliano">Bugiardini</persName> and not a <persName ref="#Francia_Francesco">Francia</persName> and the other day at <placeName ref="#Fiesole">Fiesole</placeName> he had shown him the photograph of this <name type="object" ref="#The_Holy_Family_with_the_Infant_St_John_the_Baptist">Turin picture</name>, and quite convinced him of <persName ref="#Bugiardini_Giuliano">Bugiardini</persName> as the artist. We lingered so long with these pictures that we were too late for the <placeName ref="#Museo_Egizio">Egyptian gallery</placeName> - and put our visit off for tomorrow morning. Then we drove about the town, with its handsome well shaded streets and modern houses, and picturesque river bank, and were quite delighted with it - but long before we had finished our drive, one of the horses being rather restive broke his traces, and we were forced to leave the carriage - <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I taking a cab to the hotel, and <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and <persName ref="#Clarence">Clarence</persName> walking. We are having a dull evening - in our big gloomy rooms - <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> is not well - seems to have taken cold, and has been sleeping ever since dinner.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-05-03" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-05-03">Monday, May 3d</date>. <name type="hotel" ref="#Hotel_Westminster">Hotel Westminster</name> - <placeName ref="#Paris">Paris</placeName>.
          </dateline>
          <p>Yesterday morning <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> seemed much better, but not well enough to venture upon a visit to stony, cold galleries. So <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I went off at 10 o'clock for a morning in the Egyptian department. What was our dismay and disgust at finding the <name type="historical" ref="#Palazzo_dell_Accademia_delle_Scienze">Museum</name> did not open until 1 o'clock - <pb n="126"/> and we starting for <placeName ref="#Paris">Paris</placeName> at 2:10! So we ordered lunch at 12:30 and immediately afterwards started again for the <name type="historical" ref="#Palazzo_dell_Accademia_delle_Scienze">Mus&#233;e</name>, intending to drive from there in half an hour to the station, meeting the rest there. On reaching the gallery we deposited our parasols with the custodian and quickly toiled up those great staircases, only to find the doors of the Egyptian department closed! No words could describe our indignation and dismay - we tried bribery - demanded the director, who was not there of course, and baffled and angry we had to return to our hotel - wishing we had gone as usual to <placeName ref="#Paris">Paris</placeName> by the <placeName ref="#Basel">Basle</placeName> and <placeName ref="#Luzern">Lucerne</placeName> route. We got away from <placeName ref="#Turin">Turin</placeName> at 2:30 and found 2 very comfortable compartments reserved for us in the sleeping car - and the afternoon proved delightful. The Scenery was beautiful - grand with splendid effects - I think I never enjoyed a railway ride so much. As with the help of 2 powerful engines we climbed the <placeName ref="#Cenis_Mount">Mt. Cenis</placeName> mountain route, it was charming - green smiling plains - snow tipped mountains - streams of rushing, tumbling water pouring down the mountains sides - and every where fascinating Alpine plants growing - such as we try to cultivate in our rock gardens at home, and generally fail in doing. The night was very comfortable - our beds clean - and by 9 o'clock we were established in our familiar apartments here, which we have already occupied twice before. <placeName ref="#Paris">Paris</placeName> looks quiet. Few Americans here, it is said.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-05-04" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-05-04">Tuesday, May 4</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>This morning I drove with <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> away off to the <placeName ref="#Ave_de_la_Republique">Ave-de la Republique</placeName> to <placeName>Calmonts</placeName> to buy a pair of field glasses for <persName ref="#Fuli_Rais">Fuli</persName>, and another <pb n="127"/> for <persName ref="#Clarence">Clarence</persName>. It was really cold, with piercing winds - and I was very uncomfortable. We stopped at the <name type="hotel" ref="#Hotel_de_France">Hotel de France</name> at <placeName ref="#Choiseul">Choiseul</placeName> to see <persName ref="#Taylor_Mrs">Mrs. Taylor</persName> and <persName ref="#Taylor_Florence">Florence</persName> - and found them both with bad colds, and made them promise to come and dine this evening. They have just gone home.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-05-05" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-05-05">Wednesday. May 5</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>A very dreadful thing happened here yesterday - about 4 o'clock in the afternoon: a charity Bazaar was being held in a large building built and often used for such purposes in the <placeName ref="#Rue_Jean_Goujon">Rue Jean Gonjou</placeName> near the <placeName ref="#Palaiz_de_l_Industrie">Palais de l'Industrie</placeName>. At the time it was crowded with people representing the very best element in French society. The <persName ref="#Charlotte_Sophie_Duchess">Duchesse d'Alen&#231;on</persName> sister of the <persName ref="#Eugenie_Elisabeth_Amalie">Queen of Austria</persName> being at the head of it. Suddenly flames broke out, in an instant the light painted wooden roof was in flames, and within 20 minutes the whole thing with nearly 200 of the audience, who did not succeed in escaping, were all a charred and smoking mass. People escaped without clothing, and shoes. The crowd of waiting carriages did not receive half of their occupants - almost before help could be rendered the thing was over - the <persName ref="#Charlotte_Sophie_Duchess">Duchesse d'Alen&#231;on</persName> was burned at her stall, and no remnant of her has been discovered. The streets are almost silent - a pall over the whole city - one thinks, talks, and sees nothing else. Never was a catastrophe so sudden - so complete - so full of horrible details. The weather is bad - cold - rain and even a little snow. <pb n="128"/></p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-05-06" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-05-06">Thursday. May 6</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>We have plunged into the travail of dress making and shopping which seems almost heartless in this stunned and bereaved city. The daily details of this horrible accident grow worse and more harrowing. The whole civilized world stands aghast. The weather of yesterday repeats itself today, - rain, snow, and cold, cold winds. I am a little wretched - and so is <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName>. <persName ref="#Boal_Terry">Terry Boal</persName> arrived today from <placeName ref="#Thonon">Thonon</placeName> - with his wife - having left the baby with his <persName ref="#Buttles_Sara">Aunt Sara</persName> and <persName ref="#Davis_Annie">Annie</persName> at their home in <placeName ref="#Thonon">Thonon</placeName>. They are on their way to <placeName ref="#United_States_of_America">America</placeName> - and why they have left the baby, with the mothers heart rent with grief, no one can say - their plans seem very vague and uncertain.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-05-07" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-05-07">Friday. May 7</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>This is <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore's</persName> birthday - his 58 birthday. We made a little festa this afternoon, and asked <persName ref="#Taylor_Mrs">Mrs. Taylor</persName> and <persName ref="#Taylor_Florence">Florence</persName> to tea, and <persName ref="#Boal_Terry">Terry</persName> and <persName ref="#Boal_Mathilde">Mathilde</persName> were here. A cold, rainy day - I spent most of the morning in <persName ref="#Bull_Dr">Dr. Bull's</persName> office, having my eyes examined - and this afternoon <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I tried to accomplish something, but were driven home by the wind and rain. <persName ref="#Taylor_Florence">Florence Talylor</persName> came to dinner, and has gone to the <placeName ref="#Paris_Opera">Opera</placeName> with <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName>, <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and <persName ref="#Clarence">Clarence</persName>, to hear <name type="opera" ref="#Lohengrin">Lohengrin</name>. The theatres have been closed for 2 days, on account of the dreadful catastrophe. This morning, I could hardly drive to the Flower market at the <name type="historical" ref="#La_Madeleine">Madeline</name>, on account of the carriages ranged around it, and the front draped in black. This is the day of most of the enterrements - some of the churches are dressed in white, marking the funerals of the young, the others in black. <pb n="129"/></p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-05-16" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <name type="event" ref="#Good_Shepherd_Sunday">Fourth Sunday after Easter</name>. <date when="1897-05-16">May 16</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>A week or more has gone by, with very little to chronicle, except continued bad and gloomy weather and constant shopping and sight seeing and wrestling with <placeName ref="#Paris">Paris</placeName> dressmakers and milliners. It has seemed as if the weather were in mourning with the city. The <persName ref="#Taylor_Florence #Taylor_Mrs">Taylors</persName> dined with us last night and said goodbye and <persName ref="#Boal_Terry">Terry</persName> and <persName ref="#Boal_Mathilde">Mathilde</persName> come to dine tonight. We are off tomorrow for <placeName ref="#London">London</placeName>, and very glad we all are. We are very much delighted these last days because <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> has secured the beautiful <name type="object" ref="#Virgin_and_Child_with_an_Angel">Chigi Madonna</name> of <persName ref="#Botticelli_Sandro">Botticelli</persName> for which he has been bargaining since before we left <placeName ref="#Rome">Rome</placeName>. He has also stumbled upon a charmingly interesting <name type="object" ref="#The_Madonna_and_Child_before_a_red_curtain">painting of a Madonna and Child by that rare old Venetian painter the father of the Venetian school, <persName ref="#Vivarini_Bartolomeo">Bartolemmeo Vivarini</persName>. He saw it a few days ago at <persName ref="#Durand_Ruel_Paul">Durand-Ruel</persName>'s rooms - who had bought it with two or three old Italian daubs at an auction or sale from an old Paris family - he paid 400 dollars for it and evidently did not know its value. It was in a wretched condition - the panel warped and worm eaten. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> wanted it from the first and took me and <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> to see it - we were charmed. <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> pronounced it excellent and when a day or two after <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> heard that the <placeName ref="#Louvre">Louvre</placeName> people were looking at it, he decided to buy it and have it transferred to canvas. He paid 1600 dollars for it. The Madonna is seated with the child on her knee - behind her a red curtain hung on a black cord, a gold background, beautifully dulled and reddened by time - signed - <pb n="130"/>
          </name></p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-05-21" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <placeName ref="#London">London</placeName> - <name type="hotel" ref="#Hotel_Bristol">Hotel Bristol</name>.<date when="1897-05-21">Friday - May 21</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>We came over from <placeName ref="#Paris">Paris</placeName> last Monday the 17th - had a good but cold crossing - but a comfortable cabin, in which <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I stretched ourselves out, and slept almost the whole way over. We have a gorgeous appartment here, on the first floor. <placeName ref="#London">London</placeName> is very empty of Americans. Everyone is I suppose waiting for the <persName ref="#Victoria_Queen">Queen's</persName> 60th anniversary of her reign - it will be a great Jubilee - decorations and scaffoldings for seats are going up everywhere. The weather has been very good ever since our arrival - we have been busy shopping for the house and the dahabeah - seeing pictures and driving. <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I go out to <placeName ref="#Sanderstead_Court">Sanderstead Court</placeName> tomorrow to stay over Sunday with the <persName ref="#Wallace_Miss #Wallace_Mr">Wallaces</persName> - and <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and <persName ref="#Clarence">Clarence</persName> go to <placeName ref="#Oxford">Oxford</placeName> to stay over Sunday.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-05-24" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-05-24">Monday. May 24</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p><persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I came back from <placeName ref="#Sanderstead_Court">Sanderstead Court</placeName> this morning, where we had gone on Saturday to pay a visit to those dear <persName ref="#Wallace_Miss #Wallace_Mr">Wallaces</persName>. The weather was bright - but a cold north east wind blowing - so that it was a great contrast to our last visit there. There was a pleasant house party - especially an interesting old woman, <persName ref="#Ogle_Ms">Miss Ogle of Northumberland</persName> and we talked and walked about the park, and the terrace, and investigated the gardens - <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> sang to them in the evenings, to their great delight. There is such comfort and luxury in these English country houses. <persName ref="#Farrer_Gaspard">Gaspard Farrar</persName> came to dinner tonight. <pb n="131"/> Wednesday evening. May 26. We made our 3d visit to the <placeName ref="#National_Gallery">National Gallery</placeName> this morning - weather cold and threatening. We have found driving, even in the park, disagreeable. Busy shopping and seeing things. Last evening we dined at <persName ref="#Farrar_William_Sir">Sir William Farrars</persName> - and had a charming evening.  <persName ref="#Farrar_William_Sir">Sir William</persName> in spite of his age and infirmities very interesting and agreeable. To the play this evening: "My Friend the Prince". Very laughable.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-05-30" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            Sunday - after <name type="event" ref="#Ascension_Day">Ascension</name>. <date when="1897-05-30">May 30</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p>We spent a delightful day on Thursday. Going out to <placeName ref="#Sevenoaks">Sevenoaks</placeName> where we had lunch at the <placeName ref="#Royal_Crown_Hotel">"Royal Crown"</placeName> and then drove to <placeName ref="#Knole">Knole</placeName> - and saw that wonderful house with its picturesque courts and rooms and countless treasurers. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and I were fascinated with the beautiful Persian rugs, which are said to have been in the house since the time of <persName ref="#Elizabeth_I_Queen">Queen Elizabeth</persName>. Then we walked and drove about the great park with its renowned beeches, until it was time to take the train back to <placeName ref="#London">London</placeName>. <persName ref="#Fielding_Mr">Fielding</persName> was with us. On Friday, <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and <persName ref="#Clarence">Clarence</persName> went to <placeName ref="#Sanderstead_Court">Sanderstead Court</placeName> to lunch - the day cold and stormy. <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I went to the <name ref="#National_Gallery">National Gallery</name>, and took a drive and in the evening we all went to dine with <persName ref="#Fielding_Mr">Fielding</persName> and his sister <persName ref="#Elwes_Cary_Winifred_Lady">Lady Winifride Cary-Elwes</persName> and such a pleasant evening, as they are musical, and <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> sang a great deal - and it was after 12 o'clock when we came home. On Saturday <persName ref="#Fielding_Mr">Fielding</persName> and <persName ref="#Elwes_Cary_Gervase">Mr. Cary-Elwes</persName> came early, and <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> sang the <pb n="132"/> whole morning - they stayed to lunch, and most of the afternoon. Rain all day - <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> went out to <placeName ref="#Hothorpe_Hall">Hothorpe</placeName> to stay until Monday. This morning, the weather being fairly pleasant, we decided, <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName>, <persName ref="#Clarence">Clarence</persName> and I, that we would go to <placeName ref="#Hampton_Court_Palace">Hampton Court</placeName> - and ordered a carriage to be ready at 11 o'clock. Waited until half past, when the porter sent word he had not been able to get a carriage, having tried 3 stables. So very wrathfully we gave up <placeName ref="#Hampton_Court_Palace">Hampton Court</placeName>, and ordered a hansom for the <placeName ref="#National_Gallery">National Gallery</placeName> - which we found closed, the policeman saying it was only open on Sunday from 2 to 6. Then we decided to go to <placeName ref="#Westminster_Abbey">Westminster Abbey</placeName>, where we found the congregation just dispersing, and were told the <placeName ref="#Westminster_Abbey">Abbey</placeName> was closed on Sunday between services. There was nothing then to do but come home and have lunch and start for <placeName>Kno Gardens</placeName> - for which we had ordered a carriage. We spent 2 delightful hours walking about there - and just after we got home, after 6 o'clock, <persName ref="#Davis_Annie">Mrs. Davis</persName>, and <persName ref="#Boal_Terry">Terry Boal</persName> and <persName ref="#Boal_Mathilde">Mathilde</persName> arrived from <placeName ref="#Paris">Paris</placeName>.</p>
        </div>
        <div xml:id="EBA-1897-06-01" type="entry">
          <dateline>
            <date when="1897-06-01">Tuesday evening. June 1st</date>.
          </dateline>
          <p><persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> departed this morning for <placeName ref="#Florence">Florence</placeName>. Afterwards <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and I went to the stores, and at the top of the first staircase, I met <persName ref="#Sandwith_Mrs">Mrs. Sandwith</persName>, just arrived from <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName>, and as she turned away, I saw <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> speaking to <persName ref="#Somers_Clarke_George">Mr. Somers-Clarke</persName> who said he left <placeName ref="#Cario">Cairo</placeName> a few days since, the thermometer had been 106 in the shade - and a damp heat at that. His boat is lying next the <name type="boat" ref="#Beduin">Beduin</name>, at <placeName>Shubron's yards</placeName>. We left cards this afternoon on various friends - and settled our final arrangements - packing etc. <persName ref="#Davis_Annie">Mrs. Davis</persName>, <persName ref="#Clarence">Clarence</persName>, <persName ref="#Boal_Terry">Terry Boal</persName> and <persName ref="#Boal_Mathilde">Mathilde</persName> all took an early <pb n="133"/> dinner, and departed for the <name type="event" ref="#Royal_Tournament">Military Tournament</name> - and at this hour 11:30 are not yet home. <persName ref="#Elwes_Cary_Winifred_Lady">Lady Winifride</persName> and <persName ref="#Elwes_Cary_Gervase">Mr. Cary-Elwes</persName>, <persName ref="#de_Trafford_Agnes_Mary_Pia_Feilding_Lady">Lady Agnes</persName> and <persName ref="#de_Trafford_Charles_Edmund">Mr. de Trafford</persName>, and <persName ref="#Fielding_Mr">Mr. Fielding</persName> came to dinner with <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName>, and me at 8 o'clock, and we had a charming, jolly evening. Delightful people. They have just gone. We are off tomorrow at noon for <placeName ref="#Liverpool">Liverpool</placeName> and will sail about 5 in the afternoon. 11</p>
        </div>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
  </TEI>
  