<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Diary of Mrs. Emma B. Andrews. Volume 9 1901-1902</title>
            <author>
               <persName ref="#Andrews_Emma_B">Emma B. Andrews</persName>
            </author>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Originally prepared by</resp>
               <persName ref="#SLK">Sarah L. Ketchley</persName>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>TEIPublisher development</resp>
               <persName ref="#EF">Emma Fritzberg</persName>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Historical Markup Tool development</resp>
               <persName ref="#AH">Audrey Holmes</persName>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>transcription</resp>
               <persName>name name</persName> <!-- replace with correct names -->
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>proofreading and tagging</resp>
               <persName ref="#SK">Sarah Ketchley</persName>
               <persName ref="#HB">Hannah Burrows</persName>
               <persName ref="#SF">Sabrina Fang</persName>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>biographical research and writing</resp>
               <persName ref="#XX">name name</persName> <!-- replace with correct names -->
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>
               <orgName ref="#EBA_Diary_Project">Emma B. Andrews Diary Project</orgName>
            </publisher>
            <address>
               <addrLine>University of Washington, Seattle, WA</addrLine>
            </address>
            <availability>
               <licence target="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/">This work is
                  licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International
                  License.</licence>
            </availability>
            <date>08-2020</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p><orgName ref="#American_Philosophical_Society">American Philosophical
               Society</orgName>,<placeName ref="#Philadelphia">Philadelphia</placeName></p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Established in 2010, the goals of the <orgName ref="#EBA_Diary_Project">Emma B.
               Andrews Diary Project</orgName> include the transcription and digitization of a
               wide range of primary historical material from the 'Golden Age' of Egyptian
               archaeology at the end of the 19th and beginning of the 20th centuries. A founding
               partner of <orgName ref="#Newbook_Digital_Texts">Newbook Digital Texts</orgName>
               (www.newbookdigitaltexts.org), the <orgName ref="#EBA_Diary_Project">EBA Diary
                  Project</orgName> offers undergraduate and graduate digital humanities education
               and internships at the <orgName ref="#University_of_Washington">University of
                  Washington</orgName>.
               <persName ref="#Andrews_Emma_B">Emma B. Andrews</persName> is best remembered for her
               association with the millionaire lawyer turned archaeologist/art and antiquities
               collector, <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore M. Davis</persName>. Traveling
               to <placeName ref="#Egypt">Egypt</placeName> with him between 1889 and 1913, she kept
               detailed journals of these voyages along the <placeName ref="#Nile">Nile</placeName>,
               including his important yet under-reported excavations of over 20 significant tombs
               in the <placeName ref="#Bībān al-Mulūk">Valley of the Kings</placeName>.
               <persName ref="#Andrews_Emma_B">Emma</persName> provides a vital commentary on the
               archaeology and pioneering Egyptologists of the time, painting a revealing picture of
               the lives of the colonial gentry and the cultural and scientific literati in at the
               dawn of the twentieth century. Analysis of the content of her diaries, along with a
               broad range of additional primary source material, will afford scholars information
               about important historical resources for the first time.</p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <correction>
               <p>Obvious misspellings (eg place names and people's names) which are misreadings of original handwritten diary are corrected
                  with choice, sic and corr.</p>
            </correction>
            <normalization>
               <p>Original spelling and typography is otherwise retained.</p>
            </normalization>
         </editorialDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <list>
            <item>
               <date when="2021-08-02">2 August 2021</date> create XML update header by SLK</item>
            <item>
               <date when="2021-08-15">15 August 2021</date> HB added output from Historical Markup
               Tool and began separating entries
            </item>
            <item>
               <date when="2021-08-26">26 August 2021</date> HB reorganized entries so they were in
               correct date order and matched typewriter transcript
            </item>
            <item>
               <date when="2021-10-31">31 October 2021</date> HB finished separating entries and
               adding date tags
            </item>
            <item>
               <date when="2022-03-31">31 March 2022</date> HB and SF finished initial tagging.
            </item>
         </list>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1901-11-20" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <placeName ref="Naples">Naples</placeName> &#8211; <name type="hotel" ref="#Grand_Hotel">Grand Hotel</name>.
            <date when="1901-11-20">Nov. 20, 1901</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            We arrived this morning after a rough and disagreeable voyage. There was not a day when I
             could have written an intelligible word. We sailed in the Hamburg
             <name type="boat" ref="#SS_Columbia">SS. Columbia</name> from <placeName ref="#New_York">
            New York</placeName> the <date when="1901-11-09">9th of November</date>,
             <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName>, <persName ref="#Koon_Bessie">Bessie
             Koon</persName> and I. We passed the <choice><sic>asores</sic><corr><placeName ref="#Azores">
            Azores</placeName></corr></choice> on <date when="1901-11-14">Thursday the 14th</date>
             but the weather was so thick they could just be discerned. Reached <placeName ref="#Gibraltar">
            Gibraltar</placeName> at 3 P.M. <date when="1901-11-17">the 17th</date> &#8211; were off again in two
             hours &#8211; touched at <placeName ref="#Algiers">Algiers</placeName> at 4 o'clock on <date when="1901-11-18">the 18th</date>. It did
             not look very attractive and it was too late and stormy to land. <placeName ref="#Naples">Naples</placeName>
             is radiantly beautiful &#8211; splendid weather. We are in our old rooms &#8211;
             <placeName ref="#Vesuvius">Vesuvius</placeName> very quiet. <persName ref="#Bronson_Ethel">Ethel Bronson</persName> who crossed
             with us, went on to <placeName ref="#Genoa">Genoa</placeName>.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1901-11-24" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1901-11-24">Sunday evening. Nov. 24</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            We are obliged to stay here until Thursday of next week, and then take that long railway
             journey over to <placeName ref="#Brindisi">Brindisi</placeName>, to catch our <orgName ref="#Österreichischer_Lloyd">Austrian Lloyd</orgName>
             S.S. We had hoped to get rooms on the <name type="boat" ref="#Prins_Heinrich">Prins Heinrich</name>
             going from here the same Thursday, on which will be <persName ref="#Agassiz_Mr">Mr.
             <choice><sic>Agassig</sic><corr>Agassiz</corr></choice></persName> and
             his son <persName ref="#Agassiz_Max">Max</persName> on their way to <placeName ref="#Sri_Lanka">Ceylon</placeName>.
             <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> wrote for these rooms 3 months ago &#8211; but on reaching
             here found there was no chance for them. Two young men, who are to go with
             <persName ref="#Agassiz_Mr"><choice><sic>Agassig</sic><corr>Agassiz</corr></choice></persName>
             came over on the <name type="boat" ref="#SS_Columbia">Columbia</name> with us.
             <persName ref="#Woodward_Dr">Dr. Woodward</persName> and <persName ref="#Bigelow_Mr">Mr. Bigelow</persName> from
             <placeName ref="#Boston">Boston</placeName> &#8211; such pleasant fellows. They are constantly with
             us. The weather has been unsettled for 2 days. Yesterday <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName>
             and the young people went up to <placeName ref="#Vesuvius">Vesuvius</placeName>. Today it has rained, and hailed several times
             &#8211; the clouds clearing away and returning suddenly - vivid lightning. We have been
             in doors all day.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1901-11-25" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1901-11-25">Tuesday, Nov. 25th</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            I have never known a stormier day - and it followed a night of roaring wind. It has
             rained without ceasing - and no one has been out. Yesterday was clearing, with clear
             skies, and a bracing <name type="event" ref="#Tramontana">Tramontana</name> air that was delicious.
             <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName>, <persName ref="#Koon_Bessie">Bessie</persName>
             and <persName ref="#Bigelow_Mr">Mr. Bigelow</persName> went
             to <placeName ref="#Pompeii">Pompeii</placeName>, and came home enchanted with their visit.
             <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I drove and shopped and talked, and were happy.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1901-11-26" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1901-11-26">Wednesday, Nov. 26.</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            We all had a fine drive this morning, and stopped at the
             <name type="hotel" ref="#Hotel_Splendide">Hotel Splendide</name>, one of <persName ref="#Bertalini_Mr">
            Bertalini</persName>'s hotels to see it. It is splendidly situated, almost on the level of
             <placeName ref="#Capodimonte">Capo di Monte</placeName>, and <placeName ref="#San_Martino">San Martino</placeName>. It has just been
             opened - and is very attractive. The <placeName ref="#Naples">Naples</placeName> tram lands you
             just below the hotel, where a huge lift has been built straight through the rock -
             and you are carried straight up to the restaurant level, which is at the top of the
             house. We, however, preferred to drive to the entrance. The third floor of the
             hotel retreats far enough from the front of the two lower floors to give a very
             wide esplanade or terrace, running the whole length of the building, and giving
             the most fascinating view of the whole of that wonderful region - the city below,
             the sea, the islands and <placeName ref="#Vesuvius">Vesuvius</placeName>. The hotel is furnished quite
             in the <name type="hotel" ref="#Waldorf_Astoria">Waldorf Astoria</name> style heated by steam - and arranged
             with many appartments, so that you can have your own sitting room and dining room -
             bath rooms galore. We did not know the house was opened, or we would have stayed
             there. Just a little below the hotel, is a piece of property, consisting of a large
             courtyard, with a charming, rambling little house opening by many long windows to a
             little verandah on the terrace, and lovely garden terraces below. It is built in a
             childish, foolish fashion, simulating a ruined tower etc. but there was something
             attractive about. I wanted to buy at once - it was empty and unfurnished, but in
             very good order - an English lady having lived in it for 2
             years. We all adopted it. <persName ref="#Woodward_Dr">Woodward</persName> and
             <persName ref="#Bigelow_Mr">Bigelow</persName> as well as the rest of us - and call it our
             <name>Villa del Torre</name>. <persName ref="#Koon_Bessie">Bessie</persName> went off to
             <placeName ref="#Florence">Florence</placeName> at 3 o'clock - a little sad - and
             <persName ref="#Woodward_Dr">Woodward</persName>, <persName ref="#Bigelow_Mr">Bigelow</persName>,
             <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName>, <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">
            Nettie</persName> and I drove up to the <name type="hotel" ref="#Hotel_Splendide">Splendide</name>
             to dine - in an open carriage in the brilliant moonlight.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1901-11-27" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1901-11-27">Thursday, Nov. 27</date>,
             	<placeName ref="#Brindisi">Brindisi</placeName> - <name type="hotel" ref="#Hotel_International">Hotel International</name>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            A weary ride from <placeName ref="#Naples">Naples-</placeName> starting at 12, and arriving at 10
             P.M. We find this dismal hotel somewhat improved. The boys came down to the station
             to see us off, and brought me some flowers. They hope for the tardy arrival of their
             steamer tonight. Our steamer is due at 3 tomorrow.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1901-12-01" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> - <name type="hotel" ref="#Shepheards_Hotel">Shepheards</name> -
             <date when="1901-12-01">Dec. 1st - Monday</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            We have had fearful experiences since my last entry. The <name type="boat" ref="#Cleopatra_boat">Cleopatra</name> of the
             <orgName ref="#Österreichischer_Lloyd">Austrian Lloyd Line</orgName> arrived at
             <placeName ref="#Brindisi">Brindisi</placeName> on time, and we were soon off, and found a gale
             outside waiting for us. It was very cold too. <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I
             went to bed at once to get warm, - the night was hideously rough. We did not get
             up until before dinner next evening, when we went to table - but only stayed
             through 3 courses. Hardly any one at table - the roof leaking - pools of water
             here and there, dishes smashing - moving about dangerous. We got back to our
             cabins as soon as possible and into our beds which we did not leave until 6 o'clock
             this morning, after we had succeeded in getting into harbour. The boat was
             indescribably dirty - cockroaches crawling over everything - no service - 2 old
             hags of stewardesses. The last night was really awful - I was quite worn out with
             trying to keep in bed - and the raging of the storm - the tons of water pouring
             upon the deck over my head - and the fact that we might not be able to get over
             the bar at the harbour, drove all sleep and rest away - we did get in however
             in a lull of the storm but the wind and rain began again as soon as we had
             landed. We caught the morning train, and arrived at noon - and are once more
             settled in our old rooms looking on the garden. We found
             <persName ref="#Tytus_Mrs">Mrs. Tytus</persName> and <persName ref="#Tytus_Bob">Bob</persName> here waiting for
             their boat to be finished - and <persName ref="#Newberry_Percy">Mr. Newberry</persName> came to
             tea with us - he left this evening for <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName>.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1901-12-08" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1901-12-08">Monday, Dec. 8th</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            A busy week here, pushing on our preparations on the boat. It has been cold and
            rough - almost unprecedented weather it is said. But the good north wind has lately
            been blowing, and we are anxious to get off while it lasts.
            <persName ref="#von_Bissing_Baron">Baron v. Bissing</persName> is going with us as far as
            <placeName ref="#Asyut">Assiut</placeName>. We dined at the
            <name type="hotel" ref="#Ghezireh_Palace_Hotel"><choice><sic>Chesireh</sic><corr>Ghezireh</corr></choice></name>
            last evening and had <persName ref="#Quibell_James #Quibell_Annie_Pirie">Mr. and Mrs. Quibell</persName> and
            <persName ref="#Tytus_Bob">Bob Tytus</persName> with us. Have had tea at the
            <persName ref="#Quibell_James #Quibell_Annie_Pirie">Quibell</persName>'s, in their pleasant quarters.
            There have been improvements at the
            <name type="hotel" ref="#Ghezireh_Palace_Hotel"><choice><sic>Chesireh</sic><corr>Ghezireh</corr></choice></name>.
            They have opened a big chimney in the great hall - and it is not only comfortable but
            cheerful. Tea with <persName ref="#Sandwith_Mrs">Mrs. Sandwith</persName>.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1901-12-10" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1901-12-10">Tuesday evening, Dec. 10th</date>. <name type="boat" ref="#Beduin">Beduin</name>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            We are once more in this dear little home, with its many interests. We had
             <persName ref="#Tytus_Mrs">Mrs. Tytus</persName> and <persName ref="#Tytus_Bob">Bob</persName>,
             <persName ref="#Baltassi_Mme">Mme. Baltassi</persName> and her daughters to tea. We hope to get
             off tomorrow. I forgot to enter the strange incident of the fate of the
             <name type="boat" ref="#Cleopatra_boat">Cleopatra</name>. A few hours after we landed, the
             <name type="boat" ref="#Messagrius">Messagrius</name> steamer trying to make a landing in the gale,
             fell foul of the <name type="boat" ref="#Cleopatra_boat">Cleopatra</name>, and crushed into her
             broadsides, literally cutting her in half - she sank in a few moments and now lies
             in the bottom of the harbour. No lives lost.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1901-12-11" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1901-12-11">Wednesday, Dec. 11th</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            <persName ref="#von_Bissing_Baron">Baron v. Bissing</persName> appeared promptly at 10 o'clock having
            sent his luggage and a box of huge books last evening so that
            <persName ref="#Jones_Daniel">Jones</persName> had his room quite ready for him. I wanted to go to
            the zoo to see the magnificent lion again, but everything was so sticky with mud
            from the rain of yesterday, that I decided to stay at home and busy myself with
            getting in order in my room - About two we started with a very light wind - and made
            more or less progress. We passed the "<name type="boat" ref="#Seven_Hathors">Seven Hathor's</name>",
            <persName ref="#Wilbur_Mr">Mr. Wilbur</persName>'s old boat, and soon lost sight of her. Then
            the "<name type="boat" ref="#Safa">Sa &#8216;fa</name>" flying the English flag - both of which had started
            out sometime before us. Tied up for the night near
            <placeName ref="#Ţurá">Turah</placeName> - making 6 miles.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1901-12-12" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1901-12-12">Thursday, Dec. 12</date>. 14 miles.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            A Heavy fog on the river this morning and did not get away until after 9 o'clock.
             The day has been warm and charming - we got on the sand about four o'clock and
             although worked hard until after 7, we did not get off, until the <name type="boat" ref="#Safa">Sa &#8216;fa</name>
             came up to us, and sent her men over to help us - when we were soon free - and
             both boats tied up for the night. The silver crescent of the new moon appeared
             tonight. This little home seems more charming than ever - its prettiness -
             its compactness, its convenience make it delightful. And now the days of repose
             and pleasant sensible occupation begin!
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1901-12-13" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1901-12-13">Friday, Dec. 13</date>. 36 miles. <placeName ref="#Al-Wasta">Wasta</placeName>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            An encouraging run - we might have gone on for another hour, but that the
             <persName ref="#von_Bissing_Baron">Baron</persName> had to stop for his mail. He,
             <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName>,
             <persName ref="#Jones_Daniel">Jones</persName> and 2 of our men went into the town and
             were not home until after dark. We will not have our mail until we reach <placeName ref="#Al_Minya">Minieh</placeName>.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1901-12-14" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1901-12-14">Saturday, Dec. 14</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            Still <placeName ref="#Al-Wasta">Wasta</placeName> - a dead calm all day - but warm and pleasant.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1901-12-15" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            Third Sunday in <name type="event" ref="Advent">Advent</name>. <date when="1901-12-15">Dec. 15</date>. 5 miles.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            We have tracked, polled and pulled to an anchor most of the day - with helps from
             an occasional puff of wind, - clear and warm. We have lost sight of the
             <name type="boat" ref="#Seven_Hathors">Seven Hathors</name> and the
             <name type="boat" ref="#Safa">Sa &#8216;fa</name>.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1901-12-16" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1901-12-16">Monday, Dec. 16</date>. 10 miles.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            With a light wind and much tracking we have come to within 3 miles of
             <placeName ref="#Benisoef">Benisoef</placeName>.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1901-12-17" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1901-12-17">Tuesday, Dec. 17</date>. 10 miles.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            The record of yesterday again.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1901-12-18" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1901-12-18">Wednesday, Dec. 18</date>. 23 miles.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            A light wind during the morning, freshening in the afternoon brought us to
             <placeName ref="#Al_Fashn">Feshn</placeName> about two o'clock - where we stopped to get mail for
             <persName ref="#von_Bissing_Baron">v. Bissing</persName> and butter and yeast for ourselves. A lovely day - our new
             little moon makes it quite light enough to sail into the evening.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1901-12-19" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1901-12-19">Thursday, Dec. 19</date>. 53 miles. <placeName ref="#Al_Minya">Minieh</placeName>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            We are very proud of our record today. The wind has not been strong but fair
             and persistent and kept unfalteringly along - the pleasant rippling of the water
             making music that I love. Sailed until 10 - and after dinner all went up on
             deck to enjoy the marvellous night. Most pleasantly occupied all day.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1901-12-20" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1901-12-20">Friday Dec. 20</date>. 17 miles.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            <persName ref="#Jones_Daniel">Jones</persName> went off to the town today before breakfast and came
             back with a crammed mailbag - and a very discouraging mass of newspapers - and
             with the information that the <name type="boat" ref="#Istar">Istar</name> is just below us - and that
             he had gone on board to speak to <persName ref="#Sayce_Archibald">Mr. Sayce</persName>. Soon after
             <persName ref="#Sayce_Archibald">Mr. Sayce</persName> himself appeared, looking very well I thought - with
             dire tales of having broken his rudder near <placeName ref="#Jirjā">Abu Girgeh</placeName>
             and having to spend days in getting it repaired. He has
             <persName ref="Ward_Mr">Mr. Ward</persName> the writer on Scarabs and
             other topics with him - and <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> asked them to come
             into dinner if they should find themselves near us tonight. But we have sailed them
             out of sight, and are now lying about 3 miles above
             <placeName ref="#Bani_Hasan">Beni Hassan</placeName>. The night is incomparably lovely!
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1901-12-21" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1901-12-21">Saturday, Dec. 21</date>. 8-1/2 miles.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            <placeName ref="#Rhoda">Rhodah</placeName> - with a light wind we have worked hard to
             reach this place - we did at 6 o'clock - warm and pleasant.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1901-12-22" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            4th Sunday in <name type="event" ref="Advent">Advent</name> - <date when="1901-12-22">Dec. 22</date>.
            <placeName ref="#Rhoda">Rhodah</placeName>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            We are still lying here - there being no wind. We are opposite the town, and at the
             site of the ancient <placeName ref="#Sheikh_Ibada">Antinopolis</placeName> and we walked this
             morning to its ruins, a short distance away, and saw the columns of
             <persName ref="#Rameses_II">Ramses's II</persName> temple, standing deep down in the rubbish.
             The sun was so hot that after climbing about over the mounds of potshords
             <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I came back to the boat.
             <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and
             <persName ref="#von_Bissing_Baron">v. Bissing</persName> kept on.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1901-12-23" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1901-12-23">Monday, Dec. 23</date>. 5 miles.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            Tracked and polled all the morning, and came in view of a dahabeah, which turned out
             to be the "<name type="boat" ref="#Hafiz">Hafiz</name>" with the
             <persName ref="#Christian_George_Henry #Christian_Leonara #Christian_Henry #Christian_George_Chase #Christian_Carolyn">Christian family</persName>, under
             <persName ref="#Salah_Mohammed">Salah</persName>'s care. We pulled up a little behind them and
             young <persName ref="#Christian_Henry">Christian</persName> came over for a few moments this evening.
             We gave him all our late papers among which was <persName ref="#Roosevelt_Theodore">President
             Roosevelt</persName>'s first message to Congress,
             in which we had been much interested, and sent him on his way rejoicing.
             Very hot all day.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1901-12-24" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1901-12-24">Tuesday, Dec. 24</date>. 8 miles.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            We had only a breath of wind today, but pulled along until we arrived at
             <placeName ref="#Hag_Kandil">Haji Kandil</placeName>, where the
             <persName ref="#Christian_George_Henry #Christian_Leonara #Christian_Henry #Christian_George_Chase #Christian_Carolyn">Christians</persName>
             also stopped - as we intended going to see the pavement of <name type="historical" ref="#Northern_Palace">Khaenaten's
             Palace</name>. We went across the river at 3:30 - and walked across to the
             house which <persName ref="#Petrie_William">Petrie</persName> has had constructed over this pavement
             to preserve it. A noisy lot of children and men followed us - and made it very
             disagreeable. The pavement is not so ruined as I thought it would be, and the
             graceful designs of birds and flowers, trees etc. so well known from publications,
             were charmingly interesting - as well as some remains of columns and sculptures
             characteristic of the period. We stopped on the <name type="boat" ref="#Hafiz">Hafiz</name>
             for tea - and saw a clean and most amusing little monkey - and well behaved.
             <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I have been very busy all day, with our
              preparations. It has been cooler and overcast today.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1901-12-25" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1901-12-25">Wednesday, Dec. 25</date>. <name type="event" ref="#Christmas">Christmas</name>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            We made quite a brave show at breakfast this morning with our gifts and decorations -
             and were very merry. The deck was as usual beautifully trimmed with palm branches,
             and other greens. <persName ref="#von_Bissing_Baron">Baron v. Bissing</persName> went across the river
             soon after lunch, and spent the afternoon prowling about the site of the old
             city of <placeName ref="#Amarna">Tel Amarna</placeName> and came home in great glee laden
             with spoils, - two or three quite valuable ones. The day has been bright, with
             cool south wind-- and we have not stirred.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1901-12-26" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1901-12-26">Thursday, Dec. 26</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            Such a strong wind we could not start this morning - something peculiar in the weather
             - very hazy - we have been on the look out for 2 days for <persName ref="#Tytus_Bob">Bob
             Tytus</persName> and his new steamer "<name type="boat" ref="#Scarab">The Scarab</name>". Just as we
             were finishing lunch <persName ref="#Jones_Daniel">Jones</persName> came in and said the
             <name type="boat" ref="#Scarab">Scarab</name> was just on us. We all jumped up and rushed on deck to
             give a hearty salute. She pulled up just ahead of us and we went on board. Found
             <persName ref="#Newberry_Percy">Mr. Newberry</persName> with them. They left <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName>
             Monday afternoon. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> had seen the boat several
             times unfitted and was not hopeful of her comfort and appearance; but happily was
             much blessed. We were all indeed delighted with the comfort and beauty of the
             interior. <persName ref="#Tytus_Mrs">Mrs. Tytus</persName> and <persName ref="#Tytus_Bob">Bob</persName> have
             shown a very pretty taste in the whole matter. I never saw a prettier interior.
             After an hour's visit they went off anxious to reach <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName>
             as soon as possible. Our old Captain <persName ref="#Achmed_Rais">Achmed</persName> of
             the <name type="boat" ref="#Nubia">Nubia</name> is their captain. The wind fell about 4
             o'clock, and we tracked for a mile.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1901-12-27" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1901-12-27">Friday, Dec. 27</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            We have made a good run, and 37 miles, lying now about 10 miles above
             <placeName ref="#Manfalût">Manfalout</placeName>. Passed the great
             <placeName ref="#Jabal_Abū_Fūdah">Gebel Abu Fedu</placeName> chain very successfully, until the last
             turn, where we always come to grief &#8211; we had to track &#8211; but afterwards
             sailed steadily and splendidly through the beautiful evening until 9 o'clock.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1901-12-28" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1901-12-28">Dec. 28. Saturday</date>. 16 miles. <placeName ref="#Asyut">Assiut</placeName>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            We sailed in a light wind until we reached <placeName ref="#Asyut">Assiut</placeName> at 1:30. It
             was very exciting going through the new canal, past the barrage for the 1st time. A
             huge wail for us and for <persName ref="#von_Bissing_Baron">v. Bissing</persName>
             &#8211; and the salon looks like a business office
             this evening. Last year we took 24 days to reach here &#8211; this year 17!
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1901-12-29" type="entry">
         <dateline>
             First Sunday after Christmas. <date when="1901-12-29">Dec. 29</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            A strong cold north wind has been blowing all day &#8211; and bringing to us the smoke
             of the great dredges at the barrage, so that being on deck was nasty.
             <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and the
             <persName ref="#von_Bissing_Baron">Baron</persName> went over soon after
             breakfast to the cemetery of <placeName ref="#Naj_Arab_al_Burj">Arab el Burg</placeName> &#8211; where a
             process of rifling by the natives has gone on for 2 years &#8211; and some very
             interesting things have appeared. <persName ref="#von_Bissing_Baron">V. Bissing</persName> expects to do some
             investigation, and <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> thinks he may join with him. They
             took <persName ref="#Jones_Daniel">Jones</persName>, and a lunch basket, three sailors, and crossed the
             river to where their donkeys were waiting. They did not come back until 5 o'clock,
             laden with some queer treasures &#8211; and reported an interesting day &#8211; and a
             long ride &#8211; the most beautiful he had ever taken in <placeName ref="#Egypt">Egypt</placeName>
             &#8211; <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> said.
             <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I did not go off the boat.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1901-12-30" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1901-12-30">Monday. Dec. 30</date>. 38 miles.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            We have made a run of 38 miles &#8211; not leaving <placeName ref="#Asyut">Assiut</placeName> until
             11 o'clock. The <name type="boat" ref="#Istar">Istar</name> came along at 9 o'clock and pulled up ahead of us.
             <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and the <persName ref="#von_Bissing_Baron">Baron</persName> paid a short visit
             to <persName ref="#Sayce_Archibald">Mr. Sayce</persName> and then on donkeys, <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName>
             and I in a wretched victoria went into the town to find an antiquity merchant, who
             was not at home. We are near <placeName ref="#Tahta">Tahtah</placeName> tonight.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1901-12-31" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1901-12-31">Tuesday, Dec. 31</date>. 40 miles.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            A fine strong wind all the morning brought us at 1:30 to <placeName ref="#Sohag">Sohag</placeName>,
             where we stopped only for a few moments to get our mail. Tied up this evening a mile
             below <placeName ref="#Mensheeh">Menshieh</placeName>! Day cool and fine,
             <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> read us this evening
             "<bibl><author><persName ref="#Tennyson_Alfred">Tennyson</persName></author>'s
               <title>Ring out Wild <choice><sic>Belle</sic><corr>Bells</corr></choice></title></bibl>"
             - and <persName ref="#von_Bissing_Baron">v. Bissing</persName> told us of the German customs
             pertaining to <name type="event" ref="#Sylvesters_Eve">Sylvester's Eve</name>.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-01-01" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-01-01">Wednesday, Jan. 1, 1902</date>. 21 miles.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            A cool bright day. We reached <placeName ref="#Jirjā">Girgeh</placeName> about 10 o'clock, and saw off
             in the desert opposite the house of <persName ref="#Reisner_George">Reisner</persName>, and the
             American flag flying. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> decided to stop,
             and make a visit to see how his excavations among the tombs are coming on. He and
             <persName ref="#von_Bissing_Baron"> v. Bissing</persName> went over, stayed to lunch and were not home until 3
             o'clock, when we went on, and drew up at the ugly high bank at
             <placeName ref="#Belliana">Belliana</placeName>, at 6:30 where the
             <name type="boat" ref="#Azaz">Azaz</name> was lying. A
             beautiful effect this morning on the <placeName ref="#Al_Manshāh">Gebel Tourk</placeName> just before
             reaching <placeName ref="#Jirjā">Girgeh</placeName> - the mist on the river giving an
             Alpine effect to its bold outlines.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-01-02" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-01-02">Thursday evening - Jan. 2</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            We are all so tired tonight after our excursion to
             <placeName ref="#Abydos">Abydos</placeName> - I went in my chair, the rest on donkeys - which were
             very bad as always. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName>, and
             <persName ref="#von_Bissing_Baron">v. Bissing</persName>
             went over to <persName ref="#Petrie_William">Petrie</persName>'s camp - but the poor little beasts in my
             chair were not equal to it - and as the sky was threatening we came dragging home at a
             snail's pace - we were all safely in the boat before the sharp thunder storm broke,
             and the rain fell in torrents. I never saw such a storm before in
             <placeName ref="#Egypt">Egypt</placeName>, -the effects were superb. Two steamers here tonight -
             <name type="boat" ref="#Azaz">Azaz</name> went off early this morning.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-01-03" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-01-03">Friday evening, Jan. 3</date>. 16 miles.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            We have had a strange day - cold -occasionally rain -
             no sun - I went on deck about 4:30 - and found it like one of our early cold spring
             days in the north, - the intense green of the cultivated land along the shore - the
             unusual smell of rain - and the wet look of everything, was quite like home - we have
             just had a long and animated talk with <persName ref="#von_Bissing_Baron">v. Bissing</persName> on
             <persName ref="#Ruskin_John">Ruskin</persName>, <persName ref="#Grimm_Brothers">Grimm</persName>
             and <persName ref="#Thode_Henry">Thode</persName>. How amusing everybody is!
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-01-04" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-01-04">Saturday, Jan. 4</date>. 27 miles.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            Made an early start in order to get through the bridge,
             thinking it opened at 7:30 - but had to wait until 9 o'clock - got through in fine
             style and brought up 14 miles below <placeName ref="#Keneh">Keneh</placeName> about 7 o'clock.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-01-05" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            Second Sunday after Christmas. <date when="1902-01-05">Jan. 5</date>. 34 miles.
         </dateline>
         <p>
             A beautiful warm day - with good wind - passed <placeName ref="#Keneh">Keneh</placeName>
             about noon, where the <name type="boat" ref="#Zenet-el-Nil">Zenet el Nil</name> was
             lying going down - and soon overtook the <name type="boat" ref="#Gazelle">Gazelle</name> and exchanged greetings.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-01-06" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-01-06">Monday, Jan. 6</date>. 14 miles.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            We are lying within 10 miles of <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName>,
             and have been slowly moving the whole day.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-01-06" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-01-07">Tuesday, Jan. 7</date>. 10 miles. <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            Arrived shortly after noon - and coming slowly past the town, found the
             <name type="boat" ref="#Scarab">Scarab</name> lying above the <placeName ref="#Castle_Carter">Castle</placeName>, and pulled
             up a little distance ahead of her - against a high bank to be sure, but a sloping
             one, covered with a sweet green crop of wheat - we have taken 27 days less 3 hours
             from <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> - last year we took 37 days. Found a big mail
             waiting for us. <persName ref="#Tytus_Mrs">Mrs. Tytus</persName> and <persName ref="#Tytus_Bob">Bob</persName> came
             to dinner.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-01-08" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-01-08">Wednesday, Jan. 8</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            Such a beautiful day - we started at 10 o'clock - for the other side
             with <persName ref="#Jones_Daniel">Jones</persName> and our lunch paraphernalia. Crossed directly to
             opposite bank, and took the little path straight away through the pleasant fields to
             <placeName ref="#Medinet_Habu">Medinet Habou</placeName> and presently came to the place of digging on
             the site of the palace of <persName ref="#Amenhotep_III">Amenhotep III</persName> where <persName ref="#Tytus_Bob">Bob
             Tytus</persName> under <persName ref="#Newberry_Percy">Mr. Newberry</persName> is excavating the site and
             near where <persName ref="#Newberry_Percy">Newberry</persName> is excavating the dust and sand mounds for
             me. Work had only begun on these a few days ago - but a beautiful painted floor in
             the palace had been uncovered, and many fragments of highly decorated walls - the
             colour perfectly fresh. I am going to have a tent taken over where we can find
             shelter and rest, and have luncheon and tea. The desert is beautiful just there -
             and I feel that I would like to try living there.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-01-09" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-01-09">Thursday Jan. 9th</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            Went into town this morning with <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> on our donkeys, - to
             the Indian shop - to the <name type="hotel" ref="#Luxor_Hotel"><choice><sic>Luxer</sic><corr>Luxor</corr></choice> hotel</name>
            - and various places. Home in the afternoon - a cold, high wind blowing -
             <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> off all day.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-01-10" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-01-10">Friday, Jan. 10</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            A real gale has been blowing all day - cold, the river is rough waves. I have not been
             off the boat - and we have had our little stoves going. The
             <persName ref="#Hennass_Mr #Hennass_Mrs #Hennass_girls">Hennass</persName> family came to tea - <persName ref="#Hennass_Mr">Father</persName>,
             <persName ref="#Hennass_Mrs">Mother</persName> and the two tall <persName ref="#Hennass_girls">girls</persName> - also
             <persName ref="#Wallis_Mr">Mr. Wallis</persName> - and as <persName ref="#Newberry_Percy">Mr. Newberry</persName> was here
             most of the afternoon we had quite a tea party - and the little saloon seemed very full.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-01-11" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-01-11">Saturday, Jan. 11</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            The morning dawned in lovely fashion - and <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I went on
             deck after breakfast and said how charming it was to see the placid river once more,
             and to have no wind - but hardly had we spoken, when with a sudden blast, the wind
             came cold and strong - however <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName>,
             <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I went out
             to <placeName ref="#Karnak">Karnac</placeName> - where the dust and sand blew in clouds, paid a
             visit to <persName ref="#Mohassib_Mohammed">Mohassib</persName> and saw some pretty enormously dear things.
             This is the beginning of <name type="event" ref="#Id_al-Fitr"><choice><sic>Bieram</sic><corr>Bairam</corr></choice></name> - and it was nice to see the
             people all in their best attire, and the dignified figures walking about in best
             black robes, with many white draperies. All the crew, headed by the Captain came
             this morning to give us the usual <name type="event" ref="#Id_al-Fitr"><choice><sic>Beiram</sic><corr>Bairam</corr></choice></name> greetings.
             <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I stayed at home this afternoon.
             <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> at <placeName ref="#Der_el_Bahari">Der el Bahari</placeName> and brought
             home <persName ref="#Carter_Howard">Carter</persName> for dinner. <persName ref="#Newberry_Percy">Newberry</persName> also here.
             Our lovely little new moon was seen for the first time tonight.
             <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I at tea with <persName ref="#Tytus_Mrs">Mrs. Tytus</persName>,
             <persName ref="#Dunmore_Lady">Lady Dunmore</persName> and 2 girls - such typical
             English Women of a certain kind.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-01-13" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-01-13">Monday, Jan. 13</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            This morning <persName ref="#von_Bissing_Baron">v. Bissing</persName> went to <placeName ref="#El_Kab">El Kab</placeName> to
             spend a few days with <persName ref="#Somers_Clarke_George">Mr. Somers- Clarke</persName>. Soon after lunch
             <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName>, <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">
            Nettie</persName> and I rode over to the palace to see what was
             going on at the diggings. <persName ref="#Jones_Daniel">Jones</persName> and the tea basket went along.
             The day was charming and so was the ride.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-01-14" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-01-14">Tuesday, Jan. 14</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            A cold wind today. <persName ref="#Parker_Group">The Parkers</persName> from the dahabeah
            <name type="boat" ref="#Safa">Sa &#8216;fa</name> which they have just bought came this
             morning to pay us a visit - much interested in our boat, as they are obliged to quite do over theirs next year.
             <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> went over to
             <placeName ref="#Medinet_Habu">Medinet Habu</placeName> and then on to the palace this afternoon - but
             I would not go in this furious wind. <persName ref="#Maspero_Gaston">Maspero</persName>, on the
             <name type="boat" ref="#Miriam">Miriam</name>, arrived down today.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-01-15" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-01-15">Wednesday, Jan. 15</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            <persName ref="#Goodwin_William_Watson">Prof. Goodwin</persName> and <persName ref="#Goodwin_Mrs">his wife</persName>
            of Harvard came to lunch today. <persName ref="#Newberry_Percy">Newberry</persName> and
            <persName ref="#Carter_Howard">Carter</persName> to dinner, and
             played bridge all the evening. <persName ref="#Maspero_Gaston #Maspero_Louise">
            M. and Mme. Maspero</persName> made us a long call in the afternoon. Still very cold
             and high wind, the boat rocking a good deal.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-01-16" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-01-16">Thursday, Jan. 16</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            At home all day - because of the wind. <persName ref="#de_Deak_Mlle">Mlle. de Deak</persName>, and
             <persName ref="#Culbord_Miss">Miss Culbord</persName> came to tea. The <persName ref="#von_Bissing_Baron">Baron</persName> came
             home this afternoon.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-01-17" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-01-17">Friday, Jan. 17</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            Again the same account. I have never known <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName> like this.
             Every morning the ther. goes down to 50-52&#176; in my room and we have had no life
             on deck since we came. Our little stoves in daily use. <persName ref="#Carter_Howard">Carter</persName>
             dined with us - always so pleasant - in spite of his dominant personality. His taste
             for all natural things is so charming to me and how he draws and paints. He is very
             much absorbed now in trying to bring on the trial of the thief who broke into the
             tomb, and robbed the body of the great <persName ref="#Amenhotep_III">Amenhotep III</persName>. The
             administration of justice is in this country administered in a very funny and
             desultory fashion. The thief of whose identity everyone is convinced, is at large on
             bail at the magnificent sum of [symbol] 1 and the film gaffirs, or watchmen who are
             suspected of complicity, are contentedly reposing in prison having now no work to do,
             and more to eat than they usually have and although <persName ref="#Carter_Howard">Carter</persName> has
             offered [symbol] 100 to anyone who will tell him the truth, the natives stand in
             such fear of each other that they all swear total ignorance.
             <persName ref="#Carter_Howard">Carter</persName>, who is Inspector of <placeName ref="#As_Said">Upper Egypt</placeName>
             has proved himself a most efficient officer - is absolutely fearless - carries no
             arms - and rides about quite unattended at all hours of the night.
             <persName ref="#Sayce_Archibald">Sayce</persName> and his friends <persName ref="Ward_Mr">Mr. Ward</persName> dined also
             with us. I think we were all a little tired - for directly after breakfast we had
             started over to the <placeName ref="#Bībān al-Mulūk">Tombs of the Kings</placeName> &amp; I in my chair - in which
             I have had so comfortable a ride, as both donkeys went so well. It proved to be
             rather a bad day for the expedition, for the wind grew violent, and as 2 steamers
             were in port, we had two parties of tourists there - and every available lunch place
             being in use, <persName ref="#Carter_Howard">Carter</persName> gave us permission to have our lunch table
             spread just behind the grille of the tomb now decided I believe to have been that of
             <persName ref="#Rameses_IV">Ramses IV</persName> where in great privacy and comfort we ate it; first,
             however, going with <persName ref="#Maspero_Gaston">Maspero</persName> and <persName ref="#Carter_Howard">Carter</persName>
             into the raided <persName ref="#Amenhotep_III">Amenhotep III</persName> tomb - what a sad change we
             found! It has not been shown since the robbery, and <persName ref="#Maspero_Gaston">M. Maspero</persName>
             was to make his official examination of the body. No one but
             <persName ref="#Carter_Howard">Carter</persName> and the head police officer had been in it. On his
             first visit <persName ref="#Carter_Howard">Carter</persName> found certain footprints belonging to one
             pair of feet, which he instantly photographed, and on reaching home found they
             agreed perfectly with photos he had lately taken of suspected foot prints in
             another raided tomb - and on an official examination of the suspected man, these
             photos matched perfectly in lines and size, his feet! We found the coffin of
             cartonnage had been lifted from the sarcophagus, laid on the floor, and the
             wrappings ripped from the feet to the head - and in a state of utter ruin - and the
             mummy which had hidden on the boat, in a neighboring room, was smashed to pieces
             and the boat taken away. After a short glimpse of the wall paintings we climbed to
             the entrance, and to the light of day and fresh air - and then waited until the
             men had finished their examination. They reported that not the slightest thing of
             value - no inscription remained. That the king was quite majestic - reminding one
             of <persName ref="#Rameses_II">Ramses II</persName> - that his hair was brown, and parted in the
             middle! After lunch, <persName ref="#Maspero_Gaston">Maspero</persName> and <persName ref="#Carter_Howard">Carter</persName>
             walked about with <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> to fix upon the site of an
             exploration, which <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> under <persName ref="#Carter_Howard">Carter</persName>
             is to make in the <placeName ref="#Bībān al-Mulūk">Valley of the Tombs</placeName>. The sky was threatening, and we then started
             for home. On coming out of the valley with its sheltering mountains we found a
             raging wind, the plain all one cloud of dust and sand, and
             <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName> hardly visible. We came home rapidly - how horrid it
             was - the shouting men - the galloping donkeys - the wind tearing my wraps off me
             - my hat hopelessly on the side of my head! Glad we were to get here - and to the
             ameliorating influences of hot water, brushes, and fresh clothes. The winds still rages.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-01-18" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-01-18">Saturday, Jan. 18</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I in doors all day - violent cold wind - stoves
             going in my room and saloon.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-01-19" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-01-19">Second Sunday after <name type="event" ref="#Epiphany">Epiphany</name>, Jan. 19</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            Again cold and windy - I went with <persName ref="#Burgnoyne_Amelie">Amelie</persName> to the little church -
             and heard a short, good sermon from <persName ref="#Sayce_Archibald">Mr. Sayce</persName>. I would have
             liked my fur cloak. <persName ref="#Newberry_Percy">Newberry</persName> came in the afternoon and stayed
             to tea. <persName ref="#Schewinfurt_Dr">Dr. Schweinfurt</persName> and the
             <persName ref="#Tytus_Bob">Bob Tytus</persName> - and <persName ref="#Wallace_Mr">Mr. Wallace</persName> came in.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-01-20" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-01-20">Monday, Jan. 20</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            At home writing letters all the morning. Early in the afternoon we crossed and went to
             the palace - <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and
             <persName ref="#von_Bissing_Baron">v. Bissing</persName> going
             first to <placeName ref="#Medinet_Habu">Medinet Habu</placeName> to meet <persName ref="#Lyon_David_Gordon">Prof. Lyon</persName>
             and his <persName ref="#Lyon_Mrs">wife</persName>. They came to our tent and had tea. For we have a big double tent
             spread at the edge of the desert, we have a table, chairs, 2 good skeleton lounges
             with mats and rugs - and a wooden floor. The <persName ref="#Lyon_David_Gordon #Lyon_Mrs">Lyons</persName> were
             delighted, - a most lovely ride home.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-01-21" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-01-21">Tuesday, Jan. 21</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            The best day we have had since we came - almost free from wind. The
            <persName ref="#Lyon_David_Gordon #Lyon_Mrs">Lyons</persName> came to lunch - <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName>
             and <persName ref="#von_Bissing_Baron">v. Bissing</persName> went after lunch to the palace - and
             <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I had one of our old fashioned teas on
             deck. <persName ref="#Newberry_Percy">Newberry</persName> to dinner - and we had such a merry
             evening! <persName ref="#von_Bissing_Baron">v. Bissing</persName> leaves us tomorrow for
             <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> - and <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> goes
             with him for a visit to the dentist - having lost the other evening a very important
             filling from a tooth. She remains only a day in <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> -
             such a provoking thing!
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-01-22" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-01-22">Wednesday evening - Jan. 22</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            A beautiful and busy day at home - until at 5 o'clock <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName>
             and I took a walk along the high path leading back in the pretty country near us. A
             superb sunset and lovely effects - met <persName ref="#Wallace_Mr">Mr. Wallace</persName>
             coming home from his walk and we stopped at the <name type="boat" ref="#Scarab">Scarab</name> for a
             little visit. <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> dined there. Nothing more
             beautiful than Venus now and our full moon.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-01-23" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-01-23">Thursday, Jan. 23</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            A cold, but beautiful day - <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and <persName ref="#von_Bissing_Baron">v.
             Bissing</persName> went to <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> by tonight's
             train. <persName ref="#Newberry_Percy">Newberry</persName> came to stay with us.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-01-24" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-01-24">Friday. Jan. 24</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            At home all day - cold wind - <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> went over to
             the palace this afternoon, and took tea for <persName ref="#Goodwin_William_Watson">Prof.
             Goodwin</persName> and <persName ref="#Goodwin_Mrs">wife</persName>.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-01-25" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-01-25">Friday, Jan. 25</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            An almost calm day - at home this morning. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName>
             and I went over to <placeName ref="#Sheikh Abd el-Qurna">Sheik Abd el Kurnah</placeName> this afternoon
             to meet <persName ref="#Newberry_Percy">Newberry</persName> - found him with the
             <persName ref="#Ogden_party #Ogden_Mr">Ogden party</persName> at the tomb of
             <persName ref="#Rekhmire"><choice><sic>Rek-ma-ra</sic><corr>Rekhmire</corr></choice></persName>.
             Then we took our tea to <persName ref="#Carter_Howard">Carter</persName>'s
             <placeName ref="#Castle_Carter">house</placeName>, he being away,
             and had tea on his verandah. It was lovely - and all came home together.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-01-26" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-01-26"><name type="event" ref="#Septuagesima">Septuagesima</name> Sunday. Jan. 26</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> came back from <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName>
             this A.M. having got excellently well done with her dentist, - and had a very
             pleasant visit with <persName ref="#von_Bissing_Baron">v. Bissing</persName> and the
             <persName ref="#Quibell_James #Quibell_Annie_Pirie">Quibells</persName>. She reports <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> horrid,
             after a heavy rain, and any one who has been in <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName>
             under these circumstances can testify to its unpleasantness.
             <persName ref="#Ogden_Mr">Mr. Ogden</persName> and his daughter dined with us.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-01-27" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-01-27">Monday, Jan. 27</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            A very cold night, and a beautiful calm day. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName>
             went to the <placeName ref="#Bībān al-Mulūk">tombs of the Kings</placeName> with <persName ref="#Newberry_Percy">Newberry</persName>, and met
             the <persName ref="#Ogden_party #Ogden_Mr">Ogden party</persName> there. <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and
             I took a frugal lunch and went out to the palace, and spent the day - having our tea
             basket with us. <persName ref="#Tytus_Mrs">Mrs. Tytus</persName> with us.
             <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> and <persName ref="#Newberry_Percy">Newberry</persName> joined us for
             tea - but the later returned to his little <placeName ref="#Kurna">Gurneh</placeName> house.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-01-28" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-01-28">Tuesday, Jan. 28</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            Cold wind again. <persName ref="#Ogden_Mr">Mr. Ogden</persName> and <persName ref="#Collander_Livingston_John">Livingston</persName>
             came to call this evening. <persName ref="#Quibell_James #Quibell_Annie_Pirie">Mr. and Mrs. Quibell</persName> arrived
             at the <name type="hotel" ref="#Grand_Hotel">Grand Hotel</name> this morning and took lunch with us. The
             <persName ref="#Mureh_family">Mureh family</persName> and <persName ref="#Buchanan_Carrie">Miss
                <choice><sic>Buckanan</sic><corr>Buchanan</corr></choice></persName>
             and friend of the <orgName ref="#American_College_for_Girls">Girls' Mission School</orgName> came to tea -
             and the <persName ref="#Insinger_Mr #Insinger_Miss">Insingers</persName> to call.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-01-29" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-01-29">Wednesday, Jan. 29</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I went into the town - and the
             <persName ref="#Quibell_James #Quibell_Annie_Pirie">Quibells</persName> lunched with us - and then
             <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> took them over to the palace for tea.
             Cold wind as usual.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-01-30" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-01-30">Thursday, Jan. 30</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            <persName ref="#Schuyler_Philip_Mr #Schuyler_Mrs">Mr. and Mrs. Phillips Schuyler</persName>,
            <persName ref="#Frank_Millet_Mrs">Mrs. Frank Millet</persName>, <persName ref="#Carter_Howard">Mr. Carter</persName> and
             <persName ref="#Cadwalader_John">Cadwallader</persName>, all on their private steamer
             "<name type="boat" ref="#Oonas">Oonas</name>", took tea with us and
             <persName ref="#Roundtree_Dr">Dr. Roundtree</persName> dined with us.
             <persName ref="#Carter_Howard">Carter</persName> lunched with us.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-01-31" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-01-31">Friday, Jan. 31</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            A lovely warm day. <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I went over early to the palace,
             and spent a quiet day in our tent. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> had the
             <persName ref="#Quibell_James #Quibell_Annie_Pirie">Quibells</persName> to lunch, and then brought them over to
             <placeName ref="#Der_el_Bahari">Der el Bahari</placeName> for tea, where
             <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I joined them.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-02-01" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-02-01">Saturday, Feb. 1</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            A delicious warm day - which <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I enjoyed on
             deck. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> had the
             <persName ref="#Schuyler_Philip_Mr #Schuyler_Mrs">Schuyler party</persName>
             to tea at the palace.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-02-02" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-02-02"><choice><sic>Sexigesima</sic><corr><name type="event" ref="#Sexagesima">Sexagesima</name></corr></choice>
               Sunday, Feb. 2</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            Another lovely day of occupation on deck. <persName ref="#Newberry_Percy">Newberry</persName>
             lunched with us, and <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> afterwards
             rode to <placeName ref="#Karnak">Karnak</placeName>.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-02-03" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-02-03">Monday, Feb. 3</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and I went by appointment this morning to the
             <orgName ref="#American_College_for_Girls">American Mission School for girls</orgName>, which was established here this
             year. We took <persName ref="#Nubia">Nubia</persName> with us, as I want very much that she
             should go to this school. It is to be sure almost as if I should take a wild colt
             out of the fields and expect it to be satisfied and interested. We found a very
             good native house - new and large. With a really pleasant sitting room belonging to
             <persName ref="#Buchanan_Carrie">Miss Buchanan</persName> and her friend, also, who have charge of
             the school. <persName ref="#Buchanan_Carrie">Miss B.</persName> speaking very fluent Arabic asked
             <persName ref="#Nubia">Nubia</persName> if she would like to learn to read and write, and
             she promptly replied that "she wouldn't", and showed all her pretty white teeth in
             a merry smile. She further observed that she thought "those things would do for old
             ladies"! Then <persName ref="#Buchanan_Carrie">Miss B.</persName> asked "could she sew" - "No, she
             had never learned" - then, "would she like to learn to sew" "O very much". (I had
             already explained to <persName ref="#Buchanan_Carrie">Miss B.</persName> what a little savage she was).
             Then we went all through the school, saw the 5 different class rooms, in which the
             130 scholars are distributed - all very neat and most orderly.
             <persName ref="#Nubia">Nubia</persName> was much impressed with all this, and when she
             saw the long, pleasant dining room with its clean matting, its 3 tables, and neat
             dressers with nice looking dishes, she was delighted. At one of the tables the girls
             newly entered are put, where they eat in Arab fashion - at the others they are
             obliged to eat in civilized manner. They all take turn in preparing the tables,
             and in washing and cleaning the dishes and putting every thing in order afterwards.
             There are 10 boarders, who occupy 4 rooms - which we saw, - the beds were neat and
             simple, and good, with little white pillows and pink coverlids. Some of the girls
             who come from a distance, have their dinners at the school - and this was strong bait
             for my <persName ref="#Nubia">Nubia</persName>. Each morning the girls are marshalled in
             a row to pass inspection as to their cleanliness - and if they are not up to the mark,
             they are sent to a wash room to make themselves fit. The morning is occupied with
             lessons., - the afternoons with sewing and instruction in household duties. The
             scholars ranged from children of 5 to any age - one of the oldest being a widow with
             one child. We left <persName ref="#Nubia">Nubia</persName> with this widow - and she said she
             would begin her schooling the next morning. We will see. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName>
             gave the school a nice piece of ground beyond the Catholic Church for a place for their new school
             house last year - and we intend giving to the building fund. Then we went to pay a
             visit to the <persName ref="#Murch_Chauncey #Murch_Mrs">Murches</persName> - where
             <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> talked affairs with <persName ref="#Murch_Chauncey">Mr. Murch.</persName>
             <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and the <persName ref="#Quibell_James #Quibell_Annie_Pirie">Quibells</persName>
             went over quite early this morning to <placeName ref="#Sheikh Abd el-Qurna">Abd el Kurnah</placeName> to see
             the private tombs under <persName ref="#Newberry_Percy">Newberry</persName> and to lunch with him -
             and <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and I went across the river at 3:30 with
             the tea basket to <persName ref="#Carter_Howard">Carter</persName>'s <placeName ref="#Castle_Carter">house</placeName> - where the rest
             joined us - and we all rode home together - the warmest day we have had for weeks.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-02-04" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-02-04">Tuesday, Feb. 4</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            While we were at breakfast the <persName ref="#Quibell_James #Quibell_Annie_Pirie">Quibells</persName> arrived, with very
             long faces, saying <persName ref="#Quibell_Annie_Pirie">Mrs. Quibell</persName>'s young niece in
             <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName>, just out from Scotland was
             very ill with dysentery - and that she had to return to <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName>
             that night - and so she cannot go with us to <placeName ref="#Aswan">Aswan</placeName>
             as she intended to her great disappointment. We were all most dismal over it. Then
             <persName ref="#Tytus_Mrs">Mrs. Tytus</persName> came - and we sat chatting on the deck most
             of the morning, saying how nice it was to have it warm. Then I wrote letters.
             <persName ref="#Tytus_Mrs">Mrs. Tytus</persName> came to tea, and the <persName ref="#Quibell_James #Quibell_Annie_Pirie">Quibells</persName>
             - and <persName ref="#Aders_Mr">Mr. Aders</persName>, <persName ref="#Newberry_Percy">Mr. Newberry</persName>'s
             brother-in-law. Then poor <persName ref="#Quibell_Annie_Pirie">Mrs. Quibell</persName> said goodbye
             - and <persName ref="#Quibell_James">Mr. Q</persName>. returned from the station to us, as he is
             to go with us in her place - he being yet too weak from illness to go to work again
             - we get off tomorrow if wind is favorable.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-02-05" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <placeName ref="#Armant">Erment</placeName> - 13 miles. <date when="1902-02-05">Wednesday, Feb. 5</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            We got away this morning at 9 o'clock with a little breeze, which soon died out, and
             we have been scrapping along the whole day - and finally pulled to the anchor almost
             up to <placeName ref="#Armant">Erment</placeName>. It has been the warmest day of the year - deliciously warm. It is a
             strange thing that just a year ago today, we left <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName>
             for <placeName ref="#Aswan">Aswan</placeName> - and had the same experience - reaching
             <placeName ref="#Armant">Erment</placeName> at the same time.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-02-06" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-02-06">Thursday, Feb. 6</date>. 23-1/2 miles.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            We seem to be matching our record of last year - for tonight we are lying very near
             to the spot where we were tied last year. A light wind most of the day, increasing
             in the afternoon.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-02-07" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-02-07">Friday, Feb. 7</date>. 36 miles.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            We started with quite a good wind at 7 o'clock this morning - and drew up at
             <placeName ref="#El_Kab">El Kab</placeName> just as we were finishing lunch. Found the
             <name type="boat" ref="#Istar">Istar</name> here, on her downward journey, as well as
             <persName ref="#Parker_Mr">Parker</persName>'s boat the <name type="boat" ref="#Safa">Sa &#8216;fa</name>.
             <persName ref="#Somers_Clarke_George">Mr. Somers-Clarke</persName> came over at once, bringing some letters
             for <persName ref="#Quibell_James">Mr. Quibell</persName>, which determined him to leave us and return
             to <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> the next day. So he went over to stay with
             <persName ref="#Somers_Clarke_George">Somers-Clarke</persName> the night. So sorry to have him go
             - <persName ref="#Sayce_Archibald">Mr. Sayce</persName> also came and made us a visit - and wanted us
             to stop for tea - but the wind was too good - we are about 3 miles above
             <placeName ref="#Idfu">Edfou</placeName>.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-02-08" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-02-08">Saturday, Feb. 8</date>. 40 miles.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            We started out about 8 this morning - and soon overtook the
             <name type="boat" ref="#Strange_Hathor">Strange Hathor</name> - the <name type="boat" ref="#Thames">Thames</name>
             ahead of us - day very warm. Passed the <name  type="boat" ref="#Seven_Hathors">Seven Hathors</name>
             going down - and also the <name type="boat" ref="#Gazelle">Gazelle</name> - also down. A very
             good wind - tied up at 6 o'clock - 3 miles above <placeName ref="#Kawm_Umbū">Kom
             Ombo</placeName>. The ruin looked beautiful as we passed.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-02-09" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            Sunday - <name type="event" ref="#Quinquagesima">Quinquagesima</name> - <date when="1902-02-09">Feb. 9</date>. 24 miles.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            <placeName ref="#Aswan">Aswan</placeName> - arrived about 4 o'clock in a piping heat -
             decidedly the hottest day yet. Came to our mooring place of last year, a little south
             of <placeName ref="#Jaziret_al_Malik">Kitchener's island</placeName>. Rowed around the island and
             went to the post office. What a delicious dry air this! and soft and exhilarating -
             in spite of the heat. Coming home we discerned the faintest little silver thread of
             a new moon in the warm brilliant sky. Now at 10 p.m. the air is sweetly fresh and cool.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-02-10" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-02-10">Monday, Feb. 10</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            A very, very hot day. I have not been off the boat - and have felt rather done up by
             the heat. A strong north wind blowing all day. <persName ref="#Andrews_Frank">Frank
             Andrews</persName> of <placeName ref="#Newport">Newport</placeName> came to tea, and was
             most condescendingly rapturous about the boat. Some other people were here too.
             <persName ref="#Christian_George_Henry #Christian_Leonara">Mr. and Mrs. Christian</persName>
             and the <persName ref="#Christian_Henry">invalid son</persName> came to
             dinner. A right pleasant evening.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-02-11" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-02-11">Tuesday evening, Feb. 11</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            Again at home all day until at 5 - after tea - <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName>
             and I went out in the boat for an hour - lovely among the islands - the new moon
             making already such a radiance. Spent the afternoon writing letters - not quite so
             hot as yesterday - but the wind very high.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-02-12" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-02-12">Ash-Wednesday, Feb. 12</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            Not of the boat today. Breakfasted at 8 - and <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName>
             and <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> crossed to the <name type="hotel" ref="#Cataract_Hotel">Cataract
             Hotel</name>, and took one of the sand carriages to the "barrage". They came home
             within 3 hours much interested in what they saw. I had writing to do - and would not
             face the glare and heat. <persName ref="#Christian_Henry">Henry Christian</persName> came again
             to lunch, and to play chess - and after <persName ref="#Christian_George_Henry #Christian_Leonara">Mr. and
             Mrs. Christian</persName>, bringing me some flowers. Poor
             <persName ref="#Hassan_mother">Hassan's mother</persName> came, attended by the old man, and her
             nephew. We would like to have had the former kicked off the boat; but knew that he
             would only make it harder for her after. We gave her 3 pounds which is all she will
             have to live on for 6 months - even if she succeeds in keeping it out of his
             clutches - and 2 shawls - and tins of biscuit and sweet things, and soap - and
             everything we could think of - and she had brought us 2 chickens, some dates and
             eggs. We hated to keep them, but could not decline. Then <persName ref="#Yemma">
            Yemmie</persName> appeared from <placeName ref="#Philae">Philae</placeName> and two
             or three other natives - and <persName ref="#Johnson_Mrs">Mrs. Johnson</persName>
             and <persName ref="#Bruce_Miss">Miss Bruce</persName>, <persName ref="#Buchanan_Carrie">Miss
             Buchanan</persName>'s friends, Scotch bodies and very nice too, came to tea - and
             this evening a letter from <persName ref="#Anderson_Hendrick">Henry Anderson</persName>
             from <placeName ref="#Rome">Rome</placeName>, saying his brother <persName ref="#Anderson_Andreas">
            Andreas</persName> had died in <placeName ref="#Boston">Boston</placeName>
            after a short illness - just on the eve of his marriage with
            <persName ref="#Cushing_Miss">Miss Cushing</persName> - it is so sad - and I went to bed
            quite tired with the day.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-02-13" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-02-13">Thursday, Feb. 13</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            A strong north wind was blowing as usual this morning - and we had quite given up
             starting, when just after lunch it dropped so much that we started - but had only got
             opposite the <placeName ref="#Grenfell_Mountain">Grenfell Mt.</placeName> when we had to tie up to a little
             sand island just opposite the <name type="hotel" ref="#Savoy_Hotel">Savoy Hotel</name> where we are now lying, with
             little squalls breaking over us now and then. But the night is so wonderful - the air
             so warm and perfectly dry, - that we were on deck all the evening, star gazing - the
             moon so bright, and all the electric lights of <placeName ref="#Aswan">Aswan</placeName> making a
             kind of fairy land.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-02-14" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-02-14">Friday, Feb. 14</date>. 10 miles.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            We got off early at 6 this morning, in perfectly still water - and looking forward to
             a successful day - but by 10 o'clock all had changed - and the wind grew so strong we
             had to give it up. Somewhat cooler than yesterday - but hot enough. On deck this
             evening for a long time. The night so heavenly. It is strange that our journey from
             <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName> to <placeName ref="#Aswan">Aswan</placeName> of this year
             has been so far an exact duplicate of last - dates, progress, etc.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-02-15" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-02-15">Saturday, Feb. 15</date>. 33 miles.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            We have today broken our record of last year of this date - started this morning at 7
             o'clock - the day very hot, with much light north wind. Our men have done well - and
             brought us at 6:30 to within 3 miles below <placeName ref="#Gebel_el_Silsila">Sileilis</placeName>. I have been very little on deck
             the heat was so intense - The <name type="boat" ref="#Scarab">S.S. Scarab</name> passed us about 10 o'clock
             - they flew by us - and we had only a glimpse of them. The <name type="boat" ref="#Hathor">Hathor</name>
             with a powerful tug passed us near <placeName ref="#Kawm_Umbū">Kom Ombo</placeName> with
             <persName ref="#Salah_Mohammed">Salah</persName> and a large English party. At 6:30
             this evening the thermometer on the cabins stood at 85.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-02-16" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            Sunday - 1st in <name type="event" ref="#Lent">Lent</name> - <date when="1902-02-16">Feb. 16</date>. 22 miles.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            We are about 2 miles above <placeName ref="#Idfu">Edfou</placeName> tonight, and could see the
             pylons as we pulled up. The day has been very hot - with light north wind all the time.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-02-17" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <placeName ref="#El_Kab">El Kab</placeName>. <date when="1902-02-17">Monday, Feb. 17</date>. 15-1/2 miles.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            Arrived at 10:30 this morning - a very hot day - the hottest I have ever known on the
             <placeName ref="#Nile">Nile</placeName>. <persName ref="#Parker_Group">The Parkers</persName>,
             <persName ref="#Sayce_Archibald">Mr. Sayce</persName>, and <persName ref="#Somers_Clarke_George">Mr. Somers-Clarke</persName> called.
             We went to tea with <persName ref="#Sayce_Archibald">Mr. Sayce</persName> and then visited the
             <persName ref="#Parker_Group">Parkers</persName> on the <name type="boat" ref="#Safa">Sa &#8216;fa</name> - and
             <persName ref="#Somers_Clarke_George">Mr. S.C.</persName> and <persName ref="#Sayce_Archibald">Sayce</persName> dined with us - a
             very pleasant evening - and after dinner we sat on deck without an awning - with no
             wraps and found the still, dry, warm air delicious - we saw nothing of
             <placeName ref="#El_Kab">El Kab</placeName> - the day was too hot. <persName ref="#Sayce_Archibald">Mr. Sayce</persName> showed
             us some most interesting little amulets - prehistoric he said - they certainly had the
             name of <persName ref="#Neb-ka">Neb-ka</persName>- first king of the 3d dynasty.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-02-18" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-02-18">Tuesday, Feb. 18</date>. 40 miles.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            Very hot again - drew up for the night 3 miles above <placeName ref="#Armant">Armant</placeName> -
             having passed the <name type="boat" ref="#Gazelle">Gazelle</name>
             lying opposite <placeName ref="#Gebelein">Gebelein</placeName>.
             The thermometer this evening at a quarter to 7 o'clock on the cabana stood at 95.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-02-19" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-02-19">Wednesday, Feb. 19</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            Reached <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName> at 10:30 A.M. 4 days and a quarter from
             <placeName ref="#Aswan">Aswan</placeName> - counting our stop at
             <placeName ref="#El_Kab">El Kab</placeName>. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName>
             went across to <placeName ref="#Castle_Carter">Carter's</placeName> this afternoon.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-02-20" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-02-20">Thursday, Feb. 20</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName>, <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I went across to
             the <name type="hotel" ref="#Ghezireh_Palace_Hotel">Palace</name> this afternoon and took tea.
             <persName ref="#Newberry_Percy">Newberry</persName> joined us. <persName ref="#Carter_Howard">Carter</persName> lunched with
             us and is staying with us.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-02-21" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-02-21">Friday, Feb. 21</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and I dined this evening with
             <persName ref="#Tytus_Mrs">Mrs. Tytus</persName>. <persName ref="#Carter_Howard">Mr. Carter</persName>
             is still with us. The <persName ref="#Vajiravudh">Crown Prince</persName> of <placeName ref="#Thailand">Siam</placeName>
             with his suite arrived in <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName> today
             - and <persName ref="#Carter_Howard">Carter</persName> is obliged to dance attendance upon him, in
             his official character.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-02-22" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-02-22">Saturday, Feb. 22</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            Every one else went over to <persName ref="#Carter_Howard">Carter</persName>'s
             <placeName ref="#Castle_Carter">house</placeName> this afternoon to see
             two mummies <persName ref="#Newberry_Percy">Mr. Newberry</persName> found in one of the tombs he is
             excavating for <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName>. It was so hot, and the idea of a
             mummy did not allure me. <persName ref="#Tytus_Mrs">Mrs. Tytus</persName>, <persName ref="#Tytus_Bob">Bob</persName>,
             and <persName ref="#Varley_Mr">Mr. Varley</persName> dined with us. The nights are beautiful with
             the full moon.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-02-23" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            Sunday, 2nd in <name type="event" ref="#Lent">Lent</name>. <date when="1902-02-23">Feb. 23d</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            A very hot strange day - the sun hardly shining and a thick thunderous haze in the
             air. We began the day with <persName ref="#Newberry_Percy">Mr. Newberry</persName> to breakfast, and he
             stayed all the morning and to lunch. The rest of the family, <persName ref="#Gardiner_Alan #Gardiner_Mrs">Mr.
             and Mrs. Gardiner</persName>, and <persName ref="Appleby_Miss">Miss Appleby</persName> also lunched
             with us. <persName ref="#Lamb_Miss">Miss Lamb</persName> and <persName ref="#Goodwin_Mrs">Mrs. Goodwin</persName>
             came to tea - and <persName ref="#Newberry_Percy">Newberry</persName> to dinner - a pleasant evening -
             but I am very tired.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-02-24" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-02-24">Monday, Feb. 24</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            A day of wind and sand. Did not stir from the boat, though <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore
            </persName> went across to <placeName ref="#Castle_Carter">Carters</placeName> to tea.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-02-25" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-02-25">Tuesday, Feb. 25</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> went across to the
             <placeName>Tombs of the Kings</placeName>, and met <persName ref="#Carter_Howard">Carter</persName> and
             <persName ref="#Newberry_Percy">Newberry</persName> and <persName ref="#Varley_Mr">Mr. Varley</persName> for lunch, and to
             open the tomb <persName ref="#Carter_Howard">Mr. Carter</persName>'s workmen have been busy with for
             some days which he is opening for <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName>. A great deal had
             been expected of this tomb. But it was found to be quite full of water - and the
             beautiful coffin had quite mouldered, as well as the mummy. Fragments of very fine
             alabaster canopic jars and other things with fine hieroglyphs and one strange black
             scarab of good size. For the first time the new electric light was turned on the
             <name type="historical" ref="#Tomb_of_Seti_I">tomb of Sety</name> - and revealed undreamed of effects and beauties.
             <persName ref="#Buchanan_Carrie">Miss Buchanan</persName> and <persName ref="#Bell_Miss">Miss Bell</persName> came to tea
             with me by appointment and I had a very interesting visit - discussing with them about
             <persName ref="#Nubia">Nubia</persName>, their school and its work and objects.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-02-26" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-02-26">Wednesday, Feb. 26</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            Had a charming ride to the <placeName>Palace</placeName> where we had tea with
             <persName ref="#Newberry_Percy">Newberry</persName> - thence to <placeName ref="#Medinet_Habu">Medinet Habu</placeName>
             and home across the lovely barley fields - now in full head.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-02-27" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-02-27">Thursday, Feb. 27</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            A very warm morning - <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I went
            over to the <name type="boat" ref="#Istar">Istar</name> to
            see <persName ref="#Sayce_Archibald">Mr. Sayce</persName> - who is a prisoner with a bad foot. He
             fell down the shaft of one of his 12 dynasty tombs at <placeName ref="#El_Kab">El Kab</placeName> the
            other day, and is now in the doctor's hands. Then we stopped at the <name type="boat" ref="#Scarab">
            Scarab</name> to see <persName ref="#Tytus_Mrs">Mrs. Tytus</persName>. The wind was strong
             and air delicous as we rowed up the river again - but as we left the <name type="boat" ref="#Scarab">
            Scarab</name>, it had increased almost to a hurricane , and looking back to where
             the <name type="boat" ref="#Istar">Istar</name> is lying opposite <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName>,
             with the <name type="boat" ref="#Strange_Hathor">Strange Hathor</name> and the steamer <name type="boat" ref="#Oonas">
            Oonas</name> with the <persName ref="#Schuyler_Philip_Mr #Schuyler_Mrs">Schuylers</persName> on board, we saw them smothered
             in dust and sand - and soon after we got home, the <name type="boat" ref="#Oonas">Oonas</name> came
             up the river and stopped just in front of us, at 4 o'clock this afternoon we went
             across to have tea with <persName ref="#Carter_Howard">Carter</persName> - such a pleasant visit -
             <persName ref="#Newberry_Percy">Newberry</persName> was there - we had tea as usual on the terrace
             and the young donkey <name type="animal" ref="#San_Toy_Donkey">San Toy</name> was roaming about the compound
             - and much interested in us. <persName ref="#Carter_Howard">Carter</persName> showed us some of his
             beautiful drawings before we left. It was past 6 o'clock when we reached home, and
             <persName ref="#Buchanan_Carrie">Miss Buchanan</persName> was here - and we settled about
             <persName ref="#Nubia">Nubia</persName> - who after 3 weeks now at school shows such
             aptitude and cleverness that she is to live there. As her father and mother are dead,
             and she has only a precarious home with a married sister, I do not hesitate about this
             - and the girl herself seems delighted.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-02-28" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-02-28">Friday, Feb. 28</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            We were to go to the <persName ref="#Murch_Chauncey #Murch_Mrs">Murches</persName> to tea this afternoon, but
             there was such a gale blowing that we gave it up, and sent excuses. <persName ref="#Tytus_Mrs">
            Mrs. Tytus</persName> and <persName ref="#Tytus_Bob">Bob</persName> were here to tea.
             <persName ref="#Carter_Howard">Mr. Carter</persName> and <persName ref="#Newberry_Percy">Newberry</persName> here to
             dinner. <persName ref="#Schuyler_Philip_Mr">Mr. Schuyler</persName> called. <persName ref="#Carter_Howard">Carter</persName>
             stayed all night.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-03-01" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-03-01">Saturday, March 1st</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            We expected to start down this morning but the north wind began howling again and has
             not stopped. All the charitable retainers were on hand this morning - donkey boys -
             <persName ref="#Saleel">Saleel</persName> - blind man -- <persName ref="#Nubia">Nubia</persName> etc. I
             sent for <persName ref="#Nubia">Nubia</persName> to come on deck and gave her breakfast there.
             Our awnings are all down - everything ready and waiting for wind to drop -
             <persName ref="Carter_Howard">Carter</persName> went off to <placeName ref="Aswan">Aswan</placeName> to
             inspect one of <persName ref="#Lady_William_Cecil">Lady Wm. Cecil</persName>'s tombs.
             <persName ref="#Newberry_Percy">Newberry</persName> came to lunch. <persName ref="#Tytus_Bob">Bob</persName>
             and <persName ref="#Tytus_Mrs">Mrs. Tytus</persName> to say again goodbye! A quiet evening -
             and a nice one!
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-03-02" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <choice><sic>2d</sic><corr>3rd</corr></choice> Sunday in <name type="event" ref="#Lent">Lent</name>.
             <date when="1902-03-02">March 2</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            At 7 o'clock this morning when I heard the men beginning to make ready to start, I drew
             my curtain aside, I found <persName ref="#Nubia">Nubia</persName> sitting on the bank and in
             a few moments <persName ref="#Achmed_Rais">Achmed</persName>, and <persName ref="#Said">
             Said</persName>, the black dog, and all waiting sadly to see us off. The river was a
             mirror, but we had hardly passed the town when a light wind from the north came, and
             then grew stronger, in the face of which we have rowed and floated all day and are
             lying below <placeName ref="#Magadah">Magadah</placeName> about 2 miles - having made 24 miles. I
             was sorry to leave the splendid <placeName ref="#Theban_Mountains">Theban Mountains</placeName> and
             when at 6 o'clock I looked at them this morning, they were lovely indeed - all
             rose-coloured - the reflection extending almost across the river. The
             <name type="boat" ref="#Istar">Istar</name> left just before us, and we have been quite close all day -
             she is lying just behind us.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-03-03" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-03-03">Monday, Mar. 3d</date>. 24 miles.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            The weather has been a repetition of yesterday - the distance also - the same delicious
             cool air and hot sun, - the mountains with their etherially lovely heliotrope tints.
             Spoke to <persName ref="#Sayce_Archibald">Mr. Sayce</persName> as we happened to float near the
             <name type="boat" ref="#Istar">Istar</name>. He is quite well again - and stopped at
             <placeName ref="#Keneh">Keneh</placeName> - we did not, and are now about 4 miles below it.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-03-04" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-03-04">Tuesday, Mar. 4</date>. <placeName ref="#Naj_Hammadi">Nagh Hamadi</placeName>. 34 miles.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            Started at 6:30 A.M. passed <placeName ref="#Dishua">Dishua</placeName> about 11 - day hot - light
             north wind until 12 - when we had a little from the south - reached
             <placeName ref="#Naj_Hammadi">Nagh Hamadi</placeName> as usual too late to catch the bridge open -
             just what we did last year. Are tied up to a very high villainously high bank - with
             the little dahabeah "<name type="boat" ref="#Memphis">Memphis</name>" just in front of us - and later a gentleman and lady
             came to call, sending in cards of <persName ref="#Biddulph">Lt. Col. Biddulph</persName>,
             Royal Field Artillery, and <persName ref="#Biddulph_Mrs">Mrs. Biddulph</persName> and we found
             them very pleasant. He is invalided from South Africa.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-03-05" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-03-05">Wednesday, Mar. 5</date>. 16 miles.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            We got through the bridge at 8:30 this A.M. just after the <name type="boat" ref="#Memphis">
             Memphis</name> - and have been fighting our way along with an almost constant head
             wind - day fine - are about 2 miles above <placeName ref="#Balyana_Al">Balliana</placeName>.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-03-06" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-03-06">Thursday, Mar. 6</date>. 9 miles.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            The north wind was howling this morning but at 6 o'clock we started, and after battling
             for an hour with it, we pulled up about half a mile from the place we had started from
             - so we gave it up as a bad job - started a washing, and turned out our fowls. At 3
             o'clock we started again, passed <placeName ref="#Balyana_Al">Balliana</placeName> where the
             <persName ref="#Rameses_III">Rameses III</persName> was lying, with all her tourists just back from
             a hot ride to <placeName ref="#Abydos">Abydos</placeName> - at 7 o'clock we pulled up to a
             high bank, with the lights of <placeName ref="#Jirjā">Girga</placeName> in the distance, where
             we intend to stop tomorrow - high wind and water making a great noise.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-03-07" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-03-07">Friday, Mar. 7</date>. 2 miles.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            With much difficulty we managed to pull past <placeName ref="#Jirjā">Girga</placeName> opposite
             to the <persName ref="#Reisner_George">Reisner</persName> camp about noon. We sent a man across
             with a note asking <persName ref="#Reisner_George #Reisner_Mrs">Mr. and Mrs. Reisner</persName>,
             <persName ref="#Cruttenden_Mace_Arthur">Mr. Mace</persName> and <persName ref="#Lithcoe">Mr. Lithcoe</persName>
             to dine with us this evening - and <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and
             <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> at 4 o'clock braved the hot sun and the high
             wind, and went over and had tea with them. The <persName ref="#Quibell_James #Quibell_Annie_Pirie">Quibells</persName>
             are now there, and in a camp of their own, and quite a little collection of tents
             showed on the shelving desert, with the great cliffs behind. They came back late,
             bringing the guests with them. <persName ref="#Reisner_George">Reisner</persName>'s work this winter has been very interesting
             - he is making it for <persName ref="#Hearst_Mrs">Mrs. Hearst</persName> of
             <placeName ref="#California">California</placeName> and has unlimited money for it. Tombs of
             the 5-6 and 12th dynasties and an archaic cemetery which <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">
             Theodore</persName> said was most interesting. <persName ref="#Cruttenden_Mace_Arthur">Mace</persName>
             and <persName ref="#Lithcoe">Lithcoe</persName> are the real explorers - and are considered
             most intelligent - the latter is an American, from
             <placeName ref="#Providence">Providence</placeName> - <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName>
             reported the <persName ref="#Reisner_George #Reisner_Mrs">Reisner</persName> house intolerably hot, and
             crammed with flies - and gave a dismal picture of it.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-03-08" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-03-08">Saturday, Mar. 8</date>. 8 miles.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            Started early - but not too early for the n. wind - against which we struggled all the
             day - tying up just opposite the cliffs at the northern end of
             <placeName ref="#Gebel_et_Toukh">Gebel et Toukh</placeName> - with the lights of
             <placeName ref="#Mensheeh">Menshieh</placeName> visible - very hot - especially this afternoon and
             evening.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-03-09" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            Sunday - 4th in <name type="event" ref="#Lent">Lent</name> - <date when="1902-03-09">Mar. 9</date>. 38 miles.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            Started early - and have had no wind or very light wind all day. Stopped at
             <placeName ref="#Sohag">Sohag</placeName> - 11 A.M. - very hot - are lying at northern end
             of <placeName ref="#Gebel_el_Heridi">Gebel el Heridi</placeName>.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-03-10" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-03-10">Monday, Mar. 10</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            We are lying just where we stopped last night. The wind raged all night - and all today
             - now quiet - today has been comfortably cool with a delicious soft air.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-03-11" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-03-11">Tuesday, Mar. 11</date>. 33 miles.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            A very good run against a light north wind all day. Our new moon appeared - such a
             lovely little thread of silver crescent - in the orange yellow sky.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-03-12" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-03-12">Wednesday, Mar. 12</date>. 10 miles.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            When I wakened this morning, I found we were sailing finally and would soon reach
             <placeName ref="#Asyut">Asiut</placeName> - I had two letters I wanted to write, but had only time
             to write in bed to <persName ref="#Newberry_Percy">Mr. Newberry</persName>, about the money for his
             publications. We stopped for mail, and then started at 10, hoping to get through the
             canal - but the wind was so strong we could only float down to a sand bank near it
             where we are now lying. The wind has been howling and dust flying all day. Loads of
             letters and papers.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-03-13" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-03-13">Thursday, Mar. 13</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            We got through the canal this morning at 6 o'clock - I saw it very well from my windows
             and <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> from the salon. <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">
             Nettie</persName> dressed and went on deck - it is a stupendous piece of work - this
             great granite Weir, which stretches across the river. We
             came to a low sand bank in the middle of the river just below the
             Weir, and have stayed here all day - the wind too high to move.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-03-14" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-03-14">Friday, Mar. 14</date>. 5 miles.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            We made our few miles by starting out too early for the north wind. As we were trying
             to get about one of the great turns of the river here, the <name type="boat" ref="#Scarab">
             Scarab</name> passed us. It was too early to see any one, as we were
             all in bed, and I fancy they were. We have had a great change of temperature - and
             it is really cold.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-03-15" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-03-15">Saturday, Mar. 15</date>. 17 miles.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            We made these by starting at 4 o'clock but were laid up by the wind at a bank near the
             town of <placeName ref="#Al_Hawatkah">Hawatkah</placeName>, 4 miles from
             <placeName ref="#Manfalût">Manfalout</placeName>. Since then the wind has raged, and is
             still roaring and whistling. S.S. "Rameses the Great" and "Tewfih" passed down - and
             the dahabeah "Hope", german flag, with a tug.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-03-16" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-03-16">Sunday, Mar. 16</date>. 5th Sunday in <name type="event" ref="#Lent">Lent</name>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            We had a great gale last night, and today has been really cold with not a gleam of
             sunlight since early morning. Started at 6 - and made about 3 miles - then stopped
             and waited for the wind to fall - started again after some hours, and have come just
             one more mile making in all 4 miles. It has been threatening rain all day, and some
             drops did fall this afternoon - but the sky is very overcast this evening.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-03-17" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-03-17">Monday, Mar. 17th</date>. 35-1/2 miles.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            Our best day - got away early from the landing near <placeName ref="#Manfalût">
             Manfalout</placeName> - and rowing and sailing brought up here at <placeName ref="#Mallawi">
             Mellawie</placeName> at 7 o'clock. The wind came lightly from the south this afternoon
             - got past the <persName ref="#Gebel_Abu_Foda">Gebel Abu-Feda</persName> by 11 o'clock, in
             fortunately quiet weather. Came across the "<name type="boat" ref="#Safa">Sa'fa</name>"
             hard and fast upon the sand at one o'clock - dropped anchor and sent our men across to
             help them, and in less than an hour they were off. The day has been a great contrast
             to yesterday - very Khamseeny- very hot - the sky
             overclouded. From 5 o'clock after we had had our tea on deck, until we tied up, it was
             something especially lovely. No sun, and that subdued stillness that seems to belong
             to such a condition, - almost a feeling of rain in the air - the mild breeze carried
             us smoothly and mysteriously along, the flocks and herds all coming down to the river
             for their last drink, the little kids and lambs now so plentiful, crying out like
             babies - "and all the land had rest". It was a heavenly evening. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">
             Theodore</persName> has sent a man across the fields to the R.R. station, with a
             telegram for <persName ref="#Quibell_Annie_Pirie">Mrs. Quibell</persName> at <placeName ref="#Jirjā">
             Girga</placeName>, asking her to join us at <placeName ref="#Al_Minya">
             Minia</placeName>, day after tomorrow.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-03-18" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-03-18">Tuesday, Mar. 18th</date>. 12 miles.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            The north wind got up before we did this morning, and we worked hard to make out 6 miles
            to <placeName ref="#Rhoda">Rhodah</placeName>, then we lingered until this afternoon
             when we made 6 miles more, are we think within 4-5 miles from
             <placeName ref="#Bani_Hasan">Beni Hassan</placeName>. A cool day - and not clear.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-03-19" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-03-19">Wednesday, Mar. 19th</date>. 11 miles.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            From 6 o'clock until 9:30 we had 3 hours and a half of good rowing - since then the
             wind has been blowing "like the debbil" as <persName ref="#Salah_Mohammed">Salah</persName> says.
             Passed <placeName ref="#Bani_Hasan">Beni Hassan</placeName> late this P.M.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-03-20" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-03-20">Thursday, Mar. 20</date>. 7-1/2 miles.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            Made our few miles before 9:30 - when the north wind fell suddenly upon us, and has
             raged ever since. We are within a mile of <placeName ref="#Al_Minya">Minia</placeName>, and sent
             the <persName ref="#Dervish_Mohammed">Dervish</persName> in the town for our mail and with a note for
             <persName ref="#Quibell_Annie_Pirie">Mrs. Quibell</persName>, hoping she was waiting there; but a letter from
             her stated she had gone back to <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName>, but would join us
             at <placeName ref="#Benisoef">Benisoof</placeName>.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-03-21" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-03-21">Friday, Mar. 21st</date>. 24 miles.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            Came along splendidly in quiet weather until 12:30 when we were forced to the bank by
             the n. wind, where we are now lying. A heavenly day - and such cloudless nights with
             a moon nearly full - what beauty these Egyptian nights have!
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-03-22" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-03-22">Saturday, Mar. 22</date>, 	28 miles.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            A very good record for such a day of continued n. wind. We have not once tied up, but
             have floated between rowing with the plank out and are now lying at
             <placeName ref="#Maghaghah">Maghagah</placeName>. We passed 5-6 miles from here one of the
             <persName ref="#Cook_Thomas">Cooks</persName> postal boats, <name type="boat" ref="#Ammartis">Amenartis</name>,
             hard upon the sand with many gyassas about her, filled with her cargoe. Soon after,
             she got off. The Anglo-American steamer has pulled in
             ahead of us - the last big steamer on the river, I think. The afternoon had such
             strange, unrivalled beauty. We passed the town of <placeName ref="#Sharona">
             Sharona</placeName>, with such splendid palms - and pleasant looking houses - and
             find fields - such evening light on the great bald cliffs beyond the valley - and the
             full moon in the heavens above.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-03-23" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            Sunday before Easter: 	<date when="1902-03-23">Mar. 23</date>. 23 miles.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            The usual history of the day - battling with the wind - but it fell with the sunset,
             and the moon being at the full, we rowed until 9 o'clock and pulled up opposite
             <placeName ref="#Biba">Bibeh</placeName>. The river has been very difficult - enormous sand banks,
             about and around which we had to take our uncertain way. But the effects wonderful.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-03-24" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-03-24">Monday, Mar. 24</date>. 22 miles.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            We reached <placeName ref="#Benisoef">Benisoef</placeName> at 1 o'clock - in a towering heat
             - everything still and burning - we pulled up and sent <persName ref="#Jones_Daniel">
             Jones</persName> and a sailor in the town for <persName ref="#Quibell_Annie_Pirie">Mrs.
             Quibell</persName> and in about an hour they arrived. We were so glad to have her at
             last. Passed two steamers on the sand - river very difficult - spent all day on deck,
             in spite of the heat.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-03-25" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-03-25">Tuesday, Mar. 25</date>. 41 miles.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            Got to <placeName ref="#Al-Wasta">Wasta</placeName> about 8 o'clock - a light south wind. Got
             our mail, and were off again directly. The day has been exciting - on deck all the
             time - sailing so difficult - passed the <name type="#Rameses">Ramses</name> on the
             sand, just after she has passed us - and not long after we went on ourselves, where we
             stayed for more than an hour, our men working like Trojans. Had it not been for this
             detention, we might have made <placeName ref="#Giza">Gizeh</placeName>
             tonight - very hot and Kamseeny all day.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-03-26" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-03-26">Wednesday, March 26</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            It has blown a great gale all day and we have not moved, except to work across the
             river to a more sheltered place. I have been quite under the weather all day.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-03-27" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-03-27">Thursday, Mar. 27</date>: 	21 miles.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            The wind fell during the early part of the night, and the moon being bright the men
             began rowing at 2 o'clock and before we went to breakfast old <placeName ref="#Cairo">
             Cairo</placeName> could be seen. Then a strong west wind held us to a bank and the men
             pulled to an anchor, and then rowed again, until they brought us to the
             <placeName ref="#South_Kensington_Museum">Museum</placeName> landing at our usual place at 12 o'clock - just 3 months and 2
             weeks from the time we left it. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">
             Nettie</persName> went up with <persName ref="#Quibell_Annie_Pirie">Mrs. Quibell</persName> to have tea
             with her, and then walked in the Zoo, which they said was quite lovely - so many
             flowers. <persName ref="#von_Bissing_Baron">Baron v. Bissing</persName> came in and had tea with me on deck.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-03-28" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-03-28">Friday, Mar. 28</date>. Good Friday.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            A lovely morning - we drove into town, stopped at <name type="hotel" ref="#Shepheards_Hotel">
             Shepheards</name> - saw <persName ref="#Tytus_Bob">Bob Tytus</persName> for a moment
             and some other people we knew on the <placeName ref="#Sloane_Terrace">Terrace</placeName>,
             then I went to church and joined the others later and came home.
             <persName ref="#von_Bissing_Baron">V. Bissing</persName> to lunch, <persName ref="#Newberry_Percy">
             Newberry</persName> came in after - and when they had gone <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">
             Nettie</persName> and I went for a drive - and then had such a pleasant tea by
             ourselves on deck.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-03-29" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-03-29">Saturday, Mar. 29</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            The day has been heavenly beautiful - <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and I drove
             into town to <persName ref="#Cook_Thomas">Cooks</persName>, and went to say goodbye to
             <persName ref="#Tytus_Mrs">Mrs. Tytus</persName> who goes tomorrow. Thence to
             <persName ref="#Kyticas_N_D">Kytikas</persName>' and saw some valuable gold coins and various
             antiques, - then home, and hurried dressing and all went to the
             <persName ref="#Quibell_James #Quibell_Annie_Pirie">Quibells</persName> to lunch - which was most pleasant -
             <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> sang afterwards in that big hall, and it
             was ravishing - she and <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> then drove into town,
             and I had a quiet tea by myself.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-04-01" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-04-01">Tuesday, April 1st</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            This is our last evening on the dear, comfortable <name type="boat" ref="#Beduin">Beduin</name>
             this year. For tomorrow we move over to the <name type="hotel" ref="#Ghezireh_Palace_Hotel">
             Ghezireh Palace Hotel</name> to stay until we go away - it has been a busy day.
             Night before last we had <persName ref="#Quibell_James #Quibell_Annie_Pirie">Quibell</persName> and <persName ref="#Miss_Thompson">
             Miss Thompson</persName> and <persName ref="#von_Bissing_Baron">v. Bissing</persName> to dine - the
             latter spent the night here, and soon after breakfast young <persName ref="#Weigall_Arthur">
             Weigall</persName> came in. We had never met him before - and were so well pleased with
             the young Englishman - <persName ref="#von_Bissing_Baron">v. Bissing</persName>,
             <persName ref="#Weigall_Arthur">Weigall</persName> and I then with <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName>
             went over to the Zoo, ah- it was lovely and fresh. After lunch which the two fellows
             took with us, they went out to the Pyramids,
             returning for tea. <persName ref="#Newberry_Percy">Newberry</persName> came to tea, bringing
             me some lovely roses. He stayed to dine and spend the night, and
             <persName ref="#Quibell_Annie_Pirie">Mrs. Quibell</persName> and <persName ref="#Miss_Pirie">Miss Pirie</persName>
             came also to dine. This morning, <persName ref="#Newberry_Percy">Newberry</persName>,
             <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I went into town to do some little
             shoppings at the Bazaar. Met
             <persName ref="#Newman_Henry_Roderick #Newman_Mrs">Mr. and Mrs. Newman</persName>, just down from
             <placeName ref="#Aswan">Aswan</placeName>, and they came to tea, and were very pleasant.
             We have addressed ourselves for 2 days as often as we could, to packing arranging -
             weather warm, with very high winds, and dust everywhere.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-04-02" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-04-02">Wednesday, April 2d</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            A very busy fatiguing morning of packing. We went in to <persName ref="#Quibell_Annie_Pirie">
             Mrs. Quibell</persName>'s at 4 o'clock by appointment for tea - and to meet some people
             and have some music. There were several musical people there. <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">
             Nettie</persName> sang divinely. Then we came here to the <name type="hotel" ref="#Ghezireh_Palace_Hotel">
             Ghezireh Hotel</name>, where we are established in the big, pleasant rooms
             overlooking the garden, which we had years ago, when <persName ref="#Parsons_Mary">
             Mary</persName> and <persName ref="#Clarence">Clarence</persName> were with us.
             The house is much improved, and gardens in beautiful order. <persName ref="#Newberry_Percy">
            Newberry</persName> and <persName ref="#Tytus_Bob">Bob Tytus</persName> came to dinner -
             <persName ref="#Carter_Howard">Carter</persName> was also dining here with <persName>
            Lady William Cecil</persName>.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-04-03" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-04-03">Thursday, April 3d</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and I drove into town and to the boat and
             to the <placeName ref="#South_Kensington_Museum">Museum</placeName> this morning - everything at the
             boat getting into covers and closets, and all kinds of packing.
             <persName ref="#Newman_Henry_Roderick #Newman_Mrs">Mr. and Mrs. Newman</persName> are at <name type="hotel" ref="#Shepheards_Hotel">
            Shepheards</name>, going off to <placeName ref="#Florence">Florence</placeName> tomorrow.
             <persName ref="#Carter_Howard">Carter</persName> dined with us. <persName ref="#Newberry_Percy">Newberry</persName>
             and <persName ref="#Tytus_Bob">Tytus</persName> came to say goodbye.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-04-04" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-04-04">Friday, April 4th</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            In town again this afternoon - looking at carpets and antiques then home in time to
             dress for dinner, with tea before that on our big balcony - with the grey and black
             crows occasionally swooping down for biscuit and cakes - young
             <persName ref="#Weigall_Arthur">Weigall</persName> dined with us - and was so nice and amusing.
             A lot of English people in the hotel whom we know.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-04-05" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-04-05">Saturday, April 5</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            A farewell visit to the boat today - and to the <persName ref="#Quibell_James #Quibell_Annie_Pirie">
             Quibells</persName>. <persName ref="#von_Bissing_Baron">v. Bissing</persName> came to dine
             and stayed late. This morning we went with him to see the new Museum - which looks
             like a good station more than a Museum - a hideous failure.
             <persName ref="#Sayce_Archibald">Mr. Sayce</persName> lunched with us.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-04-06" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-04-06">Sunday, April 6th</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            A very busy day - a most delicious cool air. We lunched with the charming
             <persName>Mrs. Goff</persName> - who among others, also had
             <persName ref="#Carter_Howard">Carter</persName> - who poor man goes back to <placeName ref="#Luxor">
            Luxor</placeName> tomorrow for his lonely summer.
             <persName ref="#Sandwith_Dr #Sandwith_Mrs">Dr. and Mrs. Sandwith</persName> dined with us
             and a charming evening. Ready for our departure tomorrow.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-04-13" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            2d Sunday after Easter. <date when="1902-04-13">April 13</date>. <placeName ref="#Bologna">Bologna</placeName>.
            <name type="hotel">Hotel Brun</name>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            Just a week ago since we quitted <placeName ref="#Egypt">Egypt</placeName>. Laden with
             flowers, we left the <placeName ref="#Ghezireh_Palace">Ghizereh Palace</placeName> early
             <date when="1902-04-07">Monday</date> morning - and found <persName ref="#Fuli_Rais">
             Reis Fuli</persName>, <persName ref="#Mattar">Matter</persName>,
             <persName ref="#Dervish_Mohammed">the Dervish</persName>, <persName ref="#Abdul">Abdul</persName>,
             and many others waiting for us at the station. <persName ref="#von_Bissing_Baron">
             V. Bissing</persName>, <persName ref="#Weigall_Arthur">Weigall</persName>, and
             <persName ref="#Carter_Howard">Carter</persName> also came - and <persName ref="#Baehler_Charles">
             Mr. Bachler</persName> - reached <placeName ref="#Port_Said">Port Said</placeName>
             at 6:30 P.M. and rowed out to the <placeName>P. &amp; O.</placeName>
             <name type="boat" ref="#Isis">SS. Isis</name>, looking so pretty and trim - not many passengers -
             most of them arriving on the "<name type="boat" ref="#India_boat">India</name>" from
             <placeName ref="#Australia">Australia</placeName> at midnight, for whose mail we waited.
             The first day and night were quite perfect - good weather and smooth seas - and we
             went to bed quite hoping that these unusual conditions would prevail the next day,
             through the <placeName ref="#Aegean_Sea">Aegean Sea</placeName> and islands - but at 7
             o'clock we encountered a fearful storm, and the last 24 hours were diabolical. I have
             never known anything like it since many years ago we crossed from
             <placeName ref="#Alexandria">Alexandria</placeName> to <placeName ref="#Constantinople">
             Constantinople</placeName>! Reached <placeName ref="#Brindisi">Brindisi</placeName>
             <date when="1902-04-10">Thursday</date> 6 A.M. and found the <placeName ref="#London">
             London</placeName> through train de luxe waiting at the landing - and we soon were in
             the admirable sleeping car, with dining room attached. We had a double and a single
             compartment to ourselves and were most comfortable. From <placeName ref="#Faggie">
             Faggie</placeName> on, the route was unfamiliar to us - and all the way to
             <placeName ref="#Ancona">Ancona</placeName>, it was by the sea shore, -- the day was
             fine, delicious air, fragrant with apple and pear blossoms - the sea, liquid turquoise
             - and the hoary, old battlemented towns on their heights, with their towns, cathedrals,
             castles - the picturesque little fishing villages - the wide desolate plains - the
             richly cultivated fields - the roadsides brilliant with flowers of every colour, with
             poppies predominating - and towards the later afternoon, the snow covered peaks of the
             <placeName ref="#Appennin_Abruzzese">Abruggi Mountains</placeName> showing - and the fishing
             fleets coming home - with their orange, red, cinnamon coloured, sails so diversely
             painted, that they had the air of huge butterflies resting on the water - all made a
             scene of ravishing beauty, that one is thankful to remember. We reached
             <placeName ref="#Bologna">Bologna</placeName> at midnight, and are established in the
             familiar rooms of this fine old hotel, where we have been twice before. It is and has
             been dull and rainy since we arrived - not a glint of sunlight. Each day has been busy
             - on <date when="1902-04-11">Friday</date> we went to the <placeName ref="#Gallerie_dell_Accademia">Academia</placeName>, and stayed the
             morning - saw two lovely <persName ref="#Francia_Francesco">Francias</persName>, the incomparable
             [illegible] (Madonna enthroned) <placeName ref="#Raphael's_Saint_Cecilia">Raphael's St. Cecilia</placeName>,
             which one seems to care for less and less - the more one sees it - a fine
             <persName ref="#Gabriel_Loppé">Loppe</persName>. There are really few things of paramount
             worth in this gallery. In the afternoon it rained, and we all stayed indoors.
             <date when="1902-04-12">Saturday</date>, yesterday we went to <placeName ref="#San_Petronio">
             S. Petronio</placeName> - interesting but disappointing. The most interesting thing to
             me, were the 4 rude stone crosses, supposed to have been erected by
             <persName ref="#Petronius">Petronius</persName>, Bishop of
             Bologna, near the old gates in the V Century. The best were the sculptures
             outside the church, which we could not well see, because of the rain and wet - a
             beautiful <persName ref="#Francia_Francesco">Francia</persName> in one of the chapels. Then to the
             church of <placeName ref="#San_Domenico">S. Dominico</placeName> - which contains the body of
             the saint who died here - a sarcophagus or "area" by <persName ref="#Nicola_Pisano">
             Nicola Pisano</persName> and pupils - beautiful in detail but clumsy in effect
             architecturally. Two or three good figures standing on it - and 2 angels holding
             candlesticks, the one to the left quite lovely by <persName ref="#Nicola_dell'Area">
             Nicola dell'Area</persName> - the angel on the right and the <persName ref="#Petronius">
             S. Petronius</persName> with the church in his hand are said to have been by
             <persName ref="#Michelangelo">Michaelangelo</persName>. In the vestibule a monument of
             <persName ref="#Alessandro_Tartagni">Tartagni</persName>, jurist, by <persName ref="#Francesco_di_Simone">
             Francesco di Simone</persName>. The Piazzo outside
             called Galileo, is very pretty and picturesque -
             with two columns bearing statues of <persName ref="#Saint_Dominic">S. Dominico</persName>
             and the <persName>Madonna</persName>, and two important monuments of the
             XIII Cent. on columns, - the one belonging to the family <persName ref="#Fascherari_Group">
             Fascherari</persName> is very interesting because of an elegant work of the
             VIII C. an arc of a ciborium applied to the tomb - a
             rich archivolt with foliage, in the corners 2 peacocks in rather coarse work.
             <persName ref="#Carlo_Cattaneo">Cattaneo</persName> pronounces this to be "veritable and pure
             remains of the antique. Then to the church of <placeName ref="#San_Giacomo_Maggiore">
             S. Giacomo Maggiere</placeName>, where in the <objectName ref="#Cappella_Bentivoglio">Capella
             Bentivoglie</objectName> is one of the finest paintings of
             <placeName ref="#Francia_Francesco">Francia</placeName> - <persName>Madonna</persName>
             with saints - the child almost the same as the one in <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">
             Theodore</persName>'s pictures - and the <persName>Madonna</persName>
             very like - lovely - outside the chapel, the monument of <persName ref="#Antonio_Dontiveglio">
             Antonio Dontiveglio</persName> by <persName ref="#Jacopo_della_Quercia">Jacopa
             della Quercia</persName> - with beautiful figures of the virtues - the Oratory of
             <persName ref="#Saint_Cecilia">S. Cecilia</persName> with frescoes by <persName ref="#Francia_Francesco">
             Francia</persName>, <persName ref="#Lorenzo_Costa">Costa</persName>, <persName ref="#Amico_Aspertini">
             Aspertini</persName> - those of <persName ref="#Francia_Francesco">Francia</persName> quite
             lovely. After lunch we went to the <placeName ref="#Museu_Civico">
             Museu Civioco</placeName>, where we were intensely interested in the
             Etruscan and Egyptian
             remains - and the exquisite "Head" supposed to be a copy from the bronze original of
             <persName ref="#Phidias">Pheidias</persName> - stopped on coming home at a shop near
             here and bought some beautiful embroideries on linen, native Bolognese work - and also
             visited <placeName ref="#San_Vitale">San Vitale</placeName>, or the
             "Seven Churches" most interesting - but gloomy, and cold. This morning I went
             for a drive to a <placeName ref="#Villa_Revedin">Villa Revedin</placeName>, belonging
             to a <persName ref="#Ferrara_Group">Ferrara</persName> family of that name - very high with
             fine views of the town, and the level, flat plain beyond. The grounds were pretty with
             some fine trees - and some wonderful Wistaria vines coming into flower - a large
             pergola, walls, terraces covered with them - a great terrace in front of the house -
             which must be charming - then to the Park - which was not good. Today has been a local
             festa day - with banners flying - and crowds filling the streets, and a fine procession
             bearing a <persName>Madonna</persName> from one church to another.
             Italian religious functions possess such incongruities and I always wonder if they are
             not apparent to the populace and priests. We go to <placeName ref="#Florence">
             Florence</placeName> tomorrow.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-04-14" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-04-14">Tuesday, April 14</date>. <placeName ref="#Florence">Florence</placeName>.
            <name>Grande Bretagne Hotel</name>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            We arrived last evening at 7 o'clock - being an hour late. A very pleasant day's
             journey, though there were some unpropitius moments at the railway station, when we
             found in all the hurry and crowd that a lot of noisy Germans had appropriated our
             reserved compartment - great vociferation and indignation on the part of the
             <persName ref="#Capodi_Stagieni">Capodi Stagieni</persName>, when he discovered it; but it
             did not avail to dislodge the rude intruders - so the train was held, until a fresh car
             could be brought up, which was fresh, clean and convenient and which we had entirely to
             ourselves. Found <persName ref="#Koon_Bessie">Bessie</persName> and <persName ref="#Newberry_Mary">
             Mary</persName> waiting at the station. This morning we spent at the
             <placeName ref="#Uffizi_Gallery">Uffissi</placeName> - and afternoon at the
             <persName ref="#Constantini_David #Constantini_Mrs.">Constantini</persName>'s and at tea at <persName ref="#Buttles_Lizzie">
             Lizzie</persName>'s. Delighted to have a visit today from <persName ref="#Clarke_Miss">
             Pheobe Clark</persName> and <persName ref="#Doctor_Clarke">her husband</persName> - they have
             come over for a stay of 6 months for a rest for him; who looks poorly.
             <persName ref="#Constantini_David">Constantini</persName> dined this evening with us.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-04-24" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-04-24">Thursday, April 24th</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            We go tomorrow to <placeName ref="#Venice">Venice</placeName>- and will take
             <persName ref="#Newberry_Mary">Mary</persName> with us, and then to <placeName ref="#Paris">
             Paris</placeName> - we have had a charming stay here. The weather has been beautiful,
             and I have been perfectly well - delightful combination indeed! We have seen the
             beautiful pictures, marbles and statuary and churches, seen all our friends - made many
             visits - received many. Last Sunday we drove up to "<placeName ref="#Villa_I_Tatti">
             I Tatti</placeName>" to lunch with the <persName ref="#Abbott_Senda_Berenson #Berenson_Bernard">Berensons</persName>
             in their charming villa - two pleasant Englishmen also to lunch. The old house with its
             corridors, stately rooms, pretty courts and gardens and the little chapel is entirely
             interesting and charming - and the whole world of <placeName ref="#Florence">
             Florence</placeName> is seen below it. This morning <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName>
             went about with me for half an hour, and then we drove, in spite of threatening clouds,
             to <placeName ref="#San_Miniato">San Miaiato</placeName>. We had it quite to ourselves -
             and after coming out of the church, we hung over the parapet of coarse and looked at
             <placeName ref="#Florence">Florence</placeName> as she winds her lovely length through
             the plain - and at the great shadows of the clouds on the mountains. The young
             <persName ref="#Countess_Cigala">Countess Gigala</persName> and her brother
             <persName ref="#Enrico">Enrico</persName> came to lunch. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">
             Theodore</persName> and I started for a drive at 3 o'clock but such a sudden and heavy
             storm came up we stopped at <persName ref="#Buttles_Lizzie">Lizzie</persName>'s
             and had tea, and finally drove home in the rain.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-04-26" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-04-26">Saturday, April 26</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            We had a charming and not at all tiring ride from <placeName ref="#Florence">Florence
            </placeName> yesterday - and I was so pleased to see again the rich, level lands of
             <placeName ref="#Venetia">Venetia</placeName> - with their slender minarets, and
             ancient cities - and to have sight again of the lagoons, and opalescent waters, and the
             city of all others, rising from them, with the setting sun burnishing its towers and
             buildings. We are in the same princely apartment of two years ago, and we found
             <persName ref="#Clarke_Miss">Phoebe</persName> and <persName ref="#Doctor_Clarke">Dr. Clarke</persName>
             here. This morning we went to <placeName ref="#San_Francesco">S. Francesco</placeName> to
             see the <objectName ref="#Antonio_Falier_da_Negroponte">Negroponte</objectName> beautiful <persName>Madonna</persName>,
             and to <placeName ref="#Santa_Maria_Formosa">S. Maria Formosa</placeName>, to see especially a painting
             in the sacristy of a <persName>Madonna</persName> and Child by
             <persName ref="#Pietro_da_Messina">Pietro da Messina</persName> - the artist by whom was
             painted a very charming Madonna <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName>
             bought in <placeName ref="#Florence">Florence</placeName>. It was very like - and
             was a signed picture. Then we went to the great <placeName ref="#Giovanni_o_Paola_Church">
             Giovanni o Paola Church</placeName> - and looked at its monuments and pictures and
             studied its effects - and home for lunch. In the afternoon <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">
             Theodore</persName> and I went to <persName ref="#Berozzo">Berozzo</persName>'s and
             after we met the girls, and <persName ref="#Clarke_Miss">Phoebe</persName> and
             <persName ref="#Doctor_Clarke">Dr. Clarke</persName> in the piazza and had tea - and the
             rain came down, and we had to go inside the cafe. Then we brought up at
             <placeName ref="#Orcania">Orcania</placeName>'s the publishers, and quite late, dodged
             the showers and got home. This morning we went to <persName ref="#Berozzo">
             Berozzi</persName>'s atelier and saw some lovely frames, and a casom - which
             <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> bought. The rest of the morning we spent at
             the <placeName ref="#Gallerie_dell_Accademia">Academia</placeName>. This afternoon we went to see
             the <persName ref="#Benson_Mr">Benson</persName>'s - and found them as usual - such a
             sufferer and cripple as she is! and so cheerful and interesting!
             <persName ref="#Clarke_Miss">Phoebe</persName> and <persName ref="#Doctor_Clarke">Dr. Clarke</persName>
             came in the evening - and we have arranged to take them out in a steam launch tomorrow
             to <placeName ref="#Torcello">Torcello</placeName>.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-04-27" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-04-27">April 27</date> - Sunday.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            It has been a day of constant wind and rain - <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName>
             is the only one who has been out - A gondola in the wind was impossible. We have not
             only lost a day, but our chance of seeing <placeName ref="#Torcello">Torcello
             </placeName>-- and <persName ref="#Doctor_Clarke">Dr. Clarke</persName> and <persName ref="#Clarke_Miss">
             Phoebe</persName> wisely decided to go over to <placeName ref="#Duomo_di_Milano">Milan</placeName>,
             in order to have more time there.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-04-28" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-04-28">Monday, April 28th</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            A very busy day - with churches, pictures etc. A large part of the morning at the
             <placeName ref="#Basilica_di_Santa_Maria_Gloriosa_dei_Frari">Frari</placeName> - <persName ref="#Koon_Bessie">Bessie</persName>
             and I brought up at <placeName ref="#St_Marks_Campanile">St. Marks</placeName> at 4:30 - after
             having had tea on the Piazza; the church was
             glorious, a little too late to see all the details, but the effect wonderful - for all
             the dim harmony of colour of the church leads up to the splendour of the high altar,
             where the <objectName ref="#Pala_d'Oro">Pala d'Oro</objectName> was shining - like a rich high
             light. That church is a great marvel - a dim, mysterious, encrusted jewel - there is
             nothing like it in all the world.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-04-29" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-04-29">Thursday, April 29th</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            Another busy day - with the delights of <placeName ref="#Venice">Venice</placeName> -
             <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> has bought a really beautiful statue of
             the <persName>Madonna</persName> and Child - except for the difference of
             material and size it reminds one of the old French ivory statuettes - the leaning
             Virgin and child. It came from a suppressed convent in <placeName ref="#Verona">
             Verona</placeName> - and is claimed to be by one of <persName ref="#Nicola_Pisano">Pisanos</persName>.
             He has also bought some lovely frames and a cassone from <placeName ref="#Bergeggi">Bereggi</placeName>.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-04-30" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-04-30">Friday, April 30th</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            Left <placeName ref="#Venice">Venice</placeName> this morning, 2 P.M. most reluctantly, and
             arrived here at <placeName ref="#Verona">Verona</placeName>, <name type="hotel" ref="#Hotel_de_Londres">Hotel
             de Londres</name>, at 5:30. Our hotel is comfortable enough - not cheerful - and very
             frigid. The town looks tremendously interesting - <persName ref="#Newberry_Mary">Mary</persName>
             and I walked a short distance from here and found the <placeName ref="#Scaliger_Tombs">
             Scaliger tombs</placeName> - the great square of <placeName ref="#Piazza_della_Signoria">Signoria</placeName>,
             the ancient palace of the <placeName ref="#Palazzo_del_Podestà">Padesta</placeName> - many curious
             and ancient forms of architecture and home by the busy and quaint
             <placeName ref="#Piazza_d'Erbe">Piazza d'Erhe</placeName>, now a market.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-05-02" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-05-02">Friday, May 2</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            We are off for <placeName ref="#Duomo_di_Milano">Milan</placeName> this afternoon - have found <placeName ref="#Verona">
            Verona</placeName> delightfully interesting. Spent yesterday at the
             <placeName ref="#Uffizi_Gallery">Gallery</placeName>, where there are some good things - and
             then went to the great old church of <persName ref="#Basilica_di_San_Zeno">S. Zeno</persName>, about
             which I had read and know from photographs - wonderful bronze doors - carvings - grand
             effects - mediaeval features. <persName ref="#Andrea_Mantegna">Mantegna</persName>'s
             great enthroned Madonna and Saints - which
             <persName ref="#Napoleon_Bonaparte">Napoleon</persName> kindly conveyed to <placeName ref="#Paris">
             Paris</placeName>, but which was returned afterwards to <placeName ref="#Italy">
             Italy</placeName>. After lunch, to the <placeName ref="#Duomo_di_Milano">Duomo</placeName>
             - Baptistry - wonderful Roman pavement, discovered
             under the cloister and then for a fine drive into the country - with all
             <placeName ref="#Verona">Verona</placeName> and its surroundings - and the splendid
             sweep of blue, blue mountains with the <placeName ref="#Tyrolean_Alps">Tyrolean
             Alps</placeName> covered with snow
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-05-04" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            Rogation Sunday - <date when="1902-05-04">May 4</date> -
             <name type="hotel">Hotel Cavour</name> - <placeName ref="#Duomo_di_Milano">Milan</placeName>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            A charming ride from <placeName ref="#Verona">Verona</placeName> on Friday - with the chain of
             the snow covered <placeName ref="#Tyrolean_Alps">Alps</placeName> with us all the way - arrived at
             7:30 - found our old rooms in readiness - fire - dinner table all ready, with its
             shining silver, and spotless linen. This is certainly the best and most comfortable
             hotel in Europe! We spent all day yesterday in stony galleries - the morning at the
             <placeName ref="#Brera">Brera</placeName> which is undergoing great changes and
             improvements; the afternoon at the <placeName ref="#Museo_Lapidario">Museo Lapidario</placeName>
             in the old <placeName ref="#Visconti_Castle">Castle</placeName> - the home of the
             <persName ref="#Visconti_family">Viscontis</persName> and <placeName ref="#Sforza_family">Sforzas</placeName>
             - enormously interesting - I saw for the first time the beautiful monument of
             <persName ref="#Gaston_de_Foix">Caston de Foix</persName> - and so many charming and
             interesting sculptures - afterwards we had a drive. <persName ref="#Sayce_Archibald">Mr.
             Sayce</persName> who came here the same day we did, called soon after breakfast - and
             came to dine. This morning it rained and was cold, and I stayed at home, with
             <persName ref="#Newberry_Mary">Mary</persName>, who is not very well. <persName ref="#Sayce_Archibald">Mr.
             Sayce</persName> came in to say goodbye - and sat some time - we started soon after
             for <placeName ref="#London">London</placeName>. <persName ref="#Gwynne_Maria">Marie Gwynne</persName>
             came to lunch - and went out with <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and
             <persName ref="#Koon_Bessie">Bessie</persName> to see <placeName ref="#Basílica_de_Sant'Eustorgio">S. Eustorgio</placeName>
             and <placeName ref="#Basílica_de_Sant'Eustorgio">S. Lorenzo.</placeName> It has poured with rain this afternoon.
             Tomorrow we go over to <persName ref="#Lucero">Lucerno</persName>.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-05-06" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <name>Hotel National</name> - <placeName>Lucerno</placeName> -<date when="1902-05-06">May 6</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            We had the most beautiful day yesterday - most of the morning at the
             <placeName ref="#Museo_Poldi_Pezzoli">Poldo-Pezzoli</placeName> - left <placeName ref="#Duomo_di_Milano">Milan</placeName>
             at 12:30 in 2 comfortable compartments. The afternoon was warm, even hot - and we were
             glad to get into the shade of the big <placeName ref="#Gotthard_Pass">St. Gotthard</placeName>
             tunnel. What was our astonishment to find on emerging from it, the snow falling fast
             and continuously. We drew up at the station of <placeName>G&#246;sechnen</placeName>,
             and had some of their excellent coffee, which was handed into the windows to us - then
             began such a beautiful sight - the mountains, trees, ground, every blade and branch
             laden with snow - making a delightful fairy land - the great fires climbing up the
             steep mountain sides, with their pointed white tops looked positively eerie. The snow
             changed to rain as we reached the valley level - but a wonderful sunset promised a fine
             morrow which promise sadly was not fulfilled - for it has rained most of the day - and
             has been very cold. No one but <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> went out
             -and no views of the mountains - hardly of the lake. We are off at 7 A.M. tomorrow for
             <placeName ref="#Paris">Paris</placeName>.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-05-10" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <placeName ref="#Paris">Paris</placeName> - <date when="1902-05-10">May 10th</date> - Saturday. <name>Hotel Westminster</name>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            We reached here the other day after a not very fatiguing ride - and were so glad to
             establish ourselves in our comfortable, familiar rooms. The weather is horrid - and we
             are busy.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-05-17" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-05-17">Saturday, May 17th</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            This morning, <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName>, <persName ref="#Constantini_David">Constantini</persName>,
             who is staying with us, and I spent the morning at the <placeName ref="#Louvre">
             Louvre</placeName>, in the Renaissance Rooms - how cold they
             were - we were perished on coming out - but what treasures! Rain all the time - took
             tea the other day with the <persName ref="#Kerb">Kerbs</persName> - he very suffering,
             poor man. <persName ref="#Tommy_Whistler">Tom Whistler</persName> came in the evening.
             <persName ref="#Boal_Mathilde">Mathilde Boal</persName> in <placeName ref="#Paris">Paris</placeName>,
             managing her sister's wedding. She is here much of the time. <persName ref="#Davis_Annie">
             Mrs. Davis</persName>, <persName ref="#Buttles_Sara">Sara Buttles</persName>, <persName ref="#Lacau_M">
             Pierre</persName> and <persName ref="#Lacau_Governess">his governess</persName> down in
             <placeName ref="#Savoy">Savoy</placeName>.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-05-20" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-05-20">Tuesday, May 20</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            The bad, cold, stormy weather still prevails - and between it and visits to many a
             stoney gallery, I have picked up quite a respectable cold - we are all very busy.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-05-24" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-05-24">Saturday, May 24</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            This is our last day here, and we have altogether in the 17 days here, not had one
             pleasant one. Business and sightseeing have occupied us - and paying and receiving many
             visits. <persName ref="#Margaret_La_Farge">Margaret La Farge</persName> and <persName ref="#La_Farge_Mother">
            her mother</persName> made a long pleasant visit this afternoon.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-05-28" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <name>Claridge's Hotel, Brooke St.</name>
             	<placeName ref="#London">London</placeName>, <date when="1902-05-28">28 May</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            We had a fine crossing the other day - but I had to enjoy it from the seclusion of my
             cabin because of my cold. <persName ref="#Boal_Mathilde">Mathilde</persName>, <persName ref="#Boal_Sister">
             her sister</persName> and sister's fiance, <persName ref="#Seychelle-Dulong_Mr">M. Seychelle-Dulong</persName>
             came to say goodbye before we left, and <persName ref="#Boal_Mathilde">Mathilde</persName> brought
             me some lovely pansies, from "my fazzer's little garden". We left poor
             <persName ref="#Newberry_Mary">Mary</persName> in tears, but she was to go off directly to the old
             place in <placeName ref="#Rue_Bassano">Rue Bassano</placeName>, now the <name type="hotel" ref="#Hotel_Belmont">
             Hotel Belmont</name>, where she once spent a winter. <persName ref="#La_Farge_Mother">Mrs.
             La Farge</persName> and <persName ref="#Margaret_La_Farge">Margaret</persName> are there, and
             we hear almost daily from her. <persName ref="#Buttles_Lizzie">Lizzie</persName> and
             <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> leave <placeName ref="#Florence">Florence</placeName>
             on <date when="1902-06-02">June 2</date> - and they all meet at <placeName ref="#Wiesbaden">
             Weisbaden</placeName>, and go on to <placeName ref="#Schwalbach">Schwalback</placeName> for
             the summer. We have had fine weather ever since we came to <placeName ref="#London">
             London</placeName> - but I alas! have been staying indoors with my troublesome cough.
             <persName ref="#Fielding_Mr">Fielding</persName> lunched with us yesterday -
             <persName ref="#Farrer_Gaspard">Gaspard Farrer</persName> turned up on Monday - and asked
             us all to dinner with him for last night. I couldn't go, and <persName ref="#Koon_Bessie">
             Bessie</persName> stayed with me. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> went,
             and had a jolly time - old <persName ref="#Farrar_William_Sir">Sir William</persName> was there,
             alert and vigorous as ever, except for his lameness. We like this hotel immensely -
             except the prices! We have a charming apartment on the 4th floor above the neighboring
             chimney pots - and we actually see the sunset from our windows. Everything is new,
             fresh and pretty, and such a pleasant contrast to the dingy old <placeName ref="#Hotel_Bristol">
            Hotel Bristol</placeName> where we stayed such years.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-05-30" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <date when="1902-05-30">Friday, May 30th</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            Such a dull story to tell - in doors all the time - weather bad and cold -
             <persName ref="#Weigall_Arthur">Weigall</persName> came to tea yesterday - and to lunch
             today. <persName ref="#Fielding_Mr">Fielding</persName> here too - and this afternoon
             <persName ref="#Koon_Bessie">Bessie</persName> and I went out in a closed carriage - and
             left cards on the <persName ref="#Farrar_William_Sir #Farrer_Gaspard #Farrer_Miss">Farrers</persName> and <placeName ref="#Denbigh">
             Denbighs</placeName> - <persName ref="#Farrer_Miss">Miss Farrer</persName> having been here,
             and I having to decline even lunch - and not able to see
             <persName ref="#Feilding_Rudolph_Lord #Denbigh_Lady">Lord and Lady Denbigh</persName> when they called.
             <persName ref="#Newberry_Percy">Newberry</persName> came this afternoon to say goodbye - and
             <persName ref="#Farrer_Gaspard">Gaspard Farrer</persName> - we are off tomorrow.
         </p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1902-06-07" type="entry">
         <dateline>
            <placeName>Holland House</placeName> - <placeName ref="#New_York">New York</placeName>.
             <date when="1902-06-07">Sunday, June 7</date>.
         </dateline>
         <p>
            We arrived safely yesterday at 7 o'clock P.M. being the evening of the 8th day of the
             voyage - the longest <placeName ref="#Atlantic_Ocean">N. Atlantic</placeName> crossing I have
             made for years. The "<name type="boat" ref="#St_Louis">St. Louis</name>" was a very comfortable
             boat but not a fast one - I had a charming deck room, with private bath room - and as
             it was cold, gray and damp - I stayed in my room - most of the time in bed. We cannot
             get rooms on Monday's boat - and are obliged to stay over for Tuesday morning - vexing!
         </p>
      </div>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
