<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>Diary of Mrs. Emma B. Andrews. Volume 19 1912-1913</title>
        <author>
          <persName ref="#Andrews_Emma_B">Emma B. Andrews</persName>
        </author>
        <editor>
          <persName ref="SK">Sarah Ketchley</persName>
        </editor>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>
          <orgName ref="#Emma_B_Andrews_Diary_Project">Emma B. Andrews Diary Project</orgName>
        </publisher>
        <address>
          <addrLine>University of Washington, Seattle, WA</addrLine>
        </address>
        <availability>
          <licence target="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/">his work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial Share-Alike 4.0 International License.</licence>
        </availability>
        <date>2021-04-13</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <p><name ref="#American_Philosophical_Society_Philadelphia">American Philosophical Society, Philadelphia</name></p>
      </sourceDesc>
      <encodingStmt>
        <projectDesc>
          <p>Established in 2010, the goals of the <orgName ref="#EBA_Diary_Project">Emma B. Andrews Diary Project</orgName> include the transcription and digitization of a wide range of primary historical material from the 'Golden Age' of Egyptian archaeology at the end of the 19th and beginning of the 20th centuries. A founding partner of <orgName ref="#Newbook_Digital_Texts">Newbook Digital Texts</orgName> (www.newbookdigitaltexts.org), the <orgName ref="#EBA_Diary_Project">EBA Diary Project</orgName> offers undergraduate and graduate digital humanities education and internships at the <orgName ref="#University_of_Washington">University of Washington.</orgName> <persName ref="#Andrews_Emma_B">Emma B. Andrews</persName> is best remembered for her association with the millionaire lawyer turned archaeologist/art and antiquities collector, <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore M. Davis</persName>. Traveling to <placeName ref="#Egypt">Egypt</placeName> with him between 1889 and 1912, she kept detailed journals of these voyages along the <placeName ref="#Nile">Nile,</placeName> including his important yet under-reported excavations of over 20 significant tombs in the <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">Valley of the Kings</placeName>. <persName ref="#Andrews_Emma_B">Emma</persName> provides a vital commentary on the archaeology and pioneering Egyptologists of the time, painting a revealing picture of the lives of the colonial gentry and the cultural and scientific literati in at the dawn of the twentieth century. Analysis of the content of her diaries, along with a broad range of additional primary source material, will afford scholars information about important historical resources for the first time.</p
        </projectDesc>
      </encodingStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <pb n="105"/>
            <div xml:id="EBA-1912-11-21" type="entry">
                <dateline>
                    <date when="1912-11-21">Nov. 21. 1912.</date>
                </dateline>
                <p>After a hurried and tiring week spent in <placeName>New York</placeName> at that perfect hotel, the <placeName>St. Dennis,</placeName> we sailed on Saturday the 16, for <placeName>Egypt</placeName> via <placeName>Naples</placeName> on that ship well known to us, the "Berlin", on which we have crossed for two years. Only, this time I was not upstairs in the <placeName>Captain's</placeName> room as usual. We have <persName>Mary Newberry</persName> and her daughter, <persName>Doris,</persName> with us, making their first acquaintance with these southern waters. But we are unfortunate - for our second day out was bad - the wind and sea increasing in violence, and for 24 hours it was terrific - it is now better, but the rain and mist continue, and we have only caught a glimpse of the <placeName>Azores</placeName> - which we are now passing.</p>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="EBA-1912-11-21" type="entry">
                <dateline>
                    <date when="1912-11-21">Sunday. Nov. 24th.</date>
                </dateline>
                <p>We dropped our anchor about 2 o'clock at Gibraltar. Most of the passengers went ashore, <persName>Jones</persName> guiding <persName>Mary</persName> and <persName>Doris.</persName> They were duly impressed and charmed. We were soon off - it growing wilder as we got well into the <orgName>Mediterranean.</orgName></p> 
            </div>
            <div xml:id="EBA-1912-11-26" type="entry">
                <dateline>
                    <date when="1912-11-26">Tuesday. Nov. 26th.</date>
                </dateline>
                <p>Reached <placeName>Algiers</placeName> after dark - many went ashore - mild and lovely.</p>
            </div>
            <pb n="106"/>
            <div xml:id="EBA-1912-11-27" type="entry">
                <dateline>
                    <date when="1912-11-27"><choice><sic>Wednesday. Oct. 27th.</sic><corr>Wednesday. Nov. 27th.</corr></choice></date>
                </dateline>
                <p>Arrived at noon today - found <persName>Harry</persName> waiting for us. The pleasant old appartment at the <placeName>Grand Hotel</placeName> - a tea at <placeName>Bertolini's</placeName> - and off in the <placeName>Prinz Heinrick</placeName> for <placeName>Egypt</placeName> on Friday - a very smooth passage over a summer sea, and <placeName>Egypt</placeName> at last, and once again. How glad we were for <persName>Theodore's</persName> sake - and he was so happy to find himself once more here! <persName>Dahabya Beduin.</persName></p>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="EBA-1912-12-11" type="entry">
                <dateline>
                    <date when="1912-12-11">Dec. 11th.</date>
                </dateline> 
                <p>We are now established on our boat - waiting for our tug - which should arrive in the morning. How pleasant it is! after a whole month from home spent in hotels and steamers! It has been a busy week in <placeName>Cairo</placeName> - <persName>Mary</persName> and <persName>Doris</persName> have been sightseeing and motoring about. I have been once to the <placeName>Museum</placeName> making a visit to Sir <persName>Gaston Maspero</persName> with <persName>Theo.</persName> We spoke of the magnificent cover to the so-called <placeName>Tyii's</placeName> coffin which has never been shown to the public and is kept entirely apart in a private room. A man capable of repairing it has been found, and has agreed to do the whole thing and to finish it within 5 months. The gold work, as well as the exquisite inlay - it will be a grand addition to <orgName>Theodore's</orgName> exhibit at the <placeName>Museum.</placeName> We had quite a little tea party on Sunday afternoon, on the boat. Mr. <persName>Sayce, Artin Pasha, Claudius Bey</persName> and the young Leavitts. Mr. <persName>Sayce</persName> is on his way to <placeName>India.</placeName> We gave a morning to the zoo - and generally a lot of sight seeing.</p>
            </div>
            <pb n="107"/>
            <div xml:id="EBA-1912-12-21" type="entry">
                <dateline>
                    <date when="1912-12-21">Saturday. Dec. 21</date>
                </dateline>     
                <p>We arrived about noon today - after a pleasant and successful voyage of 10 days - one day of showers - clearing with most beautiful rainbow. We have several fine new sailors - young men - making a fine crew - of course our tug was a good strong one, making a fast voyage. We find several friends here - Mr. <persName>Whymper, Contessa di Villamarina, Mr.</persName> and <persName>Mrs. Pier,</persName> and their 2 heavenly little girls - <persName>Miss Buchanan</persName> fortunately for 2 days. She is now at the head of the <name>American College</name> for girls in Cairo. On the 24th the <persName>Serapis</persName> arrived with Mr. and <persName>Mrs. Tuck</persName> of <persName>Paris, Major Curley</persName> of <persName>Newport, Miss Nelson</persName> and <persName>Miss Morgan,</persName> niece of <persName>Mr. Tuck.</persName> They and Mr. <persName>Nicol</persName> were here to tea on Christmas day, and <persName>Harry Burton</persName> and <persName>Mr. Crane</persName> to lunch.</p>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="EBA-1912-12-27" type="entry">
                <dateline>
                    <date when="1912-12-27">Friday. Dec. 27th.</date>
                </dateline>
                <p>We all - four of us, and <persName>Jones</persName> went over to the <persName>Valley,</persName> and stayed 3 days - and had a jolly visit. Mr. and Mrs. <persName>Arthur James</persName> of <placeName>Newport,</placeName> who sailed from there on their yacht, the "Aloha" just before we left, arrived on the "Hyksos" came to tea. They were so pleased with our boat. They are going to join their yacht again at <placeName>Mombasa</placeName> for the return home.</p>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="EBA-1913-01-01" type="entry">
                <dateline>
                    <date when="1913-01-01">Wednesday. Jan. 1st.</date>
                </dateline>
                <p>Mr. <persName>Whymper</persName> came to breakfast and brought us all the news of <orgName>Luxor.</orgName></p>
            </div>
            <pb n="108"/>
            <div xml:id="EBA-1912-01-02" type="entry">
                <dateline>
                    <date when="1912-01-02">Thursday. Jan. 2nd.</date>
                </dateline>
                <p><persName>Contessa di Villamarina</persName> and Mr. <persName>Trevaine</persName> came to tea - <persName>Baron</persName> and <persName>Baroness v. Bissing</persName> are lying in their boat, just behind us - and <persName>Mary</persName> and I went to tea with them last evening.<p>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="EBA-1913-01-03" type="entry">
                <dateline>
                    <date when="1913-01-03">Saturday. Jan. 3rd.</date>
                </dateline>
                <p><persName>Mary, Doris</persName> and I crossed over and paid a visit to Mr. <persName>Nicol.</persName> He has the very best picture I ever saw of his - the wonderful mountain range opposite <placeName>Luxor</placeName> - the finest view in all <placeName>Egypt</placeName> I think. He says he painted it for me - but Mr. and <persName>Mrs. Pier</persName> who were her to lunch, say that they are to have it.</p>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="EBA-1913-01-06" type="entry">
                <dateline>
                    <date when="1913-01-06">Monday. Jan. 6th.</date>
                </dateline>
                <p>The <persName>v. Bissings</persName> were here to tea - and Mr. <persName>Nicol</persName> dined with us.</p>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="EBA-1913-01-07" type="entry">
                <dateline>
                    <date when="1913-01-07">Tuesday. Jan. 7th.</date>
                </dateline>
                <p>We have all been over to see <orgName>Harry's</orgName> diggings at <placeName>Medinet Habu.</placeName></p>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="EBA-1913-01-12" type="entry">
                <dateline>
                    <date when="1913-01-12">Sunday. Jan. 12th.</date>
                </dateline>
                <p>We have had <persName>Baron</persName> and <persName>Baroness v. Bissing</persName> to lunch, <persName>Miss Ferroir</persName> to tea and <persName>Miss Downie</persName> and the <persName>Piers</persName> to lunch this week. We have paid a visit to the <placeName>Fahnstocks,</placeName> who are lying near. The weather is at last clear and warm.</p>
            </div>
            <pb n="109"/>
            <div xml:id="EBA-1912-01-19" type="entry">
                <dateline>
                    <date when="1912-01-19">Sunday. Jan. 19.</date>
                </dateline>
                <p>We have had among other visitors this week, the <name>Hardys</name> to tea, Sir <persName>Gaston</persName> and <persName>Lady Maspero,</persName> and Mr. and Mrs. <persName>Carlstone Sprague</persName> sent by Mrs. <persName>Metcalf,</persName> and Mr. <persName>Allen Marquand,</persName> windy and cold.</p>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="EBA-1913-01-26" type="entry">
                <dateline>
                    <date when="1913-01-26">Sunday. Jan. 26.</date>
                </dateline>
                <p>It has been warm and charming most of the week. We have had the <name>Contessa</name> and Mr. Tremaine, Mr. <persName>Alan Gardner</persName> (Sarah:sic), Mr. and <persName>Mrs. Longyear</persName> and son on their homeward bound voyage from <orgName>India,</orgName> Mr. <persName>Fahnstock</persName> to tea, <persName>Mr. Tremaine</persName> to lunch, and Mr. <persName>Whymper</persName> to breakfast this week, to say nothing of a charming little white baby donkey, which one of the sailors brought on the lower deck, to amuse the <placeName>Pier</placeName> children. We have had some warm days.</p>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="EBA-1913-02-02" type="entry">
                <dateline>
                    <date when="1913-02-02">Sunday. Feb. 2nd.</date>
                </dateline>
                <p>Various visits from friends - we have lunched with the <orgName>Fahnstocks</orgName> and <orgName>Masperos</orgName> - visits to the diggings etc - cold and windy.</p>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="EBA-1913-02-09" type="entry">
                <dateline>
                    <date when="1913-02-09">Sunday. Feb 9th.</date>
                </dateline>
                <p>It has been very warm - various visitors - among them the <orgName>Longyears</orgName> back from the <placeName>South</placeName> as far as Khartoum. <persName>Mr. Whymper</persName> to breakfast this morning.</p>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="EBA-1913-02-16" type="entry">
                <dateline>
                    <date when="1913-02-16">Sunday. Feb. 16th.</date>
                </dateline>    
                <p>We dressed the ship on Wednesday - <persName>Lincoln's</persName> birthday - the <pb n="110"/>usual routine - this week - we have had light rain on one day and cold stormy weather since. Contessa here for luncheon.</p>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="EBA-1913-02-16" type="entry">
                <dateline>
                    <date when="1913-02-16">Sunday. Feb. 23rd.</date>
                </dateline>
                <p>Very warm. Mr. <persName>Whymper</persName> to breakfast - the <persName>Piers</persName> to lunch. <persName>Mrs. Aylener</persName> and <persName>Morehouse</persName> to tea. We have had Mr. and <persName>Mrs. Hardy</persName> to tea - <persName>Senator Aldrich</persName> also. <persName>Mary N.</persName> and I have been over to the <placeName>Winter Palace</placeName> for tea - we looked very smart on Washington's birthday with all our flags.</p>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="EBA-1913-03-02" type="entry">
                <dateline>
                    <date when="1913-03-02">Sunday. March 2nd.</date>
                </dateline>
                <p>On Monday <persName>Mary</persName> and I went to tea with the <name>Contessa</name> in the gardens of the <placeName>Luxor Hotel</placeName> - met <persName>Lady Baring, Miss Murray,</persName> and <persName>Contessa Pappenheim</persName> and daughter. Charming people all - yesterday we left for Asw&#226;n.</p>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="EBA-1913-03-09" type="entry">
                <dateline>
                    <date when="1913-03-09">Sunday. March 9th.</date>
                </dateline>
                <p>This is our record for the week - very high wind from the time we left <persName>Luxor.</persName> Stopped at <placeName>Edfou</placeName> - <placeName>Kom Ombo</placeName> - where we were held some time by furious wind - after leaving we passed the most wonderful mass of flamingoes - absolutely dense masses of them - attending a mile or two - very remarkable - reached <placeName>Aswan</placeName> the 4th. The wind horridly bad. <persName>Mary</persName> and <persName>Doris</persName> went to <placeName>Barrage</placeName> - the next day we moved down opposite <placeName>Grenfell's</placeName> tomb, and the girls visited them. The 7th we left <persName>Aswan,</persName> the terrific wind still holding - so that we were tied up some time <pb n="111"/>below <placeName>Kom Ombo</placeName> - the next day we struck upon 3 sand banks, or rather our tug did - and reached here this morning.</p>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="EBA-1913-03-16" type="entry">
                <dateline>
                    <date when="1913-03-16">Sunday. Mar. 16th.</date>
                </dateline>
                <p>We spent the days Monday and Tuesday in <placeName>Luxor</placeName> - <persName>Doris</persName> and I went over to the town - and Mrs. <persName>Crispell</persName> and her niece came from the <persName>Mayflower</persName> to tea - I was so pleased with her. Mr. <persName>Crane</persName> and <persName>Harry</persName> came to tea, and we left <placeName>Luxor</placeName> the 12th at noon - having had a nice visit from <placeName>Old Hagg Mahassib</placeName> - <persName>Nag Hamadi</persName> the 13 - <persName>Balliana</persName> the 14 - where we stopped for <persName>Mary, Doris, Amelie, Jones</persName> and <persName>Hassein</persName> to visit <placeName>Abydos</placeName> - very cold and terrific wind - very severe in the night and rough today. We passed the <placeName>Arabia</placeName> stuck at 8:30 A.M. Cold, constant wind.</p>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="EBA-1913-04-02" type="entry">
                <dateline>
                    <date when="1913-04-02">Wednesday. April 2nd.</date>
                </dateline>
                <p>We left the boat very reluctantly several days ago, that charming little home, and came to the <placeName>Ghizereh Palace Hotel</placeName> - and into our old rooms. Hotel almost empty. The new bridge is finished, and trains are running over it. A very fine and long one - and a great convenience - but it spoils the garden somewhat. <placeName>Cairo</placeName> is fast changing and improving but losing its unique interesting eastern features. Mrs. <persName>Graham</persName> called with <persName>Major Watson</persName> and asked us to tea on Friday and very pleasant it was, as always. Mr. <persName>Tremaine</persName> and Mr. <persName>Carter</persName> called.</p>
            </div>
            <pb n="112"/>
            <div xml:id="EBA-1912-04-06" type="entry">
                <dateline>
                    <date when="1912-04-06">Sunday. April 6th.</date>
                </dateline>
                <p>Home all day - <persName>Baron v. Bissing</persName> called and stopped for tea. <persName>Contessa Villamarina</persName> and <persName>Mlle.</persName> <persName>Johannis</persName> too.</p>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="EBA-1913-04-07" type="entry">
                <dateline>
                    <date when="1913-04-07">Monday. April 7th.</date>
                </dateline>
                <p><persName>Elena Rathbone</persName> and her friend <persName>Miss Cholanley</persName> just back from <placeName>India</placeName> came to tea, as well as Mr. <persName>Anthony</persName> and Mr. Lythgoe.</p>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="EBA-1913-04-12" type="entry">
                <dateline>
                    <date when="1913-04-12">Saturday. April 12th.</date>
                </dateline>
                <p>Arrived in <placeName>Naples</placeName> at 7:30 this morning, landed in the hideous confusion characteristic of the N.G.L. steamers - rain and cold winds.</p>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="EBA-1913-04-16" type="entry">
                <dateline>
                    <date when="1913-04-16">Wednesday. April 16th.</date>
                </dateline>
                <p>Came to <placeName>Florence</placeName> - a long days journey - very cold. <placeName>Vesuvius</placeName> and the mountains all this way up, covered with snow. We came to the <placeName>Grande Bretagne</placeName> and to our old appartment - we have had a little fire every day. <persName>Theo</persName> has been almost every day motoring, with <persName>David Costantini</persName> and <persName>Harry Burton,</persName> and some one or two of the girls. The season is very backward - the roses just beginning to show. Have made some pleasant visits - <persName>Theo</persName> has made excursions to <persName>Faenza, Settignano</persName> - <name>Volterra</name> and enjoyed it keenly. He has loved going to the <placeName>Villino</placeName> and hearing <persName>Nettie</persName> sing - and to drive to the <placeName>Cascine</placeName> for a walk along the little river, with its lovely entourage of blue mountains and green meadows and magnificent trees. Above all I have enjoyed the companion- <orgName>PAGE 113</orgName> ship of the two dear nieces, <persName>Nettie</persName> and <persName>Mary.</persName> We go tomorrow at 5 P.M. via the <placeName>Mt.</placeName> Cenie pass to <placeName>London.</placeName> 1912-1913 6</p>
      </div>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
