<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>Diary of Mrs. Emma B. Andrews. Volume 6 1898-1899</title>
        <author>
          <persName ref="#Andrews_Emma_B">Emma B. Andrews</persName>
        </author>
        <editor>
          <persName ref="SK">Sarah Ketchley</persName>
        </editor>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>
          <orgName ref="#Emma_B_Andrews_Diary_Project">Emma B. Andrews Diary Project</orgName>
        </publisher>
        <address>
          <addrLine>University of Washington, Seattle, WA</addrLine>
        </address>
        <availability>
          <licence target="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/">This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</licence>
        </availability>
        <date>YYYY-MM-DD</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <p><name ref="#American_Philosophical_Society_Philadelphia">American Philosophical Society, Philadelphia</name></p>
      </sourceDesc>
      <encodingStmt>
        <projectDesc>
          <p>Established in 2010, the goals of the <name ref="#Emma_B_Andrews_Diary_Project">Emma B. Andrews Diary Project</name> include the transcription and digitization of a wide range of primary historical material from the <orgName ref="#'Golden_Age'">'Golden Age'</orgName> of <orgName ref="#Egyptian">Egyptian</orgName> archaeology at the end of the 19th and beginning of the 20th centuries. A founding partner of <name ref="#Newbook_Digital_Texts">Newbook Digital Texts</name> (www.newbookdigitaltexts.org), the <name ref="#EBA_Diary_Project">EBA Diary Project</name> offers undergraduate and graduate digital humanities education and internships at the <name ref="#University_of_Washington">University of Washington.</name> <persName ref="#Andrews_Emma_B">Emma B. Andrews</persName> is best remembered for her association with the millionaire lawyer turned archaeologist/art and antiquities collector, <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore M. Davis.</persName> Traveling to <placeName ref="#Egypt">Egypt</placeName> with him between 1889 and 1912, she kept detailed journals of these voyages along the <orgName ref="#Nile">Nile,</orgName> including his important yet under-reported excavations of over 20 significant tombs in the Valley of the Kings. <persName ref="#Emma">Emma</persName> provides a vital commentary on the archaeology and pioneering Egyptologists of the time, painting a revealing picture of the lives of the colonial gentry and the cultural and scientific literati in at the dawn of the twentieth century. Analysis of the content of her diaries, along with a broad range of additional primary source material, will afford scholars information about important historical resources for the first time.</p>
        </projectDesc>
      </encodingStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1894-11-19" type="entry"><name>
        <dateline>
          Bedrescheyn</dateline></name> &#8211; <placeName>Egypt.</placeName> Dec. 12, 1898.
        </dateline>
          <p>It is just one month today that we sailed from <placeName>New York,</placeName> again on the <orgName>Kaiser Wilhem</orgName> II. The voyage was a slow and very tiresome one. The weather warm, grey and showery. We reached <placeName>Gibraltar</placeName> the evening of Monday the 21st about 8 o'clock &#8211; and lost that ever interesting sight of the approach of the big rock. A fleet of seven <orgName>English</orgName> war vessels were in harbour, and would have made a pretty spectacle by daylight. Got away at 10 o'clock, and reached <placeName>Naples</placeName> too late on the evening of the 24th to land &#8211; although every one was packed and ready to get off. The disappointment was all the greater. We passed the usual night of din and turmoil, incident to coaling, and landed at 8 o'clock the next morning, finding <persName>Andersen</persName> and <persName>Mary Buttles</persName> waiting for us. A day and night at the <placeName>Grand Hotel,</placeName> and off on Saturday in the very comfortable "Regina <placeName>Margherita"</placeName> for <placeName>Alexandria</placeName> which we reached on Tuesday morning at 9 o'clock and <placeName>Cairo</placeName> in the evening. <persName>Mrs. Edwin Parsons (Lellie Swayne)</persName> with two nieces came out with us from <placeName>New York,</placeName> and has engaged the dahabeah <persName>Sol el-Nil,</persName> commonly known as the <orgName>Hungarian</orgName> dahabeah, and our faithful old <persName>Salah</persName> and we all started together this morning, and will keep together. She is delighted with everything and so is <persName>Bessie Whaling</persName> whom we brought for the winter. There is the usual crowd at <placeName>Cairo,</placeName> thinner perhaps as we are nearly two weeks earlier than usual. The <placeName>Nile</placeName> is very high this year &#8211; and we have just escaped a week of rain which they have had here, and which has filled <placeName>Cairo</placeName> with mosquitos. And right glad I was to escape <persName>Shepheards,</persName> and constant combats with mosquitos, and come to our own home on this beautiful <orgName>Bedouin.</orgName> She has never been in such perfect order &#8211; or so pretty and comfortable &#8211; and peace and repose are again descending upon me.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-"></div>
        <dateline>Bedrescheyn. Dec. 13. Tuesday.</dateline>
          <p>Everyone went out to <placeName>Saqqara</placeName> this morning except <persName>Lellie Parsons</persName> and myself. About 4 o'clock it began to look rather threatening &#8211; and in a few moments the rain came in torrents. I never saw it rain more furiously for a little while. Great excitement on the boat &#8211; all hands gathering the bread that was drying on deck into safe quarters. I had to take refuge below, while the deck was quickly dismantled and everything put under canvass. I was uncomfortable about our people &#8211; as I saw the <persName>Cook</persName> party from the <placeName>Ramesis</placeName> arriving in bedraggled condition. But they came home dry, having taken refuge under cover. It has rained at intervals since &#8211; is warm- the cloud scenery after the heavy storm was wonderful. Our boat did not leak in the slightest degree.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-"></div>
          Wednesday, Dec. 14. Beautiful weather, but no wind until about 4 o'clock, when we started and made a mile or two.
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-"></div>
          Thursday, Dec. 15. Did not move &#8211; lovely, serene weather &#8211; no wind. Thermometer at 2 o'clock in the shade stood at 65&#730;. Friday, Dec. 16. Our men tracked about half a mile, but <persName>Theodore</persName> thinks this such a waste of time and strength, that he does not often permit it. We are still in sight of <name>Helouan</name> &#8211; and the <placeName>Saqqara</placeName> pyramids.
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-"></div>
          <name>Saturday,</name> Dec. 17. We all took a walk into the town on the railroad this morning to post some letters. Our way was by the pleasant palm forest &#8211; along the canal, and the picturesque, but vilely smelling mud town. A charming country about &#8211; still no wind &#8211; but rather promising signs in the sky this evening. 
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-"></div>
          Wasta. Dec. 18. Fourth Sunday in Advent. 36 miles. We at last got off this morning at 7 o'clock, in a good wind that held finely, and we had a glorious run, bringing up here at 4 o'clock. The <name>Lul el Nil,</name> came along an hour after &#8211; and tomorrow we will all go by rail to the <placeName>Fayum</placeName> &#8211; returning the same day. This will not of course give us time to see much. But the <orgName>Greek Inn</orgName> at the <placeName>Medina</placeName> is impossible, and we could not see our way to doing the whole thing, much as we would like to see it, as we should be obliged to carry a camp outfit and spend three or four days there. High wind tonight and we are rolling a good deal.
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-"></div>
          Monday, Dec. 19. Started for <name>El Medina, Fayum</name> by rail at 10:30, <persName>Parson</persName> included &#8211; and folted in fairly comfortable fashion across the desert to <placeName>Medina</placeName> which we reached at 12 o'clock &#8211; and had an excellent luncheon at the <placeName>Hotel du Fayoum</placeName> &#8211; where one could be very comfortable for a few days and see the district thoroughly. Then we had 3 carriages! and drove about through the town and environs. The town is quite <orgName>European,</orgName> is of much importance, 40,000 inhabitants &#8211; and the great canal, the <persName>Bahr Jusuf</persName> which leaves the <placeName>Nile</placeName> near <placeName>Assiut</placeName> and flows to the <placeName>Fayoum</placeName> gives extraordinary fertility to this district. Its many branches flowing through the town, and the numerous bridges we crossed gave many novel features &#8211; making a kind of <placeName>Egyptian Venice</placeName> or Amsterdam. Very good streets, with handsome buildings, and gardens &#8211; most interesting. <persName>Theodore</persName> made the acquaintance of an unknown <orgName>Englishman</orgName> who has lived there for 10 years &#8211; and he says one can drive quite comfortably to the pyramids of <placeName>Hawara</placeName> and <placeName>Illahun.</placeName> Home by 5 o'clock tired and glad. Fine evening effects returning across the desert. The <orgName>Meydum</orgName> pyramid touched to radiance by the setting sun, while all about was grey and dark.
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-"></div>
          Tuesday, Dec. 20. Very heavy fog this morning &#8211; and no wind until 11 o'clock &#8211; very shifting all day &#8211; with heavy clouds about late in the afternoon, and some lightning and a little rain. Made about 6 miles. I had one charming hour on deck just after lunch, while we were anchored in a dead calm. Water like glass &#8211; the delicate colouring of that hour of the day &#8211; the utter stillness only emphasised by a boat descending the other side of the wide river, with its boatmen crooning and singing. What heavenly repose!
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-"></div>
          Wednesday, Dec. 21. A cool morning and but little wind until about 3 P.M. when with a west wind we sailed until 4:30 and made near 6 miles, and then obliged to tie up to the bank. 
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-"></div>
          Thursday, Dec. 22. 3 miles. A splendid cloudless day with light south west wind &#8211; we pulled to the anchor to opposite side of river, tracked a little way, and then pulled back and tracked &#8211; making 3 miles, we suppose we are about 15 miles south of Wasta. A radiant night! 
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-"></div>
          Friday, Dec. 23. One mile. <placeName>S.E.</placeName> wind still holds &#8211; tracked a little &#8211; and beginning to feel a little discouraged. The "Thames" with the <orgName>Kidders</orgName> from <placeName>Boston,</placeName> is lying ahead of us, too far for visiting. The "Eurydice" somewhere near her, on which are a <orgName>Canadian</orgName> family (Smith) who crossed with us on the <persName>Kaiser Wilhem.</persName> 
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-"></div>
          Saturday, Dec. 24. Still lying where we were last night with high south wind blowing. If it had not been so cold last night, I should have thought a khamseen coming for it has been thick and hazy all day &#8211; the sun a pale round orb disappearing early in an atmosphere laden with dust and sand. We have been trying to put the boat into festive <orgName>Xmas</orgName> attire with the very poor things we could find at a garden near here. The little salon now looks gay with bunches of rosemary in masses over sideboard and pictures, making a pleasant atmosphere &#8211; and looking like hemlocks.
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-"></div>
            Christmas. Dec. 25. Sunday. A brilliant, beautiful morning &#8211; and our breakfast table had a very festive air with its flowers, and its many presents. Mrs. <persName>Parsons</persName> and the girls came to dine &#8211; and we had a nice evening. The same <placeName>S.W.</placeName> gale has continued to blow, and we have not moved.
     </div>
     <div xml:id="EBA-"></div>
            Monday, Dec. 26. 8 miles. West wind &#8211; between tracking and sailing made 8 miles, and are now near <placeName>Benisoef,</placeName> tied up to an island. It has rained slightly two or three times this afternoon. 
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-"></div>
          Tuesday. Dec. 27. 13 miles. A strong wind, dying down by 11 o'clock, enabled us to make a start, and tracking, pulling to the anchor, and sailing brought us near <placeName>Bibeh,</placeName> where we are tied up &#8211; having made about 13 miles. Cold.
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-"></div>
          Wednesday, Dec. 28th. 34-35 miles. Started in light wind soon after 9 &#8211; then we tracked and at 11 a light wind brought us along until 7 o'clock, when we brought up a mile this side of <persName>Abu Girgeh</persName> &#8211; having made about 35 miles &#8211; still cold &#8211; the thermometer went last night down to 39&#730;. 
            Thursday, Dec. 29. 31 miles. A dense fog this morning and calm &#8211; wind rose at 11 and remained light and fitful all day. We brought up at 7:30, 5 miles north of <placeName>Minieh,</placeName> having made 31 miles. 
            Friday, Dec. 30. 5 miles. No wind until after 3 P.M. when a light one carried us down to <persName>Minieh</persName> &#8211; the <placeName>Luli el-Nil,</placeName> coming in half an hour after. Just too late to get the mail &#8211; for then we had to wait until 8 o'clock &#8211; many letters but happily no bad news. Heaps of papers bringing us news of the great gale at <placeName>Newport</placeName> and along the coast on the 27 Nov. also of the sudden death by pneumonia of Mr. <persName>Calvin Brice.</persName> 
            Saturday, Dec. 31. Still at <placeName>Minieh.</placeName> Have been dining with <persName>Lellie Parsons</persName> on the <persName>Luli el-Nil.</persName> Young <persName>Gouverneur Morris</persName> from <placeName>New York,</placeName> and a friend of his having come up to spend the night and dine with them. Just before coming away as we were such a party of <orgName>Americans,</orgName> we all stood up and sang, "My Country &#8216;tis of Thee". <placeName>Monday,</placeName> 
            Jan. 2, 1899. 5 miles. Yesterday a dead calm &#8211; or wind in the <placeName>South</placeName> &#8211; today the same, but between tracking and polling have made 5 miles. 
            Tuesday, Jan. 3. 8-1/2 miles. Calm until early in the afternoon &#8211; when we began tracking and sailed a little bringing up at <placeName>Beni Hassan,</placeName> or a mile north of it about 5 o'clock, making 8-1/2 miles. 
            Saturday, Jan. 7. 7 miles. A strong, cold, south wind has been blowing since Tuesday &#8211; sometimes amounting to a gale &#8211; so that sitting on deck, and even walking has been disagreeable &#8211; sand flying etc. We laid all the time just opposite the <placeName>Beni Hassan</placeName> hills, with the tombs plainly in sight &#8211; and the afternoon sun falling softly upon them made them seem a splendid resting place. <persName>Theodore</persName> and <persName>Bessie,</persName> with the people from the other boat went over yesterday morning &#8211; <persName>Mary</persName> and I would not face the wind and sand. This morning we began tracking about 8 Page 9 o'clock and soon the wind shifting to the west, made it possible to sail, as there was a favorable bend in the river &#8211; and we made 7 miles, and are near Rhoda. Thermometer last night 42&#730;. 
            Sunday, Jan. 8. 1st Sunday after <orgName>Epiphany.</orgName> We began tracking this morning at 7 o'clock &#8211; thus making a difficult turn, when we were able to sail, and kept on nearly until 10 o'clock, when the wind became so strong, we had to bring up near the town which lies almost on the site of the old town built by <persName>Hadrian</persName> in memory of Antinous. A lovely place it was, amidst its lovely palms. I did not walk with the rest to see the few scant ruins of the ancient town &#8211; for the wind was so strong and cold, and the dust and sand flying in such blinding fashion. Everything inside and out was covered with it. We got away this afternoon in a fine wind, which brought us to <persName>Hadji Kandil</persName> about 7 o'clock, making 17 miles. <name>Mercury</name> again at 42&#730; last night. Monday, Jan 9. 28 miles. Tracking begun at 7 o'clock this morning &#8211; it being calm and misty. By 10 o'clock the wind had risen, and we were bowling along in splendid fashion, until we approached the difficult <placeName>Abu F&#234;da</placeName> cliffs &#8211; where the great bends in the river make such difficult sailing when the wind became fitful &#8211; coming in dangerous gusts &#8211; followed by <orgName>Page 10</orgName> almost dead calms &#8211; even drawing ahead. The situation further complicated by many gyasses, made it so exciting, that we feel quite worn out this evening. The <orgName>Beduin</orgName> behaved splendidly, and our men were enthusiastic. We are now lying opposite <placeName>Manfal&#251;t,</placeName> where we hope to get some coal or charcoal, as our fuel is exhausted &#8211; and although there is a lot waiting for us at <placeName>Assiut,</placeName> and we are only 26 miles from there, yet in this uncertain sailing we may not be able to get there tomorrow. The <placeName>Lulu</placeName> el-Nil lies just behind us. 
            Tuesday, Jan. 10. 26 miles. Started at 7 A.M. and with wind more or less light sailed until after dark &#8211; about 6 we struck the sand, and our men worked hard for an hour before we were off &#8211; fairly lifting the boat along. Then we were off, and reached <placeName>Assiut</placeName> at 7 o'clock P.M. One of the most beautiful sunsets it was ever vouchsafed to man to see &#8211; beginning with a glory that the river everywhere reflected, with masses and great sweeps of light clouds &#8211; dying down through every range of colour &#8211; and leaving earth and sky in a deep blue and pink darkness! Very cold this morning &#8211; thermometer at 38&#730; last night.
            Wednesday, Jan. 11. Assiut. 22 miles. Still very cold this morning though mercury only at 42&#730; - <persName>Mary, Bessie</persName> and I, taking <persName>Abdul,</persName> drove into the town as far as the <name>Post Office,</name> intending to keep on to the <orgName>Page 11</orgName> bazaar. But meeting <persName>Jones</persName> and the <persName>Cook</persName> entering with all their purchases made, and the wind being favourable, and <persName>Theodore</persName> who went off early to inspect the new barrage works, having instructed us not to stay long, we obediently turned back at the P.O. We had a travesty of a carriage, a most curiously compounded harness &#8211; and two poor, little, starved horses that made one's heart ache. Came very near an upset &#8211; off at 11:30, and sailing and tracking we kept on until 9 this morning, bringing up 7 miles south of <placeName>Aboutig.</placeName> 
            Sohag. Thursday, Jan. 12. 45 miles. A very heavy fog this morning &#8211; tracked, and began sailing at 1 o'clock, and the wind holding we kept on until 8 o'clock &#8211; when we brought up at <placeName>Sohag,</placeName> under its high bank with its fine street and electric lamps. Soon after we pulled up heavy firing began just above us, making us jump in our seats at each discharge. It was the announcement that <persName>Ramadan</persName> begins tomorrow, the new moon having shown herself last night, I hope she will bring us warmer weather, it is a pleasure to look forward to the lovely nights she brings. The wind has been cold all day &#8211; and there is a penetrating cold tonight. We have the little stove lighted and placed in the hall. 37&#730; last night. Early this morning we passed dahabeah "Cairo" with the <orgName>English</orgName> flag, later the <orgName>Enterpe,</orgName> also with <orgName>English</orgName> flag. We have left the <persName>Luli el Nil</persName> with our friends behind &#8211; they did not get off from <placeName>Assiut</placeName> as early as we did.
            Friday, Jan. 13. Girgeh. 24-1/2 miles. A fair sailing day &#8211; though obliged to track past <persName>Akmim</persName> &#8211; an awkward thing as its banks are strewn with large stones, and many boats are always lying there. Brought up at <placeName>Girgeh</placeName> at 6:30. Cold. <persName>Salah</persName> not yet in sight. <persName>Girgeh</persName> has been for years shut off from boats by a huge sand island which the high <placeName>Nile</placeName> of this year has completely carried away &#8211; so that for the first time we could approach the town.
            Saturday Jan. 14. 8 miles. Did not reach <placeName>Balliana</placeName> until near one o'clock &#8211; as the wind was so light. <persName>Theodore, Mary</persName> and <persName>Bessie</persName> with <persName>Jones,</persName> 3 of our men and the lunch started at once for <orgName>Abydos.</orgName> <persName>Mary</persName> in my chair, with 2 donkeys &#8211; she pronounces the new harness a success. They had a beautiful excursion &#8211; I with the memory of my last two rides on the bad donkeys for which <persName>Abydos</persName> has long been famous, declined to go and had a pleasant busy day at home. An ideal day for such a long ride, cool, cloudy and no wind. We passed a large gyassa lying at <placeName>Balliana,</placeName> which looked as if it must have come straight from <orgName>The Sudan,</orgName> or from the <orgName>Arabian Nights</orgName> &#8211; loaded with strange interesting looking bales, in mattings, with pretty rugs &#8211; and patches of colour &#8211; queer looking skins filled with valuables hung about the masts &#8211; one red, and one green flag with characters from the <persName>Koran</persName> &#8211; and a lot of swarthy fellows in enormous white turbans, and spotless white gowns, sitting and lying about. Page 13 <persName>Salah</persName> not yet in sight &#8211; we hear they are at <placeName>Sohag</placeName> today. I am so sorry to lose them &#8211; but hope we may soon get together again. Sunday &#8211; 2d after Epiphany. Jan. 15. 10 miles. Light wind and tracking made 10 miles above <placeName>Balliana</placeName> weather warmer.
            Monday, Jan. 16. 28 miles. Could not start until near noon. When the wind came up we reached <placeName>Nag Hamade</placeName> at one o'clock &#8211; and waited for the bridge to open. The wind very strong and cool, and we were suffocated with the dust that blew over the high bank above us. At 3:30 when the bridge opened the wind so strong that I was surprised that <persName>Theodore</persName> would venture through. Our sailors took the rope on shore and we worked through under a good deal of excitement as the wind carried us against the iron barge, and it was with some scratches and much effort that we got through. A tearing wind for an hour growing somewhat quieter brought us at 10:30 to Dishneh.
            Sunday, Jan. 17. 20-1/2 miles. Off at 7 o'clock, reaching <placeName>Denderah</placeName> at 9:30. Wind high and much dust. The rest went to the temple. I wisely stayed at home &#8211; and took my exercise on the clean deck. They were back for one o'clock lunch, and we were off immediately, flying along in the highwind, when we found the chicken boat was full of water, <orgName>Page 14</orgName> and we made for land, coming in unpleasant contact with the Nitocris. We found 3 chickens dead, and several of the pigeons. The coops were lifted to shore and opened, and the half drowned survivors came out to dry themselves &#8211; but our one precious goose with a cry of joy made for the water, and took a long and enthusiastic bath. After the boat had been cleaned, and fowls put back, we started again &#8211; but the river was so dangerous with its sudden turns and gusts of wind we stopped at 5 o'clock at <placeName>Kuft.</placeName> Wednesday, 
            Jan. 18. 28 miles. Started at 7:30 &#8211; light wind &#8211; tracking, polling, we came to within 4 or 5 miles of <placeName>Luxor</placeName> &#8211; but cannot make the last turn in the river, without wind &#8211; so have stopped for the night.
            Thursday, Jan. 19. Luxor. 4 miles. We were until 2 P.M. making the four miles here, found only one dahabeah here &#8211; having passed the <name>Gazelle</name> early this morning. We came to our usual mooring, our favorite place under the <persName>Castle</persName> &#8211; and soon our friends had found us out. <persName>Achmed</persName> with his donkey boys &#8211; our chicken boy &#8211; <persName>Sablool</persName> &#8211; and all &#8211; I did not leave the boat, always enjoying the settling for a prolonged stay. The rest went to <placeName>Karnak</placeName> &#8211; still cool, even cold.
            <name>Thursday,</name> Jan. 26. Still at Luxor. It grows a little warmer. The <name>Lul&#232;e el Nil</name> came in on the 21st, and is just behind us. We have done the usual things. Races, visits to ruins etc &#8211; I went for the day with all, to the <placeName>Tombs of the Kings</placeName> &#8211; a lovely day, and coming home for the first time I used the carrying chair which <persName>Theodore</persName> has had rigged for donkeys &#8211; and found it most successful. Mr. <persName>Huhatt</persName> has been as usual to lunch and to play chess. The <name>Insingers</name> have been to call etc. etc. <persName>Reginald Norman</persName> and his brother <persName>Max,</persName> the <persName>Rough Rider</persName> whom we left recovering from fever in <placeName>Newport,</placeName> came up in the <placeName>Rameses</placeName> the Great to our surprise, and came to dine. Very calm weather. The <name>Lul&#232;e el Nil</name> went off today, and we shall go tomorrow if there is a breath of north wind. The moon is full, and the beauty of the nights is beyond belief and what a view we have of the mountains opposite, their soft yellow tones changing with every hour of the day. I can never weary of this &#8211; night or day &#8211; each hour has its own charm, and I do not want to leave the boat and lose it.
            Friday, Jan. 27. 34-1/2 miles. We got off this morning at 12 o'clock with a very light wind, which growing stronger brought us at 11 o'clock to Esneh.
            Saturday. Jan. 28. 41 miles. A fine wind began at 7 o'clock which has lasted Page 16 all day, and we have made our best record. A splendid day &#8211; every hour delightful. We are about 10 miles south of <placeName>Edfu</placeName> &#8211; passed <placeName>El Kab</placeName> this morning. Mr. <persName>Somers-Clarke</persName> not there &#8211; house shut &#8211; no dahabeah. Brought up at 2:30 at <placeName>Edfu</placeName> where we found the <orgName>Lul&#232;e el Nil.</orgName> The rest went off to the Temple. The natives here very noisy and unmanageable. We got away sometime after the <persName>Lulie el Nil,</persName> but passed her in the evening and are now tied up near each other. A splendid night &#8211; the sight of the full moon sailing up out of the horizon was wonderful.
            <placeName>Septuagesima</placeName> Sunday. Jan. 29. 31 miles. <name>Kom Ombo.</name> Started at 7 &#8211; in good wind, reached <persName>Silsilis</persName> at noon &#8211; and visited the quarries. The other boat came up and joined us &#8211; and we both succeeded in reaching <placeName>Kom Ombo</placeName> about 6 P.M. <persName>Mary</persName> has gone up with the girls from the other boat to see the <persName>Temple</persName> by this pleasant soft moonlight.
            Asw&#226;n. Jan. 30. Monday. 26 miles. Went up to the <persName>Temple</persName> after breakfast and were off at 10:30, sailing splendidly into <placeName>Asswan</placeName> at 5 o'clock. The <name>Lulie el Nil</name> not far behind us. Found the <name>Istar, Hathor, Cairo, Ammon Ra, Nephthis, Oonas,</name> and <persName>Isis</persName> here &#8211; with <persName>Cheops</persName> and <orgName>Horus.</orgName> Difficult to find a place.
            <name>Asw&#226;n</name> &#8211; Feb. 5th. Sunday. We start tomorrow for <persName>Wady Halfa,</persName> with Mrs. <persName>Parsons</persName> and the girls. We are really sorry to leave <persName>Prof. Sayce,</persName> behind whose boat we are lying. He is suffering from a bad case of blood poisoning &#8211; with a bad carbuncle on his neck just mending, and a very bad finger with an inflamed arm &#8211; and being quite alone on his boat, his situation has seemed so triste, that we have been having him with us most of the time. He has dined with us almost every night, in spite of his protests about his bandaged appearance. He gives us all the news we have had as to work along the river. The <name>Marquis of Northampton</name> on his <persName>dahabeah M&#226;at</persName> has gone down earlier than usual, in order to put <name>Lady Northampton</name> under the care of a <placeName>Paris</placeName> doctor. It is feared that the nervous disorder of which she has been the unhappy victim, is the forerunner of creeping paralysis. The <orgName>Marquess</orgName> is bearing all the expense of the excavations <persName>Newberry</persName> is making at <placeName>Thebes</placeName> &#8211; and they have found a rich and interesting tomb of one <orgName>Tahuti,</orgName> "the beloved friend of Queen <persName>Hatshepsowet",</persName> and are on the track of another tomb &#8211; all the finds go to the <placeName>Ghizeh Museum</placeName> &#8211; which is very generous on the part of the <persName>M.</persName> of <persName>N. Flinders-Petrie</persName> is excavating near <persName>Hou</persName> &#8211; and <placeName>Quibell</placeName> and <placeName>Somers-Clarke</placeName> are still at work at <placeName>Kom el Akmar</placeName> opposite <placeName>El Kab.</placeName> The latter has taken his boat up above the <orgName>Cataract,</orgName> but is expected down this month. The weather has been comfortably warm here &#8211; we have spent one day at <placeName>Philae</placeName> &#8211; found the <orgName>Newmans</orgName> there, and went down to their boat after lunch. <persName>Yemma</persName> was there clean and well grown &#8211; but very thin, having just recovered from pneumonia. Came home in one of Page 18 the cataract boats &#8211; quite exciting, as the river is so full. Thousands of workmen are now employed on the weir at <placeName>Assouan.</placeName> I went across the desert to <placeName>Philae</placeName> in the donkey chair &#8211; and great numbers of masses of quarried stone are lying in orderly array along the route &#8211; and blasting going on in various places, and red flags fluttering here and there, and the beautiful red brown tint of the rocks bringing the bare white surfaces of the lately quarried rocks into glaring and painful contrast, and more painful still were the transformed shores of the river along the cataract. Their beautiful isolation, and quiet loveliness, now broken with the sounds of blasting &#8211; the raw surfaces of the newly cut rocks &#8211; the almost continuous buildings of the agents and employees, hospitals, storehouses etc., steam launches rushing about &#8211; and the barbaric quiet of the river gone for ever! It is a pity! Mr. <persName>Sayce</persName> came to tea and sat until after dark &#8211; looking very miserable indeed.
            Monday, Feb. 6th. <name>S.S. Tewfik.</name> We had an early breakfast and were across the river and off in time for the train at 9 o'clock. Our cook came with us, as he wanted to see his old friends, having been employed on this boat for two years. He took great pains to confide as to the attention of all the servants. We find our former cook boy <persName>Tommy</persName> among the crew. We were off at 11 o'clock &#8211; and are delighted with this very comfortable, clean boat. There are not many passengers, our rooms, the table, and the service, <orgName>Page 19</orgName> are excellent. We passed <persName>Dab&#226;d</persName> where is a temple of an <orgName>Ethiopian</orgName> monarch, a contemporary of <orgName>Ptolemy IV</orgName> but did not stop &#8211; then <persName>Cartassi</persName> where are a ruined temple and quarries &#8211; then <persName>Wady Tafa</persName> also with temple ruins, then <persName>Kal&#226;bsha</persName> with its temple built in the reign of <persName>Augustus</persName> on an older foundation as stones with the names of <persName>Amenhotep II</persName> and <persName>Thothmes III</persName> have been found there. We saw this on our former journey up here, and were little interested in it. Passed also <persName>K&#234;t el-Wali,</persName> with temple ruins of <persName>Ramses II</persName> &#8211; arriving at <placeName>Dendur</placeName> about 7 o'clock P.M. which was our first stop, and where we spent the night &#8211; I did not go up with the rest to see the temple. Made 52-1/2 miles.
            Feb. 7. Tuesday. Started at 5 o'clock &#8211; and made <persName>Dakka,</persName> where we stopped to see a temple of <persName>Aeg-Amen,</persName> an <orgName>Ethiopian</orgName> king, built on foundation of <persName>Amenemhat I.</persName> I did not go to see it. Then we stopped at <placeName>Wady es-Sab&#251;</placeName> &#224;, where is a temple of <orgName>Ramses II,</orgName> lying almost buried in yellow sand &#8211; which was not inviting in the hot noon time. Reached <placeName>Korosko,</placeName> the large and important town at 7:30 where we spent the night, making 69 miles. We are impressed with this part of the <placeName>Nile</placeName> &#8211; so different in its features from the lower part of the river. The villages, desolate but clean looking &#8211; the houses so well and squarely built &#8211; large with their domed roofs and many window openings, looking almost attractive. The people look cleaner &#8211; but there are so few of them &#8211; and what can they in this desert country live on!
            Wednesday, Feb. 8. This morning half of the passengers were called at 5 o'clock, to make the ascent of the mountain at <placeName>Korosko</placeName> &#8211; and see the sun rise &#8211; naturally the other half found their slumbers much interrupted by the departure and arrival of the others. Before the <placeName>Sudan</placeName> trade was interfered with by the war years ago, this was the point of departure for <persName>Abu Hamed</persName> &#8211; and when we were here 7 years ago, there was a large and important garrison here, which does not exist now. Stopped at <placeName>Amada</placeName> about noon, and I got out with the rest to see the temple founded by <persName>Usertesen III</persName> and added to and restored from time to time by <orgName>Thotmes III Amenhetep</orgName> II, Thotmes IV and <persName>Seti</persName> I &#8211; whose cartouches we found. It needs excavating, as the sand has almost covered and filled it. Fine d&#244;m palms are showing themselves in profusion &#8211; and the splendid drifts of yellow, yellow sand &#8211; what <persName>Miss Edwards</persName> happily describes as "snow drifts turned to gold". Between <name>Amada</name> and <persName>Derr,</persName> the country is rich with splendid palms &#8211; the best dates come from here. <persName>Kasr Ibr&#238;m</persName> we passed in the afternoon with its <orgName>Roman</orgName> ruins on the cliffs, and rock tombs beneath &#8211; and we brought up at 8 o'clock at <placeName>Abu Simbel</placeName> where we are now lying &#8211; the rest went with their lanterns up to see it &#8211; but as we stop on our way down, <persName>Lellie Parsons</persName> and I stayed home. We had a little sensation yesterday late in the afternoon when we came to where the little steamer "Edfu", of the <placeName>Khedivial</placeName> line had been sticking in the sand for 21 days. A large force of men were at work, and we stopped to give them a pull &#8211; but in vain &#8211; and after breaking our cable twice, we left her. 
            68-1/2 miles. Thursday, Feb. 9. <persName>Wady Halfa.</persName> Left <persName>Abu Simbel</persName> early this morning &#8211; I was awakened at 3 A.M. by the different people being aroused to see the <name>Southern Cross</name> &#8211; and again by our early start. We reached <name>Halfa</name> at 11 o'clock, passing dahabeah "Thames" on her way down. The country in spite of its desert air, is interesting &#8211; and even beautiful, with its strange mountain peaks, and the evidences everywhere of proplonged water action &#8211; and everything partly submerged in yellow, pink sand drifts &#8211; no birds to be seen &#8211; many fine dome like sycamores, and the finest tamarasks I have ever seen &#8211; the foliage so thick and brightly green. We have made 40 miles. We drew up to what is an entirely new quarter of <name>Halfa,</name> called <name>Tewfikyia</name> &#8211; good <orgName>European</orgName> houses, new and clean &#8211; a fine modern mosque, bazaar, <orgName>Greek</orgName> shops, etc. All our people chose to go to the 2d cataract this afternoon, instead of waiting for the regular excursion in the morning. The wind was strong and cold, and sand flying in clouds. They took one of the large sail boats, and with the <persName>Reis</persName> of the steamer and several of the sailors started, not returning until we had nearly finished dinner. They reported that they were not only able to sail up to the rock of <placeName>Abusir,</placeName> but 3 miles beyond. I spent a quiet, nice afternoon with <persName>Mrs. Parsons</persName> &#8211; the whole boat enveloped in canvass, to protect us from the wind and sand. However the little open space in the center of the steamer, which really serves us as drawing room, was very comfortable. It is where afternoon tea is served, and coffee. This evening we took refuge in the dining saloon Page 22 as it was so cold. The doctor of the <persName>Fort</persName> was on board, and was presented to us &#8211; and has invited us to see the fort tomorrow.
            <placeName>Friday,</placeName> Feb. 10. <persName>Abu Simbel.</persName> Immediately after breakfast we mounted donkeys and started for <placeName>Salah's</placeName> house, stopping en route at the <placeName>Fort,</placeName> two miles from <placeName>Tewfikyia.</placeName> It is very large &#8211; indeed is <name>Halfa</name> &#8211; with its railway &#8211; machine shops &#8211; hospitals &#8211; prisons, officers' quarters and barracks &#8211; we saw the hospital, and a company of conscripts just arrived &#8211; and dervishes working in chains. They were not permitted to show "Mamoud" whom we would like to have seen &#8211; saw an interesting collection of dervish arms etc. &#8211; at the doctor's quarters &#8211; and a lovely little gazelle wandering about among the palms of the little enclosure. A very dusty ride of 2 miles or more to <placeName>Salah's</placeName> house &#8211; which we found greatly improved since our last visit. We were shown into a large room well lighted with good windows &#8211; nice rugs on the floor, and divan &#8211; and tea waiting for us &#8211; with good china etc. The old mother, supposed to be over 90, and quite blind, was led in by <persName>Salah</persName> &#8211; and then he brought his pretty wife <persName>Tamai,</persName> with a clean and very pretty baby in her arms, who was frightened into tears at the sight of such fearsome white beings as we were. <persName>Tamai</persName> has grown a trifle stouter since I saw her 7 years ago &#8211; was well, even richly dressed. She evidently hated to have us look at her baby. Home by one o'clock, and off immediately for <persName>Abu Simbel,</persName> reaching here at 4:30. We went to the temples at once. "Thames" lying Page 23 here &#8211; and post boat stopped to allow her few passengers to see the temples. An elderly man was pointed out to me as the <name>Earl of Carlisle</name> who had been to <placeName>Khartoum</placeName> to see the grave of his son, Mr. <persName>Howard</persName> who met his death, after the battle in the streets of <placeName>Omdurm&#226;n.</placeName>
            Saturday, Feb. 11. Got up at 6 to see the dawn on the faces of the splendid colossi &#8211; went again to the great temple after breakfast &#8211; started at 10 o'clock &#8211; wind high and cold &#8211; stopped at <placeName>Derr,</placeName> about 2 o'clock &#8211; did not get off &#8211; a crowd of the noisiest natives I ever saw, besieged the boat and made a hideous din &#8211; passed <persName>Korosko</persName> at 5:30 &#8211; and are still steaming down the river, and will not stop until we reach <orgName>Marakya.</orgName> In getting away from <persName>Derr</persName> we broke one of the paddle blades, and had to stop to repair it.
            Sunday evening &#8211; Feb. 12. It was a pleasant thought on waking this morning to know that we would reach home this afternoon. We stopped for an hour at <placeName>Kalabshi</placeName> I did not go to the temple, which I had seen before, and which is only interesting from its inscriptions which of course we could not read. The most typical and barbaric crowd about the boat, offering <orgName>Dervish</orgName> arms, dresses etc. for sale. Many of these people had served as officers servants during the late campaign, and of course had possessed themselves of many trophies &#8211; which they held at enormous prices. I saw one naked black boy, clothed in a <orgName>Seaforth Highlander</orgName> waistcoat! and another Page 24 black fellow with enormous white turban, and bristling with arms, smoking a pipe! After we got away from <persName>Kalabshi,</persName> had a nice little service, our pleasant little vicar (Brockenbury) officiating &#8211; passed <persName>Somers-Clarke</persName> boat at <placeName>Dabb&#244;d</placeName> &#8211; reached <placeName>Shellal</placeName> at 2 o'clock, and found it entirely en f&#234;te, the Duke and <placeName>Duchess of Connaught</placeName> having arrived en route for Khartoum. <orgName>Flags,</orgName> pennants, everywhere, and the royal standard floating over the little steamer on which they were. We were soon in one of the <orgName>Cataract</orgName> boats, making the descent, and at 5 o'clock were once more on this blessed <orgName>Beduin</orgName> &#8211; a band of happy pilgrims, home from their wanderings. <persName>Theodore</persName> and <persName>Bess</persName> crossed the river to <placeName>Asswan,</placeName> stopping at the <placeName>Istar</placeName> on their way home, reporting Mr. <persName>Sayce</persName> better. 
            Monday, Feb. 13. Such a pleasant quiet day at home. Mr. <persName>Sayce</persName> came to tea and afterwards to dinner &#8211; looking rather better. Mr. <persName>Somers-Clarke</persName> came for a call this morning, and Mrs. <persName>Parson</persName> and the girls, the vicar and his friend came down in a cataract boat, and made us a farewell visit &#8211; as they went off on the <placeName>Post</placeName> boat at noon &#8211; expecting to pick up their dahabeah between this and Esneh. The <persName>Craiks,</persName> the vicar and Mr. <persName>Brotherton</persName> came to tea also, and everybody stayed later than everybody else. Mr. <persName>Somers-Clarke</persName> left his boat at <placeName>Philae,</placeName> and rode over &#8211; not expecting to come down for a few days. He says he found the upper <placeName>Nile</placeName> enchanting in a dahabeah. He stopped at 60 places &#8211; and has made plans and drawings of 20. Happy occupation! We are trying to persuade <persName>Theodore</persName> to wait until Saturday, and start down in the company of the Page 25 <name>Istar</name> and <name>Althar</name> &#8211; but in vain. I am always struggling to get amongst these <orgName>Egyptologists</orgName> for the interesting things they can give &#8211; but it is generally in vain. Tuesday, Feb. 14. We are ready to start tomorrow, having found <persName>Theodore</persName> obstinate &#8211; <persName>Mary</persName> and I went to tea this afternoon on the <persName>Istar,</persName> and then took a last, little row in the charming river among the rocks. Met on the <name>Istar, Mr. Buxton</name> of dahabeah <persName>Nephthys</persName> &#8211; and <persName>Lord</persName> and <persName>Lady Bellhaven</persName> staying at the hotel &#8211; Mr. <persName>Sayce</persName> came to dinner.
            Wednesday, Feb. 15. Started this morning at 9 and have made 15 miles. 
            <placeName>Thursday,</placeName> Feb. 16. Got off at 6 o'clock and have made about 13 miles &#8211; strong north wind &#8211; passed the <orgName>Chonsu,</orgName> which lay just behind us at <placeName>Elephantine</placeName> at <placeName>Kom Ombo.</placeName> Though small, she is a heavy, wooden boat, and outfloats us entirely. We have pulled up to a low sand bank in the river, and lying quite out in the water &#8211; without a visible human being near us. I would always like to lie in such a spot &#8211; it is an ideal place to stop at &#8211; the river itself so wide here, and the desert on each side wider still. We are about two miles from <placeName>Silsilis</placeName> &#8211; I stayed on deck until 10 minutes of dinner time, and went up again after dinner. The moon is still in her first quarter &#8211; and the stars so radiant &#8211; such beautiful Page 26 loneliness &#8211; one could almost touch it, and feel the Divine Creative force and meaning. 
            Friday, Feb. 17. 6 miles. Off at 7 o'clock &#8211; north wind increasing &#8211; we however passed <persName>Silsilis</persName> soon after breakfast, and are lying tonight only about 4 miles below &#8211; having fought our way along for even this distance. Very warm and heavy clouds collected, and about 2 o'clock, a sand storm broke upon us, and for an hour or more the heat was great, 78 on my balcony. A beautiful rainbow afterwards &#8211; and tonight is serenely lovely and cooler.
            Saturday, Feb. 18. 28 miles. Got off at 7 P.M. &#8211; calm &#8211; reached <persName>Edfou</persName> at one o'clock, and stopped for certain things such as yeast, butter and such &#8211; then the wind began to blow, and drifting and rowing we tied up 6 miles below <placeName>Edfou.</placeName> Passed this morning dahabeah <persName>Cleopatra</persName> with tug going up &#8211; and this P.M. also going up, the <persName>Juliette, Manhattan, Gamilla</persName> and one other. Warm - 76&#730;.
            1st Sunday in Lent. Feb. 19. 23 miles. Starting at our usual time this morning, 7 o'clock &#8211; we reached <name>El Kab</name> at 9 o'clock &#8211; and went out to the tombs &#8211; I riding a wretched little donkey, the others walking. It was just 6 years ago that we did the same thing &#8211; and made Page 27 a visit to Mr. <persName>Tyler,</persName> and <persName>Mr. Somers-Clarke</persName> who were then excavating there. We were warmly welcomed by my old woman, and the three dogs who live at <placeName>Mr. Somers-Clarke's</placeName> house &#8211; and I fancy all four will sleep more comfortably tonight, from the good feeding they got. We are now at <placeName>Esneh</placeName> &#8211; a beautiful day &#8211; and inspiring air &#8211; and a radiant night &#8211; wind a little cool. Passed a large dahabeah going up &#8211; and one of the <orgName>Khedivial</orgName> steamers going up for the Duke and <placeName>Duchess of Connaught.</placeName> 
            <placeName>Monday,</placeName> Feb. 20. Luxor. 34-1/2 miles. We reached here at 3 o'clock this afternoon &#8211; very warm indeed. Came again to our old place under the <orgName>Castle.</orgName> Found only two dahabeahs here &#8211; and I never saw <placeName>Luxor</placeName> so quiet. 
            Tuesday, Feb. 21. Very high wind all day &#8211; <persName>Theodore</persName> and <persName>Bessie</persName> went to <name>Der el Medineh.</name> Wednesday, 
            Feb. 22. Cool weather with strong wind from the north. <persName>Rode</persName> into <placeName>Luxor</placeName> and Mr. <persName>Huhatt</persName> came to play chess with <persName>Theodore,</persName> and stayed to lunch. <persName>Mary</persName> and <persName>Bessie</persName> spent the day at <placeName>Deir el Bahri.</placeName> 
            <name>Luxor,</name> Thursday. March 2. We must start down the river tomorrow &#8211; though we hate the necessity. It is so pleasant here &#8211; so many interesting things to do, and people to see. We have had 9 days here. <persName>Theodore</persName> has had Mr. <persName>Huhatt</persName> almost every day to lunch &#8211; and to play chess &#8211; I have crossed the river 3 times and had that charming ride, on my best of little donkeys, <placeName>Yankee Doodle Plymouth Rock!</placeName> First, <persName>Theodore, Bessie</persName> and I went to <persName>Gurnah,</persName> to call on Mr. <persName>Newberry</persName> whom we found at home. <persName>Earl Spencer</persName> and his wife were making him a visit and after they went away we looked at many of the beautiful things belonging to Mr. <persName>Newberry.</persName> All the things found in their excavations were packed and most of them on their way to the Museum. We had tea, and then he and <persName>Prof. Spiegelberg</persName> who has been working with him all the winter showed us one of the tombs they had opened, called the <orgName>Gardeners Tomb,</orgName> with very beautiful decorations in painting &#8211; the colours bright as new. The tomb was just below the house of the <persName>Sheik</persName> which they have been living in all winter. Mr. <persName>Newberry</persName> asked us to go with him to some of the private tombs, I had never seen &#8211; and the following Sunday morning <persName>Theodore, Bessie</persName> and I went over after breakfast &#8211; charming morning. The ride along the high canal embankment is now rather disagreeable, as hundreds of workmen are busy digging out the silt, left from last years inundation. In this way this great embankment grows higher and wider every year. The sun proved very hot while we were clambering over and down the rough desert of that ancient necropolis, with its yawning pits. We went first to one that had been delicately beautiful in its low relief. Page 29 It is now inhabited by fellaheen, and the sculptures are almost entirely buried in debris. Then to the tomb of <persName>Nekht</persName> &#8211; then to one of <persName>Rekh-ma-ra,</persName> who was Governor of <persName>Thebes,</persName> and died in the reign of <persName>Amenhotep II.</persName> This tomb with its elaborate sculptures and paintings, Mr. <persName>Newberry</persName> is doing for publication, and we must have it when it comes out. It was delightful to have Mr. <persName>Newberry</persName> show it to us, which he did con amore &#8211; with every explanation. It was after 12 when we said goodbye to him, he having promised to come to dinner with us the next night. We found him more interesting than we thought &#8211; knows everybody and everything &#8211; began life as a scientific botanist under Sir <persName>Joseph Hooker</persName> &#8211; and we fraternised at once over our mutual tastes in gardening and architecture. Then we met Mr. <persName>Howard Carter</persName> &#8211; who has been doing such beautiful work at <placeName>Der el Bahri,</placeName> for so long. He also came to dine, and we went over and had tea with him the afternoon before we came away &#8211; and I chose the subjects of two sketches he is to make for me &#8211; <persName>Queen Aahmes</persName> &#8211; and Queen Sensenet, Mother of Thothmes I. The <persName>Buxtons,</persName> who are on the <orgName>Nepthys,</orgName> and whom we met at <placeName>Asw&#226;n,</placeName> taking tea with us one afternoon, told us that Mrs. Buxton's (Gurney) grandfather's gamekeeper, was this young <persName>Carter's</persName> father, and that he had great talent (the father) in drawing animals. An interesting history &#8211; we came very near stumbling upon the Duke and <name>Duchess of Connaught</name> one afternoon as we went to pay a visit to the Buxtons. They asked us to come again a little later, as the <persName>Duke</persName> had sent word that they were coming to have tea with them &#8211; so we refrained from entering the boat. The <name>Nephtys, Thames</name> and <name>Istar</name> all came down the same day. Poor Mr. <persName>Sayce</persName> is again in great suffering Page 30 and under the surgical care of the doctor here. <persName>Theodore</persName> and I went to see him yesterday &#8211; he was in bed &#8211; but called to me to come and speak to him. It really seems very serious. We have made the acquaintance of Mr. <persName>Chauncey Murch,</persName> the head of the <orgName>American Mission</orgName> here at <placeName>Luxor.</placeName> He has been 15 years in <placeName>Egypt</placeName> &#8211; and is a native of <name>Ohio</name> &#8211; of <placeName>Reynoldsburg,</placeName> nor far from <placeName>Columbus,</placeName> where I used sometimes to drive as a child with my father. Mr. <persName>Murch</persName> is really huge &#8211; a nice little wife. He has the most rare and beautiful collection of scarabs I have ever seen &#8211; and of small objects. Our old friend <persName>Mohammed Mohassib</persName> has had some very interesting things. Among others some pre-historic mummies &#8211; brought from <placeName>Nagada.</placeName> One of which <persName>Theodore</persName> bought, and is going to present it to the <placeName>Metropolitan Museum of New York.</placeName>
            Friday, March 3d. <persName>Theodore</persName> and I went to see Mr. <persName>Sayce</persName> this morning &#8211; but I did not see him. He reported himself going on as well as could be hoped &#8211; we got away about noon, in a light north wind, passed the <orgName>Nepthys</orgName> lying at <placeName>Karnac.</placeName> Have made about 17-1/2 miles and are now some 5 miles south of <placeName>Nagada.</placeName>
            Saturday, March 4th. Have made only 7-1/2 miles, and are 2 miles below <placeName>Nagada.</placeName> Day cool &#8211; but wind very fitful.
            Third Sunday in <placeName>Lent.</placeName> March 5th. An early start, but have accomplished little. Are now within 2 or 3 miles of Keneh. The wind has raged at times. The <persName>Nephthys</persName> appeared early in the afternoon, and the <name>Buxtons</name> and <persName>Miss Gurney</persName> came to tea. We are now lying at anchor, both boats, almost side by side.
            Monday, March 6. 14 miles. We have struggled with the wind all day, and are now lying near the bank about 12 miles below <placeName>Keneh.</placeName> The <orgName>Buxtons</orgName> stopped there. I love to lie near some desert shore, or best some lonely stretch of sand, and anchored near the land. The feeling of being so apart, the lapping of the water and the silence, all, all, delightful. 
            Tuesday, March 7. 17 miles. The same history for the day &#8211; an early start, baffling winds, then calms, until as usual about 4 o'clock a regular gale began &#8211; and we lay sometime at anchor, until we finally pulled to shore, starting again about 9 o'clock, and going a short distance, about 10 miles above <placeName>Nagh Hamadi.</placeName>
            Wednesday, March 8. 14 miles. Started early, and reached <persName>Nagh Hamadi</persName> about 10 o'clock, finding the bridge closed, so we tied up to the float next the bridge, and waited for the three o'clock Page 32 opening. The day very hot. Soon after the <persName>"Manhattan"</persName> came down, and took a position behind us &#8211; and in the distance the <orgName>Nepthys</orgName> appeared, but she was too far behind to take advantage of that opening, and I suppose will have to wait for tomorrow 6 o'clock A.M. We got through with some little excitement, and have made 4 miles since, and are lying at an island, with the <placeName>Manhattan</placeName> near.
            Thursday, March 9. 38-1/2 miles. We have done very well today, and are now 4 miles below <placeName>Menshieh,</placeName> or 3-1/2 miles south of <placeName>Akmim.</placeName> Very hot - 85&#730; on my cabana, and the mercury standing at 50 this morning.
            Friday, March 10. 26 miles. We started early - I heard the sailors at their oars by 5:30 - and at 8:30, we were tying up at the handsome town of <placeName>Sohag</placeName> - to get our mail and provisions. We must have been there two hours - and pulled up at 7:30 this evening within 7 miles of <placeName>Tahtah.</placeName> Calms and contrary winds all day. Much cooler than yesterday. We have been struggling with a great batch of newspapers today - all of them full of extraordinary storms in <orgName>America,</orgName> and the unprecedented cold - which is hard for us to realize. They bring too, the welcome news of <orgName>Kipling's</orgName> improvement, who has been so ill with pneumonia. He is now said to be out of danger. The world can ill spare such a mind and spirit. Page 33 Saturday, Mar. 11. 22 miles. Started at 5:30 &#8211; with the exception of about 3 hours of calm, we have had baffling north winds all day &#8211; very warm &#8211; deck disagreeable. We are now about 2 or 3 miles north of <placeName>Gaen,</placeName> and are lying pleasantly anchored near the shore. Fourth Sunday in <placeName>Lent.</placeName> Mar. 12. 15 miles. Reached <persName>Aboutig</persName> at one o'clock, where we stayed two hours &#8211; <persName>Theodore</persName> writing and telegraphing Cook at <placeName>Cairo</placeName> about our passage across to <orgName>Italy.</orgName> High north wind much of the time all day, in spite of the heat. <persName>Mary</persName> and <persName>Bessie</persName> walked into the town to the <placeName>P.O.</placeName> with the sailors. While they were away, I sat out in the shade of my cabana, and looked at the white heat that pervaded the world. Across the water at the edge of a broad stretch of sand, were two large groups of native men, engaged in some disputation. I took my glass and watched them &#8211; and could not but admire their gestures and bearing &#8211; in spite of their heavy, trailing garments of black and dark brown, which looked so inappropriate &#8211; and, as they in the heat of argument threw their white scarfs off, and again on, they might have served as studies to a school of acting. At last they separated, going their ways across the burning sand, striding along, one after the other. The country is full of poppy fields in bloom &#8211; such pretty pictures they make along the bank.
            <name>Monday,</name> March 13. 20 miles. Reached <placeName>Asyut</placeName> at 11 o'clock, and stopped long enough to get our mail. I had some nice letters &#8211; one from Mrs. <persName>Norman,</persName> full of wailing about the dreadful winter at home. One from Mr. <persName>Sayce,</persName> saying he was able to walk a little, and the Doctor thought him progressing favorably. After quitting <persName>Asyut,</persName> we passed the place of the future barrage &#8211; where 3 or 4 thousand men are at work. It was a scene from the <orgName>Inferno</orgName> &#8211; dust &#8211; turmoil &#8211; smoke of machines &#8211; shrieks of steam &#8211; inconceivable &#8211; and in such a heat! I was thankful when a turn in the river hid the hideous sight. We had the fowls out for a little while, and <persName>Dick</persName> came up to the deck to see me, and get his biscuit. A little new moon has appeared. Tuesday, Mar. 14. 36-1/2 miles. A very hot gray day &#8211; like a <orgName>Kamseen,</orgName> without the wind. Occasionally a gentle south wind which carried us along successfully the whole <placeName>Abu Feda</placeName> chain, with its dangerous bends. A very hot night - 86&#730; on the cabana, and 82 in my room! Wednesday, Mar. 15. Minia. 48-1/2 miles. We have had a beautiful run, and are now ahead of our time. The heat has been great &#8211; of a more trying quality than that of yesterday &#8211; still very gray and overcast, and apparently threatening rain every moment. Lying at the disagreeable bank of <orgName>Minia.</orgName> Page 35 Thursday. Mar. 16. 28-1/2 miles. A perfectly calm, translucent grey day, sometimes a light wind from the north. The men have worked hard with their oars, and we are now near <persName>Sheik Fadl</persName> &#8211; and can see the lights of the great sugar factories &#8211; I think we must be within two miles of it. Have spent most of the day down stairs writing. Have finished my questions on the <name>Constitution of the</name> <placeName>United States.</placeName> Every moment today has threatened rain &#8211; mercury at 85&#730;! We are lying out in the stream &#8211; both of my big windows are uncurtained, and I look out unimpeded on the night, with the water softly gurgling about the boat. How I love it! Friday, Mar. 17. 32-1/2 miles. Another gray and very hot day, until late in the afternoon when the wind grew strong, coming in gusts, and tonight it is from the north and cold. We are within 4 miles of <placeName>Fashen</placeName> &#8211; we saw our young moon last night for the first time. Thermometer 90 on deck today. We smashed our bowsprit this afternoon, the wind driving us on the bank. Saturday, Mar. 18. 28 miles. A gray day again, but cooler &#8211; and several times rain has fallen. We were driven below by quite a smart little shower this morning &#8211; saw one of the most beautiful pelicans &#8211; with bill quite red in under portion, and green above. <name>Rowed Page</name> 36 until after 8 o'clock &#8211; and are now 5 miles below Benisoef. 5th Sunday in <placeName>Lent.</placeName> Mar. 19. 28 miles. Stopped at <placeName>Wasta</placeName> for mail this morning at 11 o'clock &#8211; and tied up at 6 o'clock tonight 26 miles from <placeName>Bedrasheyn.</placeName> Day hot &#8211; and wind cold. How we do hate to be winding up the pleasant <orgName>Nile</orgName> days &#8211; and how I shall miss my charming room. The brilliant nights, when with uncurtained windows I could look out upon the night &#8211; the swiftly flowing river &#8211; the desert, or the palm fringed shore. The early morning readings in bed, or the watching of the dawn. How tame the land will seem, and how shut in and stifling a curtained room will seem! Then how comfortable to move from place to place with no packing to do &#8211; simply to keep on one's way in one's own house!
            Monday, March 20. 26 miles. Are once more lying at <placeName>Bedrasheyn,</placeName> which we reached at 7 o'clock. Strong wind from the north.
            <name>Tuesday,</name> March 21. 15 miles. Started very early this morning &#8211; and reached the <placeName>Museum</placeName> landing at <placeName>Ghizeh</placeName> at 9:30. Our old man, the guardian of the Museum barge, was very glad to see us, and we found the <persName>Loulie-el-Nil,</persName> lying just in front of us &#8211; and her Captain and sailors welcomed us warmly, and with ready help. We are very glad to have got <orgName>Page 37</orgName> a berth here as it is so convenient to visit the Museum. <persName>Theodore</persName> went to town, and came back with our mail, and <persName>Salah,</persName> bringing his arms full of flowers for me. <persName>Mary</persName> and I drove into town in the afternoon, and met Mr. <persName>Newberry,</persName> and asked him to dine tomorrow. He came on the train this morning, and said he passed us below <placeName>Bedrescheyn</placeName> this morning at 6 o'clock. We drove about the orange gardens on our way home. <persName>Alas!</persName> owing to some disease last year, they have all been shorn of their branches, and cut almost to the ground, and all the diseased branches and leaves have been left everywhere as they fell from the trees, and are now quite withered and dry &#8211; and have fully no doubt, impregnated the ground with their disease germs &#8211; when this has been thoroughly accomplished, they will cart them away &#8211; and this is the native method with everything in life &#8211; and this is why <orgName>Egyptians</orgName> and <placeName>Egypt</placeName> will always need an intelligent domineering.
            Wednesday, March 22. We all went over early to the Museum this morning &#8211; and how pleasant it was to see it all again. The new finds are enormously interesting. One of the most remarkable is a statue of bronze, heroic size, found at <placeName>Kom el-Ahmar,</placeName> opposite <placeName>El Kab,</placeName> by Mr. <persName>Quibell</persName> &#8211; with a smaller statue near it of the same material; and the gold hawks head that we saw last year on Mr. <persName>Somers-Clarke's</persName> dahabeah, found at the same place, and above all a large slate, from the same place, and with the name of a king preceeding <persName>Mena</persName> &#8211; a most remarkable piece. We spent a long time among all the beautiful little objects up stairs &#8211; and I Page 38 looked at the mummy of the beautiful <persName>Nefertari</persName> and fancied I could trace lines of beauty in the shrunken black face &#8211; and wondered why she was not laid beside her victorious and famous husband <persName>Aahmes,</persName> the first king of the 18th dynasty. We met Mr. <persName>Newberry</persName> there, and he showed us such interesting things &#8211; and he introduced Mr. <persName>Quibell,</persName> and also <persName>Baron von Bissing,</persName> a very clever young scholar who is working at the <placeName>Museum.</placeName> <persName>Mary</persName> and I drove in the afternoon and we had a charming evening with Mr. <persName>Newberry</persName> &#8211; and we talked <placeName>Egypt</placeName> and things <orgName>Egyptian</orgName> galore. The moon is almost full now &#8211; and I enjoy the nights, with my curtains not drawn and all the night looking in upon me.
            <name>Thursday,</name> March 23. Again at the <placeName>Museum</placeName> this morning &#8211; though first Mr. <persName>Newberry</persName> came by appointment to go to <persName>Ali</persName> the <orgName>Antiquity</orgName> man in <placeName>Ghirgeh</placeName> with us. <persName>Theodore</persName> bought some good things &#8211; we stumbled by chance in the Museum after Mr. <persName>Newberry</persName> left us, upon a room entirely filled with things from the tomb of <placeName>Amenophis III</placeName> which was found last year by <persName>M. Loret</persName> of the Museum. Such wonderful blue glazes &#8211; and such exquisite work! In the afternoon <persName>Mary</persName> and I drove out almost to the Pyramids. It was tremendously hot &#8211; and a high wind blowing as it has blown for days. One of our horses soon after we turned to come home, had the blind staggers &#8211; <persName>Mary</persName> and I easily stepped out of the <persName>Victoria,</persName> the coachman and <persName>Salah</persName> sprang from the box &#8211; but these people are so unready and helpless in an emergency &#8211; they could not relieve the poor animal of the harness &#8211; a mounted gens d'armes fortunately arrived, and gave <persName>Page</persName> 39 what help he could &#8211; the horse at last struggled on his feet, and then began the wildest scene, the poor beast crazed, kicked everything to pieces, overturned the nice carriage, which by great exertion on the part of <persName>Salah</persName> and the coachman was just saved as it was going over the embankment &#8211; the dash board, dashes, lamps were smashed &#8211; the pole broken in 3 pieces &#8211; the harness a wreck. The other horse behaved most beautifully and intelligently &#8211; as quiet as possible, and showed such concern for the sick one, that it was quite touching. Everyone who passed offered assistance, but we sent to the <placeName>Mena House</placeName> for another carriage, and arrived at home a few minutes before dinner. 
            Friday, March 24. Museum &#8211; driving &#8211; <persName>Mr. Newberry</persName> to lunch &#8211; very hot &#8211; wind still very strong.
            Saturday, March 25. Another morning at the <persName>Museum,</persName> and Mr. <persName>Quibell</persName> to lunch &#8211; a kamseen day &#8211; dry &#8211; hot &#8211; windy &#8211; I declined going out.
            Sunday, March 26. Sunday before Easter. A very hot morning - <persName>Mary</persName> and <persName>Bessie</persName> drove into town - <persName>Theodore</persName> to the <placeName>Museum,</placeName> a long visit from Mr. <persName>Paterson</persName> which prevented me from doing what I had devoted the morning to do. At home all day - <persName>"Thames"</persName> came down today - and the <orgName>Ammon-Ra</orgName> last evening with a tug. Saw the <orgName>Buxtons</orgName> today. Very gray and stormy - some rain fell two or three times. Too unpleasant to be on deck.
            Monday, March 27. <persName>Theodore</persName> and I went into town today to antiquity shops - met Mr. <persName>Newberry</persName> and persuaded him to come to lunch - and we talked <name>Museum</name> matters all the time. <persName>Mary</persName> drove him home, <persName>Theodore</persName> and <persName>Bessie</persName> went to ride as they do every day - and I began my little arrangements for packing. Much fever in <placeName>Cairo</placeName> - it is said. Mr. <persName>Newberry</persName> starts today for <placeName>England.</placeName> <persName>Baron von Bissing</persName> came to dine - very clever - nervous, interesting - talks a great deal - has the clearest and keenest eyes I have ever seen.
            Tuesday, March 28. A great change in the temperature since yesterday - it is gray - cold - and a howling wind. We had all the canvass down on the deck - but there was such a flapping and such a blow, we could hardly pack up there. These last days of packing are so triste and trying - and the <orgName>Beduin</orgName> grows in spite of it the more attractive, as these last days draw on - I hate to leave this river life.
            Good Friday - March 31st. We came to the <placeName>Ghezireh Palace Hotel</placeName> on Wednesday afternoon - quitting the <orgName>Beduin</orgName> with sad hearts - we have the same big rooms overlooking the garden we had two years ago. The weather has been very bad, cold - with such tremendous winds. The storm along the coast has been so great that steamers have not been able to leave <placeName>Alexandria</placeName> for days. Snow on the <placeName>Continent</placeName> and skating in <placeName>England!</placeName> Not a good prospect for Page 41 sailing as we expect to do on the 3d April, from <placeName>Port Said</placeName> for Brindisi. We have been to the boat every day - and have this afternoon said good-bye to the sailors who go to their homes up the river at once. <placeName>Cairo</placeName> begins to look deserted - and this hotel a vast wilderness.
            Saturday, April 1st. Visits to the antiquity shops this morning - and immediately after luncheon a last drive and visit to the <orgName>Beduin.</orgName> All the sailors had left - and there only remained <persName>Rais Fuli</persName> and <persName>Abdul,</persName> and a friend of <persName>Fuli's</persName> who is to stay with them. She will drop down a little way tomorrow, to a better resting place for the summer. She is in her dress of coarse canvass, shrouded entirely. On the lower deck, this canvass was lifted on the river side and everything was so clean and orderly I felt like stopping forever. <persName>Dick,</persName> with his little white hen, strutted across the gangway to have a last biscuit from me, and even the geese swam around to have a last look at us. Then back to the <name>Gezireh</name> - <persName>Baron von Bissing</persName> came to tea, and for a final talk about <orgName>Egyptian</orgName> matters - <persName>Theodore</persName> was so tired, I thought he would have fallen asleep. <placeName>Brindisi</placeName> - April 6. We arrived in port about midnight and had decided to stay on the steamer and take breakfast, but what with many passengers going off at once, and the others to catch the 7 o'clock A.M. train, there was but little sleep to be had. We left <placeName>Cairo</placeName> on Easter morning at 10 o'clock - <persName>Fuli, Abdul,</persName> the <persName>Cook, Salah</persName> and <persName>Mr. Landus</persName> to see us off. A Page 42 very tiring, dusty ride to <placeName>Ismailia</placeName> which we reached at 3 o'clock and where we changed cars, for <orgName>Port Said,</orgName> where we arrived about 7 o'clock, an uncomfortable dinner in the overcrowded hotel, where we met the <persName>Buxtons</persName> who were going off in the <placeName>Arabia</placeName> for <placeName>Marseilles,</placeName> and then we went out to our own boat the <name>Osiris, P. & O.</name> and went comfortably and early to bed in our clean looking cabins. We had to wait until the morning for the <orgName>Arabia,</orgName> for the mails - and were off at 9 o'clock on the 3d and went immediately into the most tempestuous sea I ever knew, which grew worse as each hour went by - until finally smashing part of the bridge and the forward galley, the boat was put at a low rate of speed. I was comfortably taking my breakfast in bed when we started - I never finished it, and I did not leave my berth until last evening, for dinner. <persName>Theodore,</persName> the <persName>Captain,</persName> one other officer and <persName>Jones,</persName> were the only persons at table, and the ships doctor was in bed all the way over. We decided we would never again try this route. We are rather comfortable here. Took a bright drive about this bare and dreary town and country this afternoon - and will take the early train to <placeName>Rome</placeName> tomorrow morning.
            Hotel Bristol. First Sunday after Easter. April 9. Arrived evening before last at 7:30 - after a long journey of 13 hours - which was not as tiring as I had feared it would be. But after our rude experience at sea, I find my head still going round and <persName>Page</persName> 43 round, and my legs failing. We are in our pleasant old rooms overlooking the <placeName>Piazza Barberini.</placeName> I went out this afternoon, but only to <placeName>St. Peters</placeName> - where we stayed some time - and I walked up and down that splendid building, until I was tired. Day damp and rainy and cold. We find <persName>Andersen</persName> looking much better; he takes most of his meals with us. After <placeName>St. Peters</placeName> we went to the <placeName>Elliotts</placeName> and found them at home. <persName>Dr. Bull</persName> dined with us.
            Monday, April 10. Raining and cold. The <persName>Elliots</persName> and <persName>Andersen</persName> dined with us.
            Tuesday, April 11. Went to the <placeName>Palazzo Patri&#232;c&#232;</placeName> to see the pictures with <persName>M. Jeubert.</persName> A desperately dismal palace, and not a picture that I would have had. Did some rummaging about in an old shop, and then drove in the fine, bracing cold air on the <orgName>Pincian.</orgName> At home in the afternoon. <persName>Mary</persName> and <persName>Bessie</persName> hard at work every day sight seeing. <persName>Countess Freufelli-Cibo</persName> called.
            Wednesday, April 12. Steady, hard rain all the morning - for a short drive in the afternoon. Dr. <persName>Richter</persName> here for a long time. In spite of rain went with Mr. <persName>Elliot</persName> to the house of the artist <persName>Villegas</persName> and saw and bought some nice stuffs.
            Thursday, April 13. Drove in the rain to the <placeName>Colonna</placeName> Gallery. Met <persName>Miss Alexander</persName> there, <persName>Daisy Busk's</persName> friend - asked her to tea on Saturday. Home in the rain, growling at the weather. Dr. <persName>Richter</persName> to lunch - and did not leave the house again. <persName>Basil Fielding</persName> called. He is now <persName>Father Fielding,</persName> mature, and somewhat less exuberant - and very devote.
            Frida, April 14th. Met Mr. <persName>Hobson</persName> and <persName>Andersen</persName> at the <placeName>Vatican</placeName> this morning by appointment, and went through the <orgName>Borgia</orgName> appartments. Saw the <orgName>Bradleys</orgName> there. Then I made a bold effort to get into the <placeName>Museo Cristiano,</placeName> which I had never seen, and after traversing the great galleries back to the entrance, we gained the door to the <placeName>Bibliot&#232;que,</placeName> through which we had to walk, before reaching the <orgName>Museo.</orgName> Here we found all the pictures shut away behind glass cases, which were locked, and no catalogues - and the attendants ignorant and surly. I had a small list which I had gathered from <placeName>Berenson's Italian Central</placeName> Painters. There are beautiful treasures of <orgName>Sienese</orgName> and <orgName>Umbrian</orgName> art. Home just in time for luncheon - and <persName>Mary</persName> and I went at 5 o'clock to a reception at <placeName>Countess Freufelli-Cibo's</placeName> which was nice - she so cordial - and so many <orgName>Italian</orgName> people, - Duchesses, Princesses galore - I talked with many pleasant people. In the evening <persName>Theodore</persName> and I went to dine at the <placeName>Palazzo Borghese</placeName> with <persName>Mrs. Bronson</persName> - a beautiful dinner, several people and a very grand appartment. Well tired tonight.
            Saturday, April 15. We are ready to make an early start tomorrow. It has rained all day - I did a little shopping this morning, and <persName>Mary, Bessie</persName> and I drove over to <placeName>St. Peters</placeName> in the afternoon to find it closed in preparation for the great anniversary of the <orgName>Pope's</orgName> coronation tomorrow. The venerable <persName>Pope</persName> has now well recovered from the serious operation he has lately gone through, and is pronounced able to bear the excitement. It rained so hard that I came home, while <persName>Mary</persName> and <persName>Bessie</persName> went to some churches. Miss <persName>Alexander</persName> came to tea and <persName>Mrs.</persName> and <persName>Miss Bronson</persName> came to say goodbye. <persName>Basil Fielding</persName> dined, and stayed a long time talking.
            Monday, April 17. Not a bad journey from <placeName>Rome</placeName> yesterday. I slept much of the time. <persName>Lizzie Buttles,</persName> and <persName>Nettie</persName> with <persName>Hassan</persName> met us - and we came to our old quarters at the <placeName>Grande Bretagne.</placeName> The weather still &#225; la pluie. The <orgName>Arno</orgName> full. <persName>Andersen</persName> came with us from <orgName>Florence.</orgName> Mr. <persName>Berenson</persName> came to dine. This morning I went after breakfast to the <persName>Villino</persName> to see the much talked of little house - and found it charming - full of pretty and valuable things - clean, modern, and convenient and a sweet little garden. I was charmed with it, and with their satisfaction in it. Then <persName>Nettie</persName> and I went to the <orgName>Academia,</orgName> and had a beautiful time. There is no one I so enjoy going to a gallery with. Some very remarkable and beautiful tapestires have been hung there in the long corridor - once a part of the <orgName>Medician</orgName> riches - delightful things. This afternoon, <persName>Theodore, Bessie</persName> and I drove up to <persName>Mrs. Castello's</persName> in the <orgName>Page 46</orgName> rain to have tea, and see her and <persName>Berenson's</persName> pretty things. We met there her brother <persName>Mr. Logan-Smith,</persName> and a young <persName>Percy Fielding</persName> a cousin of our friends - and we had good tea and buttered toast in a charming hall overlooking the valley, surrounded with quaint things, looking at <orgName>Sienese</orgName> paintings and discussing its beauties, and many things besides, and had a charming time, and stayed an unconscionable time, and drove home in the rain, dressed, and drove to <persName>Lizzie's</persName> and dined - and enjoyed ourselves hugely.
            Tuesday, April 18. <persName>Nettie</persName> and I went to the <placeName>Ufizzi</placeName> this morning, and stayed until we were blind with fatigue. In the afternoon we all went to a reception at <placeName>Lizzie's</placeName> which she was very anxious to give me - and I met many of her friends, who were most cordial. The house looked charming -Mr. <persName>Berenson</persName> came to dine.
            Wednesday, April 19. Went with <persName>Theodore</persName> this morning across the river to the antiquity shop of <persName>Constantine</persName> to see a lovely medallion of <persName>Madonna</persName> and Child by <persName>Mino da Fiesole,</persName> that <persName>Berenson</persName> had told him about. <persName>Theodore</persName> decided to buy it - but felt the embarrassment of getting it out of the country - it is necessary to be very quiet about it, as its history is so peculiar and interesting. It came from the unimportant church of <placeName>St. Bridget</placeName> in <placeName>Rome</placeName> only a short time since. Constantine, prowling Page 47 about some months ago for treasures came upon this church and persuaded the sacristan or priest to allow him to have a copy made to replace the original - it was done, the <persName>Mino</persName> gave place to the copy, the church received the money, and the precious <persName>Mino</persName> goes to <placeName>America</placeName> to take her place in our hall, and to administer to us daily some of the sweet peace and pure beauty of that XVth century art. A young man, the son of <persName>Constantine,</persName> who lived some time in <placeName>New York,</placeName> and was a clerk at <placeName>Tiffany's</placeName> and who speaks excellent <orgName>English</orgName> told <persName>Theodore</persName> that he was going over to <placeName>America</placeName> next month and would take in the medallion and charge himself with all responsibility and trouble. So, on the strength of this, we bought several things - chairs, stuffs etc. - so that they might all go over together. Then we prowled into some other shops, and bought a little exquisitely painted portrait, probably French. In the afternoon I and <persName>Bessie</persName> went for <persName>Lizzie,</persName> and the girls and we went to <placeName>Mrs. Ryerson's</placeName> pretty appartment to a reception given me, and met some pleasant people. Saw and talked a long time with <persName>Prof. Fiske,</persName> who asked us to tea tomorrow. <persName>Berenson</persName> to dinner.
            Thursday, April 20. <persName>Nettie</persName> and I went to the <placeName>Pitti</placeName> this morning and met <persName>Theodore, Anderson</persName> and <persName>Bessie</persName> there - went to the flower market for flowers and bought some trinkets at a shop - in the afternoon we drove in the rain out to <persName>Prof. Fiskes,</persName> had tea, ices and strawberries!! (at 5 o'clock in the afternoon) went all over his beautiful old <orgName>Italian</orgName> villa, which is entirely furnished in brutal <orgName>American</orgName> and <orgName>French</orgName> fashion - looked <persName>Page</persName> 48 longingly at his <orgName>Italian</orgName> garden from each window, and marvelled at the opportunities going to waste everywhere, - then drove to <persName>Berensons,</persName> had tea again and watched the clouds rolling away, and the sun deciding to show himself for a few moments, and listened to the thrushes and blackbirds, saw 4 charming panels of <name>Saints</name> by <persName>Taddeo di Bartoli</persName> which <persName>Berenson</persName> had just received from <persName>Siena,</persName> and which <persName>Theodore</persName> bought at once, and drove home late enough for dinner with <persName>Berenson</persName> and <persName>Andersen</persName> to dinner. 
            Friday, April 21. We are ready to start tomorrow for <placeName>Venice</placeName> - <persName>Nettie</persName> goes with us fortunately and Andersen. Shopping, sightseeing, dodging the rain all day. <persName>Lizzie</persName> and the girls dined and have just gone.
            <name>Grand Hotel, Venice,</name> April 22. A not fatiguing journey yesterday - quitting <placeName>Florence</placeName> at 11:30 - arriving at 6 - rather cold - this morning was cold with high winds, went to the <orgName>Academia.</orgName> What treasures of <orgName>Venetian</orgName> art! and how deadly chill the galleries! <persName>Andersen</persName> has a violent cold and is wretched. <persName>Mrs. Costello</persName> is here with her brother <persName>Mr. Pearsall-Smith</persName> - <persName>Percy Fielding</persName> and <persName>Miss Duff-Gordon.</persName> We met them all at the <placeName>Academia</placeName> this morning. They are keen searchers after antiquities. <persName>Miss Duff-Gordon</persName> would be beautiful did she not look so delicate - she is a grandchild of <persName>Lady Duff-Gordon.</persName> <persName>Theodore, Bessie</persName> and <persName>Andersen</persName> walked home, while I and <persName>Nettie</persName> went in our gondola beyond the <placeName>Rialto</placeName> some distance to see <orgName>Page 49</orgName> the beautiful <orgName>Cadoro,</orgName> and to enjoy the warmth of the sun, which was actually shining for a time. In the afternoon we all went along the <placeName>Grand Canal</placeName> again to visit some antiquity shops - as I am on the lookout for two or three marbles for the garden. Mrs. <persName>Costello</persName> came to tea. It seems there is a very choice and modest little shop in <placeName>London</placeName> known as <name>Toplady's</name> where very good choses anciennes are found. The firm consists of Prince <persName>Hohenloke, Percy Fielding</persName> and <persName>Pearsall Smith,</persName> and a lady from <placeName>Baltimore, Maryland,</placeName> a relative of the <persName>Smiths (Mrs. Costello</persName> was a <orgName>Logan-Smith)</orgName> presides and earns her living thus. Prince <persName>Hohenloke</persName> lives here in a charming little house with a beautiful lady supposed to be his wife, and as Mr. <persName>Pearsall-Smith</persName> lives part of the year in <placeName>Florence</placeName> with his sister, they are in the way of picking up many choice things. And they are immensely amusing over it - Mr. <persName>Pearsall-Smith</persName> suggests that the firm should be called, "Hohenloke, Hapsburg, Smith" (the Fieldings being descendants of the <orgName>Hapsburgs).</orgName> It seems that there is a combination of Hotels and several large dealers in antiquities known as the <orgName>___________,</orgName> and they attempt to crowd out smaller dealers, and those who will not enter this combination. The porters of the hotels, the gondoliers, the guides all direct you to those places sanctioned by this ________ and divert you from the others. <persName>Lady Layard</persName> who lives here gave Mr. <persName>P. Smith</persName> a list of the pure dealers which he gave to me and the <persName>_________</persName> are furious at <placeName>Lady Layard,</placeName> because she took the Empress <persName>Frederick,</persName> and the Princess of <placeName>Wales,</placeName> who have lately been here to these independent dealers, where they made large purchases - and one of these men showed me with great pride their signatures in his book.
            Monday, April 24. Again to the <name>Academia</name> this morning - met Mr. <persName>Egerton Winthrop</persName> and <persName>Mr.</persName> and <persName>Mrs. Lorehan</persName> there - they are just over from home, coming in the <orgName>St. Louis.</orgName> This afternoon though there was little sunlight, <persName>Nettie</persName> and I went to the <placeName>Grand Church</placeName> of <persName>S. Giovanni</persName> e <persName>S. Paolo.</persName> Found it raining when we came out, -at 4:30, the <persName>Costello</persName> party came here and <persName>Nettie</persName> and I went with them to <persName>Barozzi's</persName> where I saw some really beautiful old <orgName>Italian</orgName> things. A grand old painted <persName>Casone</persName> of the 14 century and some beautiful stuffs. We are just home this evening from a charming dinner given by <persName>Theodore</persName> at a fine restaurant near us, to the <persName>Costello</persName> people. We walked there and found a fine room up stairs with beautifully decorated table, and a delicious dinner and a very merry one, it was pleasant walking home in a half moonlight and it seemed like the stage of a theatre.
            Tuesday, April 25. Went to the <placeName>Correr Museo</placeName> this morning. A few gleams of sunshine. With Mr. <persName>P. Smith</persName> to see some marbles in the afternoon. After dinner they all came in to see us - and showed us their treasure trove of little things - among them an exquisite statuette in ivory of <persName>Madonna</persName> and <persName>Child.</persName> Mrs. <persName>Costello</persName> has bought a very beautiful bronze statuette, about 18 inches high - strong, of fine workmanship - a <orgName>Venetian</orgName> knight with staff - by one called <persName>Razzi</persName> or <persName>RIzzi,</persName> who made the fine bronze bust in the <placeName>Correr,</placeName> with the hair arranged in almost bonnet form, shielding the face. She paid 500 for it - and it is for <orgName>Page 51</orgName> Berenson. She offered it to <persName>Theodore</persName> for 600. it is a beautiful and valuable thing. <persName>Andersen</persName> very wretched this evening. He goes back with Mrs. <persName>Costello</persName> tomorrow as far as <orgName>Florence.</orgName> 
            Wednesday, April 26. A day of disappointment and pouring rain - <persName>Nettie, Bessie</persName> and I, equipped with overshoes, cloaks, wrap and umbrellas went to the <placeName>Frari</placeName> this morning - came home quite drenched. In the afternoon it clearing a little, <persName>Theodore</persName> and I started for <orgName>Barozzi's</orgName> - but it began to pour and has come in torrents ever since - much thunder and lightning this evening. <persName>Andersen</persName> left at noon - somewhat better.
            Thursday, April 27. Weather somewhat better - at home this morning - and in the afternoon we looked for marbles. Found some very charming ones at <placeName>Dorigo's</placeName> - a pair of <orgName>Roman</orgName> vases, 4 little lions - a splendid griffin, and a lion's mask for the base of the big jar bought at Baroggi's.
            Friday, April 28. Weather beautiful - a bright sun - and <placeName>Venice</placeName> transformed - went to churches - and to return the <name>Benson's</name> call. Found them in an old palace, in a splendid appartment with a hall running straight through the building - said to be the 2d finest hall in <placeName>Venice,</placeName> with fine rooms opening on either side. The palace fronts the <orgName>Canal</orgName> - but has gardens on both sides, and such a big garden behind that it is like a farm. Here Page 32 <persName>Mrs. Benson</persName> spends her days - digging, planting, caring for her precious flowers. Mr. <persName>Benson</persName> who is a very mediocre artist, has very good taste and having lived 15 years in this palace, has collected many beautiful and rare things - making a charming tout-ensemble. It is a strange history as told us by <persName>Mrs. Costello.</persName> <persName>Mrs. Benson,</persName> of <orgName>French</orgName> extraction was the only child of very strict and religious parents from whose rigidity when she came of age she much revolted. She married, had one son, and one daughter. Then met Mr. <persName>Benson</persName> who was a <orgName>Baptist</orgName> clergyman of artistic proclivities. They became violently attached and eloped, - the son remained with the father, the daughter went with the mother. After some time the original husband died, and Mr. and <persName>Mrs. Benson</persName> married. They are now in reduced circumstances - the daughter chiefly supporting them. She is a writer of some reputation made her first success with "Kismet" a story of the <placeName ref="Nile">Nile</placeName>. <persName>Mrs. Benson</persName> is said to have been very beautiful - one would not now think it - she is infirm and crippled from rheumatism, and was run over by a carriage sometime since, and almost killed - one eye being entirely destroyed. It was piteous to see these two old people ( for the daughter we did not see ) devotedly attached to each other, amongst their beautiful things, so shut away from the world, and striving to keep their heads above water. Mrs. <persName>Costello</persName> had told <persName>Theodore</persName> that <persName>Benson</persName> would occasionally sell some of his possessions, when he was pressed for the necessities of life - and that some of his friends would occasionally buy one of his <orgName>Page 53</orgName> pictures, only for the sake of putting a little money in his pocket. So after the poor man had tried to sell us one of his pictures, and we had given all the faint praise and evasive comments we could, he ended by suggesting to <persName>Theodore</persName> that if he really admired so much a certain persian bowl in copper, he could part with it etc. etc. so <persName>Theodore</persName> gladly gave him 500 francs for it, and we brought the beautiful thing away with us. Mr. <persName>Fielding</persName> and Mr. <persName>Pearsall-Smith</persName> came in this evening to say goodbye - as they start at midnight for London.
            Saturday, April 29. Another beautiful day. We went to the church of the <persName>S. Francesco della Vigna</persName> to see a beautiful <persName>Madonna</persName> by <placeName>Negro Ponte</placeName> a <orgName>Paduan</orgName> painter - and a <orgName>Madonna,</orgName> child and angels by <persName>Bellini</persName> - the light so bad it could not well be seen. Then to the church of <persName>S. Maria Mater Domini</persName> and saw the beautiful <orgName>Catena</orgName> of <placeName>St. Catherine</placeName> and <persName>Angels,</persName> - exquisite in colour and feeling. Much damaged by the dampness of the cold damp little church. <persName>Theodore</persName> and I went acrows to the <placeName>Guidena</placeName> to the <placeName>Redentore Church</placeName> and had a long look at the lovely <orgName>Madonna</orgName> of <placeName>Alvise Vivarini.</placeName> The church inexpressibly cold and hideous - and the little <orgName>Sacristy</orgName> was the only cheerful place, with its paintings, among which was a so-called <orgName>Bellini,</orgName> and a sweet <orgName>Bissolo.</orgName> Then we met <persName>Nettie</persName> and <persName>Bessie</persName> at <persName>S. Marco's</persName> and afterwards had tea in the <orgName>Piazza,</orgName> and did some shopping - we are ready to start for <placeName>Milan</placeName> tomorrow. Theodore, <persName>Nettie</persName> with <persName>Mr. Benson</persName> make an early start for <placeName>Padua</placeName> - <persName>Bessie</persName> and I with <persName>Am&#232;lie</persName> and <persName>Jones</persName> do not go until 2 o'clock P.M. and they will join us as we pass through. 
            Milan. April 20. Sunday. Had a very charming and not tiresome ride from Venice. <persName>Theodore</persName> and <persName>Nettie</persName> departed early for <placeName>Padua</placeName> - after breakfast, <persName>Bessie</persName> and I went out to the <placeName>Piazza San Marno</placeName> and walked about it, and then went into the church and wandered about and sat looking at its marvelous colour and ornamentation. Had an early lunch, picked up <persName>Theodore</persName> and <persName>Nettie</persName> at <placeName>Padua</placeName> - they report the gallery (private) they went to see, dismally uninteresting - the so called <persName>Antonello da Messina</persName> a fraud, and the chatelaine an ogre. We are in our old delightful quarters at this best of all hotels - the "Cavour" writing letters all the evening. We discovered two letters in the travellers box for Mr. <persName>Sayce</persName> - so I wrote a note to be left for him.
            Monday, May 1st. A day of picture seeing - the morning at the <placeName>Brera</placeName> - beautiful weather - <persName>Theodore,</persName> and I walked in the <persName>Park,</persName> after leaving the <placeName>Cathedral</placeName> this afternoon, until 7 o'clock. Quite delicious - the air so full of spring scents.
            Hotel National. <placeName>Lake Lucerne.</placeName> Wednesday, May 3. We left <name>Milan</name> yesterday at 2 P.M. having spent most of the morning at the <orgName>Poldi-Pezzoli.</orgName> It is much improved - many changes have been made - and a new catalogue is under way. The handsome rooms are full of lovely things - and the beautiful so called <persName>Pui dei Fronnschi Page</persName> 55 lady still holds her wondrous profile to the admiration of all the world. We had a fine day for the journey over the mountains, though we found bad weather on this side. All day long the Mts. have been, at least the snow peaks, hidden by clouds. I have been in the house nursing a cold. <persName>Nettie</persName> and <persName>Bessie</persName> took a steamer this afternoon to <placeName>Kussnach,</placeName> but said they found it cold and gloomy. I have just been standing at the big window in our charming salon, looking out upon the lake, on whose shores we are. What an entourage is this of <orgName>Lucerne!</orgName> The steamers leaving now and then their widening ripple across the blue water - and the green hills, so dark on this sombre day, with their bright patches of tender young foliage - and the myriads of blossoming trees which stand about everywhere. A yellow billed black bird has been sitting at intervals all this afternoon on a slender tree outside my window - and making such delicious, penetrating music! We start at 7 A.M. tomorrow for <placeName>Paris</placeName> - which means an early breakfast, and a still earlier getting up! Paris.
            <placeName>Hotel de Londres.</placeName> Friday - 5th May. It seems a long time since we left <placeName>Lucerne</placeName> yesterday morning in the rain and cold. We breakfasted at 6 o'clock. Met <persName>Mrs.</persName> and <persName>Miss Bronson</persName> at the station, they having arrived the night before from Rome. They had the compartment next to us in the car. We made a very comfortable journey to <placeName>Paris</placeName> though for two or three hours of the morning we were quite frozen, it was so cold - and though the sun came out <orgName>Page 36</orgName> later the air remained cold and penetrating. <persName>Jones</persName> was left at <placeName>Chaumont</placeName> with several others - and they did not arrive until 10 P.M. We began our usual struggle for clothes this morning. <persName>Mrs. Parsons</persName> and <persName>Miss Cowdry</persName> here this afternoon, they go to <placeName>London</placeName> tomorrow. <persName>Mrs. Bronson</persName> and her daughter have rooms next to us in this hotel - and we find ourselves so comfortable that we do not regret the <placeName>Hotel Bristol,</placeName> where our rooms were engaged for yesterday, but owing to a sudden illness, the family who were occupying them, and who intended going the day before, were not able to quit the appartment.
            <name>London,</name> May 15. Hotel Bristol. Nothing of interest to chronicle of our ten days spent at Paris. The inevitable dress maker - rain - and cold weather - saw much of the <orgName>Bronsons.</orgName> The <name>Austins</name> dined with us one evening. Mrs. <persName>Parsons, Virginia,</persName> and <persName>Miss Cowdry</persName> came to tea. <persName>Burt Hagerman</persName> appeared at our hotel three days before we left, and was with us most of the time. A nice, clean, handsome interesting fellow. He had much to tell us about his life at <placeName>St. Petersbourg</placeName> - where he is 2d Secretary in the <placeName>U.S.</placeName> Legation. Thursday being <orgName>Ascension</orgName> day we all went out to <placeName>St. Germain</placeName> to spend the day. We had a long drive about the Park - but were driven back at last by the rain - found the Hotel crowded by those driven indoors by the rain - got some tea - and at last reached <placeName>Paris,</placeName> the rain pouring in torrents. Crossed on Sunday - yesterday - very wet - heavy rain - but the Channel smooth. Came to our charming old quarters at this hotel. 
            Wednesday, May 17. Have been in the house for two days with a bad throat - weather bad and cold - took my cold in the <placeName>National Gallery</placeName> the day after we arrived - it was frigid there. <persName>Theodore</persName> also took a cold coming over, and was in for 2 days - but is now out - <persName>Fielding</persName> has twice dined with us, and we dine with him tomorrow. Yesterday <persName>Nettie</persName> and <persName>Bessie</persName> took him to the <placeName>Lamorean Concert,</placeName> and they were invited afterwards to Lady <persName>Agnes de Trafford's</persName> to a drawing room tea, <persName>Lady Agnes</persName> having that day introduced a young cousin - <persName>Bessie</persName> thought the long trains very fascinating - <persName>Gaspard Farrer</persName> has been in twice, and so has Mr. <persName>Rathbone,</persName> where <persName>Theodore</persName> is dining tonight. We are all invited down to <placeName>Sandhurst,</placeName> Sir <persName>William Farrer's</persName> country place, to spend Whitsuntide - but only <persName>Theodore</persName> will go - as we had engaged rooms and arranged to go down to <placeName>Liphook</placeName> to spend Sunday and Monday. The girls and I will go there, for, with my cold I am not fit for a visitor. Mr. and Mrs. <persName>Percy Newberry</persName> lunched with us today - and afterwards Mr. <persName>Sayce</persName> came in, looking very well indeed. Liphook. Hampshire.
            Royal Anchor Hotel. May 20. Could not go out of the house until yesterday afternoon - Thursday I spent in bed. Came down here at 11:30 - Heavy showers alternating with bursts of sunshine all morning. But since lunch there has been nothing to do but to stay in our little sitting room, and watch the rain pouring against the window panes. We all had a <orgName>Page 58</orgName> most cordial invitation to go down to Sir <persName>William Farrers</persName> place, <persName>Sandhurst,</persName> and spend today, Sunday and Monday - and at any other time I would have been enchanted, but with my bad throat, I cannot talk - and quiet is necessary - being "en evidence" all the time, evening dress, and much talk, would have been impossible for me. So <persName>Theodore</persName> accepted the invitation, and <persName>Nettie, Bessie</persName> and I, with <persName>Amelie</persName> came down here. A comfortable historic Inn - one of the posting inns of the past. <persName>Pepys</persName> mentions in his diary, having "lain" here for the night. A storey has been added to it, and our rooms were chosen there by Mr. <persName>Rathbone,</persName> who advised us coming here. The rooms are clean and comfortable and have not been "lain" in, as often as those in the older part of the house. A lovely country, famous for its views, and fine, dry air, - but we could see nothing as yet - except dissolving views of the garden, and the fine trees about the house.
            Whit. Sunday, May 21. A gray and lowering morning dawned - but we had the courage to start at 10:30 for a drive. We had a very comfortable landau, two good horses - a stout and careful coachman - and we soon began to make acquaintance with this beautiful country - at first through characteristic <orgName>English</orgName> lanes - splendid hedges of hawthorn and holly - with towering oaks, beeches and larches - then out upon the moors, covered with gorse in full bloom - with the dark pines beyond, and the somber, stormy sky, making such ravishing effects of light, shade and colour - and such delicious air! it was a rapture to breathe. We went through <persName>Woolmer Page</persName> 59 <name>Forest,</name> and home again across the moor, in time for lunch at 1:30. Then a rest until 3 o'clock - and out again for <persName>Selborne</persName> - to see the old home of <persName>Gilbert White</persName> - again the lovely lanes - the moor - up hill and down dales - exclaiming at the splendid oaks and beeches - the great stretches of valley, the picturesque cottages - the handsome estates, until in an hour and a half we entered the little village of <placeName>Selborne,</placeName> the quaintest and most delightful thing I ever saw. The strange timbered houses, with a peculiar use of different coloured bricks, and the thatched roofs, made me long for some sunlight to photograph them. We stopped at a little Inn to rest the horses and had a very good cup of tea, and then walked down the street to see the house of <persName>Gilbert White,</persName> which I thought I knew from the prints of it - all of which it seems were taken from the garden side which we could not see - its back is almost upon the street. Then we walked a few steps to the old church, and into its churchyard, with lovely views across the valley - a glorious chestnut - and a wonderful old yew - some of the grave stones so eaten with age and lichens, that no trace of name or inscription remained. "The rude forefathers of the hamlet" or whoever they were, had indeed passed into oblivion. Coming home, the rain poured in torrents - and we had to have the carriage closed. Tonight, the whole world is shrowded in a heavy <orgName>Scotch</orgName> mist. I have a pleasant little room in a corner of the house, with two windows, and a tiny grate in which I have a little fire every night. It looks out on the little irregular square before the hotel, made by the crossing of two streets, and in this square stands the biggest and finest white <orgName>Page 60</orgName> horse chestnut I have ever seen, now laden with bloom, and looking like some great chandelier, holding up its lights to heaven.
            Monday, May 22. We have had another day of driving in this delicious neighborhood, from whose height we saw the world all around us, or would have done so, had not a blinding rain swept through the valley, - but it was soon over and we drove home with the carriage open. Then this afternoon we drove four miles over to <persName>Hashmere,</persName> to see <persName>Mr. Pearsall-Smith</persName> and have tea with him. We went through the beautiful estate of <placeName>Lord Hawkshaw</placeName> - the most magnificent drive I ever had - on the way I stopped and photographed a wonderful shire horse - the biggest thing in the way of a horse I have ever seen. We found Mr. <persName>P.-S.</persName> in a charming little estate - in an old manor house, which he has made delightful and very much occupied with his pretty garden. Just after we got home, the clouds began to at last roll away, the sun came out, and the moon is now shining superbly. Never have I heard such a riotous chant of birds, as we hear here - nightingales - blackbirds, thrushes and larks - we go back to <placeName>London</placeName> tomorrow.
            Tuesday, May 23. The sun did not appear before we left <placeName>Liphook</placeName> at 11:05 this morning. I tried a few photographs but I have little hope they will amount to anything. We reached the hotel in time for lunch - and found <persName>Theodore</persName> already returned - he gave us very glowing accounts of his <orgName>Page 61</orgName> visit to <placeName>Sandhurst</placeName> - and said Sir <persName>William</persName> surpassed himself in charm and interest - and in spite of his age and infirmities went about everywhere. <persName>Nettie</persName> and <persName>Bessie</persName> went to <placeName>Westminster Abbey</placeName> this afternoon while <persName>Theodore</persName> and I went to leave cards at various places. <persName>Gaspard Farrer</persName> came to dine with us.
            Wednesday, May 24. A busy morning with <persName>Theodore</persName> in some shops - and with <persName>Nettie</persName> this afternoon driving and shopping. 
            Thursday, May 25. Met Mr. <persName>Sayce</persName> this morning at the <placeName>Paddington</placeName> station at 9:40 and went to <placeName>Oxford</placeName> - almost a wintry morning - and mr. <persName>Sayce</persName> with a violent cold, poor man. We drove at once to <placeName>Queen's College,</placeName> to his rooms, where there was a bright fire burning, and a very pleasant young woman, a neice of <persName>Tennyson's,</persName> waiting to receive us, and help Mr. <persName>Sayce</persName> out with his hospitalities. We tried to induce Mr. <persName>Sayce</persName> to stay by his fireside, and let us do our sightseeing, but our persuasions were all in vain - and he would at least show us his own college - and promenaded through the windy quads - and through the chill corridors and staircases. <placeName>Queen's</placeName> is not an interesting college. Then we went to what was called the upper common room for our lunch, which was indeed charming - and a most elaborate lunch beautifully served - by three grave servitors. The room had several interesting historical portraits and a beautiful outlook on quads, gardens and college towers. A Prof. Page 62 <placeName>Oman</placeName> and his wife, celebrated already as an historical writer <persName>(Prof.) Miss Weld,</persName> and <persName>Miss Scott,</persName> daughter of Sir <persName>John Scott,</persName> whom we had known in <placeName>Egypt,</placeName> lunched with us. We sat a long time at lunch, so that we had only a little more than an hour before the train left. Then we walked to <name>All Lords,</name> saw its lovely garden, and chapel - then to <placeName>Jesus College</placeName> where <persName>Miss Scott</persName> was staying with the Principal - <persName>Prof. Rhys.</persName> She took us to see the old drawing room in his residence - a lovely old panelled room of the time of <persName>Charles I</persName> - with a fine ceiling. Then we all hurried back to town, full of thanks to Mr. <persName>Sayce</persName> for our pleasant day. But they are exhausting, these kinds of days! <persName>Fielding</persName> came to dine, and Mr. <persName>Rathbone</persName> came in for tea. <persName>Nettie</persName> and <persName>Bessie</persName> off to the theater with Mr. <persName>Zug.</persName>
            <placeName>Friday,</placeName> May 26. This our last day has been crowded - visits - driving - shopping - Mr. <persName>Pearsall-Smith</persName> came to lunch - and we had such a pleasant time. Then he, <persName>Theodore</persName> and <persName>Nettie</persName> went to look at a picture, and to visit "Toplady's", where <persName>Theodore</persName> bought a charming little <orgName>Batterse&#224;</orgName> enamel box, in an old shagreen case, and brought it home to me. Mr. <persName>Percy Newberry</persName> came in, after <persName>Bessie</persName> and I got home from our drive, bringing me a box of flowers from an <orgName>Egyptian</orgName> tomb at <placeName>Hawara,</placeName> dating some 2000 years B.C. They are beautifully packed in a tin box -which I shall carry in my hands - trusting it to no one. Mr. <persName>Rathbone</persName> and <persName>Fielding</persName> came to dine, a pleasant dinner - but it was late when they left, and it is long past 12 o'clock - all my little arrangements are <orgName>Page 63</orgName> made, and we must be off early tomorrow for Southampton. How I hate the thought of another voyage! Lady <persName>Agnes de Traffords</persName> paid us a long visit - and <persName>Gaspar Farrer.</persName>
            Saturday, May 27. <name>S.S. St. Paul.</name> We said a reluctant goodbye to <persName>Nettie</persName> this morning, who was to leave an hour after we did. She goes directly to Florence. <persName>Fielding</persName> came to the station to say goodbye, he promises to come over this summer. We reached <name>Southampton</name> in due time, and by one o'clock were off. <name>Cherbourg</name> at 5 o'clock - where we took on board several passengers from the <orgName>Paris.</orgName> We now have a goodly representation of her passengers - and one hears from all sides accounts of that disaster. We have a charming suite of deck rooms - and I have a private bathroom opening from my room!
            Thursday, June 1st. The fog whistle has been going since early last evening - a melancholy music it is - the fog very thick - last night there was ice near us, and we stopped twice for a few moments. Half speed almost the whole time since the fog began, and that means a late arrival on Saturday, instead of an early one. I have spent all my time in my pretty big room - and two days I stayed in bed, getting a good rest. There has been no incentive to get up and go out as there has been cloudy, damp, rainy weather until the fog came - I have read <orgName>Miss Page</orgName> 64 <persName>Jekyls's</persName> delightful "Wood and <persName>Garden",</persName> a fascinating sea narrative, "The Cruiser of the <orgName>Cachalot</orgName> for Sperm Whales". "Pages from a <name>Private Diary"</name> and <name>Baring-Gould's</name> rather stuffed and padded "Old <orgName>English</orgName> Home". I am now rereading <name>Trollope's</name> admirable "Phineas Redeux". But how long the hours are, and how blessed is the thought of home growing nearer and nearer!
            Sunday, June 4th. <placeName>Holland</placeName> House. <placeName>New York.</placeName> We reached our dock yesterday at one o'clock. Very good time considering the fogs we encountered during the last two days and nights. <persName>Dr. Doty</persName> came on board to see us at Quarantine. We found <persName>John</persName> and <persName>Ettie Whaling</persName> waiting on the wharf - and were not detained long in the <orgName>Custom House.</orgName> Warm weather. <persName>Sam Medary</persName> and <persName>Louise</persName> came to see me in the evening - and <persName>Andrews Rogers</persName> - very warm today. <persName>Theodore</persName> in the house with a very hoarse cold - and thoroughly tired out. Just as we reached the <placeName>Holland House</placeName> yesterday, <persName>Jeannie</persName> and <persName>Mr. Convere</persName> turned up - and we had a long visit from them. <persName>Jones</persName> went to <placeName>Newport</placeName> on the evening boat yesterday - and the dogs must be happy. <persName>Ettie, John</persName> and <persName>Bessie</persName> left at one o'clock for the <placeName>West</placeName> - the poor things will suffer from the heat. We hope to get off on tomorrow nights boat. 11</p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
  </TEI>
  