<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Diary of Mrs. Emma B. Andrews. Volume 15 1907-1908</title>
                <author>
                    <persName ref="#Andrews_Emma_B">Emma B. Andrews</persName>
                </author>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>Originally prepared by</resp>
                    <persName ref="#SLK">Sarah L. Ketchley</persName>
                </respStmt>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>TEIPublisher development</resp>
                    <persName ref="#EF">Emma Fritzberg</persName>
                </respStmt>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>Historical Markup Tool development</resp>
                    <persName ref="#AH">Audrey Holmes</persName>
                </respStmt>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>transcription</resp>
                    <persName ref="#SJ">Sarah Johnson</persName>
                    <persName ref="#CC">Chelsea Cooper</persName>
                    <persName ref="#AF">Ariella Fish</persName>
                    <persName ref="#JG">Janice Garr</persName>
                    <persName ref="#MR">Megan Rowland</persName>
                    <persName ref="#AS">Allison Skinner</persName>
                    <persName ref="#TC">Tessa Carter</persName>
                </respStmt>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>proofreading and tagging</resp>
                    <persName ref="#SLK">Sarah Ketchley</persName>
                    <persName ref="#MT">Molly Taylor</persName>
                    <persName ref="#OH">Olivia Hyre</persName>
                </respStmt>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>biographical research and writing</resp>
                    <persName ref="#SK">Sarah Ketchley</persName>
                    <persName ref="#JJ">Jasmine Jones</persName>
                    <persName ref="#JC">Jasmine Choi</persName>
                    <persName ref="#SR">Samuel Roller</persName>
                    <persName ref="#AAD">Avery Dahl</persName>
                    <persName ref="#AD">Avneet Dhaliwal</persName>
                    <persName ref="#IH">Iona Hillman</persName>
                    <persName ref="#LK">Lexi Kinzer</persName>
                    <persName ref="#PH">Priya Hariharan</persName>
                </respStmt>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>
                    <orgName ref="#EBA_Diary_Project">Emma B. Andrews Diary Project</orgName>
                </publisher>
                <address>
                    <addrLine>University of Washington, Seattle, WA</addrLine>
                </address>
                <availability>
                    <licence target="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/">This work is
                        licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0
                        International License.</licence>
                </availability>
                <date>08-2020</date>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p><orgName ref="#American_Philosophical_Society">American Philosophical
                        Society</orgName>,<placeName ref="#Philadelphia"
                    >Philadelphia</placeName></p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <encodingDesc>
            <projectDesc>
                <p>Established in 2010, the goals of the <orgName ref="#EBA_Diary_Project">Emma B.
                        Andrews Diary Project</orgName> include the transcription and digitization
                    of a wide range of primary historical material from the 'Golden Age' of Egyptian
                    archaeology at the end of the 19th and beginning of the 20th centuries. A
                    founding partner of <orgName ref="#Newbook_Digital_Texts">Newbook Digital
                        Texts</orgName> (www.newbookdigitaltexts.org), the <orgName
                        ref="#EBA_Diary_Project">EBA Diary Project</orgName> offers undergraduate
                    and graduate digital humanities education and internships at the <orgName
                        ref="#University_of_Washington">University of Washington</orgName>.
                        <persName ref="#Andrews_Emma_B">Emma B. Andrews</persName> is best
                    remembered for her association with the millionaire lawyer turned
                    archaeologist/art and antiquities collector, <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M"
                        >Theodore M. Davis</persName>. Traveling to <placeName ref="#Egypt"
                        >Egypt</placeName> with him between 1889 and 1913, she kept detailed
                    journals of these voyages along the <placeName ref="#Nile">Nile</placeName>,
                    including his important yet under-reported excavations of over 20 significant
                    tombs in the <placeName ref="#Bībān al-Mulūk">Valley of the Kings</placeName>.
                        <persName ref="#Andrews_Emma_B">Emma</persName> provides a vital commentary
                    on the archaeology and pioneering Egyptologists of the time, painting a
                    revealing picture of the lives of the colonial gentry and the cultural and
                    scientific literati in at the dawn of the twentieth century. Analysis of the
                    content of her diaries, along with a broad range of additional primary source
                    material, will afford scholars information about important historical resources
                    for the first time.</p>
            </projectDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p>Obvious misspellings (eg place names and people's names) which are
                        misreadings of original handwritten diary are corrected with choice, sic and
                        corr.</p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p>Original spelling and typography is otherwise retained.</p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <!-- update this with major revision list-->
            <list>
                <item>
                    <date when="2021-05-08">8 May 2021</date> Last checked by SLK. Updated header,
                    fixed placeName and name tags.</item>
                    <item><date when="2021-05-30">30 May 2021</date> Last checked by SLK. Minor semantic edits, updated list of biographers.</item>
                    <item><date when="2021-07-11">11 July 2021</date> Isabelle Schlegel began edits</item>
            </list>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-12-02" type="entry">
        <dateline><placeName ref="#Al_Badrashayn">Bedreschein</placeName> - <date when="1907-12-02">Dec. 2d. 1907</date>.</dateline>
        <p>This little record of travel should have begun a month ago - as we sailed from <placeName ref="#New_York">New York</placeName> just a month ago - the <date when="1907-11-02">2d of Nov.</date> on the <name type="boat" ref="#Freiderick_der_Grosse">Freiderick der Grosse</name>. We had a rough unpleasant passage - there was no day on which I could have written with comfort. It was the worst passage I ever made. On some days, the best thing was to stay in bed - and that was a difficult thing to do. A friend of ours was thrown from his berth, and dislocated his shoulder - several accidents occured - sprains etc. Reached <placeName ref="#Naples">Naples</placeName> finally the morning of the <date when="1907-11-15">15th</date>. <persName ref="#Baldwin_Dr">Dr. Baldwin</persName> of <placeName ref="#Rome">Rome</placeName>, and <persName ref="#Peck_Mrs"><choice><sic>Mrs. Beck</sic><corr>Mrs. Peck</corr></choice></persName> of <placeName ref="#Milwaukee">Milwaukie</placeName>, were on the boat, and added much to the pleasure of the voyage - coming when possible to my sitting room for tea. We knew that <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and <persName ref="#Ransom_Williams_Caroline">Carrie</persName> would be waiting for us at <placeName ref="#Naples">Naples</placeName>, and we hoped to have at least a night and day with <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> at the <name type="hotel" ref="#Grand_Hotel">Grand Hotel</name>. But we were so belated that we had only time to drive to the hotel and get them, and drive back to the dock - and that was so disappointing. <persName ref="#Costantini_David">David Costantini</persName> was there also - and <persName ref="#Baldwin_Mrs">Mrs. Baldwin</persName> who had come from <placeName ref="#Rome">Rome</placeName> to meet her husband - the voyage across the <placeName ref="#Mediterranean_Sea">Mediterranean</placeName> was as charming as the other was horrid. We arrived at <placeName ref="#Alexandria">Alexandria</placeName> at 8 o'clock on <date when="1907-11-18">Monday the 18th</date>, stopped at the <placeName ref="#New_Khedivial_Hotel">New Khedivial Hotel</placeName> long enough to have a lunch put up for us, then paid a visit to the <placeName>Museum</placeName> <!--greco-roman?--> (our first) though it is hardly worth a visit, and were off for <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> at noon - and found our old rooms ready for us, and were eating dinner on the evening of the 16th. A sister with them - a quiet, beautiful day <!--error?--> from <placeName ref="#New_York">N.Y.</placeName> A very good record. We got away from <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> today - having settled ourselves on the <name type="boat" ref="#Beduin">Beduin</name> the <date when="1907-12-01">1st</date>. We tried to get through the bridge yesterday - but there was such a crowd of gyassas at the draw, that we waited for most of them, dreading the dangers of that shouting, reckless, unmanageable crowd - but the Bridge time was up before they had all passed, and the draw was shut in our faces. We tied up at the <placeName ref="#Kasr_el_Nil">Kasr el Nil</placeName> <!--getty name?--> barracks, and waited for today. We were so near when the draw was opened at 1 o'clock that we started as soon as the down boats had got through - but there was a good wind, and the reckless gyassas in spite of orders and <choice><sic>shreiks</sic><corr>shrieks</corr></choice> of the bridge officers crowded upon us in full sail - and it was a very nasty twenty <choice><sic>mimrtes</sic><corr>minutes</corr></choice> we had - such noise, such frantic efforts. One of them crashed her bow into us, fortunately broke her bow sprit, and left her anchor embedded in the landing stage, or she would have <choice><sic>ripper</sic><corr>ripped</corr></choice> our side open. She did break one of the window frames, but luckily spared the glass, knocked much of our nice new paint off us etc. One of our men took out the window frame, and we left him in <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName>, to take it to the carpenters and painters. He rejoined us at <placeName ref="#Ţurá">Tourah</placeName> by rail and says the carpenters and painters will reach <placeName ref="#Al_Badrashayn">Bedreshein</placeName> <!--sic on PDF?--> tomorrow at 8 o'clock. As <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> and <persName ref="#Ransom_Williams_Caroline">Carrie</persName> are to make a visit to <placeName ref="#Ṣaqqâra">Sakkarah</placeName> we will not be detained. We saw <persName ref="#Trefusis_Walter_Capt">Capt. Trefusis</persName> and his sweet sister <persName ref="#Trefusis_Evelyn">Evelyn</persName> who is out with him this winter. They lunched with us several times, and she came in to stay one night (they are staying at <placeName ref="#Hulwan">Helouan</placeName>) and go with <persName ref="#Ransom_Williams_Caroline">Carrie</persName> early the next morning to see the ceremony of the Kishwa <!--tag?-->. He is now in a large business at <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName>. We also made the acquaintance of <persName ref="#Feilding_Rudolph_Lord">Lord Denbigh</persName>'s eldest son, <persName ref="#Feilding_Rudolph_Viscount">Viscount Fielding</persName>. He is in the <orgName ref="#Coldstream_Guards">Coldstream Guards</orgName>, who have lately been sent out here. He is a nice young fellow simple and natural. <persName ref="#Peck_Mrs">Mrs. Peck</persName> of <placeName ref="#Milwaukee">Milwaukie</placeName> was at <name type="hotel" ref="#Shepheards_Hotel">Shepheards</name> most of the time we were there, and we saw much of her. <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName>, and the whole of <placeName ref="#Egypt">Egypt</placeName> is now in serious financial straits, following the absurd speculative craze of the last 2 years. Prices are incredibly high.</p>
      </div>
      <!-- The boat's name might actually be Friedrich (not Freiderick) der Grosse, German for Frederick the Great (Prussian king) -->
      <!-- Not sure what "the Museum" is. It seems to be some not-so-great museum in Alexandria, likely close to the New Khedivial Hotel. Maybe this one: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Graeco-Roman_Museum -->
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-12-03" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1907-12-03">Tuesday, Dec. 3rd</date>.</dateline>
        <p>I have had a busy day settling - while <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> and <persName ref="#Ransom_Williams_Caroline">Carrie</persName> went to <placeName ref="#Ṣaqqâra">Sakkarah</placeName>. A lovely day. The <name type="boat" ref="#Ramesis_boat">Ramesis</name> was lying by us all day - with a handful of passengers - but went off at 6 o'clock. The carpenter and painter have been here all day repairing damages.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-12-04" type="entry">
       <dateline><date when="1907-12-04">Wednesday, Dec. 4</date>. <measure type="distance">41 miles</measure>.</dateline> 
       <p>We get away from <placeName ref="#Al_Badrashayn">Bedraschein</placeName> at 7 o'clock this morning - and have had a lovely day - river like glass, both of our sails out much of the time. The river is enormously broad about here. When I went on deck about 4 o'clock, I found a scene of ravishing beauty - the broad smooth river, the distant cliffs and Mts. and desert, with the heliotrope shadows, and the soft brilliant sun. It was too entrancing. We had tea on deck - and are now lying opposite <placeName ref="#Al-Wasta">Wasta</placeName>.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-12-05" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1907-12-05">Thursday, Dec. 5th</date>. <measure type="distance">29 miles</measure>.</dateline>
         <p>A quiet uneventful day - though the tug went on the sand once for a few minutes. It is a slow heavy tug, but was the only one <persName ref="#Cook_Thomas"><choice><sic>cook</sic><corr>Cook</corr></choice></persName> had reoccupied. We are about a mile above Ribbeh <!--how to tag?-->.</p> 
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-12-06" type="entry">
         <dateline><date when="1907-12-06">Friday, Dec. 6th</date>. <measure type="distance">25 miles</measure>.</dateline>
         <p>Our tug, <name type="boat" ref="#Anubis_boat">Anubis</name> by name, went on the sand soon after nine this morning, and got off at 10:25. The river is so very broad here, that it is difficult to find the channel. The gyassas seemed to be having as much trouble as we had. Such a wonderful sunset - the sky, crimson pink with one long narrow cloud near the horizon, above which shone <persName>Venus,</persName> quite resplendent, and the new moon, the veriest silver thread of a little crescent, just below the cloud.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-12-07" type="entry">
         <dateline><date when="1907-12-07">Saturday, Dec. 7</date>. <measure type="distance">44 miles</measure>.</dateline>
          <p>Made an early start - and tied up at 5:30 within 3 miles of <placeName>Minia.</placeName> Lovely day, and perfect evening. Second Sunday in <name type="event" ref="#Advent">Advent</name></p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-12-08" type="entry">
         <dateline><date when="1907-12-08">Dec. 8th</date>. <measure type="distance">28-1/2 miles</measure>. </dateline>
          <p>A very heavy fog on the river this morning delayed our starting until 9:25 - spent about 2 hours at <placeName>Minia</placeName> waiting for mail and express parcels - a good sailing day - tied up at <placeName>Redah</placeName> about 6 o'clock.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-12-09" type="entry">
         <dateline><date when="1907-12-09">Monday. Dec. 9th</date>. <measure type="distance">41-1/2 miles</measure>. </dateline>
         <p>Started at 6 o'clock - a cloudy day - and cold wind. Passed <persName>Mellawi, Hadji Kandel,</persName> and the <persName>Gebel Abu Feda</persName> and pulled up opposite <persName>Menfalout</persName> at 6 o'clock. We missed our channel this afternoon and had to go back to find it. It was a wonderful sight passing the <persName>Gebel.</persName> In all the years I have been on the <orgName>Nile,</orgName> I have not see such a transcendently beautiful sunset - and the colour reflected from the rocks made a great effect.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-12-10" type="entry">
         <dateline><date when="1907-12-10">Tuesday, Dec. 10</date>. <placeName ref="#Asyut">Asyut</placeName>. <measure type="distance">8 miles</measure>.</dateline>
         <p>Arrived at 1 o'clock having had the tug one hour on the sand. <persName>Theo</persName> dismissed the tug at 2 o'clock and we sailed at 3:30 - quite a good wind until 6 p.m. at which hour we tied up for the night, 8 miles above <placeName>Asyut.</placeName> It seemed very good to get rid of the tug. They are only tolerable to make speed, and this one couldn't do it. Last year the <name>Thothmes</name> took us in 10 days to <persName>Luxor.</persName> This year the <persName>Anubis</persName> took 9 days to go to Asy&#251;t.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-12-11" type="entry">
         <dateline><date when="1907-12-11">Wednesday, Dec. 11th</date>. <measure type="distance">19 miles</measure>.</dateline>
         <p>We had no wind until noon - but a very good one until 5:40 when we tied up and with the towing we did before noon we made our 19 miles - lovely and warm.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-12-12" type="entry">
         <dateline><date when="1907-12-12">Thursday, Dec. 12</date>.<placeName ref="#Sohag">Sohag</placeName>. <measure type="distance">41-1/2 miles</measure>.</dateline>
         <p>Started at 7 - the wind freshened finely at 8 o'clock and we came splendidly on until within a mile of the <placeName>Sohag</placeName> about 7 o'clock we struck the sand sharply - and were there 3/4 of an hour. Earlier in the afternoon we came near having a serious experience, - just as we approached the landing stage at <placeName>Tahta</placeName> which was crowded with gyassas and people, the wind shifted, and at that moment a gyassas, crowded with people, pushed out before our prow. We could give her no room - in spite of the yells and cries of our men she came on - and disaster seemed certain for if we had struck her we would have capsized here and gone over her. It is impossible to say why this kind of thing occurs so often - it is one of the greatest dangers on the <placeName ref="Nile">Nile</placeName>. A delightful day.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-12-13" type="entry">
         <dateline><date when="1907-12-13">Friday, Dec. 13</date>. <measure type="distance">28-1/2 miles</measure></dateline>. 
         <p>We waited at <placeName>Sohgg</placeName> this morning until 9:30 for mail and provisions. Stopped within 4 miles of <placeName>Balliana</placeName> at 6 P.M. A good wind, a heavenly day. The nights too, with the young moon and the resplendent <orgName>Venus,</orgName> are wonderful.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-12-14" type="entry">
         <dateline><date when="1907-12-14">Saturday, Dec. 14</date>. <measure type="distance">8-1/2 miles</measure>.</dateline> 
         <p>A perfectly calm morning - but tracking and polling we made <persName>Balliana</persName> at 4:30 - no mail, so we were off at once, and with a light wind went on until 6 P.M.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-12-15" type="entry">
         <dateline><date when="1907-12-15">Sunday - Third in <name type="event" ref="#Advent">Advent</name>. Dec. 15</date>. <measure type="distance">6 miles</measure>.</dateline>
         <p>A perfectly windless day - bright and hot. Our men have worked like <name>Trojans</name> every minute of the day - polling and tracking, we think we have made 6 miles.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-12-16" type="entry">
         <dateline><date when="1907-12-16">Monday, Dec. 16</date>.</dateline>
         <p>A repetition of yesterday - clear, hot, windless day. The men have been polling, tracking, pulling to anchor in the burning sun all day. <persName>Theo</persName> thinks we have made about 12 miles. We are now at <placeName>Nagh Hamadi,</placeName> waiting to pass the bridge tomorrow.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-12-17" type="entry">
         <dateline><date when="1907-12-17">Tuesday, Dec. 17</date>. <measure type="distance">30 miles</measure>.</dateline>
         <p><persName>Keneh.</persName>We got quietly through the bridge at 8 o'clock this morning. Found the <orgName>Istar</orgName> lying there, closed, and with flags down. Her men said that Mr. <persName>Sayce</persName> had gone to <placeName>Cairo</placeName> to see his dentist. We have had a splendid day and fine wind, and are now lying at <placeName>Dendera,</placeName> as <persName>Theo</persName> wants <persName>Carrie</persName> to see it tomorrow.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-12-18" type="entry">
         <dateline><date when="1907-12-18">Wednesday, Dec. 18</date>. <measure type="distance">18 miles</measure>.</dateline> 
         <p>We got off as soon as <persName>T.</persName> and <persName>C.</persName> came back from the <orgName>Temple,</orgName> about 11 o'clock - and with good wind came to within 4 miles of <placeName>Nagadah.</placeName></p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-12-19" type="entry">
         <dateline><date when="1907-12-19">Thursday, Dec. 19</date>. <measure type="distance">21 miles</measure>.</dateline>
         <p>Started early, 6 o'clock, hoping to make <placeName>Luxor</placeName> tonight, but are tied up 4 miles below it. Very contrary and shifting wind - and cold - pulled to the anchor for hours. Beautiful night.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-12-20" type="entry">
         <dateline><date when="1907-12-20">Friday, Dec. 20</date>.</dateline>
         <p><persName>Luxer</persName> at last, arriving at 10:30 this morning. Came to our usual mooring place opposite the Castle - and soon the men were busy settling us. A huge mail waiting for us. <persName>Theo</persName> and <persName>Carrie</persName> went to <placeName>Karnac</placeName> this afternoon.</p> 
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-12-21" type="entry">  
         <dateline><date when="1907-12-21">Saturday, Dec. 21</date>.</dateline>
         <p>I was at home all day. <persName>Theo</persName> and <persName>Carrie</persName> went to the <placeName>Valley</placeName> to look at the pit tomb <persName>Ayrton</persName> wrote about. They opened it - it proved only a pit with large vases - some sealed - some more or less broken. They report our little house finished, but too damp to live in at present - though <persName>Ayrton</persName> is living in one room. The <orgName>Miriam,</orgName> with tug <orgName>Thothmes</orgName> got in about 5 P.M. I received a note from <persName>Madame Maspero.</persName> They leave early tomorrow morning - bound for <placeName>Asw&#226;n,</placeName> and <placeName>Halfa.</placeName> One of the most wonderful moon rises this evening.</p> 
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-12-22" type="entry">
         <dateline><date when="1907-12-22">Fourth Sunday in <name type="event" ref="#Advent">Advent</name>. Dec. 22nd</date>.</dateline>
         <p>Theor and <persName>Carri</persName> again to the <placeName>Valley</placeName> - but <persName>Carrie</persName> this time on a donkey - an exquisite day. I have had a beautiful quiet Sunday. This morning I was amused watching the loading of 2 camels with all our furnishings for our house in the <placeName>Valley.</placeName> One of the camels had the most delicious young camel with her - about a month old I should think, a lovely creature - so affectionate to its mother and so full of life and pranks.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-12-23" type="entry">  
         <dateline><date when="1907-12-23">Monday, Dec. 23rd</date>.</dateline>
         <p>All went over to the town this morning - <persName>Carrie</persName> and I to see <persName>Miss Buchanan</persName> - then to <persName>Mrs. Weigalls</persName> and saw the new baby - and I delivered the cup I brought over for <persName>Corinna Smith.</persName> Then I went to see poor <persName>Mrs. Murch</persName> - who is most sad - but very brave. Then we encountered <persName>Theo</persName> on our way home - and stopped at the <placeName>Winter Palace</placeName> to see the Iddings. Mr. <persName>Iddings,</persName> the girl, <persName>Carrie</persName> and <persName>Theo</persName> went to <placeName>Karnak</placeName> at 4 o'clock and <persName>Mrs. Iddings</persName> came over and had tea with me.</p> 
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-12-24" type="entry">  
         <dateline><date when="1907-12-24">Tuesday, Dec. 24</date>.</dateline>
          <p>I have been busy all day in the boat, first getting my pots of bulbs into order - then the Christmas presents for the men - in which <persName>Jones</persName> and <persName>Carrie</persName> helped - and so did not go out - the morning lovely, but cold high winds this afternoon. <persName>Theo</persName> and <persName>Carrie</persName> went at 3 o'clock to <placeName>Medinet Habu.</placeName></p>
     </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-12-25" type="entry">    
         <dateline><date when="1907-12-25">Dec. 25. Wednesday.</date><name type="event" ref="#Christmas">Christmas</name>.</dateline>
         <p> A beautiful winters day - the distribution of presents to the men went off successfully. Mr. <persName>Ayrton</persName> came over to spend the night, and Mr. and Mrs. Iddings came to dine - and we had a concert from the men, which amused the <orgName>Iddings</orgName> very much.</p> 
     </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-12-26" type="entry">    
         <dateline><date when="1907-12-26">Thursday, Dec. 26</date>.</dateline>
         <p><persName>Carrie</persName> and I went over to the <placeName>Winter Palace</placeName> to lunch with the Iddings. They had such pleasant rooms - and the whole house looked very attractive. <persName>Carrie</persName> and <persName>Theo</persName> to <persName>Der el Bahari</persName> in the afternoon.</p>
     </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-12-27" type="entry">    
         <dateline><date when="1907-12-27">Friday, Dec. 27</date>.</dateline>
         <p><persName>Theo</persName> and <persName>Carrie</persName> went over to the <placeName>Valley</placeName> for lunch, and had Mr. and <persName>Mrs. Iddings</persName> and their girls to lunch in the little house. They were delighted. Mr. <persName>Sayce</persName> called in the afternoon.</p> 
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-12-28" type="entry">   
         <dateline><date when="1907-12-28">Saturday, Dec. 28</date>.</dateline>
         <p>A quiet day, mostly at home. <persName>Theo</persName> and <persName>Carrie</persName> at the <placeName>Weigalls</placeName> for tea, and afterwards met the <name>Iddings</name> at <placeName>Karnae.</placeName></p>
     </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-12-29" type="entry">    
         <dateline><date when="1907-12-29">Sunday, Dec. 29</date>.</dateline>
         <p>The <name>Iddings</name> came over this morning to say good-bye - were very nice and friendly. Mr. <persName>Sayce</persName> at dinner.</p> 
     </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-12-30" type="entry">    
         <dateline><date when="1907-12-30">Monday, Dec. 30</date>.</dateline> 
         <p>Over in <placeName>Luxor</placeName> this morning - <persName>Theo</persName> and <persName>Mr. Sayce</persName> at shops.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1907-12-31" type="entry">   
         <dateline><date when="1907-12-31">Tuesday, Dec. 31</date>.</dateline>
         <p>At last a windless day. The <persName>Misses Collins</persName> came to tea - such a pleasant visit.</p>
      </div>
      <!-- Molly Taylor's Code -->
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-01-01" type = "entry">
        <dateline><date when="1908-01-01">Jan. 1. 1908.</date></dateline>
        <p>We went over to the <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">Valley</placeName> this morning for the day - <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> having invited <persName ref="#McIlwraith_Malcolm">Sir Malcolm McIlwraith</persName> and his wife to lunch with us. A sister was with them - a quiet, beautiful day.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-01-02" type = "entry">
        <dateline><date when="1908-01-02">Jan. 2nd.</date></dateline>
        <p>Another quiet fine day. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> paid some visits in <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor,</placeName> and took <persName ref="#Ransom_Williams_Caroline">Carrie</persName> to the races this afternoon.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-01-03" type = "entry">
        <dateline><date when="1908-01-03">Jan. 3rd.</date>
          </dateline>
          <p><persName ref="#Hayes_Edmund">Mr. Edmund Hayes</persName> and his daughter lunched with us, and <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> and <persName ref="#Ransom_Williams_Caroline">Carrie</persName> went with them after to <placeName ref="#Der_el_Medinet">Der el Medinet</placeName>, and <placeName ref="#Medinet_Habu">Medinet Habu</placeName>.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-01-04" type = "entry">
        <dateline><date when="1908-01-04">Jan. 4th</date></dateline>
        <p>A warm wind - quiet day at home for me, <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> and <persName ref="#Ransom_Williams_Caroline"><choice><sic>Carry</sic><corr>Carrie</corr></choice></persName> to <placeName ref="#Karnak">Karnak</placeName>.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-01-05" type = "entry">
        <dateline><date when="1908-01-05">Jan. 5th.</date></dateline>
        <p><persName ref="#Erskine_David">Mr. Erskine</persName> to dinner. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> and <persName ref="#Ransom_Williams_Caroline">Carrie</persName> to the <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">Valley</placeName> this morning - coming home he reports a promising tomb in sight - thinks it will take several days to clear the doorway.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-01-06" type = "entry">
        <dateline><date when="1908-01-06">Jan. 6th.</date></dateline>
        <p>At home all day. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> at <placeName ref="#Karnak">Karnak.</placeName></p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-01-07" type = "entry">
        <dateline><date when="1908-01-07">Jan. 7th.</date></dateline>
        <p><persName>Haynes</persName> called to say goodbye.</p>
      </div>
      <!-- I THINK THIS MIGHT BE HAYES (as in Edmund Hayes), NOT HAYNES -->
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-01-08" type = "entry">
        <dateline><date when="1908-01-08">Jan. 8th.</date></dateline>
        <p><persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> at the <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">Valley</placeName> today - very hot. He thinks the tomb will prove only a pit tomb. <persName ref="#Erskine_David">Mr. Erskine</persName> lunched with us and <persName ref="#Ayrton_Edward">Ayrton</persName> came over for the night.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-01-09" type = "entry">
        <dateline><date when="1908-01-09">Jan. 9th.</date></dateline>
        <p>The tomb proves to be a shaft 30 ft. long - with a room about 20 ft. Water has been in it.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-01-10" type = "entry">
        <dateline><date when="1908-01-10">Jan. 10th.</date></dateline>
        <p><persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> and <persName ref="#Ransom_Williams_Caroline">Carrie</persName> to  <placeName ref="#Karnak">Karnac.</placeName> I had a delightful visit from <persName ref="#Gardner_Mrs.">Mrs. Gardner</persName>.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-01-11" type = "entry">
        <dateline><date when="1908-01-11">Jan. 11th.</date></dateline>
        <p><persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> and <persName ref="#Ransom_Williams_Caroline">Carrie</persName> a long ride into the country.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-01-12" type = "entry">
        <dateline><date when="1908-01-12">Jan. 6th.</date></dateline>
        <p><persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> and <persName ref="#Ransom_Williams_Caroline">Carrie</persName> at the <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">Valley.</placeName> The tomb proves to be filled with an accretion of gravel and dried mud 5 ft. deep - exceedingly hard. <persName ref="#Ayrton_Edward">Ayrton</persName> began the clearing this morning - at the S.W. corner, and on reaching 2 ft. from the bottom, came upon a deposit of silver and gold objects of most unique importance and value. They were busy with these all afternoon - containing cartouches of <persName ref="Sety_II">Sety II</persName> and <persName ref="#Tausert">Tausert</persName> - all of which <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> brought home with him. </p>
        <p><persName ref="#Weigall_Arthur #Weigall_Hortense">Mr. and Mrs. Weigall</persName>, and <persName ref="#Craggs_Mrs.">Mrs. Craggs</persName> and <persName ref="#Ayrton_Edward">Ayrton</persName> to dinner.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-01-13" type = "entry">
        <dateline><date when="1908-01-13">Jan. 13th.</date></dateline>
        <p><persName ref="#Ayrton_Edward">Ayrton</persName> here all day - inexpressibly shocked to hear of dear <persName ref="Collins_Frances">Miss Frances Collins'</persName> death in church last evening. She was playing the organ in the little chapel and was in the midst of the "Gloria" when she suddenly stood up and fell to the floor dead! It was a beautiful passing away of her lovely, useful spirit.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-01-14" type = "entry">
        <dateline><date when="1908-01-14">Jan. 14th. Tuesday.</date></dateline>
        <p><persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> and <persName ref="#Ransom_Williams_Caroline">Carrie</persName> went to  <placeName ref="#Karnak">Karnac</placeName> at 4 o'clock. <persName ref="#Winlock_Herbert">Mr. Winlock</persName> called with letter of introduction from <persName ref="#Jones_Harold">Harold Jones.</persName></p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-01-15" type = "entry">
        <dateline><date when="1908-01-15">Jan. <choice><sic>16.</sic><corr>15.</corr></choice> Wednesday.</date></dateline>
        <p>Cold, cloudy day. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> and <persName ref="#Ransom_Williams_Caroline">Carrie</persName> to the <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">Valley.</placeName> Several beads etc. had been found.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-01-16" type = "entry">
        <dateline><date when="1908-01-16">Jan. 16th. Thursday.</date></dateline>
        <p><persName ref="#Humphreys_Mr.">Mr. Humphreys</persName> called and <persName ref="#Buchanan_Miss">Miss Buchanan</persName> and friend. Cloudy cold day - strong S. W. wind. <persName ref="#Ransom_Williams_Caroline">Carrie</persName> and I went over to the <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor,</placeName> to see the two old <persName ref="Collins_Miss">Miss Collins</persName> - so sad.</p>
      </div>
      <!-- COLLINSES: AGAIN, 2 PEOPLE REFERENCED AT ONCE. ALSO, DIDN'T SHE TALK ABOUT FRANCES' DEATH ON JAN 13TH? -->
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-01-17" type = "entry">
        <dateline><date when="1908-01-17">Jan. 17th. Friday.</date></dateline>
        <p><persName>Mr. and Mrs. Elliot Smith</persName> and her sister called soon after breakfast on their way to the Valley. We started ourselves after they left, as the <persName>Gorsts</persName> were to lunch with us. They arrived in time. <persName ref="#Gorst_John_Eldon">Sir Eldon,</persName> <persName ref="#Gorst_Lady">Lady Gorst</persName>, his Sec. and <persName ref="#Weigall_Hortense">Mrs. Weigall.</persName> It was a very pleasant lunch. I liked <persName ref="#Gorst_John Eldon">Sir Eldon</persName> very much - <persName ref="#Gorst_Lady">Lady G.</persName> exceedingly pretty and chic. <persName ref="#Ayrton_Edward">Ayrton</persName> found a few more small gold objects yesterday. The <persName>Gorsts</persName> came to tea with us after we got home, to see all the gold.</p>
      </div>
      <!-- SMITHS: 2 PEOPLE REFERENCED AT ONCE; GORSTS: 2 AT ONCE (at beg. and end of entry)-->
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-01-18" type = "entry">
        <dateline><date when="1908-01-18">Jan. 18. Saturday.</date></dateline>
        <p>We had the whole <placeName ref="Devonshire">Devonshire</placeName> party to tea this afternoon to see the find. The <persName ref="#Cavendish_Spencer_Duke">Duke,</persName> the <persName ref="#Cavendish_Louisa_Duchess">Duchess,</persName> her daughter <persName ref="#Acheson_Lady_Louisa">Lady Gosford,</persName> and <persName ref="#">Lord Gasford</persName> and their daughter <persName>Lady Theodora Guest</persName> - with <persName>Mr. Weigall.</persName> They looked at the gold things with great interest - at all the things in the boat, and begged for photographs of the boat and other things. The <persName>Duke,</persName> now a very old and broken man, is of course a great personage - and I was very interested in meeting him. He seemed more interested in the boat and its fittings, and was much amused with our chicken yard out on the sand. The <persName ref="#Cavendish_Duchess_Louisa">Duchess,</persName> so celebrated in her way, was a wonderful old woman - painted and enamelled, with reddish wig, an old black hat, with painted lips - very keen to see everything. <persName>Lady Gosford</persName> very different, as nice as possible, and her husband and daughter were very pleasant. I heard the <persName>Duchess</persName> talking to <persName>Mr. Davis</persName> about how the <persName>Gorsts</persName> enjoyed their lunch yesterday in the <placeName ref="Valley_of_the_Kings">Valley House,</placeName> and I know from what she said that she intended <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> should invited them also to lunch there, and I don't think he will be able to escape it.</p>
      </div>
      <!-- DEVONSHIRES, GORSTS: 2 PEOPLE REFERENCED AT ONCE-->
      <!-- NEW PEOPLE: Gasfords, Mr. Davis (I would think she wouldn't talk about Theodore so formally, but in the next part of the sentence she talks about the Duchess inviting "Theo" to lunch, so I'm not completely sure) -->
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-01-19" type = "entry">
        <dateline><date when="1908-01-19">19th Sunday after Epiphany. Jan, 19.</date></dateline>
        <p><persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> was again in the <placeName ref="Valley_of_the_Kings">Valley</placeName> today, with <persName ref="#Winlock_Herbert">Mr. Winlock</persName>. <persName>M. Maspero</persName> and <persName ref="#Loret_M">M. Loret</persName> called and I showed them the gold things.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-01-20" type = "entry">
        <dateline><date when="1908-01-20">Jan. 20, Monday.</date></dateline>
        <p><persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> again in the <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">Valley</placeName> with <persName>M. Lacau</persName> to lunch - quite cold.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-01-21" type = "entry">
        <dateline><date when="1908-01-21">Jan. 21. Tuesday.</date></dateline>
        <p>The 2 <persName>Miss McKewus</persName> called today. <persName ref="#Ayrton_Edward">Ayrton</persName> to tea. <persName ref="#Ayrton_Edward">Ayrton</persName> to tea. A note from <persName>"Louisa" Duchess of Devonshire</persName> tells <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> that they are going to the <placeName ref="Valley_of_the_Kings">Valley</placeName> on Thursday, and will be happy to accept <persName>Mr. Davin's</persName> invitation to lunch!</p>
      </div>
      <!-- NEW PERSON? Or is this "Mr. Davin" the same person as Mr. Davis in 01-18? I've seen a few typos/miss-translations (not sure which) with names in these entries so far, so they might be. -->
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-01-22" type = "entry">
        <dateline><date when="1908-01-22">Jan. 22. Wednesday.</date></dateline>
        <p><persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> again to the <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">Valley</placeName> to meet <persName>M. Maspero,</persName> <persName>Erskine</persName> and <persName>Weigall,</persName> and entered the new tomb. This was uncovered a few days since, but was shallow, and contained only some remains of workmens houses, and a number of large vases - filled with broken potsherds and small objects - the most important being a head about 7 in. high, which crowned the head of a mummied bird.</p>
        <p><persName>Major Watson,</persName> and <persName>Mrs. Graham,</persName> an English woman came to tea and were shown the find, when <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> was in the <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">valley</placeName> this A.M. they opened a jar found in the gold tomb. It contained a broken vase, which was beautifully enamelled and bearing the cartouche of <persName>Sety II.</persName> This can be restored - also an alabaster vase, broken, with cartouche of <orgName>Rameses II,</orgName> of very good work. A lovely warm day. <persName ref="#Erskine_David">Mr. Erskine</persName> dined with us.</p>
      </div>
      <!-- MISS-TRANSLATION/TYPO? Erakine might be Erskine. Also, the EBA Indices page says "Erksine", but everything in Jan/Feb 1907 says "Erskine" -->
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-01-23" type = "entry">
        <dateline><date when="1908-01-23">Jan. 23rd. Thursday.</date></dateline>
        <p><persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> over in the <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">Valley</placeName> all day, having the <placeName>Devonshire</placeName> party to lunch. <persName ref="#Ransom_Williams_Caroline">Carrie</persName> and I considerately stayed at home. Quite warm.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-01-24" type = "entry">
        <dateline><date when="1908-01-24">Jan. 24. Friday.</date></dateline>
        <p>A quiet day for all at home. This afternoon <persName ref="#Erskine_David">Mr. Erskine</persName> came to say goodbye. <persName ref="#Maspero_Gaston #Maspero_Louise">M. and Madame Maspero</persName> with their sons came to see the find.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-01-25" type = "entry">
        <dateline><date when="1908-01-25">Jan. 25. Saturday.</date></dateline>
        <p><persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> and <persName ref="#Ransom_Williams_Caroline">Carrie</persName> went to  <placeName ref="#Karnak">Karnac</placeName> this P.M.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-01-26" type = "entry">
        <dateline><date when="1908-01-26">Jan. 26. 	Third Sunday after Epiphany.</date></dateline>
        <p><persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> and <persName ref="#Ransom_Williams_Caroline">Carrie</persName> went to the <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">Valley</placeName> - in a very cold wind storm - the dust quite frightful. <persName>Mr. Carter</persName> lunched with me and <persName ref="#Jones_Harold">Harold Jones,</persName> who arrived this morning. <persName ref="#Lythgoe_Albert">Mr. Lythgoe</persName> in <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor.</placeName></p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-01-27" type = "entry">
        <dateline><date when="1908-01-27">Jan. 27. Monday.</date></dateline>
        <p><persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> busy this morning with publication matter to send to <placeName ref="#London">London</placeName> and <persName ref="#Jones_Harold">Harold</persName> began his drawing of plates. <persName ref="#dalison_Max">Mr. Dalison</persName> and <persName ref="#Lythgoe_Albert">Lythgoe</persName> dined here. A very cold wind today.</p>
      </div>
      <!-- Should Dalison's reference have "Mr" in it? Some entries (like this and Mr. Max Dalison) have their titles in their references on the EBA Indices list, but others don't. -->
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-01-28" type = "entry">
        <dateline><date when="1908-01-28">Jan. 28. Tuesday.</date></dateline>
        <p>A quiet day - <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> paying some visits.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-01-29" type = "entry">
        <dateline><date when="1908-01-29">Jan. 29. Wednesday.</date></dateline>
        <p>Lovely and warm. Several people on boat today. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> and <persName ref="#Ransom_Williams_Caroline">Carrie</persName> to <placeName ref="#Tombs_of_the_Kings">"Tombs of the Queens"</placeName> this afternoon.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-01-30" type = "entry">
        <dateline><date when="1908-01-30">Jan. 30. Thursday.</date></dateline>
        <p>A lot of people on the boat today - among them <persName>Mr. and Mrs. Smith</persName> of <placeName ref="#New_York">New York</placeName> - he is something at the <placeName ref="#Metropolitan_Museum">Met. Museum,</placeName> wand with them <persName>Mr. and Mrs. Patterson</persName> of <placeName ref="Chicago">Chicago</placeName>. <persName ref="#Loret_M">M. Loret</persName> also called - a pleasant and charming personage. <persName ref="#dalison_Max">Mr. Dalison</persName> dined here.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-01-31" type = "entry">
        <dateline><date when="1908-01-31">Jan. 31. Friday.</date></dateline>
        <p><persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> as usual in the <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">Valley</placeName> with <persName ref="#Lythgoe_Albert">Lythgoe</persName> and <persName>Harold.</persName> <persName ref="#Villiers_Eric">Mr. Eric Villiers</persName> called this afternoon.</p>
      </div>
      <!-- The Smiths just arrived the day before, so is this Harold Jones or Harold Smith? -->
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-02-01" type = "entry">
        <dateline><date when="1908-01-01">Feb. 1. Saturday.</date></dateline>
        <p>A day at home. <persName ref="#Cassel_Ernest">Sir Ernest Cassel</persName> and his daughter <persName ref="#Maud_Amalia">Mrs. Ashley</persName> and the <persName>Princess Teano</persName> of <placeName>Rome</placeName> came to tea also <persName>Mr. and Mrs. Schiff</persName> of New York, <persName>Mr. Villiers,</persName> <persName>Weigall</persName> and others.</p>
      </div>
      <!-- Corrected misspelling: Cassal -> Cassel -->
      <!-- Ernest Cassel did not have a daughter named Mrs. Ashley. His daughter was Amalia Mary Maud (nee Cassel). Oddly, the EBA Indices page does mention a Mrs. Ashley Maud, but this wasn't her name either. Maybe, because her name was Prussian, she took on an English name as a kind of nickname?-->
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-02-02" type = "entry">
        <dateline><date when="1908-02-02">Feb. 2. 4th after Epiphany.</date></dateline>
        <p>In all day. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName>, <persName ref="#Ransom_Williams_Caroline">Carrie</persName> and <persName>Harold</persName> visited the interesting tombs in <placeName ref="#Sheikh_Abd_el-Qurna">Sheik Abdul Gurnah.</placeName> <persName>M. and Mme. Maspero</persName> and <persName ref="#Loret_M">M. Loret</persName> dined with us. Very warm this afternoon.</p>
      </div>
      <!-- Harold Jones or Harold Smith? -->
      <!-- Person group - Masperos -->
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-02-03" type = "entry">
        <dateline><date when="1908-02-03">Feb. 3rd. Monday.</date></dateline>
        <p>In <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName> this morning. Beautiful warm day.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-02-04" type = "entry">
        <dateline><date when="1908-02-04">Feb. 4th. Tuesday.</date></dateline>
        <p>A quiet day. <persName ref="#Sayce_Archibald">Mr. Sayce</persName> arrived on the <orgName>Istar</orgName> and is lying near - came to see us. <persName ref="#Loret_M">M. Loret</persName> and <persName ref="#Le_Grand_M">M. Le Grand</persName> came to tea and to see the find. <persName ref="#Ayrton_Edward">Ayrton</persName> lunched and dined with us.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-02-05" type = "entry">
        <dateline><date when="1908-02-05">Feb. 5th. Wednesday.</date></dateline>
        <p><persName ref="#Sayce_Archibald">Mr. Sayce</persName> and <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> went to the <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">Valley</placeName> and lunched at the little house. <persName ref="#Sayce_Archibald">Mr. Sayce</persName> also dined with us.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-02-06" type = "entry">
        <dateline><date when="1908-02-06">Feb. 6th. Thursday.</date></dateline>
        <p><persName ref="#Erskine_David">Mr. Erskine, Nicol</persName> and <persName ref="#Whymper_Charles">Mr. Whymper</persName> called. We went back with them to their boat to see <persName ref="#Erskine_David">Mr. Nicol's</persName> pictures. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> bought a beauty for &#163;50. We started for <placeName ref="#Aswan">Aswan</placeName> at 1 o'clock and having a light wind got within 3 miles of <placeName ref="#Erment">Erment,</placeName> where we had to stop for the night.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-02-07" type = "entry">
        <dateline><date when="1908-02-07">Feb. 7th. Friday.</date></dateline>
        <p>A cold west wind blowing all day - a real gale - we towed and pulled to anchor, making 1-1/2 miles!</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-02-08" type = "entry">
        <dateline><date when="1908-02-08">Feb. 8th. Saturday.</date></dateline>
        <p>30 miles. Towed from 7 A.M. to 10 o'clock. Then the gale began again and was so strong we furled the big sail and went on with the felucca sail, but struck a sand bank with such force that I was thrown off my feet - lamp overturned - ornaments etc. thrown. We then went on more slowly passing the <placeName ref="#Esneh_Bridge">Esneh bridge</placeName> and sailing until 6 o'clock.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-02-09" type = "entry">
        <dateline><date when="1908-02-09">Fifth Sunday after Epiphany. Feb. 9th.</date></dateline>
        <p>31 miles. Started at 7 A.M. with light wind, growing stronger at 10 proving a gale. We again put up our felucca sail and went on with it until driven to the bank at 4 o'clock - afterwards going on until 5:30 - cold - and atmosphere filled with dust.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-02-10" type = "entry">
        <dateline><date when="1908-02-10">Feb. 10. Monday.</date></dateline>
        <p>A fine good sailing day - have made 41 miles, and are 3 miles above <placeName ref="#Kom_OMbo">Kom Ombo.</placeName></p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-02-11" type = "entry">
        <dateline><date when="1908-02-11">Feb. 11. Tuesday.</date></dateline>
        <p>23 miles. A difficult day, light, variable winds - which have brought us our old "Sycamore tree".</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-02-12" type = "entry">
        <dateline><date when="1908-02-12">Feb. 12. Wednesday.</date></dateline>
        <p>We pulled to anchor around to our old place opposite the <placeName type="hotel" ref="#Cataract">Cataract Hotel.</placeName> Rowed around to the <placeName type="hotel" ref="#Savoy">Savoy,</placeName> and had tea in the lovely garden.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-02-13" type = "entry">
        <dateline><date when="1908-02-13">Feb. 13. Thursday.</date></dateline>
        <p>A great gale of wind - filling the air with dust from the excavations on the island. I never knew a more disagreeable day. <persName>Harold</persName> and <persName ref="#Ransom_Williams_Caroline">Carrie</persName> went to <placeName ref="Philae">Philae,</placeName> in spite of it. The big boom was taken down this morning, and we are ready to go down tomorrow.</p>
      </div>
      <!-- Harold Jones or Harold Smith? -->
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-02-14" type = "entry">
        <dateline><date when="1908-02-14">Feb. 14. Friday.</date></dateline>
        <p>The wind has prevented our starting. <persName ref="#Ransom_Williams_Caroline">Carrie</persName> and I and <persName>Harold</persName> tried to see the excavations today, but the dust and wind drove us home.</p>
      </div>
      <!-- Harold Jones or Harold Smith? -->
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-02-15" type = "entry">
        <dateline><date when="1908-02-15">Feb. 15. Saturday.</date></dateline>
        <p>We started down at 9:40 this morning - but the north wind drove us to anchor very near the <placeName type="hotel" ref="#Savoy">Savoy,</placeName> where we have remained all day - wind, still strong.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-02-16" type = "entry">
        <dateline><date when="1908-02-16">Feb. 16. Septuagesima Sunday.</date></dateline>
        <p>Started at 7 A.M. but were driven immediately to the bank, where we have lain all day. Warm.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-02-17" type = "entry">
        <dateline><date when="1908-02-17">Feb. 17. Monday.</date></dateline>
        <p>5 miles. Difficult to make even this distance.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-02-18" type = "entry">
        <dateline><date when="1908-02-18">Feb. 18. Tuesday.</date></dateline>
        <p>13 miles. Hard wind all day - cold.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-02-19" type = "entry">
        <dateline><date when="1908-02-19">Feb. 19. Wednesday.</date></dateline>
        <p>16 miles. Ditto yesterday.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-02-20" type = "entry">
        <dateline><date when="1908-02-20">Feb. 20. Thursday.</date></dateline>
        <p>34 miles. <placeName ref="Edfu">Edfu,</placeName> a good days sail. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName>, <persName ref="#Jones_Harold">Harold</persName> and <persName ref="#Ransom_Williams_Caroline">Carrie</persName> visited the temple.</p>
      </div>
      <!-- Harold Jones or Harold Smith? -->
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-02-21" type = "entry">
        <dateline><date when="1908-02-21">Feb. 21. Friday.</date></dateline>
        <p>32 miles. Very hot all day - sailing all the time.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-02-22" type = "entry">
        <dateline><date when="1908-02-22">Feb. 22. Saturday.</date></dateline>
        <p>Hard gale. No miles.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-02-23" type = "entry">
        <dateline><date when="1908-02-23">Feb. 23. 	Sexagesima Sunday.</date></dateline>
        <p>7 miles. Strong wind.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-02-24" type = "entry">
        <dateline><date when="1908-02-24">Feb. 24. Monday.</date></dateline>
        <p>26 miles. We reached <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName> at 7 P.M. making 8 days from <placeName ref="#Aswan">Aswan.</placeName></p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-02-25" type = "entry">
        <dateline><date when="1908-02-25">Feb. 25. Tuesday.</date></dateline>
        <p><persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> and <persName>Harold</persName> went over to the <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">Valley</placeName> this morning to see the condition of the tomb <persName ref="#Ayrton_Edward">Ayrton</persName> thinks he has found. They report that a stone stairway leading sharply down to a doorway has been found.</p>
      </div>
      <!-- Harold Jones or Harold Smith? -->
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-02-26" type = "entry">
        <dateline><date when="1908-02-26">Feb. 26. Wednesday.</date></dateline>
        <p>All of us went to the <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">Valley</placeName> this morning. The first door of the tomb is cleared - the corridor filled with rubbish. <persName ref="#Ayrton_Edward">Ayrton</persName> crawled through with great difficulty and said he could see another door quite filled up. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> thinks it an 18th dynasty tomb. <persName>Mr. and Mrs. Spreston</persName> called this evening, bringing a letter of introduction from <persName ref="#Fielding_Everard">Everard Fielding.</persName> She was a <persName ref="#de_Trafford_Miss">Miss de Trafford.</persName> The <persName>McKeever girls</persName> and <persName ref="#Forbes_Mr">Mr. Forbes</persName> called before dinner, and <persName ref="#Dalison_Max">Mr. Dalison</persName> this evening.</p>
      </div>
      <!-- Person Group - Sprestons, McKeever girls -->
      <!-- 2nd half of this entry makes no sense... -->
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-02-27" type = "entry">
        <dateline><date when="1908-02-27">Feb. 27. Thursday.</date></dateline>
        <p>A quiet day - <persName>Harold</persName> has stayed in the <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">Valley</placeName> yesterday and today.</p>
      </div>
      <!-- Harold Jones or Harold Smith? -->
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-02-28" type = "entry">
        <dateline><date when="1908-02-28">Feb. 28. Friday.</date></dateline>
        <p><persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> over in the <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">Valley</placeName> all day - he reports that the door of the tomb is nearly free, and the at the men are clearing a passage through the debris in the corridor. Very hot today.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-02-29" type = "entry">
        <dateline><date when="1908-02-29">Feb. 29. Saturday.</date></dateline>
        <p><persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> and <persName ref="#Jones_Harold">Harold</persName> went of course to the <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">Valley</placeName> this morning. They found <persName ref="#Ayrton_Edward">Ayrton</persName>, <persName ref="#Dalison_Max">Dalison</persName> and <persName ref="#Weigall_Arthur">Weigall</persName> waiting for them, and in spite of their protestations <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> insisted upon entering the tomb, and going first. They found it very difficult and hot. It soon declared itself as the tomb of <persName type= "historical" ref="#Horemheb">Heromheb</persName> - a very long tomb - with corridors, well, fully fresh, of Gods, a magnificent Sarcophagus, and figures in wood and marble - a few bones - no mummy - 200 ft. long.</p>
      </div>
      <!-- Harold Jones or Harold Smith? -->
      <!-- Olivia Mhyre's Code -->
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-03-01" type="entry">
        <dateline><placeName ref="#Quinquagesima">Quinquagesima</placeName> - <date when="1908-03-01">March 1st.</date>.</dateline>
        <p>Sunday. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> met the <persName ref="#Connaught_Family">Connaught</persName> party at <placeName ref="#Karnak">Karnac</placeName> this afternoon - and invited them to tea tomorrow!</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-03-02" type="entry">
        <dateline><placeName ref="#Quinquagesima">Quinquagesima</placeName> - <date when="1908-03-02">March 2. Monday</date>.</dateline>
        <p>The <persName ref="#Connaught_Family">Connaughts</persName> arrived from the <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">Valley</placeName> about 4:30 - quite an imposing array - several mounted guards arrived before them - and the <persName ref="#Connaught_Duchess">Duchess</persName> and <persName ref="#Connaught_Patricia_Princess">Princess Patricia</persName> arrived first. I took them to my room, and left them to tidy themselves. I found in the salon <persName ref="#Pelly_Miss">Miss Pelly</persName>, whom I had met before, Lady in waiting, then came the <persName ref="#Connaught_Duke">Duke</persName> with members of his staff - <persName ref="#Murray_M_Major">Major M. Murray</persName> - <persName ref="#Ponsonby_M_B_Lieutenant">Lieut. the Hon. M. B. Ponsonby</persName> - <persName ref="#Maxwell_John_Sir">Sir John Maxwell</persName>, whom we knew, <persName ref="#Watson_Major">Major Watson</persName>, an old friend, and <persName ref="#Weigall_Arthur">Mr. Weigall</persName>. They looked first at the gold find, and then went on deck for tea. I thought I had never seen so many nice looking men together - and the <persName ref="#Connaught_Family">Connaughts</persName> are delightful, simple people to entertain. After they went away the <persName ref="#McKewer_Family">McKewers</persName> and <persName ref="#Forbes_Mr #Forbes_Mrs">Mr. and Mrs. Forbes</persName> came. They said they had been watching from the Hotel opposite the royal entourage on the sand, waiting until it was over.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-03-03" type="entry">
        <dateline><placeName ref="#Quinquagesima">Quinquagesima</placeName> - <date when="1908-03-03">March 3rd.</date>.</dateline>
        <p>Tuesday. <persName ref="#Dalison_Max_Mr">Mr. Dalison</persName> and <persName ref="#Ayrton_Edward">Ayrton</persName> came to lunch. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> and <persName ref="#Ransom_Williams_Caroline">Carrie</persName> again [cut off--illegible] when they met the <persName ref="#Connaught_Duke">Duke's</persName> party. Lovely day.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-03-04" type="entry">
        <dateline><placeName ref="#Quinquagesima">Quinquagesima</placeName> - <date when="1908-03-04">March 4th.</date>.</dateline>
        <p>Ash Wednesday. All the family at <placeName ref="#Karnac">Karnac</placeName> this afternoon.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-03-05" type="entry">
        <dateline><placeName ref="#Quinquagesima">Quinquagesima</placeName> - <date when="1908-03-05">March 5th.</date>.</dateline>
        <p>Thursday. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> and <persName ref="#Jones_Harold">Harold</persName> at the <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">Valley</placeName> today. I went over to <name type="hotel" ref="#Hotel_Luxor">Luxor</name> to say goodbye to <persName ref="#Buchanan_Carrie">Miss Buchanan</persName>.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-03-06" type="entry">
        <dateline><placeName ref="#Quinquagesima">Quinquagesima</placeName> - <date when="1908-03-06">March 6th.</date>.</dateline>
        <p>Friday. A really hot day. <persName ref="#Roa_Mr #Roa_Mrs">Mr. and Mrs. Roa</persName> and <persName ref="#Mohassib_Mohamed">Mohamed Mohassib</persName> to tea.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-03-07" type="entry">
        <dateline><placeName ref="#Quinquagesima">Quinquagesima</placeName> - <date when="1908-03-07">March 7th.</date>.</dateline>
        <p>Saturday. <persName ref="#Jones_Harold">Harold</persName> and <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> have been in the <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">Valley</placeName> all day with the photographer, who came up from <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName>, to do the tomb.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-03-08" type="entry">
        <dateline><placeName ref="#Quinquadesima">Quinquagesima</placeName> - <date when="1908-03-08">March 8th.</date>.</dateline>
        <p>First Sunday in Lent. I am the only member of the household who did not go to the <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">Valley</placeName> today. All went into the tomb. <persName ref="#Dalison_Max_Mr">Mr. Dalison</persName> and <persName ref="#Ayrton_Edward">Mr. Ayrton</persName> dined with us, and spent the night - sleeping on the dock divans - very jolly evening.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-03-09" type="entry">
        <dateline><placeName ref="#Nag_Hamadi">Nag Hamadi</placeName> - <date when="1908-03-09">March 9.</date>.</dateline>
        <p>Monday. 82-1/2 miles. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theo</persName> had engaged a sugar tug to take us down the river. We started at 9:10 and reached <placeName ref="#Nag_Hamadi">Nag Hamadi</placeName> at 7:30 P.M. No wind, very warm, anchored just above the bridge.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-03-10" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1908-03-10">March 10.</date>.</dateline>
        <p>Tuesday. 51 miles. Passed the bridge at 8 A.M. and then anchored until 25 M. before 11 - allowed the tug to cool. Very hot all day. The sunset was wonderfully beautiful.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-03-11" type="entry">
        <dateline><placeName ref="#Assiout">Asyt.</placeName> - <date when="1908-03-11">March 11.</date>.</dateline>
        <p>Wed. 68 miles. A gale all day - tug on the sand for an hour this morning - afterwards sticking again for 3 hours - arrived in spite of all at <placeName ref="#Assiout">Asy&#251;t</placeName> at 6:30.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-03-12" type="entry">
        <dateline><placeName ref="#Beni_Hassan">Beni Hassan</placeName> - <date when="1908-03-12">March 12.</date>.</dateline>
        <p>Thursday. Passed the lock at 8 o'clock, early. The sand is bad in this part of the river - we have to go carefully.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-03-13" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1908-03-13">March 13.</date>.</dateline>
        <p>Friday. 60 miles. Started at 6. Stopped at <placeName ref="#Minieh">Minia</placeName>, for mail one hour and 3 hours at <placeName ref="#Sheik_Fadl">Sheik Fadl</placeName> to cool. Rather cool out of the sun.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-03-14" type="entry">
        <dateline><placeName ref="#Bedrescheyn">Bedrescheyn</placeName> - <date when="1908-03-14">March 14.</date>.</dateline>
        <p>Saturday. near <placeName ref="#Bedrescheyn">Bedrescheyn</placeName>. 90 miles. Started again at 6, stopping about 10 to assist a dahabya sticking in the mud, to get off. It proved to be a party from <placeName ref="#Chicago">Chicago</placeName> - <persName ref="#Smith_Mr">Mr. Smith</persName> the father of <persName ref="#Smith_Harold">Harold Smith</persName>.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-03-15" type="entry">
        <dateline><date when="1908-03-15">March 15.</date>.</dateline>
        <p>2nd Sunday in Lent. Arrived at the <placeName ref="#Ghezireh_Bridge">Ghezireh bridge</placeName> at 11 A.M. having made our 450 miles from <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName> in 7 days. <persName ref="#Fielding_Lord">Lord Fielding</persName> dined with us.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-03-16" type="entry">
        <dateline><placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo.</placeName> - <date when="1908-03-16">March 16.</date>.</dateline>
        <p>Came to our old place at the <name type="hotel" ref="#Ghezireh_Palace_Hotel">Ghezireh Palace</name> this A.M. Spent the morning at the <orgName ref="#Boulaq_Museum">Museum</orgName> and and had tea with the <persName ref="#Iddings_Mr #Iddings_Mrs">Iddings</persName> in the afternoon. A visit from <persName ref="#Fraser_Mr #Fraser_Mrs">Mr. and Mrs. Fraser</persName> this evening.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-03-17" type="entry">
        <dateline><placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo.</placeName> - <date when="1908-03-17">March 17th.</date>.</dateline>
        <p>Tuesday. <persName ref="#Lyons_Capt #Lyons_Mrs">Capt. Lyons and Mrs. Lyons</persName> and <persName ref="#Iddings_Mr #Iddings_Mrs">Mr. and Mrs. Iddings</persName> came this A.M. to see the find. We took all the things to the <orgName ref="#Boulaq_Museum">Museum</orgName> this morning. A good riddance.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-03-18" type="entry">
        <dateline><placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo.</placeName> - <date when="1908-03-18">March 18th.</date>.</dateline>
        <p>Wednesday. Morning at <orgName ref="#Boulaq_Museum">Museum</orgName> - afternoon driving and visiting.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-03-19" type="entry">
        <dateline><placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo.</placeName> - <date when="1908-03-19">March 19th.</date>.</dateline>
        <p>Thursday. We were again at the <orgName ref="#Boulaq_Museum">Museum</orgName> this morning. Dinner at the <persName ref="#Iddings_Mr #Iddings_Mrs">Iddings</persName> where we met some pleasant people: <persName ref="#Farnell_Mr #Farnell_Miss">Mr. and Miss Farnell</persName> - <persName ref="#Skifeuton_Smythe_Major">Major Skifeuton</persName> - Smythe - <persName ref="#Beard_Sir_John">Sir John Beard</persName> and daughter, <persName ref="#Bathhurst_Lady">Lady Bathhurst</persName> and others.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-03-20" type="entry">
        <dateline><placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo.</placeName> - <date when="1908-03-20">March 20th.</date>.</dateline>
        <p>Friday. Driving and shopping this morning - <persName ref="#Watson_Major">Major Watson</persName> called this afternoon.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-03-21" type="entry">
        <dateline><placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo.</placeName> - <date when="1908-03-21">March 21st.</date>.</dateline>
        <p>Saturday. Lunched at the <placeName ref="#British_Embassy">British Embassy</placeName> - a charming visit - <persName ref="#Gorst_John_Eldon_Sir">Sir Eldon</persName> was particularly interesting and agreeable. <persName ref="#Gorst_Lady">Lady Gorst</persName>, very pretty, chic and pleasant. <persName ref="#Hall_Caine_Mr">Mr. Hall Caine</persName> and his wife were there among others.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-03-22" type="entry">
        <dateline><placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo.</placeName> - <date when="1908-03-22">March 22nd.</date>.</dateline>
        <p>3rd Sunday in Lent. We have been staying at the <name type="hotel" ref="#Ghezireh_Palace_Hotel">Ghezireh Palace Hotel</name> since Thursday. Rain all day. <persName ref="#Sayce_Archibald">Mr. Sayce</persName> dined with us.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1908-03-23" type="entry">
        <dateline><placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName>. - <date when="1908-03-23">March 23rd.</date>.</dateline>
        <p>Monday. Very busy. Our last day. Went in the afternoon to <persName ref="#Pasha_Artin_Madame">Madame Artin Pashat</persName> to tea - interesting. <persName ref="#Dalison_Max_Mr">Mr. Dalison</persName> and <persName ref="#Lindon_Smith_Joseph">Joe Smith</persName> dined with us. <persName ref="#Dalison_Max_Mr">Mr. Dalison</persName> has been with us for 2 days, and is crossing with us to <placeName ref="#Naples">Naples</placeName> where we are to spend 3 days. <persName ref="#Carter_Howard">Mr. Carter</persName> came to tea with us this afternoon.</p>
      </div>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>