<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>Diary of Mrs. Emma B. Andrews. Volume 3 1894-1895</title>
        <author>
          <persName ref="#Andrews_Emma_B">Emma B. Andrews</persName>
        </author>
        <editor>
          <persName ref="#SK">Sarah Ketchley</persName>
        </editor>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>
          <orgName ref="#Emma_B_Andrews_Diary_Project">Emma B. Andrews Diary Project</orgName>
        </publisher>
        <address>
          <addrLine>University of Washington, Seattle, WA</addrLine>
        </address>
        <availability>
          <licence target="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/">his work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial Share-Alike 4.0 International License.</licence>
        </availability>
        <date>2021-04-27</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <p><name ref="#American_Philosophical_Society_Philadelphia">American Philosophical Society, Philadelphia</name></p>
      </sourceDesc>
      <encodingStmt>
        <projectDesc>
          <p>Established in 2010, the goals of the <orgName ref="#Emma_B_Andrews_Diary_Project">Emma B. Andrews Diary Project</orgName> include the transcription and digitization of a wide range of primary historical material from the'Golden Age' of Egyptian archaeology at the end of the 19th and beginning of the 20th centuries. A founding partner of <orgName ref="#Newbook_Digital_Texts">Newbook Digital Texts</orgName> (www.newbookdigitaltexts.org), the <orgName ref="#EBA_Diary_Project">EBA Diary Project</orgName> offers undergraduate and graduate digital humanities education and internships at the <orgName ref="#University_of_Washington">University of Washington.</orgName> <persName ref="#Andrews_Emma_B">Emma B. Andrews</persName> is best remembered for her association with the millionaire lawyer turned archaeologist/art and antiquities collector, <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore M. Davis</persName>. Traveling to <placeName ref="#Egypt">Egypt</placeName> with him between 1889 and 1912, she kept detailed journals of these voyages along the <placeName ref="#Nile">Nile</placeName>, including his important yet under-reported excavations of over 20 significant tombs in the <placeName ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">Valley of the Kings</placeName>. <persName ref="#Andrews_Emma_B">Emma</persName> provides a vital commentary on the archaeology and pioneering Egyptologists of the time, painting a revealing picture of the lives of the colonial gentry and the cultural and scientific literati in at the dawn of the twentieth century. Analysis of the content of her diaries, along with a broad range of additional primary source material, will afford scholars information about important historical resources for the first time.</p>
        </projectDesc>
      </encodingStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1894-11-19" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <placeName ref="#Gibraltar">Gibraltar</placeName>
          <date when="1894-11-19">Nov. 19th. 1894. Monday.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>We arrived this morning &#8211; dropping our anchor about 12 o'-clock &#8211; having sailed from <placeName ref="#New_York">New York</placeName> on the <name type="boat" ref="#Fulda">Fulda</name> at 3 o'clock on the afternoon of the <date when="1894-11-10">10th</date>. For the first time on the <placeName ref="#Atlantic_Ocean">Atlantic</placeName> I was really ill &#8211; and for two days kept to my berth and room &#8211; the voyage seemed endless. We had pleasant weather, but a tremendous following sea &#8211; but the <name type="boat" ref="#Fulda">Fulda</name>proved a very steady sea boat &#8211; she was clean &#8211; the service at table very poor &#8211; and on the last morning as I looked at my berth, I felt, whatever life might have before me, thankful that there was not another night there. The steamer was uncomfortably crowded, with the most unobjectionable lot of passengers I had ever seen. At our little table we had some pleasant <orgName ref="#Westchester_Co">Westchester Co.</orgName> people with whom we made friends. After two or three days out, we discovered the 2d class deck, which was big and unencumbered, except with 3 of the most amusing parrots it has ever been my good fortune to meet. There were no second class passengers &#8211; so we had our chairs carried down there, and lived there the rest of the voyage, quite to ourselves. We came to the <name type="hotel" ref="#Hotel_Royal">Hotel Royal</name> where we stayed with <persName ref="#Wilson_Charlie #Knagenhjelm_Eleanor">Charlie and Nellie Wilson</persName> seven years ago &#8211; and are fairly comfortable. We start tomorrow on a pilgrimage to <placeName ref="#Madrid">Madrid</placeName>, to see its great pictures &#8211; and <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> has asked a young man, a fellow passenger, whom he has talked to a good deal and become interested in, to go with us. We drove out to see some races this afternoon, as we will have one or two days here on our way back, to show <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> the island.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1894-11-26" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <placeName ref="#Madrid">Madrid</placeName>. <placeName ref="#Spain">Spain</placeName>.
          <date when="1894-11-26">Nov. 26.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>We left <placeName ref="#Gibraltar">Gibraltar</placeName> on the morning of the <date when="1894-11-20">20th.</date> at 8 o'clock &#8211; going by boat for half and hour to the <placeName ref="#Spain">Spanish</placeName> frontier &#8211; where we were rather roughly handled in the <orgName ref="Spanish_Custom_House">Custom House</orgName>. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> lost a lot of cigarettes &#8211; and the only thing that saved his boxes of favorite cigars was the word <placeName ref="#Spain">Spain</placeName> branded on the boxes. They dove to the bottom of my trunk and hauled out my case of homeopathic medicines &#8211; and had a solemn pow-wow over it. Then they seized my camera that <persName ref="#Jones_Harold">Jones</persName> was carrying &#8211; insisted on having the case opened, and were too much afraid of taking out the camera themselves. I took it out &#8211; took off the cap and pointed the thing at them &#8211; to their manifest alarm &#8211; for they hurriedly motioned to put it back safely in its case. Then they fell upon a stout little basket I was carrying, filled with my various bottles &#8211; drew all of them out, and came upon a big bottle of glycerine which they turned over and over, and as it looked like something good to drink, I was in hopes they would try it. I would gladly have sacrificed a cherished bottle of glycerine for the pleasure of seeing them choking over it. The <orgName ref="#English">English</orgName> have recently built a fine railway from <placeName ref="#Gibraltar">Gibraltar</placeName> to <placeName ref="#Cordova">Cordova</placeName> connecting with the other <placeName ref="#Spain">Spanish</placeName> lines &#8211; thus releasing <placeName ref="#Gibraltar">Gibraltar</placeName> from her isolated position. We had a comfortable ride to <placeName ref="#Cordova">Cordova</placeName> &#8211; through generally dreary, vast, waste country, except for the olive orchards. We were almost an hour late, and our train from <placeName ref="#Seville">Seville</placeName>, in the wagon lit of which we had 2 compartments engaged, was already in. However we had more than 15 minutes, so our luggage was scuttled into the booking office, where to our consternation we were told that they never booked luggage so late. Nothing would move them, and we stood staring indignantly at our train, until it moved off for <placeName ref="#Madrid">Madrid</placeName>. We said some bad words and commented satirically on the method of running railways in <placeName ref="#Spain">Spain</placeName>, where passengers seem to be incidental factors &#8211; but the officials' feelings did not seem to be wounded, so, making the best of the business, we drove to the Hotel where we stayed day 7 years ago &#8211; and the next morning walked to the <name type="historical" ref="#Mosque_Cathedral_of_Cordoba">Mosque or Cathedral</name>, and then afterwards to the little plaza near for a view of the bridge across the <placeName ref="#Guadalquiver_River">Guadalquiver</placeName>, the foundations of which are <orgName ref="#Roman">Roman</orgName> and the rest <orgName ref="#Moors">Moorish</orgName>. A promising era seems to have set in for the <name type="historical" ref="#Mosque_Cathedral_of_Cordoba">Mosque</name> &#8211; for many of the built up arches are being restored &#8211; the stuff added in later and <orgName ref="#Christian">Christian</orgName> times carted away, and the beautiful <orgName ref="#Moors">Moorish</orgName> arches, ornaments and paintings opened up once more. But I am afraid that the <name type="historical" ref="#Mosque_Cathedral_of_Cordoba">Cathedral</name> itself, which so obstructs and ruins the wonderful perspective effect of the arches, and all the tawdry altars which intrude themselves everywhere will never be done away with. One exquisitely beautiful portion, called the place of the Kalefs has been entirely opened up since we were here last &#8211; and the decorations and colour are quite perfect, and the tiles quite marvelous. We left a 2:30 in the afternoon for <placeName ref="#Madrid">Madrid</placeName> &#8211; <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName>, <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I having what is called a Berlina, where were 3 beds on reclining chairs &#8211; while <persName ref="#Palsley_Mr">Mr. Palsley</persName> and <persName ref="#Jones_Harold">Jones</persName> were in another. We were fairly comfortable &#8211; though the ancient smell that pervaded the cavities from which our coffin-like beds were pulled rather weighed upon my senses. At last, sleeping very soundly, I was awakened by a rush of cold air, and saw <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> sitting up staring at some porters who were jabbering Spanish to us, and we at last perceived that we had arrived at <placeName ref="#Madrid">Madrid</placeName>, so we scuttled into our things as best we could &#8211; and in the cold light of early dawn drove to our hotel, I with boots unbuttoned and no gloves, and our pockets stuffed with soap dishes, tooth brushes etc. After having made our toilets and eaten a hot breakfast, we took ourselves off to the <orgName ref="#Museo_del_Prado">Museo</orgName> &#8211; incomparable as I knew it to be, I never before realized how much so. Aside from the wonderful <persName type="historical" ref="#Velazquez_Diego"><choice><sic>Velasquez</sic><corr>Velazquez</corr></choice></persName>s there are adorable <persName type="historical" ref="#Raphael">Raphael</persName>'s and the most perfect <persName type="historical" ref="#Titian">Titian</persName>s I have ever seen. His <objectName type="painting" ref="#Equestrian_Portrait_of_Charles_V">equestrian portrait of Charles V</objectName> and the <objectName type="painting" ref="#Portrait_of_Charles_V_with_a_dog">standing portrait</objectName> – the <objectName type="painting" ref="#Portrait_of_Philip_II">portrait of the hateful<persName type="historical" ref="Philip_II">Philip II</persName></objectName> – <objectName type="painting" ref="#Adam_and_Eve">Adam and Eve</objectName> – <objectName type="painting" ref="#The_Entombment">Entombment</objectName> – and a host of others. The most adorable little cabinet picture of the <objectName type="painting" ref="#The_Holy_Family_with_a_Lamb">Holy Family</objectName> by <persName type="historical" ref="#Raphael">Raphael</persName> &#8211; 2 delightful portraits of <persName type="historical" ref="#Parmigianino"><choice><sic>Parmigianos</sic><corr>Parmigianino</corr></choice></persName> and <objectName type="painting" ref="#The_Virgin_and_Child_between_Saints_Anthony_of_Padua_and_Roch">Holy Family</name> - a <persName type="historical" ref="#Giorgione">Giorgione</persName>, and one treasure after another &#8211; until it was quite bewildering. We came away at one o'clock quite congealed with cold. The next day, <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and <persName ref="#Lapsley_Mr">Lapsley</persName>, <persName ref="#Jones_Harold">Jones</persName> and a valet de place made an early start for <placeName ref="#Toledo">Toledo</placeName>. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> spent the morning at the gallery, and came home in a maze of delight &#8211; and I not feeling very well sat by the fire and wrote letters. The next day the rest went to the <placeName ref="#El_Escorial">Escorial</placeName> &#8211; <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and I spent 3 hours at the Gallery &#8211; and yesterday being Sunday, we all went to the gallery in the morning. <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I to drive in the afternoon &#8211; the rest to a bull fight! We found the <placeName ref="#Parque_del_Buen_Retiro">royal park</placeName> distinctly depressing &#8211; limited, badly cared for, wretchedly planted &#8211; afterwards we drove to the great park &#8211; but were so cold and tired we could not enjoy anything and came home wondering at the crowds of people in the Park, and in the streets, and if anywhere in the big city of <placeName ref="#Madrid">Madrid</placeName> there could be anybody left in a house. We got off at 6 tonight for <placeName ref="#Seville">Seville</placeName>. <persName ref="#Jones_Harold">Jones</persName> is packing &#8211; and we take our last afternoon at the gallery.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1894-11-29" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <placeName ref="#Granada">Granada</placeName>.
          <date when="1894-11-29">Nov. 29.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>We had a most uncomfortable ride to <placeName ref="#Seville">Seville</placeName> the other night &#8211; arriving about 10 in the morning. Went to the <name type="hotel" ref="#Hotel_Madrid_de_Sevilla">Hotel de Madrid</name>, and were shown to the very rooms we occupied 7 years ago, with <persName ref="#Wilson_Charlie #Knagenhjelm_Eleanor">Charlie and Nellie</persName>. After breakfast went to the <name type="historical" ref="#Seville_Cathedral">Cathedral</name>, where we were not allowed to put our heads in hardly &#8211; as the whole great structure was filled with scaffolding and mighty supports. Soon after we were last there, one of the great central piers toppled over one night &#8211; and the whole edifice on examination was found so unsettled by various earthquakes that a mighty restoration was necessary. In the afternoon a short visit to the almost uninteresting gallery, and to the <name type="historical" ref="#Hospital_de_la_Caridad"><choice><sic>Caradid hospital</sic><corr>Caridad hospital</corr></choice></orgName>, and then to the <name type="historical" ref="#Royal_Alcázars_of_Seville"><choice><sic>Aleazar</sic><corr>Alcázar</corr></choice></name>, and a last peep into the <name type="historical" ref="#Seville_Cathedral">Cathedral</name> in the gloom of the evening, brought us back to the <name type="hotel" ref="#Hotel_Madrid_de_Sevilla">hotel</name> in time for tea &#8211; and we lamented, at least <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and I, that time and money had been wasted in <placeName ref="#Seville">Seville</placeName>. A start the next morning at 10, and a long railway ride to <placeName ref="#Granada">Granada</placeName> which we reached at 8:30 in the evening, very tired and a long ride up to this hotel in the <name type="historical" ref="#Alhambra">Alhambra</placeName> grounds. Today it has rained. I have stayed in doors. The hotel is almost empty &#8211; a stray <orgName ref="#American">American</orgName> or two &#8211; and 2 pleasant <orgName ref="#English">English</orgName> people. The former name <name type="historical" ref="#Biete_Suelos">Biete Suelos</name>, which it carried when we were here before, has been changed into <name type="hotel" ref="#Hotel_de_Roma">Hotel de Roma</placeName> &#8211; it is much the same thing however &#8211; with a little freshening in the way of paint and paper &#8211; but far from luxurious &#8211; the table the best thing about it. Our rooms are small and dark and not cheerful.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1894-12-21" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName>. <name type="hotel" ref="#Shepheards_Hotel">Shepheards Hotel</name>.
          <date when="1894-12-21">Dec. 21st.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>It seems a great stretch of time since I last wrote anything, and the days have been inexpressibly long and tiresome. The cold that I began to take in the chill <placeName ref="#Madrid">Madrid</placeName> gallery grew worse and worse, and I am still in its clutches. We stayed three days at <placeName ref="#Granada">Granada</placeName> &#8211; and it rained more or less all the time &#8211; it was not cold, except in the house and in our dreary little sitting room, overhung by the weeping and dripping trees, with the perpetual sound of a little splashing fountain below, it was too gloomy to be brightened by the tiny stove, that only smoked and never burned &#8211; our bedrooms were very damp. We left for <placeName ref="#Gibraltar">Gibraltar</placeName> on Sunday Dec.	 On the 5 o'clock train, which made it necessary to be called at a quarter to 4, in order to dress, breakfast, and drive the long distance to the station. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and <persName ref="#Lapsley_Mr">Mr. Lapsley</persName> breakfasted down stairs &#8211; but <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I took our wretched little meal of bad coffee, bad eggs and butter in our melancholy sitting room by the light of the lamp. It seemed quite in the middle of the night when we got into the omnibus and there was an air of flight or secret adventure in it. We had some time to wait in the draughty station &#8211; and then <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I had a Berlina to ourselves, in consideration of my ailing throat, and the necessary amount of tobacco smoke <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and <persName ref="#Lapsley_Mr">Mr. Lapsley</persName> had to manufacture. So we smuggled down in our corners, and went promptly to sleep. At 10 o'clock we reached <placeName ref="#Bobadilla">Bobadilla</placeName>, where we breakfasted and changed cars. As the day wore on the wind became very cold and violent &#8211; our speed was anywhere from 8-10 miles an hour. We arrived at <placeName ref="#Algemesi">Algemesi</placeName> after dark in a pouring rain to learn that no boat had been running from <placeName ref="#Gibraltar">Gibraltar</placeName> because of the storm, for 3 days. We were plunged into instant despair, when we were accosted by a pleasant friendly voice in English which explained to us that its owner was the Gen. Sup. of the <orgName ref="#English">English</orgName> R.R. &#8211; and he kindly invited us to his rooms near by until some place could be found for the night. The pleasant sitting room looked most cheerful &#8211; and he gave me a glass of wine and a biscuit &#8211; and we warmed and dried ourselves before getting into the curious little affair on wheels called a carriage &#8211; <persName ref="#Johnson_Mr">Mr. Johnson</persName> too, kindly sent one of his men, speaking both English and Spanish with us. The first hotel to which we went had only 2 rooms to give us. Then we went to another, where we found all the rooms we wanted &#8211; very clean and almost comfortable &#8211; and we were thankful to get a really good dinner, and go to bed. It was kept by an old man, with a large family of sons and daughters, who were the servants of the house. The next morning after breakfast we drove back to the station, uncertain whether the boat would come over from <placeName ref="#Gibraltar">Gib</placeName>. or if we would be obliged to go back for 2 stations on the R.R. and drive for 3 hours to <placeName ref="#Gibraltar">Gib</placeName>. Again <persName ref="#Johnson_Mr">Mr. Johnson</persName> came to our aid, and took us to his rooms, until we heard the boat was coming, where we sat for an hour &#8211; he and <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> talking about building railways &#8211; and he showed us a huge book of photographs that he had taken of the road in its various phases &#8211; and told us of the special difficulties they encountered from <placeName ref="#Gibraltar">Gib</placeName>. to <placeName ref="#Cordova">Cordova<placeName>. Then we went out to the pier which extends some distance &#8211; and found that some of it was quite covered with water &#8211; the waves breaking from time to time over it. Our little steamer lay some distance out, bobbing up and down on the rough water, and there were 2 small boats to take us and our luggage out. So we waded in some places ankle deep in water, and then we plumped into the boat which was dripping with water, and lifting on the waves in a most unpleasant manner. However we finally reached our former rooms in the <name type="hotel" ref="#Hotel_Royal">Royal Hotel</name> in <<placeName ref="#Gibraltar">Gib</placeName>., and <persName ref="#Lapsley_Mr">Mr. Lapsley</persName> said goodbye at once and went off to the Werra in which he was going to <placeName ref="#Genoa">Genoa</placeName>. The rain poured hopelessly all that day, and all the next, while we waited for our P.&O. steamer which was signaled at 4 &#8211; when I was bundled into numerous wraps, with a shawl tied over my head, put into a carriage, and then into a small boat, and finally landed on the deck of the <name type="boat" ref="#Oriental">Oriental</name> more dead than alive &#8211; I at once went to bed and sent for the ship's doctor &#8211; a very kind, dapper little man in his dinner dress, who told me to stay in bed, and gave me some nauseous drugs &#8211; and there I did stay for four days, with many a cockroach to keep me company &#8211; our rooms were very good &#8211; the boat was crowded &#8211; every berth full &#8211; but we all had our rooms to ourselves. We made <placeName ref="#Malta">Malta</placeName> the evening of Friday jut at sunset and stopped some hour to coal &#8211; and arrived at <placeName ref="#Brindisi">Brindisi</placeName> Sunday morning. <orgName ref="#English">English</orgName> mail &#8211; 900 bags arrived at 10pm. But it rained most of the time and I could not be on deck. I was immensely bored by the whole voyage &#8211; Wednesday afternoon we sighted the <placeName ref="#Damietta">Damietta</placeName> light &#8211; and at 5 o'clock cat anchor at <placeName ref="#Port_Said">Port Said</placeName> where we lay until midnight coaling again. What a scene from the <name type="bibl" ref="Divine_Comedy">Inferno</name> it was, those black figures in the glare of the torches! We were all packed and ready to land at <placeName ref="#Ismailia">Ismailia</placeName> early in the morning &#8211; were called at 4:30 &#8211; but it was after 6 before we got off in the tender. Our 3 nice <orgName ref="#English">English</orgName> boys who sat at table with us were up to see us off &#8211; as well as the Doctor and with no regreats I looked my last at the <name type="boat" ref="#Oriental">Oriental</name> as she steamed away to <placeName ref="#Suez">Suez</placeName>. We had breakfat and a drive at <placeName ref="#Ismailia">Ismailia</placeName> and took the train at 1 o'clock arriving here at 5:30. Found <persName ref="#Salah_Mohammed">Mohammed</persName> waiting for us and gladly took possession of our pleasant rooms here. The next morning we drove over on the other ide of the river to inspect several dahabeahs and at last went to our old <name type="boat" ref="#Herodotus_Boat">Herodotus</name> &#8211; which we found in fine order &#8211; she having been entirely scraped and repainted outside and in. Our old <persName ref="#Reis">Reis</persName>, <persName ref="#Fooley">Fooley</persName>,<persName ref="#Hasan">Hasan</persName>, and others of our old crew were on her &#8211; and gave us the heartiest welcome &#8211; and we felt at home there. We looked her carefully over, and decided to make a condition of our taking her that she should have new carpets &#8211; curtains etc. which <persName ref="#Rostovitch_Mr">Rostovitch</persName>'s agent when we saw him acceded to at once &#8211; and we were allowed to choose them &#8211; and <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I met the agent in the afternoon at <orgName ref="#Pasquales">Pasquale's</orgName> a large shop here &#8211; and drove them all out of their wit because of our impossible tastes. Never have I seen anything so hideous in the way of carpets and stuffs. We at last chose not what we liked, but what was least objectionable, and <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> report that they turn out very well. For after leaving <orgName ref="#Pasquales">Pasquale's</orgName> we drove to <persName ref="#Sandwith_Dr">Dr. Sandwith</persName>'s office, who pounded me and stethoscoped me, and said I must go home and stay in the house until I got better. Since then, I have stayed in two rooms, and the week has been long, and I find it difficult to get rid of my cough. Our rooms are at the front of the hotel, and overlook the street and entrance and terrace, so that I can stare at the amusing and ever shifting panorama and I do stand and tare, until I am too tired to look longer. Fortunately our sitting room and my room that opens out of it, have both of them open grates, and we have kept fires burning every day. The weather is not very good &#8211; as <persName ref="#Sandwith_Dr">Dr. Sandwith</persName> says "you must remember this is our rough winter weather". My room is really huge &#8211; with two lofty French windows &#8211; two single lace canopied beds &#8211;with their very necessary mosquito nets, two enormous wardrobes &#8211; equally large bureau, dressing table, washstand, lounge and square table in the middle of the room, even with four trunks in it, it remains spacious.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1894-12-26" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1894-12-26">Wednesday, Dec. 26</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>We came on board the <name type="boat" ref="#Herodotus_Boat">Herodotus</name> on the <date when="1894-12-23">23d Sunday morning</date> &#8211; a strong south wind had been blowing for days &#8211; but everything had been ready for us for some time. I was tired of the hotel and we hope the south wind would soon be discouraged. But on <date when="1894-12-24">Monday</date> it holding as strong as ever, we pulled about <measure type="distance">half a mile</measure> away along the bank &#8211; and the next day <date when="1894-12-25">Xmas</date>, we pulled over to <placeName ref="#Giza">Ghizeh</placeName>, and lay opposite the Museum about in the place we lay for a week on coming down the river last time. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> rode out on donkeys to visit the <orgName ref="#Boulaq_Museum">Museum</orgName>&#8211; but I am still condemned to indoors because this south wind is so strong and so cold. <persName ref="#Bronson_Mrs">Mrs. Bronson</persName> and her <persName ref="#Bronson_Ethel">daughter</persName> came over again to see us and have tea. <persName ref="#Sandwith_Dr">Dr. Sandwith</persName> came to see me the first day on board, and brought two leaves and a fruit of the Pawpaw tree &#8211; from which the Papoid tablets are made, that <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> relies on so entirely. It is an <placeName ref="#India">Indian</placeName> tree, and he says the native claim that if tough meat is wrapped in its leaves, it will become tender, but if left too long, putrid, and that the leaves are used in <placeName ref="#India">India</placeName> for cooking with food to make it digestible. The fruit is not unlike our <placeName ref="#Ohio">Ohio</placeName> Pawpaw tree &#8211; but the leaf entirely unlike. I must look into the matter when I get home. Have been very busy getting settled. The boat looks greatly improved &#8211; and we have such a lot of room. I have taken <persName ref="#Carter_Howard">Howard</persName>'s old room for my dressing room, and <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName>, <persName ref="#Fielding_Mr">Fielding</persName>'s old room for her dressing room &#8211; and the stern room makes a charming sitting room. Our new cook proves a great success. There seems no end to the variety of his things &#8211; and we were amazed the first morning at breakfast to have the most delicious waffles sent in to us. We had a quiet little Xmas &#8211; giving the men the present we had brought for them. Our old Captain gabbles as fast as ever &#8211; most of our old men are with us again &#8211; and being without dragoman we are going to be brought in pleasanter and closer relations to them &#8211; we all like the feeling I think, of being without a boss.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1894-12-30" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1894-12-30">Sunday after Christmas. Dec. 30</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>The south wind has held the whole week &#8211; and I have felt most impatient &#8211; <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and <persName ref="#Jones_Harold">Jones</persName> go into <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> every day &#8211; there is always some last thing to be bought. We left our landing this afternoon and pulled along a little way opposite the town of <placeName ref="#Giza">Ghizeh</placeName> &#8211; why I do not know.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-01-01" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1895-01-01">Tuesday. Jan. 1. 1895</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>The wind came out light from the north yesterday morning, and we got away at last under sail. It grew quite strong during the day, and we sailed through the night until about 6 o'clock this morning &#8211; I heard the men all through the night &#8211; and about one o'clock we stuck on a sand bank &#8211; I then got up lighted a candle, and let it burn itself out, and finally went to sleep. We think we made about <measure type="distance">50 miles</measure>. But this morning there is no wind &#8211; if any, from the south &#8211; however by tracking and polling we made <measure type="distance">one mile</measure> today. I have been up on deck two or three times &#8211; finding the sun and air delicious &#8211; we have 3 big basket hooded chairs, all lined and trimmed &#8211; that proved to be delightful things and serve equally well as a protection against sun and wind.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-01-02" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1895-01-02">Wednesday. Jan. 2.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>Tracked and polled against the wind until we reached <placeName ref="#Al-Wasta">Wasta</placeName> &#8211; <measure type="distance">56 miles</measure> from <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> The <name type="historical" ref="#Meidum_Pyramid">pyramid of Meydoum</name> has been before us for 2 days - quite splendid &#8211; made <measure type="distance">4 to 5 miles</measure>.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-01-04" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1895-01-04">Friday. Jan. 4.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>We have tracked and pulled to an anchor, and polled for 2 days, and have had our sail out at times, and have thus made about <measure type="distance">10 miles</measure> in 2 days &#8211; cold and not quite clear. Have only been on deck a few moments today. The night are now so perfect with the young moon, and these magnificent heavens &#8211; the stars so near and big and bright &#8211; it is entrancing &#8211; we pulled up at a wide low sand bank for the night &#8211; and it was really a hardship to have to stay indoors when there was such a mystical beauty and loveliness without.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-01-05" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1895-01-05">Saturday. Jan. 5.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p><persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I have just had a discussion as to whether this was or was not Saturday. It gives on such a strange, lost feeling to be uncertain as to the days, with no immediate authority to appeal to. We have had rather a cold day &#8211; with fitful winds &#8211; we have done a good deal of slow sailing - have passed <placeName ref="#Benisoef">Benisoef</placeName> - and are now at 9:30pm within a short distance of <placeName ref="#Al_Hibah">Hibeh</placeName> &#8211; we may have made about <measure type="distance">10 miles</measure>. In the midst of a good turn of wind, we had to pull up at <placeName ref="#Benisoef">Benisoef</placeName>, for a sailor who had been despatched early this morning to that town to buy some fruit and vegetables. It was rather vexatious &#8211; our nice big <persName ref="#Moussa">Moussa</persName> set off at once across the fields to look for the man and hurry him. <persName ref="#Jones_Harold">Jones</persName> took his gun and disappeared. Then <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I walked up and down the hard sand inhaling the delicious air, and staring across the fields to see <placeName ref="#Benisoef">Benisoef</placeName> lying back some distance on a canal amongst its palms &#8211; a large, important town &#8211; then the sailor appeared with is well laden basket on his head; and as the wind blew strongly, a sailor was sent off in haste to look for <persName ref="#Jones_Harold">Jones</persName> &#8211; <persName ref="#Hasan">Hasan</persName> to find <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> &#8211; and <persName ref="#Salah_Mohammed">Mohammed</persName> flew towards the town to find <persName ref="#Moussa">Moussa</persName> &#8211; and at last they all were hauled in and were off. The night is magically lovely.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-01-06" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1895-01-06">Sunday. Epiphany. Jan. 6.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>Had about half an hour of good wind early this morning &#8211; then a dead calm for the rest of the day &#8211; the water reflecting everything like a mirror. The men tracked and made about <measure type="distance">2 miles</measure> &#8211; then at one we tied up &#8211; where we will stay all night.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-01-07" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1895-01-07">Monday. Jan 7.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>A dead calm with the exception of a few moments of fair wind this morning &#8211; made <measure type="distance">4 miles</measure> by tracking &#8211; and are now lying at <placeName ref="#Al_Fashn">Fashen</placeName>. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> walked into the town and posted some letters.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-01-08" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1895-01-08">Tuesday. Jan. 8.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>Occasional light winds and with polling and tracking made about <measure type="distance">12 miles</measure>. Passed <placeName ref="#Maghaghah">Maghagah</placeName>.<p> 
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-01-09" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1895-01-09">Wednesday. Jan. 9.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>Good head wind until 11 o'clock am - the middle of the day very still and hot &#8211; light wind later &#8211; sailed until 8pm and made <measure type="distance">18 miles</measure>. <name type="boat" ref="#Stella">Stella</name> near us for 4 days.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-01-10" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1895-01-10">Thursday. Jan. 10.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>It was very hot and calm this morning- under a light south wind we have made in the afternoon <measure type="distance">2 miles</measure> &#8211; about 6 we tied up for the night, both awnings were spread &#8211; and every one settled down to stay for the night &#8211; but about 9, as <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and I had finished our game of cribbage, a strong north wind began. The Captain waited awhile to see if it had come to stay &#8211; then the awnings went down, and the stake came up, and we have been bounding along ever since &#8211; I do not think it will be a good night to sleep.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-01-11" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1895-01-11">Friday. Jan. 11.</date>
        </dateline> 
        <p>It wasn't a good night to sleep &#8211; what with the shifting of the sails, the orders &#8211; the running backwards and forwards on the deck above me, it was quite impossible &#8211; at 1 o'clock, I got up, lighted my candle and prowled into the saloon, and found some biscuit and a glass of port wine. We reached <placeName ref="#Al_Minya">Minyeh</placeName> at 2 o'clock. On our first journey up the <placeName ref="#Nile">Nile</placeName> we reached <placeName ref="#Al_Minya">Minyeh</placeName> the 2d day &#8211; on our last the 7th day. We were obliged to stop as we had ordered our mail sent there, and some fresh butter from the Swiss Dairy at <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName>. <persName ref="#Jones_Harold">Jones</persName> went off with old <persName ref="#Moussa">Moussa</persName> to the town, coming back with a big parcel of letters and papers. Then we got under way, and have been sailing ever since &#8211; though <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> has given orders that we shall stop at 10 o'clock. We have passed <placeName ref="#Ar_Rawḍah"><choice><sic>Beni Hassan, Rodah</sic><corr>Rodah</corr></choice></placeName>, where we pulled up on the opposite side, and sent the felucca across to the town to get the ironing man for whom <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> had written to <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> for. They found him waiting, with the lot of fresh butter, which did not turn up at <placeName ref="#Al_Minya">Minyeh</placeName> this morning. He is a very likely looking fellow &#8211; and his name is <persName ref="#Ibraim">Ibraim</persName> &#8211; we are so glad to have a new name. There are already so many Mohammeds and Hasans! While the rest were away at <placeName ref="#Ar_Rawḍah">Rodah</placeName>, I sat down on the lower deck out of the wind for a few minutes &#8211; not having been out before &#8211; we had tied up unceremoniously at a poor fellahs garden &#8211; where onions, cucumbers and tomatoes were growing, carefully tended &#8211; he was a good looking fellow, who came forward in his long black robe, to protect his property as well as he could &#8211; we bought some tomatoes of him &#8211; and gave him a little money to pay for any damage we might have caused. They never protest against the <orgName ref="#Howadji">"Howadji"</orgName> in a dahabeah &#8211; and indeed the greatest damage is done by the troops of people who as soon as they see a dahabeah approach the land, leave all, and come to stare.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-01-12" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1895-01-12">Saturday. Jan. 12.</date>
        </dateline>   
        <p>We have made <measure type="distance">2 or 3 miles</measure> &#8211; the day has been warm and still. On deck from 11 o'clock until 5 &#8211; such fragrant delicious air and such effects. The moon is so full &#8211; and the nights lately have had a wonderful beauty.</p> 
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-01-13" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1895-01-13">Jan. 13th. Sunday &#8211; first after Epiphany.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>A fair wind most of the day brought us about 8 o'clock this evening within <measure type="distance">2 miles</measure> of <placeName ref="#Manfalût">Manfalout</placeName> and we have calculated that we have made about <measure type="distance">24 1/2 miles</measure> today. I have been on deck since 11 o'clock &#8211; that is until 5 o'clock &#8211; at which I came below &#8211; before the first chill of the evening comes. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> stay above until it is time to dress for dinner. It is a real hardship to leave such beauty abroad &#8211; and this evening it was specially tantalizing &#8211; for the scene was as interesting. We came to the great <placeName ref="#Abu_Fudah_Jabal">Gebel Aboufeydah</placeName> chain early in the day. It is the most difficult part of the river, and the most dangerous for the great cliffs come sheer down to the water, and the currents are strong, and the wind shifting. Just opposite the beginning of these cliffs, there is a long, low island dividing the river &#8211; the channel next to the rocks is shorter &#8211; but the other channel is the longer and safer. The <name type="boat" ref="#Stella">Stella</name> which has again caught up with us, chose the latter and our <persName ref="#Reis">Reis</persName> the former. I had to come down during the most interesting time &#8211; and there was a great row on deck afterwards &#8211; the sails constantly shifted &#8211; the shouting of orders &#8211; the running and jumping about of the sailors. One would have thought again and again that we were going to instant destruction. The <name type="boat" ref="#Stella">Stella</name> came out best &#8211; as she did not feel in her channel the fluctuations of the wind as we did. We have however passed ahead of her a little way, and are both anchored in the broad stream, where it bends straight away from the cliffs towards <placeName ref="#Manfalût">Manfalout</placeName> These cliffs, so <persName ref="#Chester_Mr">Mr. Chester</persName>, an <orgName ref="#English">Englishman</orgName> who had been coming for 20 years to <placeName ref="#Egypt">Egypt</placeName> for his winters told me on our first voyage up, used to be the home of millions of birds &#8211; which were so tame that you could row along them and almost put your hand upon them in their nests &#8211; but that they were rapidly being driven away by the tourists and their guns. And I remember that on the first voyage <persName ref="#Salah_Mohammed">Mohammed</persName> fired his gun, quite to my displeasure, into the air to test the echo, and frighten the birds and all up the great face of the cliffs, from countless holes and caves, they came out screaming, big and little. Yesterday, on the contrary, although we were so long getting past them, we only counted six birds! The <name type="boat" ref="#Stella">Stella</name> has 2 men on her, whose great pleasure consists in popping their guns at every thing &#8211; and I am daily so annoyed at the hateful creatures, murdering the delicious peace of the river, and trying to kill the few characteristic and interesting birds, that still have the courage to live on the <placeName ref="#Nile">Nile</placeName> &#8211; that highway of tourists.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-01-14" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1895-01-14">Monday. Jan. 14.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>We are now lying at <placeName ref="#Asyut">Assiout</placeName> having made <measure type="distance">28 miles</measure>. I was on deck much of the day. Sometime before noon, we saw as usual the minaret of <placeName ref="#Asyut">Assiout</placeName> &#8211; but as usual were a long time reaching the town &#8211; the river makes such great bends below &#8211; that the distance is deluding. The wind grew very strong in the afternoon &#8211; too strong to make one of the great turns and we touched at the bank to let <persName ref="#Jones_Harold">Jones</persName> and <persName ref="#Ibraim">Ibraim</persName> go into the town for the mail and some necessary things. Our people all said the town was near &#8211; but poor <persName ref="#Jones_Harold">Jones</persName> found he had a walk of <measure type="distance">6 miles</measure> or more before getting into <placeName ref="#Asyut">Assiout</placeName>. In the meantime we tracked and sailed and after dark, pulled up opposite the light of the town, and sent our felucca over for the man &#8211; and now we are deluged with papers &#8211; <orgName ref="#American">American</orgName> and <orgName ref="#English">English</orgName> &#8211; and we feel as if we must go through with them all.</p> 
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-01-15" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1895-01-15">Tuesday. Jan. 15.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>We started out betimes this morning sailing &#8211; it must have been soon after 7 &#8211; and have been rattling along in fair style &#8211; past lovely shores of splendid palms and the most luxuriant scent trees with their soft rounded outlines &#8211; the air has been fragrant with the blossoming crops &#8211; fefl and gulhan. But the wind has been too strong for me to be out &#8211; just after tea I wrapped myself in my big cloak, and went on deck and stayed about 10 minutes in the hooded chair &#8211; it was too tantalizing to have to come down. But downstairs is not half a bad place &#8211; with the shifting scenes on either shore &#8211; the sunny windows &#8211; all the space to myself &#8211; for <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> are always on deck &#8211; and I have dozens of pleasant things to do &#8211; we are still (10 P.M.) sailing &#8211; and <persName ref="#Jones_Harold">Jones</persName> has just been in reporting that we are within <measure type="distance">4 or 5 miles</measure> of <placeName ref="#Tahta">Tahtah</placeName>.</p>
      </div>
      <!--[1//4]-->
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-01-16" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1895-01-16">Jan. 16. Wednesday.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>We pulled up to <placeName ref="#Jirjā">Girgeh</placeName> this evening about 7 o'clock &#8211; after an uninterrupted sail from <placeName ref="#Asyut"><choice><sic>Asiout</sic><corr>Assiout</corr></choice></placeName> yesterday morning. All night long we bowled along steadily &#8211; and I dreamily wondered as I have wakened through the night, how weary the <persName ref="#Rais_Mahommed">Reis</persName> and all the crew must be. The wind, grew very rough toward morning, and about 5:30 we went bang upon a and bank with a great thump &#8211; and I did not sleep again &#8211; though we soon got off the sand, and careered along on our triumphant course. We passed <placeName ref="#Sohag">Sohag</placeName> at 9:30 &#8211; and <placeName ref="#Akhmīm">Akmim</placeName> half an hour after &#8211; where we saw <persName ref="#Cook_Thomas">Cook</persName>'s big dahabeah the <name type="boat" ref="#Hathor_boat">"Hathor"</name> lying with her tug &#8211; she having passed us while we were lying at <placeName ref="#Giza">Ghizeh</placeName>. The paper reported that "<persName ref="#Amherst_of_Hackney_Lord #Amherst_of_Hackney_Lady">Lord and Lady Amherst de Hackney</persName> and their four daughters" &#8211; that they had taken this dahabeah and tug for 3 months and a camping equipage &#8211; and that they would make many excursions. They started soon after we passed them &#8211; but they could not catch us in the wind we had &#8211; we sailed a long distance close to the perpendicular cliffs, which come down quite to the water &#8211; and the setting sun made a wonderful rose color of the limestone &#8211; and shadows wonderfully blue. We have been going through much lovely country &#8211; palms &#8211; dom palms &#8211; scents and sycamores in richest profusion &#8211; and the country highly cultivated &#8211; it is one of the very richest provinces of <placeName ref="#Egypt">Egypt</placeName>. I have had to be down stairs all day, because of the wind.</p> 
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-01-17" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <placeName ref="#Jirjā">Girgeh</placeName>.
          <date when="1895-01-17">Jan. 17. Thursday</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>We have been lying here all day at the big low sand bank where we lay two years ago, opposite the town. We are here to have the sailors' bread baked &#8211; some people will not stop here &#8211; it is a dirty, uninteresting town &#8211; but the captains all prefer it to <placeName ref="#Balyana_Al">Balliana</placeName> or <placeName ref="#Akhmīm">Akmim</placeName>, where are most interesting things to do. But our <persName ref="#Rais_Mahommed">Reis</persName> lives here &#8211; and we have not the hard heart that can insist upon his stopping elsewhere, <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> have been twice over to the town to walk &#8211; but I have stayed at home &#8211; for a cold wind has been blowing from the north &#8211; a fine sailing wind &#8211; and even the deck enclosed with canvas was cold. All our fowls &#8211; the whole barnyard has been turned out on the sand &#8211; chickens &#8211; doves &#8211; geese &#8211; turkeys &#8211; ducks &#8211; rabbits and 3 little brown woolly sheep, that were bought today &#8211; and a big washing has been going on &#8211; and our fluttering clothes make a great show on their lines. Everybody very nearly deserted the boat today &#8211; and it was very quiet. My nice <persName>Mohammed</persName> <!--who is this?--> who always went everywhere with me last year, and who is a brother in law of our <persName ref="#Rais_Mahommed">Reis</persName> &#8211; heard on reaching here last night that his father died ten days ago &#8211; and there has been a great sorrow amongst them. We are interested in our daily readings in <bibl><author ref="#Kidd_Benjamin">Kidd</author><choice><sic>s</sic><corr>'s</corr></choice><title>Social Evolution</title></bibl>. For the first time a few nights ago, we saw the Zodiacal light &#8211; and since then it has been seen several times &#8211; we were a little nebulous about the affair &#8211; and got out our Astronomy <!--need tag?--> &#8211; and read about the little that is known of it.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-01-18" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1895-01-18">Friday. Jan. 18th.</date>
        </dateline> 
        <p>We left <placeName ref="#Jirjā">Girgeh</placeName> about 12 o'clock &#8211; having taken on a great stock of bread &#8211; enough to last until we reach <placeName ref="#Jirjā">Girgeh</placeName> again, the <persName ref="#Rais_Mahommed">Reis</persName> says &#8211; made <placeName ref="#Balyana_Al">Balliana</placeName> about 7 o'clock &#8211; and the wind having been very light all day &#8211; two dahabeahs &#8211; the <name type="boat" ref="#Mimi">"Mimi"</name> <!--tag?--> English &#8211; and the <name type="boat" ref="#Columbia">"Columbia"</name> with the <orgName ref="#American">American</orgName> flag. The former is a new private dahabeah, belonging to an Englishman, very attractive in appearance &#8211; and what arouses my interest in her is that she has a stove pipe! And I wonder whether they have a stove arranged or an open fire. This boat, and the very pretty new one belonging to a <orgName ref="#Polish">Pole</orgName>, which lay next us at <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> &#8211; have aroused <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName>'s ardor about building one. He always talks of building one going up the <placeName ref="#Nile">Nile</placeName> &#8211; but coming down, there is very little said about it. This afternoon just as we had landed the men for tracking, I saw them looking at something in the water floating by us, and <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I took up our glasses to see what it was &#8211; and to our horror discovered it was the body of a woman. It was a dreadfully gruesome spectacle!</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-01-19" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1895-01-19">Saturday. Jan. 19th.</date>
        </dateline> 
        <p>Got away from <placeName ref="#Balyana_Al">Balliana</placeName> early &#8211; deciding that as the day was so hot, we would not attempt the long ride out to <placeName ref="#Abydos">Abydos</placeName>. <name type="boat" ref="#Columbia">Columbia</name> near us all day. Stayed on deck most of the time. Are lying about half way between <placeName ref="#Balyana_Al">Balliana</placeName> and <placeName ref="#Farshūţ">Farshoot</placeName>, having made <measure type="distance">8-10 miles</measure>.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-01-20" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1895-01-20">2nd Sunday after Epiphany. Jan. 20.</date>
        </dateline> 
        <p>We are lying tonight at <placeName ref="#Dishna">Dishneh</placeName>, where we pulled up for the night in a strong and fitful wind &#8211; having made about <measure type="distance">29 miles</measure>. Have passed <placeName ref="#Farshūţ">Farshoot</placeName> &#8211; <placeName ref="#Hiw">Hou</placeName> &#8211; and <placeName ref="#Al_Qasr_wa_as_Sayyad">Kar el-Sayd</placeName>. The river makes great bends between <placeName ref="#Jirjā">Girgeh</placeName> and <placeName ref="#Keneh">Keneh</placeName> &#8211; and its direction is almost directly E and W. This morning instead of having the sun in my room while I was dressing as I always have &#8211; I found that apparently it was rising in the west, and I was left in the cold. At 7:30 <persName ref="#Jones_Harold">Jones</persName> always brings the lighted lamp into my room, and puts it on the floor &#8211; in a little while he brings me a fragrant cup of tea &#8211; then the hot water comes along- then the outside shutters are opened &#8211; the sun pours in &#8211; and I am ready to get up! I intended to have done a great deal of writing today &#8211; but it was so charming on deck, I could not come below &#8211; such fragrant air, full of the perfume of the blossoming crops &#8211; such lights, such shadows on the utterly desert mountains &#8211; such splendid palms and groves of scent trees &#8211; lubbeks &#8211; tamarasks &#8211; the song of the shadoof is abroad in the land &#8211; and today we have passed several musically creaking sakkiehs. At one time very near us on a low sand bank, were 10 large pelicans &#8211; the biggest I had ever seen &#8211; they waited until we were quite up to them, then spread their wings, and sailed away on the water. Fortunately <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and <persName ref="#Jones_Harold">Jones</persName> were both below, or the gun would have been out. The <name type="boat" ref="#Mimi">Mimi</name> has been ahead of us all day &#8211; but this afternoon we came up to her hopelessly stuck upon a sand bank &#8211; and there we left her. But she can much outsail us.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-01-21" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1895-01-21">Monday. Jan. 21.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>Started out this morning at 7:30 with a good wind &#8211; which held until about 11 &#8211; when it failed so much that as we drew near <placeName ref="#Keneh">Keneh</placeName>, we debated whether or not we would go ashore and find our antiquity dealer of whom <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> bought two or three very good things last year. But we decided not to stop &#8211; and the wind increasing we made the turn below <placeName ref="#Keneh">Keneh</placeName> in fine style, the river her turning quite sharply to the South once more. We careered along in a beautiful manner &#8211; the wind so high as to make the sailing exciting &#8211; and almost dangerous. I stayed below. We passed <placeName ref="#Coptos">Coptos</placeName> &#8211; then <placeName ref="#Qūṣ">Kus</placeName> &#8211; and about 5 <placeName ref="#Naqadah">Nagada</placeName> &#8211; and are now about <measure type="distance">6 miles</measure> from <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName>.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-01-31" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1895-01-31">Tuesday. Jan. 31.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>A very quiet and uneventful week at <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName>. I tried to ride over to <placeName ref="#Karnak">Karnak</placeName> the first afternoon &#8211; and spent the morning of the 2d day in <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName>, principally at <persName ref="#Mohassib_Mohammed"><choice><sic>Mohammed Mohasib</sic><corr>Mohammed Mohassib</corr></choice></persName>'s &#8211; and in the afternoon went over to the races &#8211; and between them all, grew so tired and added so much to my cold &#8211; that I have stayed on the boat every day since &#8211; except <date when="1895-01-29">Sunday</date> &#8211; when <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I went over to the little <orgName ref="#English">English</orgName> chapel <!--tag chapel?--> for service. We found 4 dahabeahs at <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName> &#8211; and they were arriving from down the river during the week. I believe we left 11 lying there. Two days before we came away, we pulled across the river to below the <name type="historical" ref="#German_Castle">German's new castle</name> <!--needs different name?-->. There has been no wind for days &#8211; we intended getting away <date when="1895-01-30">yesterday</date> &#8211; but there was not a breath &#8211; so when after breakfast this morning a fair little wind sprang up, <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> gave orders to start, but it soon failed &#8211; and we had to take to tracking. We had all our awnings up &#8211; and it was entirely charming on deck &#8211; so quiet &#8211; the whole earth wrapped in a white soft shroud of intense heat. We have had quite an unpleasant and very exciting experience this afternoon. The men were tracking and we were slowly slipping past a high bank near the village of <placeName ref="#Ad_Dabiyah">ed-Debayeh</placeName> about 2 miles from <placeName ref="#Armant">Erment</placeName>. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> was absorbed in a chess puzzle in the saloon &#8211; and I had got into my wrapper and was preparing for a good rest &#8211; when I heard loud voices and talking above &#8211; and so much stir that <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> called up to <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> who is always on deck to know what the trouble was &#8211; but he did not wait for an answer but seized a stout stick, called out to me as he passed my room that there was trouble on shore, and he was going to see what it was. Then <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> called to me to come quickly &#8211; and I hustled into my dress and rushed up on deck, just in time to see <persName ref="#Jones_Daniel">Jones</persName> disappearing over the high bank with his gun, and two of our sailors armed with poles, assisting our old <persName ref="#Abbecatto"><choice><sic>Abbocatto</sic><corr>Abbecatto</corr></choice></persName> over the bank in a most unceremonious fashion. The bank was too high and steep for <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and me to climb, even with assistance &#8211; besides there was no one left on the boat but the 2 cooks &#8211; nor could we see over the bank &#8211; but we heard a tremendous hubbub, shrieking and shouting and two report of the gun &#8211; and then I feared serious trouble. Then arrived my <persName ref="#Rais_Mahommed">Mahommed</persName> and <persName ref="#Ali">Ali</persName>, with a man in custody, whom they were kicking and beating furiously, and whom they flung over the bank &#8211; he came headlong &#8211; and <persName ref="#Ali">Ali</persName> slid down after him and resumed his infuriated beating of him &#8211; my calling and cries were not heeded, and as <persName ref="#Hassan"><choice><sic>Hasan</sic><corr>Hassan</corr></choice></persName> appeared at the top with another man, whom he knocked over the bank and plunged after, beating him unmercifully, I flew down the companionway to <persName ref="#Selim">Selim</persName>, the cook, and told him to tell <persName ref="#Hassan">Hassan</persName> and <persName ref="#Ali">Ali</persName>, that I would not suffer such conduct &#8211; that if the men were guilty the sheik of the village would punish them, but they should not beat them. Then the men were brought on board as prisoners, and I told <persName ref="#Selim">Selim</persName> to protect them from violence until we knew what the trouble was. A moment after the uproar grew nearer, and swarming over the bank came our people, followed by a crowd of women and children, but no men. These women began shrieking more wildly than ever when they saw our two prisoners &#8211; they threw dust over their heads, and danced about like wild savages. Order was given to cast off at once, and a favorable breeze having sprung up, we were able to get out of that troublesome neighborhood. They all followed along the bank, making all the noise they could and they must have sent some of their people on <measure type="distance">two <choice><sic>mile</sic><corr>miles</corr></choice></measure> to a landing near <placeName ref="#Armant">Erment</placeName>, as when we drew up there, we found two gens d'armes waiting for us. In the meantime when our men came back to the boat, it was found that the Captain <!--tag?--> had a cruel cut on his head, which was bleeding profusely, and <persName ref="#Moussa">Moussa</persName> looked as if he had been nearly slaughtered &#8211; he head cut open in two places, looking very bad. <persName ref="#Ibraim">Ibraim</persName> also had a bad cut on his arm. They were all in a perfect rage &#8211; and it was all that <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and I and <persName ref="#Jones_Daniel">Jones</persName> could do, to keep them quiet enough to wash and dress their wound. When we had landed and the officers had come on board we had a solemn hearing, except when the excitement of the old <persName ref="#Rais_Mahommed">Reis</persName> broke out. A huge audience on the bank &#8211; the broken heads were exhibited, and a man came on the lower deck from the crowd, to show a broken head of his own. Our dignified <persName ref="#Selim">Selim</persName> was summoned from his kitchen, and acted as interpreter and then <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> called for our second captain &#8211; our favorite <persName ref="#Fuli_Rais">Reis Fuli</persName> to give his account &#8211; which he did in so calm, and perfect a manner, that it was a sight to see, in that crowd of angry savages. <persName ref="#Rais_Mahommed">Reis Mohammed</persName> wanted to go back to <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName>, as the officers suggested, to enter his complain &#8211; but <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> announced very decidedly that he had already had trouble and detention enough &#8211; and that he would wait no longer. I must say the manner of the officers was excellent &#8211; until they took possession of the prisoners &#8211; whom they hustled about in a very undignified way, but not severe &#8211; their turbans being torn from their heads, and unwound and used as fetters. One of them was quite an old man with a long wound or gash in his leg. I felt tempted to tell <persName ref="#Jones_Daniel">Jones</persName> to go and dress it &#8211; but I'm afraid our crew would almost have mobbed him &#8211; that being an act of grace to an enemy, far from their comprehension. Finally we got away, and let it all behind us &#8211; and then we began to hear the different incidents of the affair = the only one being that <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> told of our old, and almost decrepid <persName ref="#Abbecatto">Abbecatto</persName> &#8211; a painfully timid man, in all his daily manifestations, who had hurried to the scene of conflict with the hatchet in his hand &#8211; which <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> saw him using (the hammer side) on the back of one of the prisoners, as he was being led to the boat by our men. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> unceremoniously took the hatchet from him, and ordered him back to the boat, feeling that if the old man stopped and thought, he might use the other end of it. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> says that when he reached the village, the <persName ref="#Rais_Mahommed">Reis</persName> and <persName ref="#Moussa">Moussa</persName> were standing bleeding but surrounded by the sellers, and at some distance from them, the village people were facing them. <persName ref="#Moussa">Moussa</persName> had gone to help the <persName ref="#Rais_Mahommed">Reis</persName>, who had been worsted in a struggle with some of them &#8211; <persName ref="#Jones_Daniel">Jones</persName> and his gun, which he fired occasionally into the air, held the village people at bay, or no doubt our men would have fared badly. Everyone was so excited at first, and so concerned to see our men wounded, that they could not take a dispassionate view of it &#8211; and both <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> thought me severe, when I said from the first that I thought we were to blame. Our coleric old <persName ref="#Rais_Mahommed">Reis</persName>, instead of entering a complaint with the <persName>Sheik</persName> of the village, got into a temper with some of the people &#8211; and no one knows who struck the first blow, the mischievous children and boys who threw the mud, of course fell as it so often does in this world, on the innocent. The two <choice><sic>prisoner</sic><corr>prisoners</corr></choice>, maltreated as they were, were not offenders so far as we could learn. It was very comical to reflect, that every able bodied man, headed by the <persName ref="#Rais_Mahommed">Reis</persName>, made off to the fray, leaving the beat, and we two unprotected women to the care of the 2 cooks! It hardly answers to our idea of discipline on a ship! We came to <placeName ref="#Armant">Erment</placeName> and will stay all night &#8211; making <measure type="distance">9 miles</measure>.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-02-01" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1895-02-01">Friday. Feb. 1st.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>We have had a very good day &#8211; making <measure type="distance">40 miles</measure> &#8211; passed <placeName ref="#Esneh">Esneh</placeName> about 5 o'clock. The <name type="boat" ref="#Columbia">Columbia</name> which has been quite in advance of us from <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName>, landed at <placeName ref="#Esneh">Esneh</placeName>, and the <name type="boat" ref="#Mansourah">Mansourah</name>, which passed us yesterday during the fracas, still holds her own, ahead of us. We met her people in the garden at <placeName ref="#Armant">Erment</placeName>, where everybody goes to buy fruit and vegetables. We are lying <measure type="distance">2 or 3 miles</measure> from <placeName ref="#El_Kab">El Kab</placeName> this evening.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-02-02" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1895-02-02"> Saturday. Feb. 2d.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>A splendid run of today &#8211; <measure type="distance">60 miles</measure> &#8211; steady, fine sailing all the time. <choice><sic>Pased</sic><corr>Passed</corr></choice> <placeName ref="#El_Kab">El Kab</placeName> &#8211; <placeName ref="#Idfu">Edfou</placeName> &#8211; <placeName ref="#Silsilis">Silsilis</placeName> just at sunset &#8211; so that we were able to see the grottos as we sailed by &#8211; such an interesting point of the river &#8211; the rocks coming down to the narrowed river &#8211; the either side. We have been steadily gaining on the <name type="boat" ref="#Mansourah">Mansourah</name> all day &#8211; until the race became very exciting as we draw near <placeName ref="#Kawm_Umbū">Kom Ombo</placeName> &#8211; by a clever move, our old <persName ref="#Rais_Mahommed">Reis</persName> cleverly took advantage of a manouvre on their part, and passed them, and soon we lost sight of them in the night. The moon is now radiant. We have passed <placeName ref="#Kawm_Umbū">Kom Ombo</persName>, and are lying about <measure type="distance">3 miles</measure> above.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-02-03" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1895-02-03">Sunday. Feb. 3.</date>
          <placeName ref="#Aswan">Assouan</placeName>.
        </dateline>
        <p>We dragged through the whole day, arriving at <placeName ref="#Aswan">Assouan</placeName> when it was almost too dark to see that beautiful approach, a number of dahabeahs here &#8211; we are a little in advance of our former position at <placeName ref="#Elephantine">Elephantine</placeName>. The <name type="boat" ref="#Isis">Isis</name> is just opposite &#8211; and <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> have gone over to her, to see if her people are going up in their steamer to <placeName ref="#Halfa">Wady Halfa</placeName>, as they expected to do tomorrow, when we saw them last. Such a radiant night.</p> 
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-02-10" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1895-02-10">Sunday-Septuagesima. Feb. 10th.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>We have had a very hot, unsatisfactory week. The thermometer has ranged from 80-86 in the shade. At one time the dahabeahs numbered 12 &#8211; of which I am glad to say we were always first or second &#8211; but the little sand beach along the island of <placeName ref="#Elephantine">Elephantine</placeName> is very small &#8211; and grew to be very smelly. Now that so many dahabeahs go up the river this landing place should be under police supervision. There were so many steamers too, on the <placeName ref="#Aswan"><choice><sic>Asouan</sic><corr>Assouan</corr></choice></placeName> side, and the river is so narrow here, that they seem very intrusive &#8211; and the new <orgName>Cook</orgName> boats are so big and noisy &#8211; with their brilliant electric lights &#8211; they are a positive offence &#8211; and the cataract boats are now so many &#8211; and their crews so noisy &#8211; there was no peace &#8211; they were rowing up and down, until 12 o'clock at night &#8211; singing, and hip-hip hurrahing &#8211; with their "tink you tink yous" and "very good, very goods". I grew pretty tired of them &#8211; I went once out to <placeName ref="#Philae">Philae</placeName> &#8211; having an extra train all to myself &#8211; costing but $10. <persName ref="#Jones_Daniel">Jones</persName>, <persName>Mohammed</persName> and <persName ref="#Ibraim">Ibraim</persName>, <!--tag here!--> and the lunch went with me, and <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> went over early on donkeys. It was almost one o'clock before I got there &#8211; I found it crowded with tourists. <name type="historical" ref="#Trajans_Kiosk">Pharaoh's Bed</name> <!--how to tag with apostrophe?--> was filled with tables and all the <orgName ref="#Cookites">Cookites</orgName> lunching at them. So we had ours far off in one of the colonnades &#8211; almost exactly in the pot from which <persName ref="#Newman_Mr">Mr. Newman</persName>'s picture that <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> has was painted. As we were making our way over there, I saw little <persName ref="#Yemma"><choice><sic>Yema</sic><corr>Yemma</corr></choice></persName> coming and I said to <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName>, "don't <choice><sic>ay</sic><corr>say</corr></choice> anything, I want to see if he knows me". He looked at me a moment, and then threw out both hands with an exclamation that was quite tragic, and with a cry of joy rushed forward to see me. Very little grown &#8211; the same sweet, appealing little fellow &#8211; he stuck closely by me all the time. Then we asked for <persName ref="#Dendowi">"Dendowi"</persName> and he was shortly produced &#8211; looking more like a small, brown reproduction of <placeName>Queen Victoria</placeName> than ever &#8211; and with the same imperturbable dignity &#8211; <placeName ref="#Philae">Philae</placeName> seemed more lovely to me and interesting than ever &#8211; I suppose because its doom seems to have been pronounced. We could see on the walls of <placeName ref="#Trajans_Kiosk">Pharaoh's Bed</placeName> &#8211; coloured wafers at a certain level &#8211; showing where the inundation water would reach, if the dam is built. I did not see the <persName ref="#Newman_Mr #Newman_Mrs"><choice><sic>Newman</sic><corr>Newmans</corr></choice></persName> &#8211; as I did not feel equal to climbing down to their dahabeah &#8211; and I wanted so much to talk to her about <persName ref="#Yemma">Yemma</persName> &#8211; <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> saw them for a few moments in the temple &#8211; but with many people about them &#8211; <persName ref="#Yemma">Yemma</persName> told me <persName ref="#Newman_Mrs">Mrs. Newman</persName> had given him everything he had on &#8211; and proceeded to show me each article &#8211; first beginning with his turban, which we had already remarked, as being very large and impressive. This he took off his head and unwound, showing a pair of drawers, which he put on, after discreetly turning his back. We came home in one of the Cataract boats &#8211; the crew particularly picturesque with their turbans and flashing white teeth. The descent of the cataract too, seemed more exciting than ever. We passed the little island, against whose black rocks we came to grief, when we tried to get up the cataract last year with the <name type="boat" ref="#Herodotus_Boat">Herodotus</name>. And we have felt much aggrieved to see a dahabeah coming in after her descent &#8211; and to see the pretty little <orgName ref="#Polish">Polish</orgName> boat <!--tag the boat?--> pass us one morning, with banners flying and guns firing, on her way to the ascent. I have been once over to the town and the bazaar &#8211; and for a short sail one evening before dinner &#8211; all the rest of the time I have stayed on the boat &#8211; not daring to venture out in the heat of the day &#8211; or in the cool of the evening. I always think one of the pleasantest things to do at <placeName ref="#Aswan">Assouan</placeName> is to walk on the island of <placeName ref="#Elephantine">Elephantine</placeName> &#8211; but I could not do this because of the heat. It is so densely clothed with palms and other trees that in this heat it harboured millions of mosquitos, which were quite annoying. The night with the full moon have been quite beautiful &#8211; and all of the time we have the music of the same old croaking sakkish in our ears. The <persName ref="#Scott_Elliot_Mr #Scott_Elliot_Mrs #Scott_Elliot_Miss">Scott-Elliots</persName> are expected down from <placeName ref="#Halfa"><choice><sic>Wady Half</sic><corr>Wady Halfa</corr></choice></placeName> tomorrow &#8211; but we shall not wait for them, but start early for <placeName ref="#Kawm_Umbū"><choice><sic>Kom Ombos</sic><corr>Kom Ombo</corr></choice></placeName> &#8211; quite glad to get away from <placeName ref="#Aswan">Assouan</placeName>.</p> 
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-02-11" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1895-02-11">Monday. Feb. 11.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p><persName ref="#Jones_Daniel">Jones</persName> went over quite early this morning for the last mail, and then we made ready to start &#8211; all the fowls were caught and cooped &#8211; stakes brought in &#8211; ropes slipped. The <name type="boat" ref="#Zenet-el-Nil">Zunt-el-Nil</name> came up yesterday close behind us, ready to slip into our place when we left, and we saw our old <persName ref="#Achmed_Rais">Reis Achmed</persName> of the <name type="boat" ref="#Nubia">Nubia</name>, who is now Captain of the <name type="boat" ref="#Zenet-el-Nil">Zunt-el-Nil</name> so nice and dignified &#8211; we dropped down the river, stopped here and there to put off some friends of the Captains or one of the crew.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-02-12" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1895-02-12">Feb. 12th.</date>
          <placeName ref="#Kawm_Umbū">Kom Ombo</placeName>
        </dateline>
        <p>In my haste the evening of the <date when="1895-02-12">12th</date> at <placeName ref="#Kawm_Umbū">Kom Ombo</placeName> I forgot the day before &#8211; when we made <measure type="distance">18 miles</measure> only. We made our <measure type="distance">8 miles</measure> to <placeName ref="#Kawm_Umbū">Kom Ombo</placeName> by half past 3 o'clock, almost to our surprise we found ourselves at <placeName ref="#Kawm_Umbū">Kom Ombo</placeName> and the <name type="boat" ref="#Columbia">Columbia</name> lying there. We waited until 5 o'clock, until the heat had abated a little, and then went up. I had never seen this temple before, except in passing. Two years ago, it was cleaned and excavated by <persName ref="#de_Morgan_Jacques">Mr. de Morgan</persName> &#8211; too much cleaned, many people think. It is certainly very swept and garnished and is most comfortable to get about in for that reason &#8211; and no clamorous natives about. It is so imposing up on its height, and has some characteristic features. The evening light was delicious &#8211; and the views from that height &#8211; <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> went up again this evening to see the moonlight effects. The <name type="boat" ref="#Columbia">Columbia</name> has gone and 2 Cook steamers are here &#8211; but everything is very quiet, and the peace and pure air delicious after the noise and smells of <placeName ref="#Aswan">Assouan</placeName>.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-02-13" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1895-02-13">Wednesday. Feb. 13.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>We are lying at <placeName ref="#Silsilis">Silsilis</placeName> tonight, having made <measure type="distance">15 miles</measure>. We were too late to see much of the grottoes tonight. <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> intends getting up early tomorrow to see the quarries on the other side of the river. I think them one of the most impressive sights of the <placeName ref="Nile">Nile</placeName>. This morning, directly after breakfast we went up to the temple again, I took my camera, and made some views. The <name type="boat" ref="#Isis">Isis</name> came up last evening &#8211; and is lying tonight close by us. They have all been over to see us and <persName ref="#Ware_Dr">Dr. Ware</persName> spent the evening with us.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-02-14" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1895-02-14">Thursday. Feb. 14.</date>
          <placeName ref="#Idfu">Edfou</placeName>
        </dateline>
        <p>We</name> have had an intensely hot day &#8211; hotter than <date when="1895-02-13">yesterday</date> &#8211; and perfectly calm (thermometer on deck in shade 86&#176;) &#8211; so that we dropped down easily to <placeName ref="#Idfu">Edfou</placeName> &#8211; starting at 8:30 this morning, and reaching <placeName ref="#Idfu">Edfou</placeName> at 4 o'clock, making <measure type="distance">26 miles</measure>. We waited awhile, as it was too much to go out into the fiery furnace of the afternoon. The <name type="boat" ref="#Isis">Isis</name> was before us, as she started earlier than we did &#8211; and we found them all at the temple having tea, which they had taken with them. <persName ref="#Scott_Elliot_Miss">Miss Scott-Elliot</persName> vigorously photographing with her elaborate machine &#8211; and her sisters sketching. It was deliciously cool and interesting in that noble temple. The town I horridly dirty &#8211; and I have never seen such a crowd of besieging natives. The gens d'armes kept no sort of peace &#8211; and an ophthalmic hospital might have been filled with the blind beggars.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-02-15" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1895-02-15">Friday. Feb. 15.</date>
          <placeName ref="#El_Kab">El Kab</placeName>
        </dateline>
        <p>In spite of a very strong north head wind, we made this place at 5 o'clock in the afternoon &#8211; but were obliged to tie up on the opposite side of the river, because of the wind &#8211; it has been banging and knocking us about in the most pronounced manner I have ever known on the river. The <name type="boat" ref="#Isis">Isis</name> was close behind us &#8211; and most of her people, as well at <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName>, crossed in the felucca to the little new house at the <placeName ref="#El_Kab">El Kab</placeName> landing, which we had noticed on our way up, and which we were sure was occupied by <persName ref="#Tylor_Mr">Mr. Tylor</persName>, or <persName ref="#Somers_Clarke_George">Mr. Somers-Clarke</persName>. They found the latter there, busy with his excavations &#8211; and wearing the native dress. We will go over tomorrow early, and make him a visit, and see the temple that he discovered, and is now excavating. The north wind still raging &#8211; but much cooler.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-02-16" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1895-02-16">Saturday. Feb. 16th.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>We pulled across the river early this morning and directly after breakfast went up to see <persName ref="#Somers_Clarke_George">Mr. Somers-Clarke</persName>, whom we found with his workmen, busy at his excavations. He is beginning to lay bare the remains of a temple within the great inclosing <!--sic?--> walls of the ancient fortress. Thee walls are built of mud bricks, and are of extraordinary thickness, - 37 ft. wide, <!--measure?--> and of course are very ruinous &#8211; as the ancient city is supposed to have existed under the <orgName>Old Empire.</orgName> <!--needs tag?--> <persName ref="#Somers_Clarke_George">Mr. Somers-Clarke</persName> discovered the site of the temple, which was not known, and has made several trenches, which reveal certain limits, and the two entrance portals &#8211; and the lines of walls. It would seem to be in a great mix &#8211; that is newer buildings had been placed on the site of older ones &#8211; and the old materials used for the new. Thus cartouches of <persName ref="#Thotmes_II #Thotmes_III">Thotmes II and III</persName> &#8211; with the good bas relief work and painting of that period, are found with the much poorer work of much more recent periods. Fragments of columns &#8211; and bases of painting and carved columns were seen &#8211; and ruined and mutilated statues. The infiltration of <placeName ref="#Nile">Nile</placeName> water, with its decomposing salts has made the stones almost into powder, and the work has to be very carefully and slowly done. He had 12 workmen. He afterwards took us to his house, where he showed us the plans of the temple so far as he had been able to trace them. It was most interesting. He had had a mud house built in which he lives, and indeed it is still building &#8211; that is quite a large vaulted room, which is to serve as dining and living room is being completed. He has one room for himself, another for his colleague, and a little court with kitchen and room for his 2 men. His own room had merely plastered walls, and a sand floor spread upon a base of finely broken potsherds which form an excellent drainage &#8211; and as he wear the native dress, with no stockings, and the big red native shoes, which he kicks off as soon as he enters his house, and the sand is pleasant enough &#8211; then when he wants a new carpet as he said, the sand is all swept out, and fresh sand is brought in. His bed, working table, shelves for books etc. were rather primitive, but he said he found it comfortable. It was quite a revelation to see him in the native dress &#8211; he used always to be so fastidiously dressed in white flannels and gaiters. He always wears glasses, which now look so incongruous. He wears the complete dress &#8211; tarboosh, turban, white vest and blue cotton dress. He finds it most comfortable he says &#8211; and the only tolerable thing for his work, that it all goes into the wash tub every day. The dust that excavating makes would be greatly trying to <choice><sic>an</sic><corr>a</corr></choice> European dress. We were greatly entertained with him, his work and manner of living. He walked down to the dahabeah with us and sat awhile. All the men were amazed to see him. We got off by 11 o'clock, and reached <placeName ref="#Esneh">Esneh</placeName> just at dark &#8211; making the <measure type="distance">17-1/2 miles</measure> &#8211; though there was almost no wind. The <name type="boat" ref="#Isis">Isis</name> preceeded us, making a very early start from <placeName ref="#El_Kab">El Kab</placeName>, and getting the benefit of the good south wind that blew during the early morning. <persName ref="#Ware_Dr">Dr. Ware</persName> came over this evening &#8211; they will have their bread early, and will start for <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName> at 6 o'clock in the morning, while we must wait all day tomorrow here for our baking.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-02-17" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1895-02-17">Sexagesima Sunday. Feb. 17.</date>
          <placeName ref="#Esneh">Esneh</placeName>
        </dateline>
        <p>It has been excessively hot all day &#8211; and I have not been off the boat &#8211; not feeling well. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> walked to the <name type="historical" ref="#Esneh_Temple">Temple</name> this morning, and this afternoon had some donkeys and rode into the country &#8211; falling with some boys whom we met here before &#8211; and went with <persName>Alexander</persName> <!--need tag, or part of group aforementioned?--> to his house for some coffee &#8211; which visit they found quite interesting. The house large, and modern &#8211; and well furnished. All the principal people in <placeName ref="#Esneh">Esneh</placeName> are <orgName ref="#Copts">Copts</orgName>. The men of the family all came in to talk to them &#8211; and were immensely dignified, well dressed men &#8211; all having just been to church. The Egyptian part of <placeName ref="#Esneh">Esneh</placeName> is indescribably dirty and horrid, like a great gray wasp's nest &#8211; and not half as clean.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-02-18" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1895-02-18">Monday Feb. 18.</date>
          <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName>
        </dateline>
        <p>Our bread was very late arriving this morning, and as a fine south wind was blowing, we grew very impatient to get off, which we did not do until half past nine. We had both sails up, and made such splendid progress, that we stayed on deck all the time in spite of the heat. The thermometer at the hottest part of the day, was at 86&#176;. We were amazed to see the chimneys of <placeName ref="#Armant">Erment</placeName>, and at 3:30 we were tied to the bank above the <name type="historical" ref="#Castle_Armant">Castle</name> <!--needs different tag?--> &#8211; the <name type="boat" ref="#Isis">Isis</name> being just around the corner on the other side. We are lying at a very pretty bank &#8211; full of the blossoming hummis, a kind of pea &#8211; with trees at the top &#8211; and a lovely view of the broad river with the yellow desert and the mountains of the <name type="historical" ref="#Bībān al-Mulūk">Tombs of the Kings</name> &#8211; and all that great ancient Necropolis. The <name type="boat" ref="#Ammon_Ra">Ammon Ra</name>, Cooks dahabeah, with the <orgName ref="#English">English</orgName> people with the daughter ill with typhoid fever, which we left here, is now moored on the opposite side of the river, with quarantine flags on either side of her. She has now 2 cases of it, and below her is a <orgName>French</orgName> dahabeah, also in quarantine with a case of typhoid. We congratulated ourselves that we lie so far above them. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> was talking to <persName ref="#Ware_Dr">Dr. Ware</persName> this evening about them. We were having tea on deck when <persName ref="#Wallace_Miss">Miss Wallace</persName> who had been taking a row, came to see us &#8211; looking so much better.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-02-19" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1895-02-19">Tuesday. Feb. 19.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>So hot today I only went for a little walk on the top of the bank &#8211; but very glad to reach home again. <persName ref="#Wallace_Miss">Miss Wallace</persName> and <persName ref="#Scott_Elliot_Mr #Scott_Elliot_Mrs">Mr. and Mrs. Scott-Elliot</persName> came to dine with us this evening &#8211; we had a charming dinner for them. They think our boat vastly superior to theirs.</p> 
      </div>
<!--[2/4]-->
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-02-20" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1895-02-20">Wednesday. Feb. 20.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>I had a most delightful donkey ride this morning with <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> out to <placeName ref="#Karnak">Karnac,</placeName> where we did not stop, and along a high embankment near the desert, and a long route home through the delicious green, green fields, the barley just in head. Never was air so pure and fragrant. The wide valley here at <placeName ref ="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName> is highly cultivated, and almost park like in effect. It was a great treat to me &#8211; and the first real donkey ride I have had. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> met the Uncle of the typhoid <orgName ref="#English">English</orgName> young lady this morning. He was seated near <persName ref="Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> at table when we were at <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo,</placeName> and <persName ref="Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> found him very nice. He says that the 3 cases of fever are supposed to have been caught on the <orgName ref="#Messageries">Messageries</orgName>  <!-- Created new Messageries tag --> steamer, on which they all came over. But as they subsequently all stayed at the <name ref="#Grand_Continental_Hotel">Continental</name>  <!-- Created new Grand Continental tag --> in <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo,</placeName> it is not easy to attach suspicion to the right quarter.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-02-21" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1895-02-21">Thursday. Feb. 21.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>At home all the morning. At 2:30 we crossed in the felucca to the other side for a visit to <placeName ref="#Der_el_Bahari">Der el Bahari,</placeName> which I have not seen since the great excavations of the past two years. It was a rather hot ride and hard one for me. We found the <name type="boat" ref="#Isis">Isis</name> people already on the spot - photographing and sketching &#8211; of all the interesting places at this point of the river <!-- which river? --> &#8211;this most appeals to the imagination. The unique position &#8211; the baldness of the conception of a mortuary chapel (for it is now considered to be one, rather than a temple, just as the so called temple of <placeName ref="#Goornah">Goornah</placeName> &#8211; the <placeName ref="#Ramesseum">Ramesseum</placeName> &#8211; and <placeName ref="#Medinet_Habu">Medinet Habou,</placeName> are mortuary temples of the kings who built them). <persName ref="#Naville_Marguerite">M. Naville</persName> under the auspices of the <name>Egypt Exploration Fun,</name> has accomplished marvelous things &#8211; and still has an army of work people digging at the lower terraces, and at the accumulated rubbish of centuries that lies beneath the temple. A long colonnade resting against the cliff has been laid bare &#8211; and the northern and southern colonnades at right angles to this, with accompanying chapels and rooms, with brilliant paintings and carvings &#8211; though these do not compare with the fineness and beauty of the decorations of the terrace above built by Queen <persName>Hatshepshu</persName> <!-- new tag? --> &#8211; with it beautiful realistic carvings which tell so plainly the story of the expedition to the land of <placeName>Punt.</placeName> <!-- ? --> <persName ref="#Naville_Marguerite">M. Naville</persName> himself <!-- himself?, is there another male Naville? -->, who has built himself a house near came and kindly told us much of it. A large portion of the encumbering and defacing <orgName>Coptic</orgName> remains have been taken away, and some stone forming a part of the <name>Story of Punt</name> <!-- make new historical tag? --> have been found in the mass of debris, and restored to their places. The colonnaded ruins now form a picturesque sight resting against the bold yellow cliffs. Before long the terraces and approaches will all be laid bare, and the ruin will form a spectacle to delight and interest the world. It was quite dark as we came home in the felucca &#8211; only a line of crimson yellow in the western sky, reflected in the water, and above it brilliant and soft, Venus, casting a line of rippling silver across the water.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-02-23" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1895-02-23">Saturday. Feb. 23d.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>Home all day yesterday &#8211; quite used up with my expedition of yesterday. The <persName ref="#Scott_Elliot_Mrs">Misses Scott-Elliot</persName> came to breakfast with <persName ref="#Ware_Dr">Dr. Ware</persName> &#8211; and after <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> went for the whole day at <placeName ref="#Karnak">Karnac</placeName> &#8211; <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and I took <persName ref="#Ware_Dr">Dr. Ware</persName> for an inspection of that certain crossing of the island to the <placeName ref="#Bībān al-Mulūk">Tombs of the Kings,</placeName> and afterwards met <persName ref="#Scott_Elliot_Miss">Miss</persName> and Mr. <persName ref="#Scott_Elliot_Mr">Scott-Elliot</persName> and her brother <!-- Miss. Scott-Elliot's brother?--> and visited the <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName> temple &#8211; there are now no workman there &#8211; all excavation having been stopped until the mosque and another part of the town can be bought and taken down. It is tantalizing to see a beautiful colossal face looking out from the accumulation of ages, under one of the houses. Afterwards I went into the <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName> hotel grounds, and came across <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore,</persName> Dr. <persName ref="#Ware_Dr">Ware</persName> and <persName ref="#Scott_Elliot_Mr">Mr. Scott-Elliot</persName> all partaking of lemonade in the big bar room, and I was at once asked to join them, which I did, finding the lemonade uncommonly nasty, and reminding me of that we used to have in our childish feasts, the delight of which was that we made it ourselves. After tea in the afternoon, <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and I went for a ride over the richly cultivated plains back of <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor.</placeName> I had a new donkey &#8211; having declined my hard little beast I have been riding and he proved delightful &#8211; his name was I was told at first California, shortly it changed to Ohio, and at last proved to be Gazelle. Such an entrancing ride along the high banks raised like huge interesting walls about the country &#8211; bordering the deep canals most of them now quite dry &#8211; mile upon miles of barley and wheat field just coming into full head &#8211; and in the light of the declining sun, forming a light green shimmering sheen on every side &#8211; interested by villages under their pale and scent trees &#8211; the blue smoke of their evening fires in a level line above them &#8211; flocks and herds in the fields &#8211; laborers going home from their work &#8211; and the air fresh and fragrant after the hot day. In some places where we went along the little paths through the fields, the barley was higher than my donkey &#8211; and as we came home along the river bank, the crimson yellow inset line and the brilliant Venus &#8211; and all reflected in the darkening river. I am quite sure I should tire very much of living in such an unchanging climate. Nothing but the exigencies of ill health could make me contented with an unfailing cloudless sky &#8211; unreasonable as it sounds. Yet we can be truly thankful this winter for it, when all the civilized world of <placeName>Europe</placeName><!-- Can't find a europe tag? --> and <placeName ref="#United_States_of_America">America</placeName> is fast bound in ice and cold. The severity of the storm we read of in our paper and letters is quite appalling &#8211; while one thermometer during the day on deck in the shade ranges from 80 to 88 &#8211; though the night are cold &#8211; night before last after a very hot day, it was 45 at 7 o'clock in the morning. The radiation is so very rapid under this absolutely cloudless sky.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-02-24" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1895-02-24">Sunday-Qunquagesima. Feb. 24.</date>
          <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName>
        </dateline>
        <p>A very hot day. The rest crossed the river at <placeName ref="#Medinet_Habu">Medinet Habou</placeName> this morning &#8211; returning to lunch, - then again in the afternoon to <placeName ref="#Der_el_Bahari">Der el Bahari</placeName>&#8211; I did not feel up to either of these excursions &#8211; but went down to <placeName ref="#Karnak">Karnac</placeName> at 4 o'clock in the felucca, with one, where our donkeys had been sent, and spent an hour and a half there, riding home around the town the long way &#8211; which was very pleasant.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-02-25" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1895-02-25">Monday. Feb. 25.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>I rode into the town this morning, while <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName>, <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> and <persName ref="#Ware_Dr">Dr. Ware</persName> walked to <persName ref="#Mohassib_Mohammed">Mohammed Mohassib</persName>s<!-- add <sic> for the missing apostrophe? -->&#8211; where we spent an hour or two talking to the old man and looking at his things. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> bought two or three pretty things &#8211; <persName ref="#Mohassib_Mohammed">Mohassib</persName> presented us all with parting souvenirs &#8211; and we said a prolonged and quite an affectionate goodbye. Before we started on our walk this morning we had the two little arab sisters, who when we were in <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName> on our way up, moored at the gezireh on the other side of the river, used to come every day with their father, who looked after our fowls and sheep. They were such pretty children, with the most impossible garments in rags hanging about them &#8211; the older one with a bad cough. I used to watch the younger one, who was a perfect beauty of roundness and grace, as she played with the wind and in the water, with the grace and natural abandonment of a young animal &#8211; and I told <persName ref="#Selim">Selim</persName> to tell the father to go over to <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName> and buy each of them a dress and a pair of drawer, and I would pay for them. So the day after they came immensely proud and grateful to show their new clothes &#8211; a dark blue cotton dress, with an undergarment, and a thin beflowered blue cloth veil &#8211; in all of which they were not half so picturesque but much more comfortable. After we had been in <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName> this time four or five days, they discovered us, and appeared &#8211; their new clothes very much toned down by dirt and use. I gave the older child a flannel under shirt of mine, that was so shrunken I could not wear it, and she immediately retired into the depths of the wheat field at the top of the bank, and put it on, in all this unbearable heat &#8211; and although she never had worn anything so thick and warm, she persisted in keeping it on. We had them on deck &#8211; to their great delight &#8211; and gave them some oranges and sweets to carry away with them &#8211; the older girl was remarkably pretty &#8211; with perfect teeth, and the sweetest smile and her delight in everything she saw, was touching. She patted the rugs on which she sat, gazing about and saying softly to herself quies-quies (pretty). Then we made them stand in the sun and photographed them - and we had my <persName ref="#Mohassib_Mohammed">Mohammed</persName> and <persName ref="#Bani_Hasan">Hassan</persName> move the big hooded chair into the sun, and she sat by me in it, and <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> photographed us &#8211; altogether they had a beautiful spree &#8211; and when we came back from town, and word was given to start, and they saw preparations made, they came on deck to say goodbye, the older girl could not restrain her tears &#8211; and I felt quite broken myself, and almost wanted to carry her away with me &#8211; she was not more than 8. We got away at 1 o'clock, very glad to be moving in all that heat &#8211; the <name type="boat" ref="#Isis">Isis</name> came on directly behind us &#8211; the afternoon was calm, or with a flutter of South wind &#8211; and we easily made 24 miles before pulling up for the night.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-02-26" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1895-02-26">Tuesday. Feb. 26.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>With a light south wind this morning we started at 6 o'clock and made 20 miles to <placeName ref="#Keneh">Keneh</placeName> by 10 o'clock. We stopped at the <placeName ref="#Keneh">Keneh</placeName> landing and <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and <persName ref="#Buttles_Jeanette">Nettie</persName> rode into the town on a vain quest for interesting antiquities &#8211; while <persName>Jones</persName><!-- Daniel Jones? --> and <persName ref="#Selim">Selim</persName> went for provisions. Then we pulled over to <persName>Denderah</persName><!-- Blank tag on indices sheet?--> where the <name type="boat" ref="#Isis">Isis</name> was, and everybody went except myself to see the temple. The heat was too great for me &#8211; and I never find that temple very interesting. We went off, leaving the <name type="boat" ref="#Isis">Isis,</name> at 6 o'clock &#8211; but only made a short distance as the wind was against us.</p> 
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-02-27" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1895-02-27">Wednesday. Feb. 27.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>Started in a dead calm at 7 am and have made 42 miles &#8211; passing <persName>Dishneh, Kaar</persName><!-- Karnac?--> as <persName ref="#Gebel_Sheik_Said">Said</persName>, <persName>Karshout</persName><!-- who? -->, and <!-- and I?-->are now lying about 4 miles below <placeName>Farshout</placeName><!-- where? --> &#8211; the <name type="boat" ref="#Isis">Isis</name> behind us. Very hot all day &#8211; it has been impossible to do anything. Thermometer in shade on deck has been up to 94 &#8211; the night very warm and still &#8211; the little new moon, and Venus perfectly reflected in the glassy water. We find the only way to keep tolerably comfortable is to close the windows in the morning early, as soon as the servants have finished cleaning, shutters, blinds and all &#8211; and possibly the canvass<!-- add sic?--> over them &#8211; and I am pleased to find how cool the boat can be kept &#8211; but the heat is very trying &#8211; and I almost feel as if I were again living in <placeName ref="#Ohio">Ohio,</placeName> during the summer.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-02-28" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1895-02-28">Feb. 28. Thursday.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>Started at 8:30 this morning &#8211; very hot and still &#8211; and made <placeName ref="#Balyana_Al">Balliana</placeName> at 1 o'clock &#8211; 14 miles. Too late to attempt <placeName ref="#Abydos">Abydos.</placeName> The <name type="boat" ref="#Isis">Isis</name> people are waiting until tomorrow too, for the expedition. But we are feeling a little doubtful tonight about it &#8211; as the heat has been extreme &#8211; 99 on deck this afternoon, under the awning &#8211; <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and <persName ref="#Buttles_Lizzie">Nettie</persName> walked down to the <name type="boat" ref="#Isis">Isis</name> &#8211; but I preferred the clean quiet deck &#8211; at 6 o'clock the thermometer was still at 80 &#8211; and <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> has wisely announced that unless a cool north wind blows in the morning, he will start down. I shall be sorry not to see that beautiful Temple &#8211; and to miss that ride through the pleasant country &#8211; but it is a long one &#8211; 9 miles out.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-03-01" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1895-03-01">March 1st. Friday.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>The morning dawned hot and still &#8211; and <placeName ref="#Abydos">Abydos.</placeName> was impossible. So we started at 8:30 as we passed the <name type="boat" ref="#Isis">Isis</name> <persName ref="#Scott_Elliot_Mr">Mr. Scott-Elliot</persName> called out to <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> that all their party excepting his wife and himself had made a very early start for <placeName ref="#Abydos">Abydos.</placeName> &#8211; and would spend the day there &#8211; returning as late as possible. The day has been insufferably hot &#8211; thermometer was 99 on deck at 3pm &#8211; afterwards a very refreshing little wind from the north came to our relief &#8211; and we made <persName>Menshieh</persName><!-- new tag? --> at 6 o'clock &#8211; and tied up at a clean sand bank opposite the town, and went for a little walk. Made today 20 miles. Ramadan began a few days ago &#8211;and the first day was strictly kept by both our Captains, and one or two of our crew. Old Salim<!-- new tag? -->, the cook, of course keeps it, being a Mohammedan of the strictest sect. Our coleric old <persName ref="#Rais_Mahommed">Rais Mohammed,</persName> with his childish nature, was the picture of woe during the day &#8211; and unusually irascible with the sailors &#8211; and gradually as the day wore on, he accumulated at a little corner at the head of the gang way where he always stands or sits, two dishes with covers, containing food &#8211; a batch of some kind of a pickle of which they are enormously fond, a pile of dried dates, and his cigarette case &#8211; he hovered over these from time to time, and finally sat flat down upon the deck, tumbled his tobacco into his lap, and began making cigarettes. He was such a funny picture of the commanding officer of a vessel, with his bare feet sticking out from his robe. Finally the sun went down &#8211; and they had something to eat, and a smoke, and things were more serene. It is really hard on the working people &#8211; a day with nothing to eat or to smoke from sunset to sunrise. My donkey boy in <placeName ref="#Luxor">Luxor</placeName> was bewailing one day that Ramadan began the next day &#8211; he said "no eat &#8211; no smoke &#8211; no cigarettes &#8211; no water &#8211; no everything". Their habit too of eating enormously after the fast of the day &#8211; and keeping awake to eat most of the night, upsets them sadly &#8211; and makes one wish to try and reason with them. Our people, however, are not hurting themselves &#8211; and the fast was given up after the second day.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-03-02" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1895-03-02">Saturday. March 2.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>A cool, light north wind was blowing this morning. Started at 7 and made <persName>Akmim</persName> at noon &#8211; where we stopped, and sent into town on a vain search for the antiquity dealer of last year &#8211; he was not to be found however. We tried rowing for awhile but the north wind was too strong &#8211; and sunset found us anchored in the stream just below the town &#8211; then the wind falling a little, our <persName>Rais</persName> ventured again, but we got into a very difficult place &#8211; and finally put up the sail and sailed up the river for half a mile, and anchored to a sand bank.</p> 
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-03-03" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1895-03-03">Sunday. March 3. First Sunday in Lent.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>A cold north wind blowing all day &#8211; most refreshing &#8211; it grew so strong that we made only 3 miles &#8211; stopping all day at <placeName>Sohag.</placeName></p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-03-04" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1895-03-04">Monday. March 4.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>We have made a splendid run of 64 miles today &#8211; and are now lying about 4 miles from <placeName>Assiout</placeName> &#8211; have passed <name>Tahtah</name> &#8211; <placeName>Gaou</placeName> and Aboutig. The morning was exquisite &#8211; I went on deck immediately after breakfast &#8211; and was there most of the day. Nothing could be more lovely than that morning effects &#8211; the cliffs a pink yellow, with heliotrope shadows sleeping in their hollows. &#8211; the water, silverly pink, reflecting every object.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-03-05" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1895-03-05">Tuesday. March 5.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>We were at <placeName ref="#Asyut">Assiout</placeName> early - and landed for our mail, and some provisions. Met all the <name type="boat" ref="#Isis">Isis</name> people in the bazaar - nothing seemed nice in <placeName ref="#Asyut">Assiout</placeName> today - but the smell of orange blossoms as we passed the big garden - and we were glad to be back on the boat again. We are at <placeName ref="#Manfalût">Manfalout</placeName> - and have made <measure type="distance">26 miles</measure>. The day intensely hot - <meaure type="temperature">84</measure> in the saloon early this afternoon - I went out so early, that I did not superintend the closing of the windows - the only effective way of keeping the boat cool.</p> 
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-03-06" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1895-03-06">Wednesday. March 6.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>We are still lying at <placeName ref="#Manfalût">Manfalout</placeName> - but have moved across the river, and are anchored near a sandy beach. We found the bank at which we lay last night, very muddy - the <placeName ref="#Nile">Nile</placeName> having lately left it - and the rank smell that came from it most disagreeable, and I am sure unhealthy. We have a lovely air tonight, the north wind which has been blowing a gale all day, and prevented our moving, has moderated, and is very sweet, soft and fresh. All the <name type="boat" ref="#Isis">Isis</name> people over here this morning. It has seemed a long day - so hot - and under the necessity of lying quietly by.</p> 
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-03-07" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1895-03-07">Thursday. March 7.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>A north wind all day - but we have managed to make <measure type="distance">25 miles</measure> - passing the big <placeName ref="#Abu_Fudah_Jabal">Aboufoydah chain</placeName>. We overtook the <name type="boat" ref="#Isis">Isis</name> early in the day - and were also in company with the <name type="boat" ref="#London_Boat">London</name>, a dahabeah whose people had left her at <placeName ref="#Jirjā">Girgeh</placeName> - and she was making her way down to <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> - closed and shrouded in her canvass coverings. Late this afternoon as we sat on deck, she being very close to us, we heard shouts proceeding from a working boat that was coming up the river - and some excited talk between the two crews - on the working boat was a dragoman, with servant, who (as we learned) called out to the Rais of the <name type="boat" ref="#London_Boat">London</name>, that he was wanted by a gentleman to go to <placeName ref="#Aswan">Assouan</placeName>, that he would arrive by train tomorrow, and that he (the Dragoman) had orders to engage her for two months. They at once put up their oars - and unfurled their sails - and made for the shore, where the Dragoman was landing. It was such a sudden and unexpected change for the men - and they were so delighted with another engagement of 2 months - for at this time of the year they are generally falling out of work. There were many congratulations called out to them from our boat. This morning as the <name>Postal Steamer Hatasou</name> <!--?-->passed us quite close, we saw <persName ref="#Lapsley_Mr">Mr. Lapsley</persName> who was waving to us, and staring at us through his glasses. We are within <measure type="distance">two</measure> or <<measure type="distance">three miles</measure> of <persName>Haji Kandeel</persName><!--?--> - the station for <placeName re="#Amarna">Tel el-Amarna</placeName> - which we intend visiting tomorrow.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-03-08" type="entry">
        <dateline>  s
          <date when="1895-03-08">Friday. March 8th.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>A heavy north wind blowing all the morning. In the afternoon floating and rowing we reached <persName>Haji Kandeel</persName><!--?--> about 4 o'clock. A very noisy unpromising crowd of natives gathered on the shore - and such a vociferation went on, I was forced to come below, to get away from them. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and <persName ref="#Buttles_Lizzie">Nettie</persName> walked about on shore. The <name type="boat" ref="#Isis">Isis</name> having come up with us this evening,  <persName ref="#Ware_Dr">Dr. Ware</persName> came over, and we all had a game of domino whist. We are all to go to the <placeName ref="#Amarna">Tel el Amarna tombs</placeName> tomorrow.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-03-09" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1895-03-09">Saturday. March 9th.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>The day dawned very gray and cold - high wind - having taken cold a day or two ago, I wisely decided to stay in the boat. A still more noisy, rude and vociferous crowd, with their donkeys about the boat, and the choice of the latter was not difficult, when all were so poor and jaded. They came back about 11 o'clock having seen part of the grottoes or tomb - and very tired of their poor donkeys. The guides did not know anything about the grottoes - and instead of going to the North, which are the best, and seeing the tomb of <placeName ref="#Amenophis_IV_Tomb">Amenophis IV</placeName> or <placeNameref="#Khuenaten_Tomb">Khuenaten</placeName>, they had only gone to the south - and missed the rest. <persName ref="#Buttles_Lizzie">Nettie</persName>'s donkey fell with her, and gave her quite a shock. We came away from that noisy shore at once, but the north wind was so strong, that after struggling against it for half an hour, we took refuge at the end of a sand bank, opposite and a little way blow, the <name type="boat" ref="#Isis">Isis</name>, and anchored strongly - the water rushing in real waves past us - and the sand flying furiously and her we are for the night I suppose - as, although there is a full moon - there is little prospect of the wind dying out.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-03-10" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1895-03-10">2nd Sunday in Lent. March 10.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>A great gale has prevailed all day - we have not stirred from our moorings - except as we are battered about by the wind. We rowed until 3 o'clock am last night - and our men are having a good rest today. My cold very bad - indoors all day. <persName ref="#Ware_Dr">Dr. Ware</persName> came over to lunch - <measure type="distance">20 miles</measure>.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-03-11" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1895-03-11">Monday. March 11th.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>We started at 6 o'clock this morning, and in spite of a north wind, we reached <placeName ref="#Bani_Hassan">Beni Hasan</placeName> at 10 o'clock. The morning was very gray, the first gray day of the winter - and so cool that I did not venture out to the tombs with <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and <persNameref="#Buttles_Lizzie">Nettie</persName>. We were off at one o'clock and reached <placeName ref="#Al_Minya">Minieh</placeName> at 10 P.M. making <measure type="distance">25 -1/2 miles</measure>.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-03-12" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1895-03-12">Tuesday. March 12.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>The north wind not quite so strong today. <persName ref="#Jones_Daniel">Jones</persName> went into the town immediately after breakfast and got our mail - then we were off - and brought up about 3 o'clock within <measure type="distance">5 miles</measure> of <placeName ref="#Jirjā">Abou Girgeh</placeName>. The moon rose tonight about 8 - splendid and big with a yellow light that was really reflected on the sky about her. We have made <measure type="distance">30 miles<measure>.</p>
      </div>
      <!--[3/4]--> <!--Tag objectName-->
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-03-13" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1895-03-13">Wednesday. March 13.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>We have made a fine run of <measure type="distance">43 miles</measure> today - and are now at <placeName ref="#Biba">Bibeh</placeName> - and about half way between <placeName re="#Al_Fashn">Feshu</placeName> <!--sic?-->and <placeName ref="#Benisoef">Beni Soef</placeName>. The day beautiful and calm and warm. I was a great deal on deck. The night a repetition of last night - full, resplendent moon - and very calm.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-03-14" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1895-03-14">Thursday. March 14.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>The day has been very hot - I was on deck in the morning until the north wind grew too strong - have passed <<placeName ref="#Benisoef">Benisoef</placeName> and <placeName ref="#Al-Wasta">Wasta</placeName>, and made <measure type="distance">38 miles</measure> - and have pulled up at <placeName ref="#Ar_Riqqah">Rikkeh</placeName>. The splendid <name type="historical" ref="#Meidum_Pyramid">Meydoum pyramid</name> has been in sight all the afternoon. The wind is raging tonight. The <name type="boat" ref="#Isis">Isis</name> just ahead of us.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-03-15" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1895-03-15">Friday. March 15.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>We haven't stirred today - as the north wind is still howling and knocking us about. I couldn't sleep last night because of the racket - and when about 2 o'clock on or our cables parted at the stern and we swung about in the stream, rolling from side to side as if we were at sea, I was almost alarmed. There was a great row about it. <persName ref="#Wallace_Miss">Miss Wallace</persName> <!--who?-->and <persName ref="#Ware_Dr">Dr. Ware</persName> came to lunch - and we are able to go over and dine with them this evening.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-03-16" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1895-03-16">Saturday. March 16.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>We have just pulled up to the bank at <placeName ref="#Al_Badrashayn">Bedraheya</placeName><!--sic?--> - after a wearing row from 6 o'clock, until 8:30 tonight. Our poor men are very tired - but as cheerful as possible. We have made <measure type="distance">34 miles</measure> - in the face of a strong north wind that has not abated for one minute.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-03-17" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1895-03-17">Sunday. March 17. 3d Sunday in Lent.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>The <name type="boat" ref="#Isis">Isis</name> appeared early this morning - landing just in front of us - and we all started for <placeName ref="#Ṣaqqâra">Sakkarah</placeName> soon after breakfast - I however only getting as far as <placeName ref="#Memphis">Memphis</placeName> - where the temple lie, that we saw excavated last time we were here. The wind was very strong - and increased with the day - blinding clouds of dust and sand. The rest arrived at 4 o'clock - complaining much of the wind and dust. We cannot of course get away while this wind holds.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-03-18" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1895-03-18">Monday. March 18.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>Still lying at <placeName ref="#Al_Badrashayn">Bedrasheyn</placeName> <!--sic?-->tossed about by the wind. The <name type="boat" ref="#Isis">Isis</name> people, whose lease has expired today, telegraphed to <persName>Cook</persName> <!--Thomas Cook?-->for a tug and went off triumphantly just at dusk.</p> 
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-03-19" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1895-03-19">Ghizeh. March 19.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>To our great joy the wind fell last night suddenly about 12 o'clock. We were off at once, and our men easily made the <measure type="distance">12 miles</measure> here by 3 o'clock - and when we got up we found ourselves just behind the <name type="boat" ref="#Isis">Isis</name> - who it seems only got in two hours before us, the tug having broken down when they had made about <measure type="distance">5 miles</measure>. They left the boat immediately after breakfast, and went out ot the <name type="hotel" ref="#Mena_House_Hotel">Mena House</name> where they will stay sometime - and the <name type="boat" ref="#Isis">Isis</name> at once turned out into the stream and made for the <orgName>Cook</orgName> landing <!--Cook landing?--> at <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> looking very deserted to us. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> went into <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> this morning on his donkey - to see about our rooms at <name type="hotel" ref="#Shepheards_Hotel">Shepheards</name> - and to get our mail. <persName ref="#Buttles_Lizzie">Nettie</persName> and I went over to the <orgName ref="#Boulaq_Museum">Museum</orgName> - and I saw for the first time the wonderfully interesting and beautiful things found within the past few months at <placeName ref="#Dahshūr">Dahshour</placeName>. The exquisite jewelry - the wooden statue, of <persName ref"#Hor_Awibre">King Hor</persName>, and his sentry box in which the statue was enclosed - the sarcophagi - and the extraordinary group of soldiers - in 2 groups - of 40 each - the figures about a foot high - and executed in the most life like manner - one company of Egyptians, and the other of Soudanese - it is extraordinary work for the 12th Dynasty <!--tag?-->. As we were coming out of the <orgName ref="#Boulaq_Museum">Museum</orgName>, we saw <persName ref="#Parsons_Mary">Mary Parsons</persName>, whom <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> had hoped to see at <name type="hotel" ref="#Shepheards_Hotel">Shepheards</name>. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> brought a great bunch of letters and papers - and after lunch we all went again over to the <orgName ref="#Boulaq_Museum">Museum</orgName>.</p> 
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-03-20" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1895-03-20">Wednesday, March 20.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p><persName ref="#Parsons_Mary">Mary Parsons</persName> and <persName ref="#Crane_Miss">Miss Crane</persName> appeared quite early this morning - and were quite interested in going over the dahabeah. When they had gone, we stared out to the <name type="historical" ref="#Pyramids">Pyramids</name>, <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and <persName ref="#Buttles_Lizzie">Nettie</persName> on their donkeys - and I in the bid landau with <persName ref="#Rais_Mahommed"></persName> on the box - we were just in time for lunch with the <name type="boat" ref="#Isis">Isis</name> people - and afterwards <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and <persName ref="#Buttles_Lizzie">Nettie</persName> went over to the <name type="historical" ref="#Pyramids">Pyramids</name> - while I sat on the terrace and waited = and was bored, and devoured with flies - and the day was very blustering and like a March day at home - so that driving back I had the top of the carriage raised, and wrapped myself in my big cloak. <persName ref="#Parsons_Mary">Mary Parsons</persName> came to dine and pass the night, and she is much delighted with our life on board. Our men gave one of their best concerts and did some dancing, and we sat on deck, enclosed by the awnings with the lanterns lighted, until we were forced to go below by the chill night air. Tomorrow begins the unpleasant work of dismantling - settling with the men and leaving the boat - which in spite of my great joy and satisfaction in finishing this <placeName ref="#Nile">Nile</placeName> journey, still has an element of sadness in it - for after all, this <name type="boat" ref="#Herodotus_Boat">Herodotus</name> has been our home for 2 winters.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-03-21" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1895-03-21">Thursday. March 21st.</date>
          <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName>. <name type="hotel" ref="#Shepheards_Hotel">Shepheards Hotel</name>.
        </dateline>  
        <p>We came across the river and down to <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> directly after breakfast. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> took <<persName ref="#Parsons_Mary">Mary Parsons</persName> ashore, and goes to the bazaar with her and <persName>Miss Crane</persName> <!--who?--> - and <persName ref="#Buttles_Lizzie">Nettie</persName> and I, with <persName ref"#Jones_Daniel">Jones</persName>, pitched into the business of packing - our pretty adornments and personal things were soon hauled down from the walls, and when <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> came back to lunch he found a dismantled boat, and stumbled everywhere over trunks and boxes. After lunch, I sat down to write references for such of the men that we give them to, that is the Captains, 2 indoor men and cook - and <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> began piling up various little heaps of gold, intended for baksheesh for every body. The first Captain, <persName ref="#Rais_Mahommed">Reis Mohammed</persName> got <measure type="currency">six pounds</measure> - our favorite <persName>Reis Fuls</persName> <!--Fuli?-->, 2 - Capt. Got <measure type="currency">4 pounds</measure> - the cook <persName ref="#Salim">Salim</persName> <measure type="currency">10 pounds</measure> - and each sailor <measure type="currency">1 pound</measure>. This baksheesh business is always an uncertain affair - depending entirely on the generosity of the person who hires the dahabeah - and has nothing whatever to do with the regular wages of the men. There is always great expectancy on their part, and very often no doubt, great disappointment. About 4 o'clock, all these affairs having been wound up, we bade a warm farewell to all, and departed for <name type="hotel" ref="#Shepheards_Hotel">Shepheards</name> - where we are now most comfortably installed in the same apartment we had in December. But what an age ago that seems!</p> 
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-03-28" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <name type="boat" ref="#SS_Singapore">S.S. Singapore, Rubitimo Line</name>.
          <placeName ref="#Alexandria">Alexandria</placeName>.
          <date when="1895-03-28">March 28.</date>
        </dateline>  
        <p>Although we should have sailed this morning at 10 o'clock, we are still tied strongly to the dock, with the wind blowing a furious gale, and making it impossible to put to sea. We left <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> yesterday afternoon at 4 o'clock - and spent last night at the <placeName>Khedivial Hotel.</placeName> We had six days in <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> which we used to the best advantage we could. I went over to the <placeName>Bazaar</placeName> once - and once again to the <orgName ref="#Boulaq_Museum">Museum</orgName>, where I saw the 9 wonderful statues of one of the <orgName>Usertesens</orgName>, found at <placeName ref="Al_Lisht">Lisht</placeName> <!--put in MI-->, and the beautiful statue in basalt of <persName type="historical" ref="#Osiris">Osiris</persName>, found at <name type="historical" ref="#Medinet_Habu">Medinet Habou</name>. One afternoon <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and I drove to the <name type="hotel" ref="#Gezireh_Hotel">Gezireh Hotel</placeName> <!--put in MI-->which I had not seen, and called on the <name type="boat" ref="#Isis">Isis</name> people. It is quite magnificent - there can be no other quite so splendid - as it was the favorite palace of the old <persName ref="#Ismail_Pacha">Ismail Pacha</persName><!--put in MI-->, who was buried the other day in <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName>. On this palace he lavished millions - and I can well believe it. The extensive grounds are very beautiful and highly cultivated. We walked around to the <orgName>Casino</orgName>, and had tea on the terrace, where there was a gay throng of every nationality. The air was full of the fragrance of orange blossoms. I had one other little drive one afternoon, but that was all, as the wind blew violently every day, and the dust was omnipresent. <persName ref="#Parsons_Mary">Mary Parsons</persName> and the three ladies she was travelling with (among them <persName ref="#Gifford_Miss">Miss Gifford</persName>, aunt of <persName ref="#Gifford_Edie">Edie Gifford</persName> of <placeName ref="#Milwaukee">Milwaukie</placeName>, and a very sweet attractive woman) were at <name type="hotel" ref="#Shepheards_Hotel">Shepheards</name> and on their way to <placeName ref="#Syria">Syria</placeName>. <persName ref="#Parsons_Mary">Mary</persName> was so unwell, and unfit for uncertain <orgName ref="#Syrian">Syrian</orgName> travel, that it was thought best she should join our party and return home with us - which to our great pleasure she did. We used to spend hours at the carpet <placeName>bazaar of Madjar's</placeName> <!--?-->next the hotel - a most curious, delightful and original little old goose it has ever been my pleasure to meet. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> bought some lovely things of him, and the bargaining between the two, used to be a thing to hear. Much of our time was spent in the effort to arrange a method of studying English for our 2 faithful Mahommedan boys, <persName ref="#Ali_Mohammed">Mahomet</persName> and <persName>Hassan</persName> <!--<persName ref="#Hassan"><choice><sic>Hasan</sic><corr>Hassan</corr></choice></persName>-->- and an arrangement was finally made with the head of the <orgName ref="#American_Mission">American Mission School</orgName>, to provide them with a private tutor for one hour each day, <measure type="currency">a shilling</measure> an hour - for, as they know nothing of study or application it would be impossible for them to go into a school - and we want and they are very anxious to learn to speak English - as it improves their chances as sailors, and for everything. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> arranged to give them <measure type="currency">a pound</measure> a month for their living expenses - and they were to get a little room somewhere and live in it. We bought them some new clothes - gave them 2 tables and chairs we had had on the dahabeah, a big straw mat for the floor, and a big red thick blanket - towels - candles and candle-stick. <persName>Yossen</persName> <!--?--> our young Arab Copy friend, who is in business in <placeName ref="#Cairo">Cairo</placeName> is to have a friendly eye over them - and <persName ref="#Baehler_Charles">Mr. Bachelor</persName> the Manager of <name type="hotel" ref="#Shepheards_Hotel">Shepheards</name> received the money from <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName>, with exact written directions, and kindly offered to give it to the boy on their monthly application = so that we left them in very good shape. <persName re="#Ware_Dr">Dr. Ware</persName> came to luncheon on our last day, and all the <name type="boat" ref="#Isis">Isis</name> people to tea the afternoon before. <persName>Mahomet</persName> <!--?--> and <persName>Hassan</persName> <!--?-->were with us most of the time, and at the station we found <persName ref="#Abbecatto">Abbecatio</persName> and old <persName ref="#Selim">Selim</persName> - and the last thing we saw as the train moved off, was our 2 poor boys looking bereft and distressed. We are rather pleased with the look of this boat - but have always avoided this line, it was a necessity however, as we could not get into any other boat sailing about this time.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-04-07" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <name type="hotel" ref="#Hotel_Royal_Grande_Bretagne">Hotel, Grand Bretagne</name>.
          <placeName ref="#Florence">Florence</placeName>.
          <date when="1895-04-07">April 7th. Palm Sunday.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>We have passed many an uncomfortable hour since I last made an entry in this journal. We got off from <placeName ref="#Alexandria">Alexandria</placeName> the morning after but soon after sailing lost one of the sailors overboard, who fortunately was able to swim and get onto a buoy - a small boat with 6 men was sent out to him in the heavy sea, and was capsized, and had it not been for 2 pilot boats in the neighborhood, who went to their assistance, all the 7 could have been lost. It was more than 3 hours before we got them on board, during which time we lay at anchor, tossing and rolling. The <name type="boat" ref="#SS_Singapore"> proved to be very slow, very dirty - badly officered - bad food - and a noisy lot of <orgName ref="#German">Germans</orgName> and <orgName ref="#Italian">Italians</orgName> - and I thought the days and particularly, the nights would never end. On the <date when="1895-04-01">first of April</date> we arrived at <placeName ref="Messina">Messina</placeName>, where we stayed 12 hours. We went ashore and drove about the rather uninteresting <orgName ref="Italian">Italian</orgName> town - the dust and wind being the principal factors. The next morning we were at <placeName ref="#Naples">Naples</placeName>, where the boat was to stay 40 hours - and we delightfully made preparations to spend the day and night on shore. We drove to the <name type="hotel" ref="#Grand_Hotel">Grand Hotel</placeName>, which we found overflowing with people - and were obliged to go up to the <name type="hotel" ref="Wet_End">Wet End</name> where we got very pleasant rooms. But the weather was cold, wind high, and a thick atmosphere - and <placeName ref="#Vesuvius">Vesuvius</placeName> quite invisible. I was not well during the night, and the next morning when <persName ref="#Jones_Daniel">Jones</persName> appeared from the <name type="boat" ref="#SS_Singapore">, saying she would not leave until sometime in the night, and would take 24 hours to <placeName ref="#Livorno">Leghorn</placeName>, where we had expected to leave her, we held solemn council and decided to go directly by rail to <placeName ref="#Florence">Florence</placeName>. So <persName ref="#Jones_Daniel">Jones</persName> was sent back to the boat to pack and bring away our trunks, and <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> went off to secure a compartment in the night train to <placeName ref="#Rome">Rome</placeName>, and the <persName ref="Ware_Dr">Dr.</persName> was sent for to see me and say if I was fit to start, and the upshot of the whole thing was, that we had a very comfortable night on the train arriving in <placeName ref="#Rome">Rome</placeName> at 6:30am. We drove to the <name type="hotel" ref="#Quirinal_Hotel">Quirinal Hotel</name> so short a distance off, and had a good wash, followed by a delicious breakfast in the restaurant, and were off to <placeName ref="#Florence">Florence</placeName> at 8:30 - reaching there at 2:30. The town is very, very full - and we had some difficulty about the number of our rooms - but are not quite pleasantly settled. Yesterday morning <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName>, <persName ref="#Parsons_Mary">Mary</persName> and I went to the <orgName ref="#Uffizi_Gallery">Uffizzi</persName> - <persName ref="#Buttles_Lizzie">Nettie</persName> not being well enough to go with us. <persName ref="#Baldwin_Dr">Dr. Baldwin</persName> and <persName ref="#Berenson_Bernard">Mr. Berenson</persName> came to tea yesterday in the afternoon - and directly after lunch today <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName>, <persName ref="#Parsons_Mary">Mary</persName> and I drove to <placeName ref="#Fiesole">Fiesole</placeName>, and out over the Mts. <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> went off by himself this morning to the <<orgName ref="#Palazzo_Pitti">Pitti palace</orgName> - <persName ref="#Parsons_Mary">Mary</persName> to church - and I stayed home with <persName ref="#Buttles_Lizzie">Nettie</persName>, who though better is still weak - but there is now no danger of any fever, as we feared at first there might be. The <persName ref="Shaw_Quincy">Quincy Shaws</persName> of <placeName ref="Boston">Boston</placeName>, with <persName ref="#Agassiz_Louis_Mrs">Mrs. Louis Agassiz</persName> are in this hotel, and <persName>Miss Shaw</persName> and <persName ref="#Agassiz_Louis_Mrs">Mrs. Agassiz</persName> came to tea yesterday afternoon. We met the <persName ref="#Bronson_Ethel" "#Bronson_Mrs">Bronsons</name> yesterday driving - and <persName>Mrs. B.</persName> <!--Which Mrs. B?--> called today.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-04-10" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1895-04-10">Wednesday. April 10.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>We are all ready to leave this delicious <placeName ref="#Florence">Florence</placeName> tomorrow - though we do it very unwillingly - but our time is short, and beautiful and interesting things so crowd upon one here, that choice is difficult. We have arranged a little driving tour with <persName ref="#Berenson_Bernard">Mr. Berenson</persName> who will go with us - and will start tomorrow for <placeName fre="#Siena">Sienna</placeName>. The Dr. thinks <persName ref="#Buttles_Lizzie">Nettie</persName> can now safely venture. We have had some delicious drives and walks - and visits to galleries and churches. Among the things I had never before seen were the frescoes by <persName type="historical" ref="#Gozzoli_Benozzo">Benozzo Gozzoli</persName> in the chapel of the <name type="historical" ref="#Palazzo_Medici_Riccardi">Riccardipalace</name> - which I knew and admired greatly from my photographs of them - that the dark, irregularly shaped little chapel was a surprising disappointment to me - though the frescoes were not. One afternoon <persName ref="#Berenson_Bernard">Mr. Berenson</persName> took us to see the new <objectName type="painting" ref="#Pallas_Centaur">Boticelli</objectName> which has lately been discovered in the <orgName ref="#Palazzo_Pitti">Pitti palace</orgName>. It seems that an old gentleman who knew all about pictures, went one day to call on the <placeName>Duke of Aosta</placeName> <!--tag--> in his apartment at the <orgName ref="#Palazzo_Pitti">Pitti</orgName>. and being left to cool his heels sometime in the antechamber, noticed high up in a dark corner a picture which he thought in the <persName type="historical" ref="#Botticelli_Sandro">Botticelli</persName> style and knowing that a certain painting of his known once to have existed was now lost, he went to the director of the <<orgName ref="#Palazzo_Pitti">Museum</orgName> and told him what he had seen. The result was that the picture was removed to one of the private rooms of the <orgName ref="#Uffizi_Gallery">Uffizzi</orgName> - and the world has found a new art treasure - though it was not the picture that had been searched for so long - and no one at the present time knew that <persName type="historical" ref="#Botticelli_Sandro">Botticelli</persName> had painted such a picture as this. It is a picture of a woman charmingly painted in <persName type="historical" ref="#Botticelli_Sandro">Botticelli</persName>'s best manner, standing by a centaur. <persName ref="Bernad_Berenson">Mr. Berenson</persName> has written a pamphlet on the subject, which I hope soon to see. It is not yet exhibited to the public, and we saw it only through <persName ref="#Berenson_Bernard">Mr. Berenson</persName>. We took <persName ref="#Fearing_Mrs">Mrs. Fearing</persName>  <!--EBAMI-->with us - and she went with us to some of the galleries. There are so many <orgName ref="#American">Americans</orgName> in <placeName ref="#Florence">Florence</placeName> at the moment. The <persName ref="#Fearing_Dan" "#Fearing_Mrs">Dan Fearings</persName> are at the <name type="hotel" ref="#Hotel_de_la_Villa">Hotel de la Ville</name><!--EBAMI-->, near us. Today <persName ref="#Buttles_Lizzie">Nettie</persName> went out in the morning for a drive, and then again in the afternoon to <placeName ref="#San_Miniato">San Miniato</placeName>, and went into the church for a few minutes. This morning I went to <placeName>Palotti</placeName>'s<!--where?--> with <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore,</persName> where we met the <persName ref="#Adam_Thatcher">Thatcher Adams</persName> <!--EBAMI-->and <persName>Mrs. Bronson.</persName> <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> bought some lovely old <orgName ref="#Venetian">Venetian</orgName> brocade, and four charming cushions of green <orgName ref="#Genoa">Genoa</orgName> velvet.</p> 
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-04-13" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1895-04-13">Saturday, April 13.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>We left <placeName ref="#Florence">Florence</placeName> on Thursday morning soon after breakfast in two landaus - sending <persName ref-"Jones_Daniel">Jones</persName> with the heavy luggage by train - and stopping two hours during the middle of the day for rest and lunch - reached <placeName ref="#Siena">Sienna</placeName> by 6:30 - the distance being <measure type="distance">40 miles</measure>. It was an enchanting drive- the day was perfect - the roads likewise - leading over the hills and down the hills, and along the valleys - the country very hilly, with strange abrupt little hills, almost every one crowned with a walled town, or a convent, or a fortress. Olive orcharcs and vineyards everywhere, violets and anemones and periwinkles blooming along the banks and roadsides. We went clattering through the narrow, tony street of one little town after another - and with our jingling bells and creaking whips - and as it was Holy Thursday<!--tag?--> all the people were out in their best attire, and having a holiday. I had never posted through <placeName ref="#Italy">Italy</placeName> before - and we were enchanted with the mode of travel - and I was not one bit tired on reaching <placeName ref="#Siena">Sienna</placeName> - which is very effective on the crest of its 3 hills as it were, with its campaniles and tower, and great encircling wall. Our hotel, the <name type=="hotel" ref="#Grand_Hotel_Royal_de_Seinne">Grand Hotel Royal de Seinne</placeName>, was an old palace and stands high above the valley with beautiful views, and our lofty rooms open on to a stone parapet overlooking the neighborhood to the wet - <persName ref="#Buttles_Lizzie">Nettie</persName> is again not well - and I have been staying at home with her all day - she got too tired I fear the other day on her drive here. Yesterday we sallied out early under <persName ref="#Berenson_Bernard">Berenson</persName>'s leadership, and walked about the town, visiting the <name type="historical" ref="Palazzo_Pubblico">Palazzo Publico</name>, the great town hall, built in the latter part of the 11th century. Close to it rises the slender campanile called <name type="historical" ref="Torre_del_Mangia">Del Mangia</name> - it stands in the square now called <persName>Vittorio Emanuele</persName>, and used to be the <placeName ref="#Piazza_del_Campo">Piazza del Campo</placeName> - it is strangely semicircular in form, and rising like an amphitheatre. <bibl><author><persName ref="#Dante_Alighieri">Dante</persName></author>, in his <title>Purgatorio</title></bibl> speaks of this piazza. The interior is very interesting - with frescoes of the <orgName ref="#Siennese">Siennese</orgName> masters - a large one of the <objectName type="fresco" ref="#Siena_Virgin_and_child">Virgin and child</objectName>, with a canopy borne by saints, and opposite an equestrian portrait of a martial figure of <objectName ref="painting" ref="#Fogliani_de_Ricci">Fogliani de Ricci</ojectName> - by <persName ref="#Simone_Martini">Simone Martini</persName>. In the <name type="historical" ref="#Sala_dei_Nove">Sala dei Nova</name>, are <objectName type="fresco" ref="#Allegory_and_Effects">frescoes</objectName> by <persName type="historical" ref="#Ambrogio_Lorenzetti">Ambrogio Lorenzetti</persName> painted in 1337-39 - much injured by dampness, but most quaint and interesting. Then we went to the <name type="historical" ref="Duomo_di_Siena">Duomo</name>, which was begun in the early part of the 13th century. It is built in courses of white and black marble, which at first give a very bizarre effect - but the infinite variety of detail, and the richness of the marbles make the interior very interesting. The pavement too is remarkably rich in graffiti - though much of it is covered with boards and cannot be seen.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-04-14" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1895-04-14">Easter, April 14.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>We spent most of the morning at the <name type="historical" ref="Duomo_di_Siena">Duomo</name>, listening to a high mass - music not very good, but the whole scene was impressive. When we all became quite frozen we came away. It has been raining a little all day - and I have been indoors all the afternoon. At sunset last evening, <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName>, <persName ref="#Parsons_Mary">Mary</persName> and I walked to the fortress as it is called, or the "Lizza"<!--tag?--> a beautiful promenade with fine trees and shrubberies up the side of a former fortress built by <persName type="historical" ref="#Charles_V">Charles V</persName>, - giving charming views from its height over plain and mountains.</p> 
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-04-15" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1895-04-15">Easter Monday, April 15.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>The rain of yesterday has given place to a cloudy cold day - and putting on our warmest wraps we went after breakfast to the Baptistry of the <name type="historical" ref="Duomo_di_Siena">Duomo</name>, which I called <persName>S. Giovanni</persName>, and forms a kind of crypt - though the front is open to the small piazza of <placeName>S. Giovanni</placeName>. There is here the most wonderful marble font, with splendid bronze reliefs by <persName type="historical" ref="#Lorenzo_Ghiberti">Ghiberti</persName> and <persName type="historical" ref="#Jacopo_della_Quercia">J. della Quercia</persName>, and <persName type="historical" ref="#Donatello">Donatello</persName>. There are 2 especially beautiful bronzes by <persName type="historical" ref="#Donatello">Donatello</persName> at the corners of the reliefs - figures of <objectName type="statue" ref="Hope">Hope</objectName> and <objectName type="staute" ref="Faith">Faith</objectName> - the lines so grand - the pose so dignified and natural - and 3 delicious little bronze cherubs, quite perfect - the beautiful marble work is by <persName type="historical" ref="#Jacopo_della_Quercia">della Quercia</persName>. Then we went to the <name type="historical" ref="#Opera_del_Duomo">Opera del Duomo</name>, over the way and saw many wondrous things. Quite the most wonderful were the paintings of <persName type="historical" ref="#Duccio_di_Buoninsegna">Duccio di Buoninsegna</persName> an early <orgName ref="#Sienese">Sienese</orgName> painter of the 13th century. I have never before seen any of his works - and in the novelty of the surprise I am almost ready to declare they are the mot beautiful things I have ever seen - certainly I have never seen more exquisite, sweet, religious entiment. A large Madonna with child and saints, and 26 little pictures illustrating the life of Christ. Afterwards we went into the <name type="historical" ref="Duomo_di_Siena">Duomo</name>, where was a large congregation and a monk preaching in the most energetic manner. We walked about and then went into the small and rich chapel of <persName>S. Giovanni</persName> - an admirable Renaissance work - with a statue of <persName type="historical" ref="#John_the_Baptist">John the Baptist</persName> in bronze by <persName type="historical" ref="#Donatello">Donatello</persName> - a font by <persName type="historical" ref="#Jacopo_della_Quercia">Jacopo della Quercia</persName> - and small frescoes by <persName type="historical" ref="#Pinturicchio">Pintoricchio</persName> and <persName type="historical" ref="#Baldassare_Peruzzi">Baldassare Peruzzi</persName> - illustrative of the life of the Baptist. Then into the <placeName>Library of the Duomo</placeName> <!--tag?-->- a magnificent vaulted room, with enormous frescoes by <persName type="historical" ref="#Pinturicchio">Pintoricchio</persName> - rather crude in colouring but fine in treatment and perspective - with a superb collection of old Missals, some of them with exquisite miniatures by <persName type="historical" ref="#Liberale_da_Verona">Liberali da Verona</persName>. Then across the street to the <name type="historical" ref="#Santa_Maria_della_Scala">hospital of S. Maria della Scala</name> - just after we had entered the handsome entrance hall a large company of the brothers of the <name>Misericordia</name> <!--tag?-->came in bearning a bier like stretcher with a sick person on it - and as they formed in line and waited, they made quite a scene in their long black robes and cowls. The hospital looked very clean - and in the church was a beautiful organ with artistic brass work by <persName type="historical" ref="#Baldassare_Peruzzi">Peruzzi</persName></p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-04-18" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <placeName ref="#Perugia">Perugia</placeName>.
          <date when="1895-04-18">April 18. Thursday</date>
          <name type="hotel" ref="#Perugia_Grand_Hotel">Grand Hotel</name>.
        </dateline>  
        <p>We made rather an early start on Tuesday morning by rail, and arrived at <placeName ref="#Chiusi">Chiusi</placeName> at 1:30 where we stopped for an hour, and had an excellent lunch at the station. We found two carriages waiting for us which had been sent over by <persName ref="#Beccafumi_Madame">Mme. Beccafumi</persName> - and had an enchanting drive here which we reached at 7 o'clock. For an hour or two before reaching <placeName ref="#Perugia">Perugia</placeName>, our way lay around and by <placeName ref="#Trasimeno_Lago">Lake Thrasymene</placeName> <!--sic?--> giving most charming views, and grew more beautiful as we reached this wonderful old town, lying so almost unapproachably on it mountain height - as we climbed backwards and forwards up to its great walls and fortresses, the sun was going down beyond the mountains above the great <orgName ref="#Umbrian">Umbrian</orgName> plain and the cloud scenery was quite wonderful. Our hotel is very good - and our appartments quite palatial. The house stands on one of the highest parts of the town, commanding a widely magnificent view - with the picturesque town lying about and below us - what a scenery of roofs - campaniles - gardens and winding, climbing roads - with the wide plain far below - and range after range of mountain enclosing it - some of their peaks white with snow. Yesterday morning we went for a walk about the town - then to the <name type="historical" ref="#Cattedrale_Metropolitana_di_San_Lorenzo">Cathedral</placeName> <!--?--> which is poor and uninteresting, but in the sacristy of which is a large painting by <persName type="historical" ref="#Luca_Signorelli">Luca Signorelli</persName> <!--EBAI--> - very lovely in tone and colour - with admirable figures. Then to the old <orgName>Chamber of Commerce</orgName> <!--tag?-->, where the walls are quite covered with paintings and decorations by <persName type="historical" ref="#Pietro_Perugino">Perugino</persName> - and the stalls and seats and panels are most beautifully carved and inlaid by <persName type="historical" ref="#Mercalello_Antonio">Antonio Mercalello</persName> - the designs being quite exquisite. Then we climbed flight after flight of stone steps until we came to the top of the <name type="historical" ref="Palazzo_Pubblico">Palazzo Publico</name>, where is the gallery of paintings - principally of the <orgName ref="#Umbrian">Umbrian</orgName> school. Strange, quaint things most of them were - gathered in from churches and monasteries. In spite of their archaicisms many of them truly charming in sentiment and colouring - especially the <objectName type="painting" ref="#Adoration_of_the_Magi">"Adoration of the Magi"</objectName> and the <objectName ref="#Madonna_and_Angels">Madonna</objectName> with angels playing on instruments by <persName type="historical" ref="Benedetto_Bonfigli">Benedetto Bonfigli</persName> - whose works I have never before seen - nor any of <persName type="historical" ref="#Giovanni_Boccati">Giovanni Boccati da Camerino</persName>, who has a most delightful <objectName type="painting" ref="#Madonna_of_the_Orchestra">"Madonna col Bambino e Molti Angelic che cantano a altri Santi"</objectName> - the choir of angels surround the Madonna's throne in a semicircle leaning over a parapet - their golden heads and pink cheeks most charming, singing with all their might so that one almost hears their voice - little angels on either side the throne, one playing a harp - and the other dear a mandolin - above all a canopy of flowering trees. Now have I ever seen or heard of <persName type="historical" ref="#Fiorenzo_di_Lorenzo">Fiorenzo di Lorenzo</persName> whose four panels illustrating the miracles of <persName type="historical" ref="Saint_Bernardino">S. Bernadino</persName> <!--Bernardino of Siena?-->are delightful in colour, action and sentiment - evidently painted from life in the streets and squares of <placeName ref="#Perugia">Perugia</placeName>. There was an <objectName type="fresco" ref="#Annunciation">Annunciation</objectName> by <persName type="historical" ref="#Piero_della_Francesca">Piero della Francesca</persName>, forming the upper part of a panel containing four saints, done evidently by other hands - figures in the <objectName type="fresco" ref="#Annunciation">Annunciation</objectName> beautiful with fine architectural perspective. After coming out these deadly cold galleries, the bright sun was quite blinding - and to put some warmth into us, we walked through the streets down to the old and picturesque Roman Gate, on it massive <orgName ref="#Etruscan">Etruscan</orgName> foundations, now called the <name type="historical" ref="#Arco_di_Augusto">Arco di Augusto</name>, with the inscription Augusta Perusia on it. I have long had a fine photograph of it. By the time we had climbed the stony street and reached our hotel I was almost dead with fatigue. Today the morning dawned dark and threatening, and it has gone on from bad to worse. We have all stayed indoors writing and grumbling. Among other letters <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> wrote was one to <persName ref="#Fielding_Everard">Everard Fielding</persName>, which was taken out with others late into the hall and laid on the porters desk. Soon afterwards <persName ref="#Fielding_Basil">Basil Fielding</persName> came along, and seeing the letter addressed to his brother, went to the register to see who was likely to have written it - and seeing our names, sent in his card. We were delighted to see the pleasant boy again, and persuaded him and his friend, a priest, <persName ref="#Forbes_Father">Father Forbes</persName> <!--put in EBA-->, to have lunch with us - and after a jolly lunch, and visit, they went out with <persName ref="#Berenson_Bernard">Berenson</persName> to see some sights. They had come from <placeName ref="#Assisi">Assisi</placeName> <!--EBA-->this morning, and went back this afternoon - they are spending their Easter vacation at <placeName ref="#Assisi">Assisi</placeName> - and as we intend driving over there tomorrow (only <measure type="distance">8 miles</measure>) we have arranged to meet and lunch together. <persName ref="#Fielding_Basil">Basil</persName> is still at the <placeName ref="#Scots_College_Rome">Scotch college</placeName> <!--EBA-->in <placeName ref="#Rome">Rome</placeName> - and as rampant a young churchman as ever - we have been promoted today to a very charming apartment just vacated by the <name>Dowager Duchess of Bedford</name> <!--EBA-->-my room is at the corner, overlooking the great <orgName ref="#Umbrian">Umbrian</orgName> plain, with the grand sweep of the <placeName ref="#Mountain_Apennine">Appenines</placeName> <!--EBA--> - and I seem to be hanging in mid air.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-04-20" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <date when="1895-04-20">Saturday, April 20.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>Yesterday the rain poured almost continuously - only clearing for awhile in the afternoon when we took <persName ref="#Buttles_Lizzie">Nettie</persName>, who has not been able to do any sight seeing here, to the Sacristy of the <placeName>Duomo</placeName>, <!--in Siena or Perugia?--> to see <persName type="historical" ref="#Luca_Signorelli">Signorelli</persName>'s beautiful <objectName type="painting" ref="#Madonna_with_Child_and_Saints_Signorelli">Madonna, Child and Saints</persName>. The light was more favorable than on the other day - and we sat a long time in the quiet sacristy looking at it. What harmonious color! Then we went to <name type="historical" ref="#Del_Cambio">del Cambio</placeName>, and then <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> got into the little carriage with <persName ref="#Buttles_Lizzie">Nettie</persName> and me, and we went to the charming church of <persName>S. Pietro di Casimenci</persName> <!--where??-->, with no interesting pictures, but wonderful woodwork and intarsi - and an altogether interesting old basilica of the year 1000. Last night it rained as the femme de chamber expressed it "terriblement" - and all this morning the clouds hung about the valley and trailed along the mountain sides. But we ordered luncheon early, and determined to drive to <placeName ref="#Assisi">Assisi</placeName> - but at the last moment my courage failed, and then <persName ref="#Buttles_Lizzie">Nettie</persName>'s, and so we stayed at home, and were busy all the afternoon at one window or another watching the wonderful cloud effects, and the great marshaling of light and shade across the plain. The carriage came back about 7 o'clock with our poor people chilled and tired - for the weather has changed and it is cold. We are all ready for our start for <placeName ref="#Bologna">Bologne</placeName> tomorrow morning.</p> 
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-04-23" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <name type="hotel" ref="#Hotel_Cavour">Hotel Cavour</name>.
          <placeName ref="#Milan">Milan</placeName>.
          <date when="1895-04-23">April 23.</date>
        </dateline>  
        <p>We left <placeName ref="#Perugia">Perugia</placeName> Sunday morning - the weather having cleared perfectly, giving us perfect views - changed cars at <placeName>Tarantalo</placeName> <!--where?-->- and got an excellent compartment to ourelves quite through to <placeName ref="#Bologna">Bologne</placeName> - the views as we crowned the <placeName ref="#Mountain_Apennine">Appenines</placeName> on that bright day were fine - went to the <Name type="hotel" ref="#Hotel_Brun">Hotel Brun</name>, where we stayed 9 years ago, and had the same apartment - grand but very gloomy. The next morning we went to the <name>Belli Arti</name> <!--Accademia di Belle Arti di Bologna?--> and saw some lovely <orgName>Francias</orgName> - <persName type="historical" ref="#Timoteo_Viti">Timeoteo Vitete</persName> <objectName type="painting" ref="#Mary_Magdalene_Viti">"Magdalen"</objectName>, <persName type="historical" ref="#Raphael">Raphael</persName>'s <objectName type="painting" ref="#Estacy_of_St_Cecilia_Raphael">St. Cecilia</objectName> - a lovely <objectName type="painting" ref="#Madonna_and_Child_Cima">Madonna</objectName> by <persName type="historical" ref="#Cima_Giovanni_Battista">Cima</persName>. We spent most of the morning there, and then went to the <placeName>Museo Civico</placeName>, where we spent a rather unsatisfactory hour. In the afternoon we drove up to <name type="historical" ref="#San_Michele">S. Michele in Bosco</name> <!--EBAI-->- a rather interesting and handsome church of the <orgName ref="#Olivetans">Olivetans</placeName> <!--EBAI-->- the monastery now changed into an <orgName ref="Orthopedic_Hospital_Bologna">Orthopedic Hospital</placeName> <!--EBAI--> with a beautiful view. On our way home <persName ref="#Berenson_Bernard">Mr. Berenson</persName> took us to the <placeName>San Vitale</placeName> <!--in Ravenna?-->church to show us a beautiful <persName>Francia</persName> - an altar piece - two angels with a lovely landscape. We hould have left <placeName ref="#Bologna">Bologne</placeName>at 6 o'clock - but on reaching the station heard that our train was 40 minutes late - but the waiting was very amusing - for a number of church dignitaries were waiting for an incoming train which was to bring an eminence of Cardinal Archbishop, with numerous clerical belongings to attend an important meeting. He proved an amiable looking old man - and was most respectfully greeted by the crowd. We were late getting here - and were disappointed not to get our old rooms - the hotel is crowded - and so are the trains with tourists coming north - by the time our luggage arrived and we had our supper, it was not far from one o'clock. This morning we started out soon after breakfast for the <name type="historical" ref="#Poldi_Pezzoli">Poldi Pezzoli</name> <!--EBAI-->, and spent an hour or more - then to the <name type="histocial" ref="#Biblioteca_Ambrosiana">Ambrosiana</name> <!--EBAI--> - and home by one o'clock tired indeed. In the afternoon <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> and <persNamem ref="#Berenson_Bernard">Berenson</persName> went to a private gallery to see some pictures, and then <persName ref="#Berenson_Bernard">Berenson</persName>, <persName ref="#Buttles_Lizzie">Nettie</persName> and I got into a little open cab, and drove to <name type="historical" ref="#Basilica_San_Lorenzo">S. Lorenzo</persName> <!--EBAI-->, the eldest church in <placeName ref="#Milan">Milan</placeName> - with remains of <orgName ref="#Roman">Roman</orgName> buildings about it - and in the street near it are 16 <objectName type="">Corinithian columns</objectName> <!--tag?-->, which remain from an ancient colonnade. Then to <name type="historical" ref="#Santa_Maria_presso_San_Celso">S. Maria preso S. Celso</name> <!--EBAI--> where I went the last time - and we stopped for a few moments at the magnificent <name type="historica" ref="#Policlinico_of_Milan">Opidale Maggiore</name> <!--EBAI-->- which is so vast that there are 9 courts in it.</p>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="EBA-1895-04-26" type="entry">
        <dateline>
          <placeName ref="#Milan">Milan</placeName>.
          <date when="1895-04-26">Friday, April 26.</date>
        </dateline>
        <p>Wednesday was a gloomy day - and I was too wretched to leave the house. We went to <name>Bergamo</name> at 4 o'clock p.m. - arriving there at 5:30 - went to the <placeName>Hotel d'Italia</placeName> - and were decently comfortable - after we had ordered 3 big fires made in our rooms. We must have had all the god rooms of the principal floor - and the last entry in the visitors' book was Nov. 24, '94. My room was a big ghostly thing, which with a big fire became almost cheerful - and the curtains over my bed were presided over by a big holden goose. We all crowded into a big landau the next morning and drove to the church of <persName>S. Bartolomeo</persName> - where is a splendid fascinating altar picture of <persName>Lotto</persName>'s - a <persName>Madonna</persName> and ten saints - <persName ref="#Berenson_Bernard">Mr. Berenson</persName> ordered down all the altar decorations so that we might better see the picture - and we stayed in the deadly cold little church, until we were petrified, looking at the delicious picture. In <persName ref="#Berenson_Bernard">Berenson</persName>'s recent book on <persName>Lotto</persName>, which we have not yet seen, he reproduces the principal <orgName>Lottos</orgName> - so that I won't try any description of those lovely pictures myself, but will better refresh my memory in the future by reading his descriptions. Then we went to the <placeName>S. Spirito</placeName> church - and saw another great altar piece by <persName>Lotto,</persName> the <persName>Madonna</persName> with four saints with angels in a glory above. Then to the church of <placeName>S. Bernardino</placeName> with another altar piece of <persName>Madonna</persName> and saints - quite the most beautiful of all. Then we drove to the upper town and visited <persName>S. Maria Maggiore</persName> with the adjoining chapel of <placeName>"Collogni",</placeName> most richly decorated - and the <orgName>Cathedral</orgName>, with superb tapestries, and wonderful serena and woodwork in the choir from <name>Lotto</name>'s designs. It rained quite hard by the time we drove back to the lower town. <persName ref="#Berenson_Bernard">Mr. Berenson</persName> had arranged with his friend <persName>Signor Pichinelli</persName>, one of the directors of the <orgName>Museum</orgName>, and who is the owner of many good pictures, not only to show them to us, but to take us to the palace of the <placeName>Moroni</placeName> family , and to show us two or three other places - so that soon after lunch we again packed ourselves into the carriage or rather into 2, and drove to the <placeName>Maison Pichinelli</placeName>, a most charming house with superb grounds in good order. We were received most hospitably and talked our little <orgName ref="#French">French</orgName> and <orgName ref="#Italian">Italian</orgName> as best we could - and then <persName>Signor P.</persName> went with us to the <placeName>Moroni palace</placeName>, a magnificent house in the highest part of the old town - where in a splendid loftly room we saw two of the most splendid <orgName>Moroni</orgName>'s - which have never been photographed. One of a young man in a lovely harmony of red - and the other a most distinguished middle aged man in black against a gray background - the pose, character, colour, quite perfect. While we were looking at these, the Countess <persName>Loroni</persName> arrived, a charming little person, who did the honours of her house most graciously - and took us from one pretty room to another, filled with pictures and bric-a-brac. After that we went to the <placeName>Roucardi</placeName> palace, a gloomy magnificent house - with interesting family pictures - then to the <placeName>Baglioni house</placeName> - still more gloomy, and damp - but with an excellent collection of pictures etc. - an especially beautiful <persName>Cariani,</persName> and some <name>Guardis</name> - the rain poured all the afternoon and evening. This morning we went to the famous <placeName>Bergamo Gallery</placeName> - a small gallery - but of exquisite quality - what treasures - and what a pleasure! The morning was beautifully clear and for the first time we saw the wide view from the upper town - we took a drive around the castle and were home in time for a hurried lunch, and off for the station, where we had to say a reluctant goodbye to <persName>Berenson</persName>, who had to go to <placeName>Venice</placeName> to join Mrs. <persName>Jack Gardiner</persName> for a day or two. We got back to <placeName ref="#Milan">Milan</placeName> at 2:30 and <persName ref="#Buttles_Lizzie">Nettie</persName>, <persName ref="#Parsons_Mary">Mary</persName> and I drove from the station to the <placeName>Brera</placeName>, where <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore_M">Theodore</persName> afterwards joined us - and afterwards he and I went to the private house where he had seen two little <orgName ref="#Dutch">Dutch</orgName> pictures for sale, and after having another look at them decided to telegraph <persName ref="#Berenson_Bernard">Berenson</persName> to buy them for him. We are all ready for our journey to <placeName>Lucerne</placeName> tomorrow. 1894 - 1895 1</p>
      </div>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>